<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:36:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the Community College National Legislative&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-community-college-national-legislative-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington, D.C.  Thank you, Chair Cooksey—Jim—and thank you to Dr. Richard Rhodes as well. It has been my privilege to work with ACCT and AACC as Second Lady and now First Lady.  But as a teacher, I want to say on behalf of my colleagues and students, just how grateful we are for your leadership. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Washington, D.C. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Thank you, Chair Cooksey—Jim—and thank you to Dr. Richard Rhodes as well. It has been my privilege to work with ACCT and AACC as Second Lady and now First Lady. <br><br>But as a teacher, I want to say on behalf of my colleagues and students, just how grateful we are for your leadership. <br><br>With us today are some of the hardest working and determined advocates for community colleges. <br><br>But I want to especially acknowledge the students. I know that, with work and family obligations on top of your studies, it probably wasn’t easy to get here today. But you came because you know that showing up matters. Thank you for using your voice on behalf of your community.  <br><br>Some of you may know that I’m an enormous sports fan. I’m a First Lady for all Americans—but when it comes to teams, my heart belongs to the Philadelphia Eagles, 76ers, Phillies, and Flyers alone. <br><br>The competition, the crowds, the rivalries—I love it all. <br><br>But too often, we treat what happens in our nation’s capital like a sports game too—wondering which team will score the most points with voters. <br><br>Legislation becomes a football to keep away from the other side, and Americans get lost in the playbook. <br><br>Governing isn’t a game. There are no teams to root for or against, just people—Americans from all walks of life—who need help and hope. <br><br>There’s no scoreboard—there’s no “us” versus “them.” If someone wins it doesn’t mean someone else has to lose. And most of all, there are no spectators. All of us must do our part because the decisions that are made in the halls of Congress and the rooms of the White House affect us all.<br><br>You know that. It’s why you’re here today. You know what’s at stake. <br><br>One year ago, I told this group that Joe was going to fight for community colleges. And since then, we’ve made some incredible progress. <br><br>The American Rescue Plan put billions into community colleges so they could support their students through financial aid, child care support, and other wraparound services. <br><br>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law passed, creating millions of new jobs—along with potential opportunities to train for in-demand skills. But Joe has also had to make compromises. Congress hasn’t passed the Build Back Better agenda—yet. And free community college is no longer a part of that package. <br><br>We knew this wouldn’t be easy—Joe has always said that. <br><br>Still, like you, I was disappointed. Because—like you—these aren’t just bills or budgets to me. We know what they mean for real people. For our students. <br><br>We’ve seen how entire towns can be transformed when community colleges and private companies work together to train students for jobs that are desperately needed—with skills like manufacturing or modernizing our electrical grid. <br><br>We’ve seen how fragile that grasp on a middle-class life can be—how our students struggle to pay their bills and buy their books. We know that if we can make that path a little easier—with high speed internet, or affordable prescriptions, or more Pell grants—they can actually cross that finish line.  <br><br>We’ve all had that bright, engaged student—someone who has so much passion and potential—fade from our classes because they can’t find a reliable baby sitter. They start missing lectures, they fall behind and just can’t catch up. Or the cost of child care just gets to be too much, and they have to choose between extra shifts at work and pursuing the degree that will help them earn more money. <br><br>But there is no choice when it comes to keeping your kids safe. And one day, that student is just gone. It breaks my heart.  <br><br>So, we know that affordable child care and universal preschool would profoundly change people’s lives. <br><br>Build Back Better isn’t just a piece of legislation. And it’s certainly not a football to pass or pivot.<br><br>It’s about helping community colleges train our workforce for 21st-century skills. <br><br>It’s about supporting students with tutoring, child care, and transportation. <br><br>It’s about pioneering the new climate jobs that will lead us into the future. <br><br>And it’s an investment in our kids, with universal preschool that will lay a foundation to learn and succeed for the rest of their lives. <br><br>No one can tell that story better than you. No one can help us push past the playbook and see the human heart that drives our work better than you. <br><br>Governing does have one thing in common with sports. When you get knocked down, you have to get back up. When you lose, you work harder and you come back for more. <br><br>There are a lot of reasons that I wanted Joe to run for president—but one of the biggest was because I knew that no one would work harder for my students and yours. <br><br>I’ve never believed that more than I do today. <br><br>Joe doesn’t quit. He doesn’t give up. <br><br>He is keeping his promise to rebuild our middle class and he knows that community colleges do just that. He knows that you are our greatest resource and our best investment. He will keep fighting for us.  <br><br>So, thank you for being here. This is how we move forward, step by step. We take the hard-won victories and we keep pushing for the change we need. With work and persistence, we will win the progress our students deserve.<br><br>Joe and I are with you. We will continue to work as hard for your community as you do. We are not giving up.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White&#160;House Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/white-house-task-force-on-worker-organizing-and-empowerment-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 14:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment – led by Vice President Harris as Chair and Labor Secretary Walsh as Vice-Chair – released publicly the report it delivered to President Joe Biden that includes nearly 70 recommendations to promote worker organizing and collective bargaining for federal employees, and for workers employed by public and private-sector employers.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment – led by Vice President Harris as Chair and Labor Secretary Walsh as Vice-Chair – <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/White-House-Task-Force-on-Worker-Organizing-and-Empowerment-Report.pdf">released publicly the report it delivered to President Joe Biden</a> that includes nearly 70 recommendations to promote worker organizing and collective bargaining for federal employees, and for workers employed by public and private-sector employers.</p>



<p>Additionally, the recommendations include ways to increase private sector workers’ access to information about their existing right to join and/or organize a union, and the legally-defined process of how to do so.</p>



<p>Read the entire report<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/White-House-Task-Force-on-Worker-Organizing-and-Empowerment-Report.pdf"> here.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call Previewing the German Chancellor&#8217;s&#160;Visit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/07/background-press-call-previewing-the-german-chancellors-visit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[5:09 P.M. EST MODERATOR:  Thank you, everyone, for joining us today on this background press call previewing the German Chancellor’s visit tomorrow.  As a reminder of the ground rules, this briefing will be on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow, Monday, February 7th. For your own awareness but not for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>5:09 P.M. EST<br> <br>MODERATOR:  Thank you, everyone, for joining us today on this background press call previewing the German Chancellor’s visit tomorrow. <br> <br>As a reminder of the ground rules, this briefing will be on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow, Monday, February 7th.<br> <br>For your own awareness but not for reporting, the senior administration official on today’s call is [senior administration official].<br> <br>[Senior administration official], I’ll turn it over to you for opening remarks, after which we’ll do Q&amp;A.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, [senior administration official], and thanks to everybody for joining.  Delighted to have the opportunity to speak with you tonight about the Chancellor’s visit to Washington tomorrow.<br> <br>President Biden is very much looking forward to welcoming Chancellor Scholz on his first visit to Washington and the White House, and sees it as a good opportunity to affirm the deep and enduring ties between the United States and Germany. <br> <br>Germany is one of our closest and strongest Allies in Europe.  The President and the Chancellor had the opportunity to interact last October in Rome at the G20 Summit.  Scholz, at the time, was serving as Finance Minister and coalition negotiations were going on.  But it was clear that he was the presumptive chancellor, which is why then-Chancellor Merkel brought him along to the meeting of the <s>P3</s> [Quad] countries, so it gave the President an opportunity to have an initial conversation with him as part of the handover from Chancellor Merkel to ensure continuity.</p>



<p>The President had a very early congratulatory call with Chancellor Scholz, and they have since consulted together with other European leaders a few times over the last two months since he became Chancellor.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is looking forward to getting to know Chancellor Scholz personally on this first official visit to Washington as head of state.&nbsp; And I would say that the fact he is coming here almost two months to the day from taking office illustrates the continued importance that the United States places on our bilateral relationship with Germany and the importance of this relationship between these two leaders.<br>&nbsp;<br>The leaders have a very full agenda to discuss tomorrow.&nbsp; We expect them to talk significantly about the situation in Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; They’ll likely discuss their shared concerns about Russia’s military buildup on Ukraine’s border and their shared commitment to both ongoing diplomatic efforts to encourage Russia to de-escalate tensions as well as ongoing efforts to ensure deterrence to further Russian aggression.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Related to that, they will discuss our ongoing efforts to prepare a robust sanctions package that would impose severe costs if Russia further invades Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>Germany, at the start of the year, assumed the presidency of the G7, and so I expect that will be a significant part of their conversation as well, including Germany’s agenda and the way our two countries can work together with fellow G7 members to address global challenges.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Many of the things that comprise Germany’s G7 agenda are priorities for the Biden administration as well, including the importance of continued close cooperation on ending the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing the threat of climate change, and promoting economic prosperity and international security based on our shared democratic values.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, I expect the leaders will want to discuss their support for the Western Balkans, which is a priority region in Europe for both the United States and for Germany, and how we can continue to promote stability in the region, as well as continue to make progress on the further European integration of the Western Balkans; as well as our collective response to undemocratic moves by China and continued efforts within the transatlantic relationship, including in our bilateral relationship, on how we can work together to address China’s nonmarket economic practices and human rights abuses.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, just closing thought: The United States and Germany have long worked together to address the world’s most important challenges, and we see the meeting tomorrow as an opportunity to ensure the continuity of close relations between the United States and Germany, to give the two leaders an opportunity to get to know one another personally, and an opportunity for them to discuss all of the pressing global challenges that both of our countries are facing today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let me stop there with opening comments and happy to turn it over to questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this &#8212; and [senior administration official].&nbsp; I wanted to ask about Nord Stream.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s been a lot of tension over that.&nbsp; The President has opposed that project for a long time.&nbsp; What role do you think Nord Stream will play in this discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>And if I could just follow up on the sanctions question as well &#8212; or the sanctions issue: Can you say what the German position is now about SWIFT?&nbsp; There&#8217;s been, kind of, a lot of back and forth.&nbsp; But is that a serious option for, you know, imposing costs on Russia?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much for the questions.&nbsp; In terms of the &#8212; to take your second question first, in terms of the German position on SWIFT, I don&#8217;t want to characterize what their government&#8217;s view is, so I would refer you to them to set out what their position is on the package of sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>But certainly, what I can say is: We have been coordinating very closely with Germany &#8212; including in advance of the Chancellor&#8217;s visit and just more generally over the last number of weeks, as we have with our other European partners &#8212; on a swift and severe package of sanctions that the U.S. and Europe would both impose on Russia in the event of an invasion on Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, lots of conversations with Germany and very much welcome the unity that we have been seeing from our European Allies and partners on their readiness to join with us in imposing swift and severe consequences on Russia if there is further aggression.<br>&nbsp;<br>And on Nord Stream, this, as you alluded to, is a topic that we have had numerous conversations with the German government about &#8212; with the Merkel government, as well as with the Scholz government.&nbsp; I would assume that it is going to be a topic of conversation between the leaders tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>And what I can say is that we have made our position very clear, which is that: If Russia invades Ukraine, one way or another Nord Stream 2 will not move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Senior administration official], have the Germans assured you that they are in agreement with this position?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, again, I&#8217;m not going to speak on behalf of the Germans, and we&#8217;ll let them for themselves tomorrow, and we&#8217;ll let the Chancellor speak.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, what I &#8212; what I can say is that we&#8217;ve had extensive common- &#8212; conversations with the Germans.&nbsp; We&#8217;re confident that the Germans share our concerns with Russian aggression, that they&#8217;re very involved in our ongoing efforts on both deterrence and diplomacy.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have made our position very clear, as I laid out.&nbsp; And what I can say is that we will continue to work very closely with Germany to ensure the pipeline does not move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you so much for doing this call on a Sunday.&nbsp; You know, I mean, the narrative that&#8217;s out there is that Germany has kind of been the outlier, in terms of the NATO nations, in not being particularly specific or aggressive in laying out the costs that they would impose.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m wondering if the White House is satisfied with the new German government&#8217;s, you know, approach so far to laying out costs if Russia were to invade and will the President be encouraging the Chancellor to play more of a leadership role in the, sort of, NATO/Western diplomatic effort to deter a Russian invasion.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for that question.&nbsp; And certainly recognize that &#8212; that that&#8217;s the narrative that&#8217;s been out there.&nbsp; You know, what I can say from the perspective of the White House is that we have been engaged very closely with our German partners, including the new German administration over the two months since they&#8217;ve taken office.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I said earlier, we&#8217;ve been coordinating with them very closely on the packages of sanctions that we would put into place.&nbsp; We&#8217;re coordinating very closely with them within NATO.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know there&#8217;s been a lot of churn over this question about: Is Germany going to send arms?&nbsp; What sort of role is it playing on the security side?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would point out a number of things:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, Germany, after the United States, is the second-largest donor to Ukraine and to Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, Germany has been very supportive of the things that the United States has done militarily.&nbsp; Most recently, as we announced last week, supporting our ability to move a battalion from Germany into Romania to reinforce and ensure our Ally in Romania, our Allies in the eastern flank are feeling a sufficient reassurance and deterrence to Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>And third, as an overarching point, the beauty of having an alliance with 30 NATO Allies is that different Allies step up to take different approaches to different parts of the problem.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So really, across the board, we have continued to work in close cooperation with Germany on the sanctions front.&nbsp; Germany, as I said, has been a significant donor to Ukraine, including doing a lot on the humanitarian assistance side of things, and, finally, has facilitated a lot of what we have been able to do in terms of our own military deployments of an additional number of troops that are heading out to Germany as part of our “assure and deter mission,” as well as enabling us to get a striker squadron of 1,000 service members very quickly to Romania, because they were already based in the theater in Europe, and specifically in Germany.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I really think, across the board, Germany continues to be an important member of the transatlantic Alliance, with all of us working together to address different parts of the same problem.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; I guess I would ask to see if you could expand on that a little bit.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;re seeing more public and more strident pronouncements of the &#8212; of a looming invasion &#8212; some of the stuff in the last day or so.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering: Do you expect that you&#8217;ll share &#8212; the meeting will share intelligence to kind of help Germany see, maybe, closer to the view of the U.S. of the dangers?&nbsp; And do you, kind of, see &#8212; I know that there&#8217;s consensus on some level but not on others, do you &#8212; are you sensing a coalescing a little bit more of the views between the U.S. and the German government?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, I absolutely think that our countries are unified in terms of awareness of the risk of further Russian aggression to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have been, for a long time, sharing intelligence with Germany, with the rest of our Allies.&nbsp; We are engaged in very regular conversations &#8212; both by the White House, the State Department, our embassy in Berlin, our other agencies &#8212; on the situation.&nbsp; And I think there is absolutely &#8212; absolute agreement that if there is further Russian aggression that there&#8217;s a number of things that need to be done &#8212; in terms of deployment of additional troops to the eastern flank, and to the imposition of a large package of economic sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Germany has been completely on board with the statements that have come out of the European Council meeting, the European Foreign Affairs Council on this.&nbsp; There was a statement that came out by G7 Foreign Ministers a number of weeks ago, and NATO has spoken to this as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m absolutely confident that Germany shares our concerns over Russian aggression, shares our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re continuing to work closely with them and the EU on what this package of severe economic sanctions would look like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And equally, we are both committed to trying to make diplomacy work.&nbsp; One of the things I should have mentioned in talking about the comparative advantage a few minutes ago is that Germany has also played a very significant diplomatic role through its leadership, along France, in the Normandy Format.&nbsp; And those meetings have continued both at foreign minister level and at national security advisor level by the French and Germans in recent weeks, with more engagement expected in the coming week.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, certainly, across the board on all of these things, I think there is very much unity of purpose and agreement on the need to be able to respond either diplomatically or in terms of sanctions and deterrence, depending on which path Putin chooses.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this call.&nbsp; You said that if Russia invades, you know, one way or another Nord Stream 2 won&#8217;t happen.&nbsp; Are there also conversations underway about how to block Nord Stream from becoming operational if Russia does not invade in the next few months and if, you know, it makes its way through the German regulatory process?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m not going to engage in hypotheticals.&nbsp; I &#8212; certainly, everybody hopes that that Russia does not invade, and then that’s going to be a question that &#8212; that we&#8217;re going to have to deal with.<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, the one thing that I will point out is that there is not currently any gas flowing through the pipeline.&nbsp; And there won&#8217;t be any gas for months, in part because of the diplomacy that the United States has been able to do on this issue with Germany.<br>&nbsp;<br>The &#8212; Germany&#8217;s Federal Network Agency, as you know, has suspended the certification process of Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; So, the pipeline is not currently operational and no gas is expected to flow through that pipeline anytime soon.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as you noted, there are steps that need to be taken by the German regulatory agency.&nbsp; There&#8217;s also steps that need to be taken by the EU regulatory agency.&nbsp; So, you know, more broadly, our position remains what it has been, which is that we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve always been opposed to Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; The President has made this &#8212; this clear for several years now, which he views as a Russian geopolitical project that undermines the energy security and national security of a significant part of the Euro-Atlantic community.<br>&nbsp;<br>We engaged in significant diplomacy with the Germans last summer, leading to agreement on a joint statement that sets out a number of things that we intend to do to ensure that Russia does not use energy as a weapon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, so I&#8217;ve spoken to what our position is now &#8212; if there is Russian aggression against Ukraine &#8212; in terms of ensuring that one way or another Nord Stream 2 will not move forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If we are in the happy situation where there is not a Russian invasion and we are able to move along the diplomatic path, we will continue to engage in conversations with Germany and our European partners about this issue more broadly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know that you’ve answered several questions on Nord Stream; I was just hoping to try to put a finer point on it as well.&nbsp; Over the summer when Chancellor Scholz’s predecessor visited with President Biden, there was an announcement about an agreement that the U.S. and Germany had reached about the operationality of Nord Stream 2, and I&#8217;m wondering if that agreement still holds up under the new administration and if you could detail exactly what that agreement is.<br>&nbsp;<br>And second, in the statement between the U.S. and the EU a couple of weeks ago, it said that tomorrow would also see a meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if you could detail a little bit more about whether that meeting is still taking place and what it is.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, that meeting on the U.S.-EU Energy Council is being chaired by the State Department along with the EU, so I would refer you to the State Department to be able to get more information on that.&nbsp; This is something that had been set up a number of years ago, which provides an opportunity for the United States and the European Union to come together at the level of Secretary of State here in the United States, as well as the Energy Secretary, with their counterparts on the EU side.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, lots to talk about and &#8212; in general terms and with energy issues, with our shared commitment to addressing climate change.&nbsp; And in the current context, I would expect that Ukraine is going to be a significant part of that discussion as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the statement, this was agreed, as you said, between the Biden administration and the Merkel administration.&nbsp; It was published on July 21st.&nbsp; And I just pulled it up on my computer here as we were talking, and the joint statement is actually on the State Department website, so you can take a look at that and read it in full, and it outlines the commitments that our two governments made.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is certainly something that we continue to view as an operative agreement that &#8212; that holds.&nbsp; We are continuing to have conversations about this agreement with the new Scholz administration, and they are continuing to implement the agreement.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s a number of things that are included in here in terms of, you know, commitments that they have made to address energy security issues, to abide by the spirit and letter of the Third Energy Package with respect to Nord Stream 2, you know, including climate change, to setting up a new climate and energy partnership, to German commitments to establish and administer a Green Fund for Europe, as well as the readiness of both of our countries to take a number of steps in response to &#8212; I&#8217;m looking at &#8212; sorry &#8212; “…to ensure the U.S. and the EU remain prepared, including with appropriate tools and mechanisms to respond together to Russian aggression, malign activities, including Russian efforts to use energy as a weapon.&nbsp; Should Russia attempt to use energy as a weapon or commit further aggressive acts against Ukraine, Germany will take action at the national level and press for effective measures at the European level, including sanctions to limit Russian export capabilities…This commitment is designed to ensure that Russia will not misuse any pipeline, including Nord Stream 2, to achieve aggressive political ends by using energy as a weapon.”<br>&nbsp;<br>So, sorry for the lengthy quotation from that.&nbsp; You can see the entire document on the website.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But yes, we very much still see this as an operational agreement.&nbsp; We see it as something that the Scholz administration remains bound by, even though it was negotiated by his predecessor.&nbsp; Scholz, of course, was part of that government as Vice Chancellor.&nbsp; And we continue to discuss with the German government the implementation of the provisions, including in this joint agreement.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Again, this is all the time &#8212; that is all of the questions we have time for.&nbsp; I appreciate you joining the call.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and is embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow morning, Monday, February 7th &#8212; February 7th.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you, and I hope everyone has a wonderful day.<br>&nbsp;<br>5:31 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr.’s Call with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/06/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-s-call-with-prime-minister-naftali-bennett-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 22:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of Israel to reaffirm the warm and historic partnership between the United States and Israel.&#160; The leaders discussed the shared security and other challenges in the Middle East region, including the threat posed by Iran and its proxies. &#160;The President underscored his commitment&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of Israel to reaffirm the warm and historic partnership between the United States and Israel.&nbsp; The leaders discussed the shared security and other challenges in the Middle East region, including the threat posed by Iran and its proxies. &nbsp;The President underscored his commitment to expanding stability and partnerships across the Middle East region, as exemplified by the Abraham Accords,&nbsp;together with Israelis and Palestinians enjoying equal measures of security, freedom, and prosperity.&nbsp;&nbsp;They discussed the recent U.S. operation against the ISIS leader in northwestern Syria and the ongoing U.S. commitment to protect the American people and support the defense of its partners across the Middle East region.&nbsp; President Biden conveyed his unwavering support for Israel’s security and freedom of action, emphasizing his administration’s full support for replenishing Israel’s Iron Dome system.&nbsp; The two leaders also discussed global challenges outside of the Middle East region, including the potential of further Russian aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp; The President thanked the Prime Minister for his invitation to visit Israel and said he looks forward to a visit later this year.&nbsp; They agreed that their teams would remain in close consultation.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr.’s Call with President Emmanuel Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/06/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-s-call-with-president-emmanuel-macron-of-france-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 21:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France. The leaders discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders, and affirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They agreed their teams will remain in touch and continue consulting with our Allies&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France. The leaders discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders, and affirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They agreed their teams will remain in touch and continue consulting with our Allies and partners, including Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on 900,000 American Deaths from&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/04/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-900000-american-deaths-from-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 02:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, our nation marks another tragic milestone — 900,000 American lives have been lost to COVID-19. They were beloved mothers and fathers, grandparents, children, brothers and sisters, neighbors, and friends. Each soul is irreplaceable. We pray for the loved ones they have left behind, and together we keep every family enduring this pain in our hearts. After nearly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, our nation marks another tragic milestone — 900,000 American lives have been lost to COVID-19. They were beloved mothers and fathers, grandparents, children, brothers and sisters, neighbors, and friends. Each soul is irreplaceable. We pray for the loved ones they have left behind, and together we keep every family enduring this pain in our hearts.<br> <br>After nearly two years, I know that the emotional, physical, and psychological weight of this pandemic has been incredibly difficult to bear. I know what it’s like to stare at an empty chair around the kitchen table. But I also know that we carry an incredible capacity within ourselves — not only to come through our grief stronger, but to come together to protect one another.<br> <br>We now have more tools than ever before to save lives and fight this virus — with vaccines remaining our most important tool. Vaccines and boosters have proven incredibly effective, and offer the highest level of protection. Two hundred and fifty million Americans have stepped up to protect themselves, their families, and their communities by getting at least one shot — and we have saved more than one million American lives as a result.<br> <br>We can save even more lives — and spare countless families from the deepest pain imaginable — if everybody does their part. I urge all Americans: get vaccinated, get your kids vaccinated, and get your booster shot if you are eligible. It’s free, easy, and effective — and it can save your life, and the lives of those you love.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Signing of an Executive Order on Project Labor&#160;Agreements</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/04/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-an-executive-order-on-project-labor-agreements/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Upper Marlboro, MD 2:16 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT: &#160;That&#8217;s progress. &#160;(Applause.) &#160;You know &#8212; folks, thank you. &#160;(Applause.) &#160;(Laughs.) Thank you. Before I begin my somewhat formal remarks, walking in here today and seeing you guys sitting on that beam &#8212; the first &#8220;Local&#8221; ever to endorse me was a guy named Tommy Schrank (ph)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Upper Marlboro, MD</p>



<p>2:16 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;That&#8217;s progress. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;You know &#8212; folks, thank you. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;(Laughs.) Thank you.<br><br>Before I begin my somewhat formal remarks, walking in here today and seeing you guys sitting on that beam &#8212; the first &#8220;Local&#8221; ever to endorse me was a guy named Tommy Schrank (ph) in Elsmere, Delaware, Local Ironworkers.&nbsp; And he asked me to come out to a site.&nbsp; They took me up on an elevator outside.&nbsp; There was four of them &#8212; crazy sons of guns like you all, sitting and having their lunch on a beam, I guess about 12 stories above the ground.&nbsp; You&#8217;re nuts.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And thank God you are.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I tell you what: You got to not only have some brains, but you got to be coordinated to be an ironworker, man.<br><br>And I was told that &#8212; they said, you know, they&#8217;ve done a cutout of number 46, the vice pres- &#8212; the presidency.&nbsp; I&#8217;m the 46th President.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m thinking, &#8220;Well, maybe I can take it home.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s solid steel, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And you guys did that on your time.&nbsp; Well, thank you very much.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to try and take it home.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But, look, folks, it really is &#8212; it&#8217;s an honor to be here, for real.&nbsp; And I want to thank your soon-to-be new, full-blown, full-bore ironworker.&nbsp; Marty is already trying to get her to Boston, but that&#8217;s another thing I got to warn you about.&nbsp;<br><br>But, folks, look, it&#8217;s an honor to be here with Vice President Harris and with the Labor Secretary, Marty Walsh –- a proud member and former president of the Laborers Local Union 222 &#8212; 223 up in Boston.&nbsp;<br><br>And our Secretary of Energy, Jennifer Granholm, has got a few things we&#8217;re going to build.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and I want to thank the Maryland delegation: Ben Cardin, who&#8217;s been a friend for a long time; and Chris Van Hollen, who&#8217;s a really close friend and an outstanding congressman; Anthony Brown and other elected officials that are here.&nbsp; Look, all of whom fight for the working people, in Maryland and in every &#8212; and every other state.&nbsp; Because if it happens here, it happens around the world &#8212; happens around the country.<br><br>It&#8217;s been an honor to be with the ironworkers of Local 5.&nbsp; And we talk about &#8212; we talk about building a future that’s &#8220;made in America.&#8221;&nbsp; We’re talking about you.&nbsp; And this time we&#8217;re going to get it really correct.<br><br>You know, one of the press persons said to me &#8212; and I can&#8217;t remember who &#8212; about three months ago, that &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s factual or not, but he said, &#8220;You&#8217;ve used the word &#8216;union&#8217; as President more than any other President in American history.&#8221;&nbsp; So, let me tell you &#8212; (applause) &#8212; let me tell you: I’m not sure that it&#8217;s true.<br><br>PARTICPIANT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s true!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; But I tell you what: I promised you you would have a union President.&nbsp; And I am, because you&#8217;re the best.<br><br>You know, we talk about whether, you know, Wall Street built America.&nbsp; There are good folks on Wall Street; they&#8217;re not bad folks.&nbsp; There are good people all over the country.<br><br>I tell you who built America: the middle class.&nbsp; And the people who built the middle class are organized labor &#8212; unions, union.&nbsp; Unions did it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a straight fact.<br><br>And the executive order I’m going to sign today is going to help ensure that we build a better America, we build it right, and we build it on time, and we build it cheaper than it would have been otherwise.<br><br>You know, the executive order is making sure that federal construction projects get completed on time and under budget, saving taxpayers money, clearing construction zones quickly, and ensuring that everything the federal government signs to contract to build is built to last.<br><br>You guys really, genuinely, are the best in the world.&nbsp; Not &#8212; that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a fact.<br><br>To do &#8212; to do that, we’re using a tool that ironworkers here know very well, called &#8220;project labor agreements.&#8221;&nbsp; I know you all know it, but folks who may be watching this may not fully understand it.<br><br>Simply put, these are agreements that contractors, sub-contractors, and unions put in place before a construction site gets underway &#8212; before the construction begins.<br><br>They ensure that major projects are handled by well-trained, well-prepared, highly-skilled workers, and they ward off problems.&nbsp; They resolve disputes ahead of time, ensuring safer work sites, avoiding disruptions and work stoppages that can cause expensive delays down the line.</p>



<p>And that makes a big difference for the American taxpayer.&nbsp; Because when big construction projects are completed efficiently and with the highest degree of professionalism, it’s good for the American taxpayer.&nbsp; That’s not hyperbole; that’s a fact.&nbsp; We don’t talk about it though.&nbsp; We don’t talk about how you all save the American taxpayers money.<br><br>It’s good for families who live in those communities.&nbsp; All across the country, the federal construction projects are being built as I speak.&nbsp; And it means that modernization of your local waterways will get done sooner, won’t cost twice as much as expected.&nbsp; And when the next storm comes, the power will more likely stay on and homes and businesses will be better protected from flooding.<br><br>It means new air traffic control towers at the local airport will be up and running more quickly, so flights are safer at the airports and more efficient.<br><br>It means new housing will be &#8212; built on our military bases will be of the highest quality, which these service members deserve. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp; It will hold up better and make life easier for our military families.<br><br>The executive order I’m going to sign will help defuse problems before they arise.&nbsp; They’re going to improve coordination between contractors, sub-contractors, and workers on the job site.&nbsp; It’s going to help guarantee a consistent supply of high-quality, highly trained workers.</p>



<p>You know, what people don’t understand if they’re not &#8212; don’t know the industry is, you know, it’s like you going to college, kid.&nbsp; Four years.&nbsp; Four years of busting your neck, learning a trade.&nbsp; This isn’t something you walk up and show up in a day and raise your hand, “I need a job.”&nbsp; You work like the devil for it.&nbsp; Fortunately, you get paid while you’re doing it and you’re able to do it, but it is an education &#8212; full-blown education you’re getting in your trade.</p>



<p>You’ll have a voice on the work site, full commitment to getting the job done.<br><br>And it’s going to raise the bar on quality for some of the most vital projects we’re going to be building.<br><br>And we’re going to make sure that federal construction projects are staffed with good-paying union jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of you actually came up to me today and said, “Joe, you said you’re going to do that, and you’re doing it.”&nbsp; Well, when President Obama asked me to run the Recovery Act, I made sure every single job I could get was a union job, prevailing wage.&nbsp; Because I’ve noticed when folks are getting paid a decent wage, everybody in the community does better, everything looks better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re jobs you can raise a family on.&nbsp; Or as my dad would say, “They’re jobs you can put your head on the pillow at night and just have a little breathing room&#8221; &#8212; a little security, a little breathing room.&nbsp; Jobs that can’t be outsourced.<br><br>That’s good for nearly 200,000 workers on federal &#8212; on federal construction contracts right now.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s good for everybody.<br><br>I don’t want to get going because I’ll keep you here too long, because you know all of what I’m about to &#8212; what I’ve said, and you know what I’ve done, and you know what we’re doing, and you know what &#8212; I know what you’re doing.</p>



<p>But let me close with this: A week ago, I went to Pittsburgh to tour a former steel mill that’s now a cutting-edge manufacturing research and development hub.<br><br>Right before I left on that trip, I got word that a bridge collapsed.&nbsp; You saw it on television.&nbsp; It looked as bad in person as it did at the time.&nbsp; The bridge had been rated in poor condition, like, I might add, over 3,000 bridges in Pennsylvania, 45,000 across the nation.&nbsp; It had been rated that way for the last 10 years.<br><br>When I got there, folks told me something close to a miracle had occurred.&nbsp; Because of a snowstorm that morning, school openings were late and commutes were delayed.<br><br>So, when that bridge collapsed &#8212; and it was well over 100 feet off the &#8212; two &#8212; almost two &#8212; I don’t &#8212; I didn’t &#8212; I don’t know the exact, but probably from down to the creek that it went over and the ravine, probably a couple hundred feet.</p>



<p>When it collapsed, instead of a bus with a couple people on it &#8212; being packed with school buses full of children, the people on their way to work on the bridge that is one of the busiest bridges &#8212; you know, there are more bridges in Pittsburgh than any other city in the world; the three rivers &#8212;&nbsp; the bridge was empty &#8212; relatively empty.</p>



<p>Fortunately, no one was killed but for a snowstorm.<br><br>Just imalg- &#8212; imagine the challenges we face and the opportunities to build a better America, and extend it far beyond roads and bridges now that we can &#8212; know what we have to do.&nbsp; We passed that infrastructure bill.&nbsp; But it’s not just that.<br><br>Across the country right now, there are countless buildings, ports, airports, power stations, and other federal construction projects that need to be modernized and built for the future.<br><br>We can’t count on miracles, like happened in &#8212; out in Pittsburgh, to prevent tragedies that are waiting in plain sight.&nbsp;<br><br>But what we can count on, what America has always counted on: the American worker &#8212; the hardest-working, best-trained workers in the world; American workers who, given just half a chance, have never, ever, ever, ever, ever let their country down, and gotten the job done.&nbsp;<br><br>And that’s what this day is all about, in my view: getting the job done for the American taxpayers, getting the job done right the first time.<br><br>You know, folks, there&#8217;s a law that&#8217;s existed for a long time that has too many exceptions like this one had, and that is that &#8212; Buy American.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As President of the United States, I award contracts.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m now making it the case &#8212; and it’s working; it’s one of the reasons those jobs were up &#8212; is unless the product that I&#8217;m purchasing for the American people was made in America and all of its component parts are made in America, we ain&#8217;t buying it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just simply not buying it.<br><br>And what&#8217;s going to happen here &#8212; not a joke; it’s a fact.&nbsp; It’s not a violation of any international laws either.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re talking about here, with three exceptions I won&#8217;t bore you with &#8212; and they&#8217;re highly unusual &#8212; but three exceptions: Every single project that we&#8217;re talking about that’s paid for with federal dollars and is a federal project, it’s going to be union jobs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; every single one of them.<br><br>The last time we tried it, there were so many exceptions, I think only 19, 20 jobs (inaudible).&nbsp; There are going to be thousands &#8212; thousands of people put to work.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I mean, this is serious.&nbsp;<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; The American public is going to be safer, and it&#8217;s going to be cheaper &#8212; cheaper paying the right wage and the right trained people to begin with and get the job done right and on time.<br><br>So, I&#8217;m about to walk over and sign an executive order that&#8217;s going to make that happen.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to start once that order is signed.<br><br>Just remember: It ain&#8217;t labor; it’s unions.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Now, usually you have a pen to give out to everybody around you, but we didn&#8217;t have enough pens to bring with us.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m going to sign this order, but you&#8217;re all going to get one of the signing pens, starting with the Maryland delegation.&nbsp;<br><br>(The executive order is signed.)<br><br>There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>2:30 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>October 2021 Visitor Log Records&#160;Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2022/02/04/october-2021-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Disclosures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in October 2021. This set includes 2858 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 21324. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in October 2021. This set includes 2858 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 21324.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/04/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 20:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:20 P.M. EST&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; I know also there&#8217;s a time limitation today, so we will make sure everybody is where they need to be when they need to be there.&#160;&#160;Good morning.&#160; I just wanted to note at the top: I&#8217;m wearing red today in honor of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:20 P.M. EST<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I know also there&#8217;s a time limitation today, so we will make sure everybody is where they need to be when they need to be there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Good morning.&nbsp; I just wanted to note at the top: I&#8217;m wearing red today in honor of National Wear Red Day and American Heart Month.<br>&nbsp;<br>Heart disease is the leading cause of death in the United States, claiming the lives of 650,000 people every year, with a disproportionate burden on communities of color.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is committed to supporting Americans in their efforts to achieve better heart health and closing the racial gaps in cardiovascular disease.&nbsp; That’s why we’re taking a whole-of-government approach to reduce diet-related chronic diseases and encourage every American to live a healthy lifestyle.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President has also called on Congress to launch his ARPA-H initiative, which would invest billions of dollars in preventing, detecting, and treating cancer, cardiovascular conditions, and other deadly diseases.<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are a number of other red-wearers today in here, too.&nbsp; I don’t want to &#8212; I don’t want to speak to what you picked out of your closet, but maybe you&#8217;re recognizing the same thing.&nbsp;<br> <br>Also wanted to note that a new competition and supply chain announcement that came out today &#8212; yesterday, I should say &#8212; sorry &#8212; from the Justice Department and the U.S. Department of Agriculture.&nbsp; They launched FarmerFairness.gov &#8212; a new online tool that gives farmers and ranchers a one-stop shop for reporting potentially illegal practices in agricultural markets.<br>&nbsp;<br>As the President noted when he met with farmers and ranchers last month, the meat-processing industry is highly consolidated.&nbsp; Just four companies control most of the markets for beef, poultry, and pork.&nbsp; That gives meat processors enormous power over farmers and ranchers.&nbsp; And too often, they use that power to exploit and underpay them.<br>&nbsp;<br>The launch of this new tool is a critical part of the Biden-Harris administration’s Action Plan for a Fairer, More Competitive, and More Resilient Meat and Poultry Supply Chain.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a one-stop shop to report potential violations, and it will allow the Justice Department and the USDA to better address anticompetitive actions and create meat and poultry markets that are fairer to American farmers and ranchers.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, wanted to note this &#8212; shortly, the President will sign an executive order to improve timeliness, lower costs, and increase quality in federal construction projects.&nbsp; The order presumptive &#8212; requires the use of project labor agreements on federal construction projects, which will help the management and coordination challenges that can stymie progress on major construction projects.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Federal construction projects span the country, as we all know, from the maintenance of nuclear sites, to the upkeep at our military bases, to waterways and flood projects.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Based on the FY2021 figures, the order could affect $262 billion in federal government construction contracting and improve job quality for near &#8212; for the nearly 200,000 workers on federal construction contracts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Additionally, as directly in the previous executive order, starting January 30th, federal contractors will be paid a $15 minimum wage.<br>&nbsp;<br>And briefly, the week ahead &#8212; last thing: On Monday, as you all know, the President Biden will welcome the Chancellor of Germany to the White House, Chancellor Scholz.&nbsp; They will affirm the deep and enduring ties with &#8212; between the United States and Germany, and discuss their shared commitment to ongoing diplomacy and joint efforts to deter further Russian aggression against Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>They will also discuss our close cooperation on everything from COVID-19 &#8212; the COVID-19 pandemic to addressing the threat of climate change and promoting international security based on our shared democratic values.<br>&nbsp;<br>They will then participate in a joint press availability following the bilateral meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>On Tuesday and Wednesday, the President will participate in events at the White House, providing updates on his economic plan to lower costs for the American people and create more good-paying jobs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And on Thursday, he will travel to continue promoting his agenda.&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have more details on that in the coming days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So yesterday, you and State Department Spokesman Ned Price both took issue with reporters asking for evidence of your statements with respect to the Syria strike and the Russian false-flag operation.&nbsp; Do you really believe that journalists are repeating Russian and Islamic State propaganda in pursuing those questions, first of all?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And second of all, will you be offering evidence of your claims with respect to what happened in Syria when they become available?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And I will &#8212; let me just start by saying that we welcome tough questions and good-faith scrutiny, otherwise I wouldn&#8217;t come out here &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t have come out here almost 180 times and engaged with all of you and your tough questions and good-faith scrutiny.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I noted in the response to a question from your colleague yesterday, which wasn&#8217;t in all of the context of what was put out there, we are less than 48 hours from the end of the mission, so the Department of Defense is still conducting after-action assessments.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a natural part of the process that occurs.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also conveyed in my answer to the question: The President directed his Department of Defense to take every precaution to minimize civilian casualties and that we would release all of the information we could.&nbsp; And we absolutely remain committed to that, to answer the other part of your question.<br>&nbsp;<br>While I did not go into this level of detail during the plane gaggle, we also did a number of briefings a number of you participated in yesterday to brief out a number of the specific details, including the fact that we sent out special operators, at significant risk to themselves, to minimize the risk of civilian casualties.<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, that&#8217;s different than doing a strike, which would not be as much risk to individuals involved.&nbsp; But obviously, these individuals were on the ground for a couple of hours, as we briefed out.&nbsp; It would have been easier to do an airstrike.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But as a result, we have firsthand reports from our elite service members who are on the ground and risked their lives to kill a terrorist responsible to &#8212; for the slaughter and enslavement of the Yazidi religious minority in the north &#8212; in Northwestern Iraq in 2014, who bears responsibility for a recent set of attacks against the Iraqi Security Forces &#8212; and who took a terrorist off the battlefield who seeks to harm Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>But of course, we respect and value the role of the press &#8212; otherwise, again, I wouldn&#8217;t be out here with all of you every day &#8212; and welcome the scrutiny, welcome to tough questioning.&nbsp; And as I said yesterday, of course we will do everything we can to provide as many details as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think it&#8217;s important, as people are trying to understand this, to note it is different having operators on the ground than an airstrike where it&#8217;s a different assessment after action.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the jobs report, both administration officials and outside experts expected a worse jobs report than we saw.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any sense of why those expectations were off and what exactly that means for your future, sort of, policy with respect to the recovery and the economy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what is also true: As much as we had a very encouraging jobs report today and as we look back to the revisions made as a part of the report this morning, the largest year of economic &#8212; of job creation ever in American history.<br>&nbsp;<br>Those are certainly things we are proud of, the President is proud of, and we attribute that in part to the actions he took to implement a number of important policies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is also true &#8212; and this is one of the step &#8212; one of the facts that we have been pointing out over the course of last couple of days &#8212; that Omicron forced around 8 million people to take time off of work.&nbsp; And that was during a period of time where it was measured.&nbsp; So, that is also true.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, some of these people who were sick were not &#8212; would not have been counted in these job numbers.&nbsp; And that was a fact we just wanted people to understand as we were leading up to the jobs report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is also clear that it’s very challenging to collect, analyze, adjust the data during this time of the pandemic.&nbsp; We are very grateful to the BLS team that does that.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just incredibly challenging during an ongoing pandemic.&nbsp; But we think they&#8217;ve continued to deliver timely information.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve obviously continued to provide updates on a monthly basis when the &#8212; when their assessments change.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Xi and Putin met on &#8212; today, I guess &#8212; and released a pretty lengthy statement after that meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just moving a little bit further back from the meeting itself, how does the President view the relationship between China, Russia &#8212; Xi and Putin &#8212; through the lens of his broader foreign policy goals, agenda items, relationships?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; the President views it &#8212; views it as we have our own relationship with China.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken spoke to China&#8217;s Foreign Minister Wang and underscored &#8212; just recently, last week &#8212; and underscored the global security and economic risks posed by further Russian aggression against Ukraine, and conveyed that de-escalation and diplomacy are the responsible way forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also conveyed that destable- &#8212; a destabilizing conflict in Europe would impact China&#8217;s interests all over the world.&nbsp; And certainly, China should know that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, certainly, we have our own relationship where we engage directly at a very high level, as you all know, but our focus right now is continuing to unite with Allies and partners to respond decisively if Russia further invades Ukraine.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there any concerns about that relationship &#8212; if it gets closer, if it becomes more intertwined &#8212; in terms of U.S. posture and role in geopolitical spheres?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, what we have control over is our own relationships and the projection of our own values, and also looking for ways to work with countries, even where we disagree, and that is part of diplomacy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would note that &#8212; because some of the reporting has accurately assessed or, you know, raised the question of what took place in these conversations &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything to update on that, I don&#8217;t think you would expect.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the size and the scope of economic measures on the table that we&#8217;re talking about, as it relates to Russian aggression or the potential of invasion, are unprecedented; would pose massive consequences for the Kremlin; and the inputs to &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s important for people to understand that the inputs to the major foundational technologies of the world still come from the West.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s an enormous amount of power we have as we work to continue to strengthen our diplomatic efforts with our partners around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more quick one.&nbsp; And obviously, I&#8217;m not going to try and repeat what Matt did yesterday with Ned, because I know you’ve experienced it times in a past life.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But when it comes to &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I do.&nbsp; I do.&nbsp; I had many engagements with Matt Lee in my time.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The idea though &#8212; and you&#8217;ve done this a couple times of times &#8212; and the British have, to some degree, as well &#8212; of getting out in front.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think almost giving insight into intelligence that perhaps past administrations, including past Democratic administrations, would not have done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you explain, kind of, the thinking in that, strategically, and why you guys have decided to get out front on these types of things in this moment in time?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure. &nbsp;So, over the past several months, we &#8212; but also a number of our Allies &#8212; have developed a significant amount of credible intelligence about Russian efforts to use a false pretext to justify an invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; And this evidence mirrors both public reporting and Russian accounts in past conflicts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I would note: A number of your outlets, obviously, have reporters on the ground &#8212; right? &#8212; who are seeing for themselves what is happening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is also true that &#8212; is that we&#8217;ve seen Russians&#8217; acti- &#8212; the Russians&#8217; actions &#8212; Russians&#8217; actions &#8212; over the past few years.&nbsp; You know, if you look just back at past precedent, it doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s guaranteed to repeat, but it is &#8212; it is important for people to understand contextually what they&#8217;re capable of and what tactics they&#8217;ve used in the past.&nbsp; And sometimes you see &#8212; you do see repetition of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, a few years ago, for example, Russia&#8217;s Defense Ministry falsely claim- &#8212; accused the United States of running a clandestine biological weapons lab in the country of Georgia, enabling Russia&#8217;s efforts to destabilize the Georgian government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Russia also used to fabricate stories in Syria about how attacks on international aid convoys were undertaken by rebels or terrorist, instead of the Assad regime, to enable Russia&#8217;s continued support for the Assad government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you look back at 2016, the Russian media manufactured a false claim of sexual assault against a Russian émigré named Lisa by German refugees in order to stoke hysteria against Syrian immigrants throughout Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there&#8217;s more.&nbsp; Russian state television aired a false report that claimed the Ukrainian army had crucified a three-year-old Ukrainian Boy.&nbsp; That is even more recently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, our objective is to deny Russia the opportunity to use these lies to justify an invasion of Ukraine and to convey clearly these are actions we&#8217;re seeing that are straight out of their playbook.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen them run false-flag operations in the past and use confusion to launch military action many times in history.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of course, we would prefer to make as much underlying information available as we can.&nbsp; And in fact, the &#8212; what we conveyed yesterday and was conveyed by my colleagues at the Defense Department and State Department was a result of declassifying information.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We can&#8217;t do &#8212; there are limitations because of compromising intelligence sources and methods.&nbsp; But what we&#8217;re trying to do is take steps to deny Russia the opportunity to use lies, to use past tactics to justify an invasion of Ukraine, essentially, to avoid war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; If Putin decides to make a move into Ukraine, how long does the U.S. believe that the Ukrainians could hold off a full Russian takeover?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jacqui, it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I would really point you to the Department of Defense to make any assessment, if they can.&nbsp; And obviously, some assessments they might not be in a position to make publicly.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That they would not want to share publicly or that they don&#8217;t know?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m just conveying that there are some assessments and, obviously, you &#8212; the Department of Defense does a range of contingency planning.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let them speak for themselves on what they could &#8212; what they could lay out publicly for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, we&#8217;ve known about the reality of this threat since October.&nbsp; Putin began amassing troops on the border in April.&nbsp; So, why have we waited so long to send the kind of aid that we&#8217;re seeing now?&nbsp; Why haven&#8217;t we sent, for instance, anti-aircraft weaponry?&nbsp; Because if Russia does an airstrike, wouldn&#8217;t they be able to obliterate what we&#8217;ve sent to them so far?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, remember, the President met with President Zelenskyy back in &#8212; I think it was September, but you can correct me if that&#8217;s wrong; it was sometime early in the fall &#8212; and committed to a large aid package.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is something that we&#8217;ve been implementing and delivering since that point in time.&nbsp; So, actually, it&#8217;s been continuous security assistance that we&#8217;ve been providing to the Ukrainians &#8212; an enormous package that we&#8217;ve been providing over the course of the last year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of weapon systems, I’d again point you to the Department of Defense.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the feeling within the administration is that we have responded in a timely manner to Ukraine&#8217;s concerns?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what&#8217;s important for people to understand is that this has been continuous.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t that we had never provided aid, whether it&#8217;s humanitarian or security assistance, and all of a sudden we did recently.&nbsp; We &#8212; that has been a continuous process.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve provided hundreds of billions of dollars in aid, security assistance over the course of not just the last year, but long before that, and including a commitment the President made and was announced around President Zelenskyy’s visit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, moving on to energy: I mean, gas prices are at a seven-year high here in the U.S. right after OPEC, again, snubbed requests to increase production.&nbsp; And then there&#8217;s this energy crisis in Western Europe brewing.&nbsp; Is there any point where the President would consider opening up domestic production in order to mitigate some of this?&nbsp; The inflation and, you know, assist our allies in Western Europe?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a couple of important questions you raised there.&nbsp; Let me start by saying that, as it relates to Europe and the shortage &#8212; or potential, I should say &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t exist currently.&nbsp; Everybody is experiencing high gas prices, but I think you&#8217;re asking as it relates to a potential invasion.&nbsp; That is something we&#8217;ve been very mindful of and in touch with our European partners and also suppliers about what can be done and how we can ensure or take steps to increase capacity out there to meet those needs, should they raise; some of them is natural gas, some of them is gas, as you know.&nbsp; So, that is something we&#8217;ve been quite mindful of.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that the President has been &#8212; has taken a number of steps in recent months to address the gas prices, including tapping the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, of course conveying clearly to OPEC member countries and suppliers that it&#8217;s important to meet the demand on the market.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to &#8212; to look at options that can be done to lower gas prices for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of whether or not there could be more oil drilling, you know, I&#8217;d point you to the oil companies on what available places they have and if they&#8217;re maximizing that.&nbsp; My understanding is they’re not.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any consideration for increasing, for instance, LNG export licenses?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of additional steps.&nbsp; I can &#8212; can just reiterate to you that the President raises and talks about the importance of taking every step we can to lower gas prices for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then real quick on the Johns Hopkins study on the lockdowns.&nbsp; It was this meta-analysis that came out of several studies.&nbsp; Lockdowns during the first wave of COVID in the spring of 2020 found that it only reduced COVID mortality by 0.2 percent in the U.S. and Europe, and suggested that they have little to no public health benefit but severe consequences for the economy.&nbsp; And it suggests that lockdowns shouldn&#8217;t be a part of a future pandemic response.&nbsp; Is that the shared view of the administration looking in the rearview mirror?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say &#8212; I would, sort of, first, of course, point to our health and medical experts for specifics on this specific &#8212; scientific study.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that the President has been clear we&#8217;re not pushing lockdowns; we&#8217;ve not been pro-lockdown.&nbsp; That has not been his agenda.&nbsp; Most of the lockdowns actually happened under the previous president.<br>&nbsp;<br>What our objective has been is to &#8212; conveying that we have the tools we need to keep our country open, thanks to the President&#8217;s leadership, and focus on fighting the virus.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s reflected in the fact that 98 percent of schools are open, over 210 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; We have the tools to avoid lockdowns, and we&#8217;re not moving back.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s our intention at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you guys do believe then that the lockdowns were more harmful than helpful?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I would point you to our scientific experts on the specifics of a study.&nbsp; But the President&#8217;s agenda, the President&#8217;s approach has not been lockdowns.&nbsp; It has been using the tools we have to prevent that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Supreme Court nomination, Senator Ben Ray Luján’s office is saying, today, he&#8217;s going to be out for four to six weeks.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve obviously wished him well.&nbsp; Hopefully it’s shorter than that.&nbsp; But, you know, sometimes these recoveries don’t always go as planned.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, is the White House thinking at all about timing, given the senator’s potential absence?&nbsp; Is that affecting at all how the President is now thinking about this nomination versus how he would have been thinking about it a week ago?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, so everything is still on track for a pick by the end of February?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know you&#8217;ve been asked before whether the President is considering Republican votes and whether he can get any Republicans on board.&nbsp; Is the response still: “The President is looking for the best candidate and not thinking about which votes that candidate can get”?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, but I would say it’s important to note that the President’s commitment, above all else, is to nominate a qualified woman &#8212; a Black woman &#8212; to serve on the Supreme Court with impeccable credentials.&nbsp; And he thinks anyone he chooses should have the kind of credentials and be as &#8212; and be so qualified that they should be considered by Democrats and Republicans.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just a couple things on COVID: We&#8217;ve hit the 900,000 death mark, or we&#8217;re quickly going to approach it depending on your tally, but is the President going to do anything to mark this &#8212; for the grim milestone of 900,000 deaths?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will have more on this soon, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Do you have any updates on the testing efforts &#8212; the shipping out of the free COVID tests?&nbsp; How many have there been shipped out now?&nbsp; Do you have an update on that?&nbsp; Are they still being shipped out every 7 to 12 days from the order?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have an update on numbers.&nbsp; It&#8217;s changing constantly.&nbsp; I know we confirmed &#8212; I think it was last Friday, so I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s changed since then &#8212; that we had about 60 million orders.&nbsp; And we had sent out tens of millions of tests.&nbsp; And you’ve certainly seen on social media people receiving their tests, which is always good news.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I don’t have an update on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this program, of course, is just beginning to ramp up.&nbsp; We&#8217;d said at the beginning we wouldn&#8217;t start sending tests until the end of January.&nbsp; We obviously did it ahead of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what we&#8217;re really relying on right now is as soon as testing manufacturers deliver tests to the U.S. government, we will get them out to the American people.&nbsp; And the Postal Service is doing their job packing and shipping efficiently.&nbsp; And I expect we&#8217;ll have more updates in due time &#8212; a short time, I hope.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a real quick one on Russia.&nbsp; The Senate has left town without passing a sanctions bill.&nbsp; How important does the White House think it is to get the Senate to pass a Russian sanctions bill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re in close touch with them.&nbsp; But I &#8212; it&#8217;s not essential for us to implement sanctions.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not required.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we have had &#8212; we have prepared a devastating package of sanctions &#8212; economic sanctions that would have an enormous impact on the Russian economy.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t require congressional action, but we are, of course, working closely with them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, we need to gather.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Sorry for it to be so short today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be around for a little bit.&nbsp; If people have questions, come on by.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you say anything about the Russian oil deal with China?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I have any additional comments about their meeting.&nbsp; I will see if there&#8217;s more we can offer.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that for you, Andrea.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would that undermine any potential U.S. sanctions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m happy to get back to you if there’s more we can offer, Andrea.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>12:41 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Use of Project Labor Agreements For Federal Construction&#160;Projects</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/04/executive-order-on-use-of-project-labor-agreements-for-federal-construction-projects/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 20:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act, 40 U.S.C. 101 et seq., and in order to promote economy and efficiency in the administration and completion of Federal construction projects, it is hereby ordered that:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act, 40 U.S.C. 101 <em>et seq.</em>, and in order to promote economy and efficiency in the administration and completion of Federal construction projects, it is hereby ordered that:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1. &nbsp;Policy.</span> &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Large-scale construction projects pose special challenges to efficient and timely procurement by the Federal Government.&nbsp; Construction employers typically do not have a permanent workforce, which makes it difficult to predict labor costs when bidding on contracts and to ensure a steady supply of labor on contracts being performed.&nbsp; Challenges also arise because construction projects typically involve multiple employers at a single location, and a labor dispute involving one employer can delay the entire project.&nbsp; A lack of coordination among various employers, or uncertainty about the terms and conditions of employment of various groups of workers, can create friction and disputes in the absence of an agreed-upon resolution mechanism. &nbsp;These problems threaten the efficient and timely completion of construction projects undertaken by Federal contractors. &nbsp;On large-scale projects, which are generally more complex and of longer duration, these problems tend to be more pronounced.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Project labor agreements are often effective in preventing these problems from developing because they provide structure and stability to large-scale construction projects.&nbsp; Such agreements avoid labor-related disruptions on projects by using dispute-resolution processes to resolve worksite disputes and by prohibiting work stoppages, including strikes and lockouts.&nbsp; They secure the commitment of all stakeholders on a construction site that the project will proceed efficiently without unnecessary interruptions. &nbsp;They also advance the interests of project owners, contractors, and subcontractors, including small businesses.&nbsp; For these reasons, owners and contractors in both the public and private sector routinely use project labor agreements, thereby reducing uncertainties in large-scale construction projects.&nbsp; The use of project labor agreements is fully consistent with the promotion of small business interests.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;Accordingly, it is the policy of the Federal Government for agencies to use project labor agreements in connection with large-scale construction projects to promote economy and efficiency in Federal procurement.&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 2. &nbsp;Definitions.</span> &nbsp;For purposes of this order:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;&#8220;Labor organization&#8221; means a labor organization as defined in 29 U.S.C. 152(5) of which building and construction employees are members, as described in 29 U.S.C. 158(f).<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;&#8220;Construction&#8221; means construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, modernization, alteration, conversion, extension, repair, or improvement of buildings, structures, highways, or other real property.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;&#8220;Large-scale construction project&#8221; means a Federal construction project within the United States for which the total estimated cost of the construction contract to the Federal Government is $35 million or more.&nbsp; The Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council (FAR Council), in consultation with the Council of Economic Advisers, may adjust this threshold based on inflation using the process at 41 U.S.C. 1908.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;&#8220;Agency&#8221; means an executive department or agency, including an independent establishment subject to the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act, 40 U.S.C. 102(4)(A).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;&#8220;Project labor agreement&#8221; means a pre-hire collective bargaining agreement with one or more labor organizations that establishes the terms and conditions of employment for a specific construction project and is an agreement described in 29 U.S.C. 158(f).&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 3.&nbsp; Project Labor Agreement Presumption.</span> Subject to sections 5 and 6 of this order,&nbsp;in awarding any contract in connection with a large-scale construction project, or obligating funds pursuant to such a contract, agencies shall require every contractor or subcontractor engaged in construction on the project to agree, for that project, to negotiate or become a party to a project labor agreement with one or more appropriate labor organizations.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 4.&nbsp; Requirements of Project Labor Agreements.</span> Any project labor agreement reached pursuant to this order shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;bind all contractors and subcontractors on the construction project through the inclusion of appropriate specifications in all relevant solicitation provisions and contract documents;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;allow all contractors and subcontractors on the construction project to compete for contracts and subcontracts without regard to whether they are otherwise parties to collective bargaining agreements;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;contain guarantees against strikes, lockouts, and similar job disruptions;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;set forth effective, prompt, and mutually binding procedures for resolving labor disputes arising during the term of the project labor agreement;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;provide other mechanisms for labor-management cooperation on matters of mutual interest and concern, including productivity, quality of work, safety, and health; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;fully conform to all statutes, regulations, Executive Orders, and Presidential Memoranda.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 5.&nbsp; Exceptions Authorized by Agencies.</span> A senior official within an agency may grant an exception from the requirements of section 3 of this order for a particular contract by, no later than the solicitation date, providing a specific written explanation of why at least one of the following circumstances exists with respect to that contract:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Requiring a project labor agreement on the project would not advance the Federal Government&#8217;s interests in achieving economy and efficiency in Federal procurement.&nbsp;Such a finding shall be based on the following factors:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;The project is of short duration and lacks operational complexity;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;The project will involve only one craft or trade;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) The project will involve specialized construction work that is available from only a limited number of contractors or subcontractors;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;The agency&#8217;s need for the project is of such an unusual and compelling urgency that a project labor agreement would be impracticable; or<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The project implicates other similar factors deemed appropriate in regulations or guidance issued pursuant to section 8 of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Based on an inclusive market analysis, requiring a project labor agreement on the project would substantially reduce the number of potential bidders so as to frustrate full and open competition.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;Requiring a project labor agreement on the project would otherwise be inconsistent with statutes, regulations, Executive Orders, or Presidential Memoranda.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 6.  Reporting.</span> (a)  To the extent permitted by law and consistent with national security and executive branch confidentiality interests, agencies shall publish, on a centralized public website, data showing the use of project labor agreements on large-scale construction projects, as well as descriptions of the exceptions granted under section 5 of this order.<br>     (b)  On a quarterly basis, agencies shall report to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) on their use of project labor agreements on large-scale construction projects and on the exceptions granted under section 5 of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 7.</span> Nothing in this order precludes an agency from requiring the use of a project labor agreement in circumstances not covered by this order, including projects where the total cost to the Federal Government is less than that for a large-scale construction project, or projects receiving any form of Federal financial assistance (including loans, loan guarantees, revolving funds, tax credits, tax credit bonds, and cooperative agreements).  This order also does not require contractors or subcontractors to enter into a project labor agreement with any particular labor organization.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 8.  Regulations and Implementation.</span> (a)  Within 120 days of the date of this order, the FAR Council, to the extent permitted by law, shall propose regulations implementing the provisions of this order.  The FAR Council shall consider and evaluate public comments on the proposed regulations and shall promptly issue a final rule, to the extent permitted by law.<br>     (b)  The Director of OMB shall, to the extent permitted by law, issue guidance to implement the requirements of sections 5 and 6 of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 9.  Contracting Officer Training.</span> Within 90 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Labor, and the Director of OMB shall coordinate in designing a training strategy for agency contracting officers to enable those officers to effectively implement this order. Within 180 days of the date of the publication of proposed regulations, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Labor, and the Director of OMB shall provide a report to the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy and Director of the National Economic Council on the contents of the training strategy.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 10. Revocation of Prior Orders, Rules, and Regulations<em>.</em></span>  Executive Order 13502 of February 6, 2009 (Use of Project Labor Agreements for Federal Construction Projects), is revoked as of the effective date of the final regulations issued by the FAR Council under section 8(a) of this order. Upon Executive Order 13502&#8217;s revocation, the heads of agencies shall consider, to the extent permitted by law, revoking any orders, rules, or regulations implementing Executive Order 13502.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 11.  Severability.</span>  If any provision of this order, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this order and its application to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 12. Effective Date<em>.</em></span><em> </em> This order shall be effective immediately and shall apply to all solicitations for contracts issued on or after the effective date of the final regulations issued by the FAR Council under section 8(a) of this order.  For solicitations issued between the date of this order and the effective date of the final regulations issued by the FAR Council under section 8(a) of this order, or solicitations that have already been issued and are outstanding as of the date of this order, agencies are strongly encouraged, to the extent permitted by law, to comply with this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 13. General Provisions<em>.</em></span>  (a)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>     (b)  This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>     (c)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. &nbsp;<br><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">&nbsp;The White House,</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; February 4, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
