<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:18:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: S. 2089 and ​S.&#160;2938</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/25/bills-signed-s-2089-and-s-2938/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Saturday, June 25, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 2089, the &#8220;Keep Kids Fed Act of 2022,&#8221; which extends certain flexibilities for child nutrition programs and provides temporary increases in reimbursement rates for school meals and meals provided at child care centers; Thank you to Senators Debbie Stabenow and John Boozman and Representatives&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Saturday, June 25, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 2089, the &#8220;Keep Kids Fed Act of 2022,&#8221; which extends certain flexibilities for child nutrition programs and provides temporary increases in reimbursement rates for school meals and meals provided at child care centers;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Debbie Stabenow and John Boozman and Representatives Bobby Scott and Virginia Foxx for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 2938, the &#8220;Bipartisan Safer Communities Act,&#8221; which enhances certain restrictions and penalties on firearms purchases; promotes evidence-based best practices for school safety; authorizes grants to expand access to mental health services; and appropriates emergency funding for mental health resources and school safety measures;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Murphy, Cornyn, Sinema, Tillis, as well as Senate and House leadership, and the many other Congressional leaders on these issues who helped bring this bill to passage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Australia, Japan, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and the United&#160;States on the Establishment of the Partners in the Blue Pacific&#160;(PBP) </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/24/statement-by-australia-japan-new-zealand-the-united-kingdom-and-the-united-states-on-the-establishment-of-the-partners-in-the-blue-pacific-pbp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new initiative for more effective and efficient cooperation in support of Pacific Island priorities The Pacific Islands region is home to nearly a fifth of the Earth’s surface and many of its most urgent challenges, from the climate crisis to the COVID-19 pandemic to growing pressure on the rules-based free and open international order.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>A new initiative for more effective and efficient cooperation in support of Pacific Island priorities</em></p>



<p><br>The Pacific Islands region is home to nearly a fifth of the Earth’s surface and many of its most urgent challenges, from the climate crisis to the COVID-19 pandemic to growing pressure on the rules-based free and open international order. It was in this context that the Pacific Islands Forum, the premier driver of regional action, <a href="https://www.forumsec.org/2050strategy/#:~:text=The%202050%20Strategy%20for%20the%20Blue%20Pacific%20Continent&amp;text=It%20is%20a%20regional%20strategy,Pacific%20people%2C%20place%20and%20prospects.&amp;text=Pacific%20Leaders%20recognize%20that%20building,cultural%2C%20environmental%20and%20economic%20integrity">committed</a> to organize its members “as one collective if we are to address our increasingly common challenges.”<br><br>As our countries—<strong>Australia, Japan, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, </strong>and <strong>the United States</strong>—continue to support prosperity, resilience, and security in the Pacific, we too must harness our collective strength through closer cooperation. To that end, our governments dispatched high-level officials to Washington, D.C. on June 23 and 24 for consultations with Pacific Heads of Mission and other partners, including France, as well as the European Union in its observing capacity. These meetings followed discussions with Pacific partners, including with the Pacific Islands Forum Secretariat; they remain ongoing, including with other partners engaged in the region. Today, our five countries launched an inclusive, informal mechanism to support Pacific priorities more effectively and efficiently: <strong>thePartners in the Blue Pacific (PBP).</strong><br><br>This new initiative builds on our longstanding commitment to the region. Australia and New Zealand are of the region and members of the Pacific Islands Forum; Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States are founding Dialogue Partners. Our countries maintain close people-to-people ties to and are longstanding development partners with the Pacific Islands, reflected in our combined $2.1 billion in development assistance for the region. We are united in our shared determination to support a region that benefits the peoples of the Pacific. We are also united in how we realize this vision—according to principles of Pacific regionalism, sovereignty, transparency, accountability, and most of all, led and guided by the Pacific Islands.<br><br>With these principles at its core, the Partners in the Blue Pacific aims to: </p>



<ol><li><strong>Deliver results for the Pacific more effectively and efficiently.&nbsp;</strong>Together and individually, our five countries will enhance our existing efforts to support Pacific priorities, in line with the Pacific Islands Forum’s upcoming 2050 Strategy for the Blue Pacific Continent. To do so, we will work with Pacific partners. We will map existing projects and plan future ones, seeking to drive resources, remove duplication, and close gaps, which will avoid greater burdens and lost opportunities for Pacific governments and Pacific people. In parallel, each of our governments will continue to increase the ambition of our individual efforts in the region.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Bolster Pacific regionalism.&nbsp;</strong>The PBP will forge closer connections with Pacific governments and with the Pacific Islands Forum, by facilitating stronger and more regular engagement with our governments. We will further elevate Pacific regionalism, with a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum at its center, as a vital pillar of the regional architecture and of our respective approaches in the region.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Expand opportunities for cooperation between the Pacific and the world.</strong>&nbsp;The PBP will encourage and facilitate greater engagement with the Pacific by any other partner that shares the Pacific’s values and aims to work constructively and transparently to benefit the people of the region. As it develops, the PBP will remain inclusive, informal, and open to cooperating with additional partners similarly invested in and committed to partnership with the Pacific Islands. Globally, the PBP will identify opportunities to expand Pacific participation in international fora.</li></ol>



<p>At every stage, we will be led and guided by the Pacific Islands. We will seek Pacific guidance on the PBP’s selection of its lines of effort and its flagship projects. In meetings in Washington, including at Blair House, our governments and Pacific Heads of Mission discussed diverse areas in which to deepen cooperation, including the climate crisis, connectivity and transportation, maritime security and protection, health, prosperity, and education. We commit to continuing to engage with Pacific governments as well as with Pacific-led regional institutions, particularly the Pacific Islands Forum; we will align our work with outcomes from the upcoming Pacific Islands Forum Leaders meeting in Suva, Fiji. Later this year the United States intends to invite Partner countries’ foreign ministers to convene and review our progress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the NALEO 39th Annual&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-naleo-39th-annual-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 23:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SwissotelChicago, Illinois THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, NALEO!  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)   Have a seat.  Have a seat.  Good afternoon. Oh, it’s so good to &#8212; look at this wonderful, big crowd.  It’s so good to be back together under the same roof, isn’t it?  Yeah, it’s good to see everyone.  And I hope we all walk away&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Swissotel<br><em>Chicago, Illinois</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, NALEO!  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)   Have a seat.  Have a seat.  Good afternoon.<br> <br>Oh, it’s so good to &#8212; look at this wonderful, big crowd.  It’s so good to be back together under the same roof, isn’t it?  Yeah, it’s good to see everyone. <br> <br>And I hope we all walk away from days like this and moments like this when we go back to the places where we work every day, often being one of the only like us in a room or who has had the life experience we’ve had &#8212; I think these are moments that are very important to remember that we are not alone.  There are all of us who are in these rooms together, even if we don’t see each other at a particular moment.  So, it’s a good time to be together.  So, thank you all.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And I want to thank Ricardo and Mara for that kind introduction and for your leadership of this organization during an unprecedented time during these years of the pandemic and so many crises that we have been facing as a country.<br> <br>And, of course, I am honored to be here with the board of directors of NALEO and so many of our nation’s leaders.<br> <br>Before I start speaking as I planned to speak, I do want to speak briefly about the decision from today’s United States Supreme Court decision in the Dobbs case.  <br> <br>Here is what I believe that decision means: For nearly 50 years, we have talked about what Roe v. Wade protects.  Today, as of right now, as of this very minute, we can only talk about what Roe v. Wade protected.  Past tense. <br> <br>The great aspiration of our nation has been to expand freedom.  It is something so many of us has spent our careers fighting for.  But the expansion of freedom clearly is not inevitable, and it certainly is not something that just happens &#8212; not unless we defend our most fundamental principles. <br> <br>The strength of our nation has always been that, despite the odds and the obstacles, we push to move forward; that we are guided by what we see that can be, unburdened by what has been.  And I know everyone in this room understands this and has, in many ways, lived a life that illustrates this. <br> <br>And so, because, of course, NALEO has been fighting to move our nation forward for nearly 50 years on other critical issues and the issues that fundamentally are about the ideals and aspirations of our nation, I am honored to be with you here today. <br> <br>And I also want you to know that I bring you greetings from President Joe Biden &#8212; because we are grateful, yes.  (Applause.)  We are grateful for the work of this organization and its members to galvanize policy members and leaders, to mobilize, to organize, and to do that work on behalf of the Latino community and, by extension, the entire nation &#8212; all of that work being in pursuit of progress and our collective ability for our nation to achieve its ideals.  So, I thank you all.<br> <br>I have always felt a special connection to this organization, as Ricardo said.  And, yes, as a proud daughter of California &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; (applause) &#8212; many of us the daughters and sons of California &#8212; I am proud that NALEO, of course, was founded by a great Californian, Edward Roybal.  And we must always remember him.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And throughout my career, I have worked alongside many of the leaders of this organization, including, of course, our collective friend and my dear friend, now-Senator Alex Padilla, who served &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes, he and I served together many years.  I was mostly based in the Bay Area.  He was in Los Angeles.  But then, as we were coming up, we both ended up as state constitutional officers when he was Secretary of State and I was Attorney General of California. <br> <br>And I partnered with so many of NALEO members on so many issues that range from supporting small businesses, to immigration reform, to voting rights, education, and so many more issues.<br> <br>And over the years, as Ricardo said, I have spoken with this organization many times.  But I am honored that this is the first time that I, in person, am speaking with you as Vice President of the United States.  (Applause.) <br> <br>So, I believe &#8212; in fact, I know &#8212; there is a common characteristic among us all: We all serve because we believe in the magnificence of our nation and its potential.  We all believe in fighting to achieve our nation’s highest ideals, knowing, as I said earlier, they don’t just happen.  We don’t just achieve them by being, we achieve them by being committed to reaching those ideals.<br> <br>We all believe in a future where the promise of liberty and justice is made real for all Americans.  We believe in a future where hard work pays off, where families can get ahead and stay ahead.  We believe in a future where every child can reach their God-given potential.<br> <br>We believe that all communities have a right to be safe and healthy. <br> <br>And we believe that anyone should be able to have a dream and achieve that dream &#8212; a future where immigrants have the opportunity to have what they deserve in terms of a pathway towards citizenship. <br> <br>We believe in a nation and in a future where protecting the freedom to vote is not a partisan issue. <br> <br>We believe that women should be able to make decisions about their own bodies without government interference.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so, you know, when the President and I took office, our country, as we all remember, was headed in the wrong direction.  Just think: We were facing a pandemic that was out of control.  We had a situation that, in that pandemic, it’s important to note, it was particularly devastating in terms of its impact on the Latino community, especially among those who were frontline workers and essential workers and farmworkers, so many of whom were, in terms of the essential workers, DREAMers.  We remember how folks risked their own health and the health of their families to keep safe communities and to keep our country running.<br> <br>Remember, our nation also faced &#8212; and we can talk about current day as well &#8212; but then, in particular, we faced a historic economic challenge as a result of the pandemic.<br> <br>But together with you, the President and I were not deterred.  With your partnership &#8212; remember &#8212; it was a difficult road but we got folks vaccinated.  We reopened our schools and kept people in their homes. <br> <br>Together, because of our collective work, we achieved record job creation, record labor participation, and the largest single-year drop in Latino unemployment in recorded history.  (Applause.)<br> <br>In addition, we have assembled the most diverse administration in the history of our country.  And I should note, we have appointed the most Latino leaders ever to Cabinet-level position.  (Applause.)<br> <br>In addition, we expanded the Child Tax Credit, such that so many children &#8212; and in particular, the Latino child poverty rate hit a new record low last year. <br> <br>Because of the once-in-a-generation Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we lowered the cost of high-speed Internet for nearly 40 percent of households in America. <br> <br>Because we invested in small businesses, business owners across the country kept their doors open and Latino entrepreneurs started new companies at a higher rate last year than at any other point in the last decade.<br> <br>In fact, just recently I was in Monrovia, California &#8212; many of the Californians know where that is.  (Applause.)  California.  (Laughter.)  Just joking.  I got jokes, okay.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>So, I was there in Monrovia, and I was visiting this incredible small business &#8212; it’s a woman small-business owner, and it was &#8212; the business is called Dream Big Children’s Center.  And its owner, her name is Cristina Cordeiro.  We talked for quite some time.  Her mother was there.  And we talked about her inspiration, which is her mother was a great caregiver.  Right?  She grew in a community where we care about the children.<br> <br>And so, she created this business that parents would rely on to provide daily therapy to children with special needs.  And if you can imagine, this &#8212; especially during the pandemic, for all of us who have children in our lives &#8212; it was incredibly critical, especially during those many, many months of the pandemic, that we would have access to the needs of services for our children.  So, it was very critical that she stayed open during the pandemic.<br> <br>Fortunately, because of funding she received through our administration’s American Rescue Plan, she was not only able to continue providing services in her community, but she was able to grow her business.  And since the start of the pandemic, she has opened 50 &#8212; or two new locations with 50 new employees. <br> <br>And I mention that because, during the course of the last couple of years &#8212; and in particular in the last year and half after we passed, together with your help, the ARP &#8212; I’ve met so many small-business owners who have seen success &#8212; and the kind of success that I know NALEO and this organization and its members have been fighting for, understanding that so much of the economic health and vitality of our communities has been centered in the small businesses, in men and women who are invested in their community; who understand the community &#8212; the language of the community, the culture of the community, the needs of the community &#8212; and are, therefore, best suited to actually uplift the community economically and in every other way.<br> <br>And together, because of the work that we have done, in particular with the ARP, we’ve been able to do that and we’re seeing results.<br> <br>And so, whether it is my work in the United States Senate or the work that we did, in terms of in the Senate, helping small businesses access capital, or the partnership, together, that we had to get the Restaurant Revitalization Fund included in the ARP, we are seeing that small businesses are starting to thrive in our country, and with a particular emphasis on women- and minority-owned small businesses.<br> <br>So, I want to thank you all for the work you’ve done in that regard as well.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So with that being said, we also know that people are still hurting.  There is no question that we still face a number of serious challenges.  And today then, I’d like to talk about three of the issues which I believe are among the priorities of us in this room: one, lowering costs for families, building a fair and humane immigration system, and protecting people from gun violence.  <br> <br>So, first, I think we all agree and know inflation is still too high.  We are seeing higher prices at the store because supply chains slowed down dramatically during the pandemic and higher prices at the gas pump, in large part because of Putin’s unprovoked war in Ukraine.  And families across our nation, in particular working families, are feeling the effect.  <br> <br>I know you know the President and I are using every tool at our disposal to lower costs, including the cost of gas, childcare, eldercare, and prescription drugs like insulin &#8212; which we should be capping, by the way, at $35 a month.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And as leaders of the communities that you represent, you know that these are some of the costs that most matter to the families of our communities.  And we know that making essential needs more affordable will keep our country on a path to stable and steady growth.<br> <br>So, there is work that we still have to do.  But as we are looking at these issues, as we discuss the issue of inflation, let us agree that we cannot abandon our commitment to supporting families on the issue of childcare, on the issue of eldercare, on the issue of the cost of prescription drugs.  Because these are costs that are, without any question, also weighing down the ability of families to succeed and thrive.  And in large part, a lot of these issues are incumbent on elected leaders to solve, and they have the ability to solve.<br> <br>Speaking of, let’s talk about the second issue: immigration.  There’s still so much work to be done on that.  We have partnered, so many of us, over the years to fight to fix our country’s broken immigration system and, in particular, to fight for our Dreamers. <br> <br>When I was Attorney General of California, you probably remember that we, together, fought in the courts and spoke out when they ruled against DACA and DAPA.  When I was in the United States Senate, we worked together on legislation that would create a pathway to citizenship. <br> <br>And today, our administration continues to urge Congress to create a pathway not only for DREAMers, but also for individuals with temporary protected status and for farmworkers.  In fact, when I was in the Senate, I was proud to sponsor the Farm Worker Bill of Rights.  We &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.<br> <br>And so we issued a proposed rule that would preserve and fortify DACA.  Our administration and the Department of Justice continues to defend DACA in the courts.  In fact, just last week, on the 10th anniversary of DACA, I was again reminded of why we have to continue the fight.  I invited a group of DREAMers to come in and &#8212; and they came into the White House, to my West Wing office, and each of them was so committed to paying forward the opportunity that they received and the opportunity that they know that folks who are entitled to receive.  One of the DREAMers became a kindergarten teacher after college.  And today he is organizing a diverse coalition in support of a pathway towards citizenship.<br> <br>And I don&#8217;t need to tell anybody here: DREAMers are serving in our military, they are attending college, they are working in Fortune 100 companies.  I mentioned the number who were frontline workers who were sacrificing so much of their own lives and service to their community and perfect strangers.<br> <br>And it is a tragedy that we can&#8217;t pull this together as a nation and pass legislation, creating a legal pathway for them, for farmworkers, for TPS, and understanding what this means to families every day. <br> <br>We &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s not on the front page of the newspaper, necessarily, but it&#8217;s real; I don&#8217;t have to tell anybody here.<br> <br>These kids, their parents, so many blended families, mixed families, still every day are in fear about a knock at a door and what that might mean, whether a parent might come home at night.<br> <br>And I don&#8217;t need to tell anybody here this, because most of us are in the same situation: We are a nation of immigrants. Raise your hand if you have a parent that was not born in the United States &#8212; this room of leaders.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, as do we, these young people represent the promise of who we are as a country.  You know, I said to one of them &#8212; I said to one of the young leaders that were there that day, and I said, “You know, my mother came to the United States…” &#8212; and we’re in my West Wing office in the White House, and I looked at &#8212; I looked at him and I said, “You know, my mother came to the United States from India when she was 19 years old.  And I&#8217;m Vice President of the United States.”  (Applause.)  And he broke out in a big smile.  He said, “Okay, I got it.  I understand.”<br> <br>So, all of that to say that we have to keep fighting on this issue.<br> <br>The third issue that I know is our nation&#8217;s highest priority &#8212; one of them &#8212; is our responsibility to create safe communities and protect people from gun violence. <br> <br>What happened in Uvalde broke the hearts of our entire country.  We were all shaken to our core by the massacre of those 19 children &#8212; those babies &#8212; and their two teachers.  And we, of course, still remember and mourn the 23 lives senselessly taken by a white nationalist in El Paso three years ago. <br> <br>And our hearts are heavy when news breaks about similar vicious, hateful attacks at a grocery store in Buffalo, a synagogue in Pittsburgh, or a nightclub in Orlando.<br> <br>And, of course, there&#8217;s a through-line between these tragedies: an epidemic of hate that touches us all.  And, I believe, to combat hate we must speak truth about what fuels these attacks, and we must have the courage to take action that will save lives.<br> <br>I think many of us agree that our country needs sensible gun safety laws; that yesterday&#8217;s Supreme Court decision, which struck down one of those laws, defies common sense and defies the Constitution.  And we must protect people from the gun violence that claims countless lives every day in America, which is why the bipartisan gun safety bill that is on the way to the President&#8217;s desk is an important and necessary step.<br> <br>But we cannot stop.  We cannot stop here, and we must continue to do more.  Because, I mean, let&#8217;s be &#8212; let&#8217;s be real: No 9-year-old should be scared to go to school.  No 15-year-old should fear shopping for school supplies.  No 25-year-old should be scared to go with friends to a nightclub.  And no 86-year-old should be afraid to shop for groceries.  And no 18-year-old should be able to buy a weapon of war.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, I&#8217;ll end with this point: If there is one belief that I know everyone in this room shares it is our belief in the potential, in the promise, and the strength of our nation. <br> <br>We all choose to serve because we know our country is strong enough to overcome the challenges we face, because we believe it is our duty as public officials to work together in pursuit of progress.<br> <br>So let us always remember and let us remind others that we all have so much more in common than what separates us.  And let us renew then our commitment to fight for unity, especially in these days. <br> <br>Let us continue &#8212; and NALEO has done this so well over so many years &#8212; to understand the power and the beauty of building and reinforcing coalitions based on knowing how much we all have in common.  Because I believe that the only way to tackle the biggest problems, the biggest challenges that we as a nation face is to tackle them together.<br> <br>And NALEO, of course, knows this more than most &#8212; because, again, you have been bringing folks together for nearly 50 years.  And in those 50 years, you have used your collective voice to advocate for more equity, more opportunity, and more possibility for all communities.<br> <br>So with that, I am here to say the President and I are with you.  We stand with you every step of the way.  God bless you, and God bless the United States of America.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Supreme Court Decision to Overturn Roe V.&#160;Wade</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-supreme-court-decision-to-overturn-roe-v-wade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 20:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[C.W. Avery Family YMCAPlainfield, Illinois 2:23 P.M. CDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon. Well, first, I want to thank Senator Durbin.  I had the privilege of serving with him, as he mentioned, on the Senate Judiciary Committee.  And I can tell&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>C.W. Avery Family YMCA<br><em>Plainfield, Illinois</em></em></p>



<p>2:23 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.<br><br>Well, first, I want to thank Senator Durbin.  I had the privilege of serving with him, as he mentioned, on the Senate Judiciary Committee.  And I can tell you, Illinois, you are very, very well represented by Senator Dick Durbin.  He is an extraordinary leader, a great fighter for all of American and &#8212; all of America, and in particular for the people of Illinois.<br>So, thank you, Dick Durbin, and congratulations to your grandchild, for her honor today as well. <br><br>And I want to thank all the leaders for joining us today, and a special thank you, of course, to Lauren Underwood.  Where are you?  Lauren.  (Applause.)  I have seen you when the cameras are on and when the cameras are off.  She’s always fighting for the people of her district.  And all that you have done for our government, for the people of our country, and for Plainfield, I thank you for that.  I thank you for your partnership and your leadership.<br><br>So, as Senator Durbin mentioned, we traveled here today.  In fact, they both joined me, along with the Secretary, on Air Force Two.  And we traveled here from D.C. today to talk with you about maternal health, which should be one of our highest priorities as a nation.<br><br>And I had planned to speak about our strategy for improving care for pregnant women and mothers across our country.  And as you know, on the way here, however, we learned that the United States Supreme Court had rendered its decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization.<br><br>Here’s what that decision means: For nearly 50 years, we have talked about what Roe v. Wade protects.  Today, as of right now, as of this minute, we can only talk about what Roe v. Wade protected.  Past tense. <br><br>This is a healthcare crisis, because understand: Millions of women in America will go to bed tonight without access to the healthcare and reproductive care that they had this morning; without access to the same healthcare or reproductive healthcare that their mothers and grandmothers had for 50 years.<br> <br>This is the first time in the history of our nation that a constitutional right has been taken from the people of America.  And what is that right? &#8212; some might ask.  It’s the right to privacy.<br> <br>Think about it as the right for each person to make intimate decisions about heart and home; decisions about the right to start a family, including contraception, such as IUDs and the morning-after pill; decisions about whether to have a child, including, as Senator Durbin mentioned, through in-vitro fertilization; decisions to marry the person you love &#8212; Obergefell v. Hodges, Loving vs. Virginia.<br> <br>This opinion also says, when your read it, that abortion is not deeply rooted in our nation’s history.  They offer that in the opinion as a foundation for the decision they rendered today.<br> <br>In holding that it is not deeply rooted in our history, today’s decision on that theory, then, calls into question other rights that we thought were settled, such as the right to use birth control, the right to same-sex marriage, the right to interracial marriage.<br> <br>The great aspiration of our nation has been to expand freedom, but the expansion of freedom clearly is not inevitable.  It is not something that just happens &#8212; not unless we defend our most fundamental principles; not unless we elect leaders who stand up for those principles.<br> <br>The strength of our nation has always been that we move forward. <br><br>Today, I invite all people to stand together in defense of one of the most fundamental ideals and principles that for generations, for centuries, I believe, we have held dear, which is that fundamental principle about the importance of liberty &#8212; to stand for liberty, to stand for freedom, to stand for self-determination, and for the right to privacy.<br> <br>You have the power to elect leaders who will defend and protect your rights.  And as the President said earlier today, with your vote, you can act, and you have the final word. <br> <br>So this is not over.  God bless you.  And God bless America.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END                 2:30 P.M. CDT</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 735, H.R. 767 and ​H.R.&#160;1444</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/24/bills-signed-h-r-735-h-r-767-and-h-r-1444/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 20:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, June 24, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 735, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 502 East Cotati Avenue in Cotati, California, as the Arturo L. Ibleto Post Office Building; Thank you to Representative Mike Thompson and many others for their leadership. H.R. 767, which designates&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, June 24, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 735, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 502 East Cotati Avenue in Cotati, California, as the Arturo L. Ibleto Post Office Building;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representative Mike Thompson and many others for their leadership.</p>



<p>H.R. 767, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 40 Fulton Street in Middletown, New York, as the Benjamin A. Gilman Post Office Building;<br><br>Thank you to Representative Sean Patrick Maloney and many others for their leadership.</p>



<p>H.R. 1444, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 132 North Loudoun Street, Suite 1 in Winchester, Virginia, as the Patsy Cline Post Office.<br><br>Thank you to Representative Wexton and the bipartisan efforts of the Virginia delegation for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces Actions In Light of Today’s Supreme Court Decision on Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health&#160;Organization</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/24/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-actions-in-light-of-todays-supreme-court-decision-on-dobbs-v-jackson-womens-health-organization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 19:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden announced actions that his Administration is taking to protect women who will face the grave consequences of today’s Supreme Court decision. This decision expressly took away a Constitutional right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to choose, free from government interference. This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden announced actions that his Administration is taking to protect women who will face the grave consequences of today’s Supreme Court decision. This decision expressly took away a Constitutional right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to choose, free from government interference.</p>



<p>This decision will have devastating consequences in the lives of women around the country.</p>



<p>The President made clear that the only way to secure a woman’s right to choose is for Congress to restore the protections of <em>Roe</em> as federal law. Until then, he has announced two actions the Administration is taking to protect women.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting the Right to Seek Medical Care</strong></p>



<p>As the <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/attorney-general-merrick-b-garland-statement-supreme-court-ruling-dobbs-v-jackson-women-s#:~:text=%E2%80%9CThe%20Justice%20Department%20will%20use,civil%20rights%20of%20all%20Americans.%E2%80%9D">Attorney General made clear,</a> women must remain free to travel safely to another state to seek the care they need.</p>



<p>A person has the right to travel between states for whatever reason they want – it is no one else’s business – especially the government’s. If a woman lives in a state that restricts abortion, the Supreme Court’s decision does not prevent her from traveling from her home to a state that allows it.</p>



<p>If any state or local official tries to interfere with women exercising this basic right, the Biden Administration will fight that deeply un-American attack.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting Access to Medication</strong></p>



<p>The President directed the Secretary of Health and Human Services to protect women’s access to critical medications for reproductive health care that are approved by the Food and Drug Administration—including essential preventive health care like contraception and medication abortion.</p>



<p>More than 20 years ago, the FDA approved mifepristone to safely end an early pregnancy; this drug is also commonly used to treat miscarriages. The American Medical Association and the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists wrote to President Biden and Vice President Harris, asking the federal government to protect access to this care. In the face of threats from state officials saying they will try to ban or severely restrict access to medication for reproductive health care, the President directed the Secretary of Health and Human Services to identify all ways to ensure that mifepristone is as widely accessible as possible in light of the FDA’s determination that the drug is safe and effective—including when prescribed through telehealth and sent by mail.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">***</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Supreme Court Decision to Overturn Roe v.&#160;Wade</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-supreme-court-decision-to-overturn-roe-v-wade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 18:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cross Hall 12:37 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Today is a &#8212; it’s not hyperbole to suggest a very solemn moment.&#160; Today, the Supreme Court of the United States expressly took away a constitutional right from the American people that it had already recognized. They didn’t limit it.&#160; They simply took it away.&#160; That’s never been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cross Hall</p>



<p>12:37 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Today is a &#8212; it’s not hyperbole to suggest a very solemn moment.&nbsp; Today, the Supreme Court of the United States expressly took away a constitutional right from the American people that it had already recognized.</p>



<p>They didn’t limit it.&nbsp; They simply took it away.&nbsp; That’s never been done to a right so important to so many Americans.</p>



<p>But they did it.&nbsp; And it’s a sad day for the Court and for the country.</p>



<p>Fifty years ago, Roe v. Wade was decided and has been the law of the land since then.</p>



<p>This landmark case protected a woman’s right to choose, her right to make intensely personal decisions with her doctor, free from the inter- &#8212; from interference of politics.</p>



<p>It reaffirmed basic principles of equality &#8212; that women have the power to control their own destiny.&nbsp; And it reinforced the fundamental right of privacy &#8212; the right of each of us to choose how to live our lives.</p>



<p>Now, with Roe gone, let’s be very clear: The health and life of women in this nation are now at risk.</p>



<p>As Chairman and Ranking Member of the Senate Judiciary Committee, as Vice President and now as President of the United States, I’ve studied this case carefully.&nbsp; I’ve overseen more Supreme Court confirmations than anyone today, where this case was always discussed.</p>



<p>I believe Roe v. Wade was the correct decision as a matter of constitutional law, an application of the fundamental right to privacy and liberty in matters of family and personal autonomy.</p>



<p>It was a decision on a complex matter that drew a careful balance between a woman’s right to choose earlier in her pregnancy and the state’s ability to regulate later in her pregnancy.&nbsp; A decision with broad national consensus that most Americans of faiths and backgrounds found acceptable and that had been the law of the land for most of the lifetime of Americans today.</p>



<p>And it was a constitutional principle upheld by justices appointed by Democrat and Republican Presidents alike.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Roe v. Wade was a 7 to 2 decision written by a justice appointed by a Republican President, Richard Nixon.  In the five decades that followed Roe v. Wade, justices appointed by Republican Presidents &#8212; from Eisenhower, Nixon, Reagan, George <s>W.</s> [H.W.] Bush &#8212; were among the justices who voted to uphold the principles set forth in Roe v. Wade.</p>



<p>It was three justices named by one President &#8212; Donald Trump &#8212; who were the core of today’s decision to upend the scales of justice and eliminate a fundamental right for women in this country.</p>



<p>Make no mistake: This decision is the culmination of a deliberate effort over decades to upset the balance of our law.&nbsp; It’s a realization of an extreme ideology and a tragic error by the Supreme Court, in my view.</p>



<p>The Court has done what it has never done before: expressly take away a constitutional right that is so fundamental to so many Americans that had already been recognized.</p>



<p>The Court’s decision to do so will have real and immediate consequences.&nbsp; State laws banning abortion are automatically taking effect today, jeopardizing the health of millions of women, some without exceptions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So extreme that women could be punished for protecting their health.</p>



<p>So extreme that women and girls who are forced to bear their rapist’s child &#8212; of the child of consequence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s a &#8212; it just &#8212; it just stuns me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So extreme that doctors will be criminalized for fulfilling their duty to care.</p>



<p>Imagine having &#8212; a young woman having to ch- &#8212; carry the child of incest &#8212; as a consequence of incest.&nbsp; No option.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Too often the case that poor women are going to be hit the hardest.&nbsp; It’s cruel.</p>



<p>In fact, the Court laid out state laws criminalizing abortion that go back to the 1800s as rationale &#8212; the Court literally taking America back 150 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This a sad day for the country, in my view, but it doesn’t mean the fight is over.</p>



<p>Let me be very clear and unambiguous:&nbsp;The only way we can secure a woman’s right to choose and the balance that existed is for Congress to restore the protections of Roe v. Wade as federal law.</p>



<p>No executive action from the President can do that.&nbsp; And if Congress, as it appears, lacks the vote &#8212; votes to do that now, voters need to make their voices heard.</p>



<p>This fall, we must elect more senators and representatives who will codify a woman’s right to choose into federal law once again, elect more state leaders to protect this right at the local level.</p>



<p>We need to restore the protections of Roe as law of the land.&nbsp; We need to elect officials who will do that.</p>



<p>This fall, Roe is on the ballot.&nbsp; Personal freedoms are on the ballot.&nbsp; The right to privacy, liberty, equality, they&#8217;re all on the ballot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Until then, I will do all in my power to protect a woman’s right in states where they will face the consequences of today’s decision.</p>



<p>While the Court’s decision casts a dark shadow over a large swath of the land, many states in this country still recognize a woman’s right to choose.</p>



<p>So if a woman lives in a state that restricts abortion, the Supreme Court’s decision does not prevent her from traveling from her home state to the state that allows it.&nbsp; It does not prevent a doctor in that state &#8212; in that state from treating her.</p>



<p>As the Attorney General has made clear, women must remain free to travel safely to another state to seek the care they need.&nbsp; And my administration will defend that bedrock right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If any state or local official, high or low, tries to interfere with a woman’s ex- &#8212; exercising her basic right to travel, I will do everything in my power to fight that deeply un-American attack.</p>



<p>My administration will also protect a woman’s access to medications that are approved by the Food and Drug Administration &#8212; the FDA &#8212; like contraception, which is essential for preventative healthcare; mifepristone, which the FDA approved 20 years ago to safely end early pregnancies and is commonly used to treat miscarriages.</p>



<p>Some states are saying that they’ll try to ban or severely restrict access to these medications.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But extremist governors and state legislators who are looking to block the mail or search a person’s medicine cabinet or control a woman’s actions by tracking data on her apps she uses are wrong and extreme and out of touch with the majority of Americans.</p>



<p>The American Medical Association and the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists wrote to me and Vice President Harris stressing that these laws are not based on &#8212; are not based on evidence and asking us to act to protect access to care.&nbsp; They say by limiting access to these medicines, maternal mortality will climb in America.&nbsp; That’s what they say.</p>



<p>Today, I’m directing the Department of Health and Human Services to take steps to ensure that these critical medications are available to the fullest extent possible and that politicians cannot interfere in the decisions that should be made between a woman and her doctor.&nbsp; And my administration will remain vigilant as the implications of this decision play out.</p>



<p>I’ve warned about how this decision risks the broader right to privacy for everyone.&nbsp; That’s because Roe recognized the fundamental right to privacy that has served as the basis for so many more rights that we have come to take &#8212; we’ve come to take for granted that are ingrained in the fabric of this country: the right to make the best decisions for your health; the right to use birth control &#8212; a married couple &#8212; in the privacy of their bedroom, for God’s sake; the right to marry the person you love.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, Justice Thomas said as much today.&nbsp; He explicitly called to reconsider the right of marriage equality, the right of couples to make their choices on contraception.&nbsp; This is an extreme and dangerous path the Court is now taking us on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me close with two points.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, I call on everyone, no matter how deeply they care about this decision, to keep all protests peaceful.&nbsp; Peaceful, peaceful, peaceful.&nbsp; No intimidation.&nbsp; Violence is never acceptable.&nbsp; Threats and intimidation are not speech.&nbsp; We must stand against violence in any form regardless of your rationale.</p>



<p>Second, I know so many of us are frustrated and disillusioned that the Court has taken something away that’s so fundamental.&nbsp; I know so many women are now going to face incredibly difficult situations.&nbsp; I hear you.&nbsp; I support you.&nbsp; I stand with you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The consequences and the consensus of the American people &#8212; core principles of equality, liberty, dignity, and the stability of the rule of law &#8212; demand that Roe should not have been overturned.</p>



<p>With this decision, the conservative majority of the Supreme Court shows how extreme it is, how far removed they are from the majority of this country.&nbsp; They have made the United States an outlier among developed nations in the world.&nbsp; But this decision must not be the final word.</p>



<p>My administration will use all of its appropriate lawful powers.&nbsp; But Congress must act.&nbsp; And with your vote, you can act.&nbsp; You can have the final word.&nbsp; This is not over.</p>



<p>Thank you very much.&nbsp; I’ll have more to say on this in weeks to come.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>12:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Maternal Health Blueprint Delivers for Women, Mothers, and&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/24/fact-sheet-president-bidens-maternal-health-blueprint-delivers-for-women-mothers-and-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 15:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House released the Biden-Harris Administration’s  Blueprint for Addressing the Maternal Health Crisis, a whole-of-government approach to combatting maternal mortality and morbidity. For far too many mothers, complications related to pregnancy, childbirth, and postpartum can lead to devastating health outcomes — including hundreds of deaths each year. This maternal health crisis is particularly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House released the Biden-Harris Administration’s  <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Maternal-Health-Blueprint.pdf">Blueprint for Addressing the Maternal Health Crisis</a>, a whole-of-government approach to combatting maternal mortality and morbidity. For far too many mothers, complications related to pregnancy, childbirth, and postpartum can lead to devastating health outcomes — including hundreds of deaths each year. This maternal health crisis is particularly devastating for Black women, Native women, and women in rural communities who all experience maternal mortality and morbidity at significantly higher rates than their white and urban counterparts.</p>



<p>Under President Biden and Vice President Harris’s leadership, this Administration is now taking the next step towards a future where the United States will be the best country in the world to have a baby. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to cutting the rates of maternal mortality and morbidity, reducing the disparities in maternal health outcomes, and improving the overall experience during and after pregnancy for people across the country. This commitment will require bold, unprecedented action through a whole-of-government strategy.</p>



<p>To start, the Administration is calling on Congress to improve and expand coverage by closing the Medicaid coverage gap and requiring continuous Medicaid coverage for 12 months postpartum, as well as making the significant investments included in the President’s FY23 budget to reduce maternal morbidity and mortality.</p>



<p>The Administration also recognizes that addressing the maternal health crisis in the United States requires immediate action. That is why, in addition to urging Congressional action, the White House has mobilized over a dozen federal agencies to develop the White House Blueprint for Addressing the Maternal Health Crisis. The Blueprint outlines five priorities to improve maternal health and outcomes in the United States:</p>



<p>• Increasing access to and coverage of comprehensive high-quality maternal health services, including behavioral health services.<br>• Ensuring women giving birth are heard and are decisionmakers in accountable systems of care.<br>• Advancing data collection, standardization, harmonization, transparency, and research<br>• Expanding and diversifying the perinatal workforce.<br>• Strengthening economic and social supports for people before, during, and after pregnancy.</p>



<p><strong>For women who are pregnant, postpartum, or hoping to become pregnant, the actions in the Blueprint mean:</strong></p>



<p>• <strong>Extended Postpartum Coverage: </strong>States are encouraged to extend Medicaid coverage from two months to one year postpartum, so that women do not lose or have changes in their coverage during or soon after pregnancy.<br>• <strong>Investments in Rural Maternal Care: </strong>Rural health care facilities will have more staff and capabilities to provide maternal care through increased funding from the expanding the Rural Maternity and Obstetrics Management Strategies Program and more robust training for rural health care providers.<br>• <strong>A Maternal Mental Health Hotline: </strong>Providers will be trained on mental health during pregnancy, and women will have access to a national, confidential, 24-hour, toll-free hotline if they are experiencing mental health challenges.<br>• <strong>Substance Use Services: </strong>Federal agencies will partner with community-based organizations to ensure that addiction services and people trained in substance use disorder during pregnancy are more available.<br>• <strong>No More Surprise Bills: </strong>Through the No Surprises Act, women are now protected from certain unexpected medical bills, which may occur during pregnancy, postpartum care, and/or delivery.<br>• <strong>Better Trained Providers: </strong>More providers will be trained on implicit biases as well as culturally and linguistically appropriate care, so that more women are listened to, respected, and empowered as a decisionmaker in their own care.<br>• <strong>Improved Maternal Health Data: </strong>Through enhanced federal partnerships with state and local maternal health data collection entities, communities, hospitals, and researchers will have access to better data to they can analyze poor outcomes during pregnancy and make improvements to support healthy pregnancies.<br>• <strong>A More Diverse Maternal Care Workforce:</strong> Federal agencies will invest more in hiring, training, and deploying more physicians, certified nurse midwives, doulas, and community health workers to support women during pregnancy, delivery, and postpartum. The federal government will work to ensure these providers come from diverse communities and backgrounds.<br>• <strong>Better Access to Doulas and Midwives: </strong>The Administration will work with states to expand access to doulas and midwives, and encourage insurance companies to cover their services.<br>• <strong>Expanded Social Services: </strong>Stronger partnerships between the Departments of Housing and Urban Development, Agriculture, and Health and Human Services will help make it easier to enroll in federal programs for housing, food, childcare, and income assistance, as we know health care is only one part of what makes for a healthy pregnancy.<br>• <strong>Stronger Workplace Protections for Mothers: </strong>Federal agencies will promote greater awareness of workplace protections and accommodations for new parents, like access to a private lactation room and break time to pump.</p>



<p>The actions outlined in the Blueprint are just the latest in this Administration’s multi-year effort to combat maternal mortality and morbidity. Since taking office, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken significant steps to address the maternal health crisis in the United States, including:</p>



<p>• <strong>Extending Postpartum Medicaid Coverage. </strong>Through the American Rescue Plan, states now have an easier pathway to extend Medicaid coverage from two to twelve months postpartum. Currently, 14 states and the District of Columbia have availed themselves of this opportunity, extending coverage for more than 250,000 women.<br>• <strong>Announcing the New “Birthing Friendly” Hospitals Initiative. </strong>During the December Call to Action, the Vice President announced that, through the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Administration will be deploying a “Birthing Friendly” hospitals designation—the first federal hospital quality designation with a focus on maternal health.<br>• <strong>Hosting the First-Ever Meeting of Cabinet Officials on Maternal Health.</strong> In April of this year, Vice President Harris hosted the first-ever meeting of Cabinet officials to discuss maternal health. This meeting brought together twelve agency leaders including leaders from the Departments of Health and Human Services, Defense, Veterans Affairs, Agriculture, and Housing and Urban Development to discuss ways that this Administration could deploy the resources of the federal government to tackle maternal mortality and morbidity.<br>• <strong>Leading the White House’s First-Ever Maternal Health Day of Action. </strong>In December 2021, the Vice President issued a nationwide Call to Action for federal agencies, businesses, and non-profits to collaboratively solve the maternal health crisis. During that event, the Vice President announced that this Administration had secured millions of dollars in private sector commitments aimed at improving maternal health.</p>



<p>As we continue taking bold action to confront the maternal mortality and morbidity crisis, we will continue to listen to people who are pregnant and new mothers and ensure their feedback informs our approach to improve maternal health and strengthen our health care system. With the support of all parts of government and society, we can make this vision a reality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the Surfside Remembrance&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-surfside-remembrance-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 14:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surfside, Florida Good morning. Hidden in crowds—scattered throughout workplaces, and grocery stores, and parks—there is a fellowship of loss.  To the uninitiated, we look normal, average, whole. But like a secret handshake, I can spot them—by the sadness that rests at the corner of their smile. By the curve of their shoulders, as if they can still feel the small arms of a child&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Surfside, Florida</p>



<p>Good morning. Hidden in crowds—scattered throughout workplaces, and grocery stores, and parks—there is a fellowship of loss. <br><br>To the uninitiated, we look normal, average, whole. But like a secret handshake, I can spot them—by the sadness that rests at the corner of their smile. By the curve of their shoulders, as if they can still feel the small arms of a child wrapping around their neck. <br><br>And though we are strangers, we know untellable truths about one another: That we will spend the rest of our lives longing for a face that’s gone forever—and that when they left our world, they took a light inside of us with them. <br><br>There are some who might say that the hurt fades over time. But we know that’s not true. There is a collapsed star spinning inside of us, and we will forever live in its gravity. <br><br>The things we carry are heavier now. And one year later—or many years later—our knees sometimes buckle beneath the weight of our grief. <br><br>Still, we have discovered moments of grace too. Somehow, and against all odds, we rise from the floor. We find a fortitude that we didn’t know we had—and we reach out for help. We realize that we’re not alone. <br><br>Today, we gather to remember the 98 people lost. <br><br>On behalf of my husband, President Biden, whose heart and prayers have never left this community, we stand with you today and always. And as we gather, we express gratitude for this community: <br><br>The fire fighters and other first responders who bound up wounds and spent weeks working to recover your loved ones.<br><br>The members of Surfside who came together to embrace you—who prayed for you every night, and wrapped their arms around you.<br><br>The Americans from across our country who donated and found ways to spread kindness.<br><br>We honor the light you found in each other—a fellowship you never wanted to be a part of, but draw strength from just the same. <br><br>If there is something strong enough to help us carry the burden of grief forward—something able to break its gravitational pull—it’s love. <br><br>The love that makes us tell that story one more time, that makes us laugh with tears in our eyes, and knows a part of them is still inside of us, even though they left before we were done needing them. <br><br>The love of the friends and family who refuse to leave us alone, who remind us that joy can be found even in sorrow. <br><br>The love of a community that lifts us when we’re weak—that carries us. <br><br>Take it one breath at a time. We are praying for you and grieving with you. <br><br>God bless you. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"> ###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Senate Passage of Bipartisan Gun&#160;Legislation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-senate-passage-of-bipartisan-gun-legislation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 02:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tonight, after 28 years of inaction, bipartisan members of Congress came together to heed the call of families across the country and passed legislation to address the scourge of gun violence in our communities. Families in Uvalde and Buffalo &#8211; and too many tragic shootings before &#8211; have demanded action. &#160;And tonight, we acted. This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tonight, after 28 years of inaction, bipartisan members of Congress came together to heed the call of families across the country and passed legislation to address the scourge of gun violence in our communities. Families in Uvalde and Buffalo &#8211; and too many tragic shootings before &#8211; have demanded action. &nbsp;And tonight, we acted.</p>



<p>This bipartisan legislation will help protect Americans. Kids in schools and communities will be safer because of it. The House of Representatives should promptly vote on this bipartisan bill and send it to my desk.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
