<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 17:21:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Cost of Living in America: Helping Families Move Ahead with the Build Back Better&#160;Agenda</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/the-cost-of-living-in-america-helping-families-move-ahead-with-the-build-back-better-agenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 17:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Report from the Council of Economic Advisers and Office of Management and Budget Over the last three decades, American families have experienced a rise in the costs of many necessities that has made it difficult for them to attain economic security. While prices of some services and goods have fallen substantially over this period,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New Report from the Council of Economic Advisers and Office of Management and Budget</em></p>



<p>Over the last three decades, American families have experienced a rise in the costs of many necessities that has made it difficult for them to attain economic security. While prices of some services and goods have fallen substantially over this period, especially when bearing in mind increases in their quality, several others—particularly health care, prescription drugs, childcare, and education—have risen substantially, and in many cases, faster than incomes. Rising income inequality and the fact that low- and middle-income-families spend a higher share of their budgets on necessities mean that low- and middle-income families are more exposed to these cost increases.</p>



<p>Through the&nbsp;Build Back Better economic agenda, the Biden Administration has proposed critical investments to address these long-standing cost pressures. Families with young children will benefit most from the proposed expansion of the Child Tax Credit, universal preschool, and improvements in the quality of childcare and a reduction in associated out-of-pocket costs. Proposals to lower prescription drug cost through Medicare-negotiated prices, add dental and vision benefits to Medicare, and expand access to home- and community-based care through Medicaid will especially benefit households with elderly members. Combined, these policy proposals, and others put forward by the President, will help ensure that families can meet costs and share in a broad prosperity.</p>



<p>Read the full report <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Costs-Brief.pdf">here</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Business, University and Health Care Leaders on COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccination&#160;Requirements</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-business-university-and-health-care-leaders-on-covid-19-vaccination-requirements/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 17:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden virtually met with four business, university and health care leaders who have adopted COVID-19 vaccination requirements for their workforces. The President expressed his appreciation for these leaders stepping up to protect the lives of their employees and communities. He highlighted the Administration’s vaccination requirements for the federal workforce, including requiring COVID-19 vaccinations&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden virtually met with four business, university and health care leaders who have adopted COVID-19 vaccination requirements for their workforces. The President expressed his appreciation for these leaders stepping up to protect the lives of their employees and communities. He highlighted the Administration’s vaccination requirements for the federal workforce, including requiring COVID-19 vaccinations for health care workers at the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense’s plan to add the COVID-19 vaccine to the list of required vaccinations for service members. During the meeting, the leaders shared how they arrived at their decision to require vaccinations and how they are working to implement their own requirements. The President asked each of these leaders to talk to their industry peers about this important step to share best practices and encourage additional action. He expressed his optimism that additional employers would follow suit, and he noted that the federal government will continue to support employers as they require COVID-19 vaccinations.<br> <br><u><em>Meeting Participants</em></u></p>



<ul><li>Greg A. Adams, Chairman and CEO of Kaiser Permanente</li><li>Dr. Wayne A. I. Frederick, President of Howard University</li><li>Scott Kirby, CEO of United Airlines</li><li>Diane E. Sumpter, President and CEO of DESA, Inc.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Official Travel to&#160;Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-official-travel-to-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden’s&#160;National&#160;Security Advisor Jake Sullivan,&#160;DHS Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas, and Under Secretary of State&#160;Uzra Zeya traveled&#160;to Mexico&#160;on August 10&#160;to advance U.S.-Mexico cooperation across&#160;our&#160;bilateral agenda. &#160;NSC Senior Director Juan Gonzalez,&#160;National Security Advisor to the Vice President Ambassador Nancy McEldowney, Ambassador Julissa Reynoso, State Department Senior Western Hemisphere Bureau Official Ricardo Zuniga, and Department of Homeland Security Assistant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden’s&nbsp;National&nbsp;Security Advisor Jake Sullivan,&nbsp;DHS Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas, and Under Secretary of State&nbsp;Uzra Zeya traveled&nbsp;to Mexico&nbsp;on August 10&nbsp;to advance U.S.-Mexico cooperation across&nbsp;our&nbsp;bilateral agenda. &nbsp;NSC Senior Director Juan Gonzalez,&nbsp;National Security Advisor to the Vice President Ambassador Nancy McEldowney, Ambassador Julissa Reynoso, State Department Senior Western Hemisphere Bureau Official Ricardo Zuniga, and Department of Homeland Security Assistant Secretary David&nbsp;Shahoulian&nbsp;also traveled with the delegation. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>National Security Advisor Sullivan and his team met with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador, Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard, Attorney General Gertz, and Secretary of Finance Ramirez de la O, as well as other senior Mexican government representatives. The visit followed a phone call between Vice President Kamala Harris and President López Obrador on August 9, and provided an opportunity to discuss economic and security priorities, such as competitiveness, our shared border, COVID-19 recovery, security cooperation, and development in southern Mexico and Central America.</p>



<p>During the visit, U.S. and Mexican officials reaffirmed the strategic relationship between our two countries. Given the strong economic ties binding us, the delegations advanced preparations for the upcoming relaunch of the U.S.-Mexico High-Level Economic Dialogue (HLED), which will be held in Washington on September 9. They discussed opportunities to better integrate our economies to make them more resilient, including the potential to strengthen and pivot supply chains in alignment with our domestic efforts to build back better. National Security Advisor Sullivan also affirmed our cooperation on health security, including assessing the current COVID-19 situation on the ground in both countries and collaborating to manage the pandemic together.<br><br>Officials underscored the importance of fostering development in southern Mexico and Central America to address the root causes of irregular migration, and will work toward deeper collaboration within the Root Causes Strategy. They discussed current irregular migration flows and committed to jointly managing safe, orderly migration that respects human rights. The National Security Advisor and Mexican leaders also affirmed their commitment to a regional approach to migration. In addition, Mexican and U.S. officials spoke about plans for strategic security cooperation, a central pillar of our relationship. They discussed next steps toward the commitment made during Vice President Harris’ visit in June to hold a High-Level Security Dialogue with Mexico.<br><br>During his visit, National Security Advisor Sullivan stressed that the United States and Mexico share democratic values and joint priorities, including improving global health, security, and economic prosperity for all.<br><br>Additional representatives of the Government of Mexico included National Migration Institute Commissioner Francisco Garduno, Mexican Army Major General and Southern Border Coordinator General Vicente Hernandez,  Army Lieutenant General and Commander of Military Operations General Guillermo Briseno, Mexican Navy Rear Admiral and Undersecretary for Administration Vice-Admiral Benito Galeana, Undersecretary of Public Security Ricardo Mejia, and Chief of the Secretariat of Foreign Relations North America Unit Roberto Velasco.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on the Need for Reliable and Stable Global Energy&#160;Markets</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-the-need-for-reliable-and-stable-global-energy-markets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Higher gasoline costs, if left unchecked, risk harming the ongoing global recovery. The price of crude oil has been higher than it was at the end of 2019, before the onset of the pandemic. While OPEC+ recently agreed to production increases, these increases will not fully offset previous production cuts that OPEC+ imposed during the pandemic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">Higher gasoline costs, if left unchecked, risk harming the ongoing global recovery. The price of crude oil has been higher than it was at the end of 2019, before the onset of the pandemic.<br><br>While OPEC+ recently agreed to production increases, these increases will not fully offset previous production cuts that OPEC+ imposed during the pandemic until well into 2022. At a critical moment in the global recovery, this is simply not enough. <br><br>President Biden has made clear that he wants Americans to have access to affordable and reliable energy, including at the pump. Although we are not a party to OPEC, the United States will always speak to international partners regarding issues of significance that affect our national economic and security affairs, in public and private. We are engaging with relevant OPEC+ members on the importance of competitive markets in setting prices. Competitive energy markets will ensure reliable and stable energy supplies, and OPEC+ must do more to support the recovery.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-34/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 12:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Elizabeth Prelogar, of Idaho, to be Solicitor General of the United States, vice Noel J. Francisco. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Ramin Toloui, of Iowa, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Economic and Business Affairs), vice Manisha Singh. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Elizabeth Prelogar, of Idaho, to be Solicitor General of the United States, vice Noel J. Francisco.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ramin Toloui, of Iowa, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Economic and Business Affairs), vice Manisha Singh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Nominates Elizabeth Prelogar for Solicitor&#160;General</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/president-biden-nominates-elizabeth-prelogar-for-solicitor-general/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced he has nominated Elizabeth Prelogar as Solicitor General at the Department of Justice. Elizabeth Prelogar, Nominee for Solicitor General, Department of JusticeElizabeth Prelogar began serving as the Acting Solicitor General at the U. S. Department of Justice in January 2021. Prelogar has focused her career on Supreme Court and appellate litigation. From 2014 to 2019, she served&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced he has nominated Elizabeth Prelogar as Solicitor General at the Department of Justice.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Elizabeth Prelogar, Nominee for Solicitor General, Department of Justice<br></span></strong><br>Elizabeth Prelogar began serving as the Acting Solicitor General at the U. S. Department of Justice in January 2021. Prelogar has focused her career on Supreme Court and appellate litigation. From 2014 to 2019, she served as an Assistant to the Solicitor General.  During her prior tenure at the Department of Justice, Prelogar was asked to serve on the Special Counsel’s Russia investigation and was an Assistant Special Counsel to Robert S. Mueller III. Prelogar has also spent time as a partner at Cooley LLP and an associate at Hogan Lovells, and she taught a course at Harvard Law School on Supreme Court and appellate advocacy. <br><br>After graduating from Harvard Law School, Prelogar clerked for Judge Merrick B. Garland of the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit. She then completed consecutive Supreme Court clerkships for Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg and Justice Elena Kagan. Prelogar previously completed a master’s degree in creative writing at the University of St. Andrews in Scotland, earned her undergraduate degree in English and Russian from Emory University, and was a Fulbright Fellow in St. Petersburg, Russia. Born and raised in Idaho, Prelogar lives in Washington, D.C. with her husband and their two sons.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden to Convene Leaders’ Summit for&#160;Democracy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/president-biden-to-convene-leaders-summit-for-democracy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President has said that the challenge of our time is to demonstrate that democracies can deliver&#160;by improving the lives of their own people and by addressing the greatest problems facing the wider world. In his first six months in office, the President has reinvigorated democracy at home, vaccinating 70% of population, passing the&#160;American Rescue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President has said that the challenge of our time is to demonstrate that democracies can deliver&nbsp;by improving the lives of their own people and by addressing the greatest problems facing the wider world. In his first six months in office, the President has reinvigorated democracy at home, vaccinating 70% of population, passing the&nbsp;American Rescue plan, and advancing bipartisan legislation to invest in our infrastructure and competitiveness. And&nbsp;he has rebuilt our alliances with our democratic partners and allies, rallying the world to stand up against human rights abuses, to address the climate crisis, and to fight the global pandemic, including by donating hundreds of millions of vaccine doses to countries around the globe.</p>



<p>In keeping this commitment, today President Biden is pleased to announce that in December he will bring together leaders from a diverse group of the world’s democracies at a virtual Summit for Democracy, to be followed in roughly a year’s time by a second, in-person Summit. The virtual Summit, to take place on December 9 and 10, will galvanize commitments and initiatives across three principal themes: defending against authoritarianism, fighting corruption, and promoting respect for human rights. Following a year of consultation, coordination, and action, President Biden will then invite world leaders to gather once more to showcase progress made against their commitments. Both Summits will bring together heads of state, civil society, philanthropy, and the private sector, serving as an opportunity for world leaders to listen to one another and to their citizens, share successes, drive international collaboration, and speak honestly about the challenges facing democracy so as to collectively strengthen the foundation for democratic renewal.</p>



<p>Find more here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/summit-for-democracy/">https://www.state.gov/summit-for-democracy/</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-33/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 01:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Jessica D. Aber, of Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Virginia for the term of four years, vice G. Zachary Terwilliger, resigned. &#160; &#160; &#160;Nicole L. Angarella, of Virginia, to be Inspector General, United States Agency for International Development, vice Ann Calvaresi Barr,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jessica D. Aber, of Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Virginia for the term of four years, vice G. Zachary Terwilliger, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Nicole L. Angarella, of Virginia, to be Inspector General, United States Agency for International Development, vice Ann Calvaresi Barr, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Samuel R. Bagenstos, of Michigan, to be General Counsel of the Department of Health and Human Services, vice Robert Charrow.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Alexandra Baker, of New Jersey, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense, vice James H. Anderson, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jainey Kumar Bavishi, of New York, to be Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, vice Timothy Gallaudet.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sarah H. Cleveland, of New York, to be Legal Adviser of the Department of State, vice Jennifer Gillian Newstead, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;John Patrick Coffey, of New York, to be General Counsel of the Department of the Navy, vice Robert John Sander.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Chester John Culver, of Iowa, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation, vice Myles J. Watts.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Melissa Griffin Dalton, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense, vice Kenneth P. Rapuano.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Carla B. Freedman, of New York, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of New York for the term of four years, vice Richard S. Hartunian, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;David R. Gilmour, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Equatorial Guinea.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Todd M. Harper, of Virginia, to be a Member of the National Credit Union Administration Board for a term expiring April 10, 2027. &nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Owen Edward Herrnstadt, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States for a term expiring January 20, 2025, vice Judith Delzoppo Pryor, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;William J. Ihlenfeld, II, of West Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of West Virginia for the term of four years, vice William J. Powell, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Maria Fabiana Jorge, of the District of Columbia, to be United States Alternate Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank, vice Eliot Pedrosa.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Christopher R. Kavanaugh, of Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of Virginia for the term of four years, vice Thomas T. Cullen, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Victoria Reggie Kennedy, of Massachusetts, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Austria.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Alexia Marie Gabrielle Latortue, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, vice Mitchell A. Silk.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Amy Loyd, of New Mexico, to be Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education, Department of Education, vice Scott Stump.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Darcie N. McElwee, of Maine, to be United States Attorney for the District of Maine for the term of four years, vice Halsey B. Frank, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Scott Miller, of Colorado, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Swiss Confederation, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Principality of Liechtenstein.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Brent Neiman, of Illinois, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of the Treasury, vice Ramin Toloui.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Leopoldo Martinez Nucete, of Virginia, to be United States Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank for a term of three years, vice Eliot Pedrosa.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Breon S. Peace, of New Jersey, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of New York for the term of four years, vice Robert Lloyd Capers, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Marc R. Stanley, of Texas, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Argentine Republic.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;William S. Thompson, of West Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of West Virginia for the term of four years, vice Michael B. Stuart, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Damian Williams, of New York, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of New York for the term of four years, vice Preet Bharara, term expired.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWAL SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Chester John Culver, of Iowa, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation, vice Charles A. Stones, which was sent to the Senate on July 15, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before a Briefing from the FEMA Administrator, Homeland Security, and COVID-&#8288;19 Response&#160;Teams</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/10/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-briefing-from-the-fema-administrator-homeland-security-and-covid-19-response-teams/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 4:46 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, folks.  I’ll make a brief opening statement here.  I want to thank you, Administrator Criswell, for the job you’ve been doing &#8212; outstanding work helping our country navigate what is overlapping challenges we’ve been facing.  And you’ve been very busy. We’ve got wildfires in the West. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>4:46 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, folks.  I’ll make a brief opening statement here.  I want to thank you, Administrator Criswell, for the job you’ve been doing &#8212; outstanding work helping our country navigate what is overlapping challenges we’ve been facing.  And you’ve been very busy.<br><br>We’ve got wildfires in the West.  We’ve got &#8212; approaching the peak of Atlantic hurricane season.  All across the country, the Delta variant is spreading, as Dr. Fauci and others can tell you, and it&#8217;s spreading rapidly &#8212; rapidly among the unvaccinated.  When these crises intersect, they compound one another &#8212; natural disasters and the Delta variant.<br><br>And that’s what we’re going to be discussing today with the group I’ve assembled here.  We need to be ready to manage our natural disasters caused by hurricanes hitting the Southeast and the environment and with a broad community spread of COVID-19.<br>And the best thing we can do is &#8212; to prepare for that is for everyone who is not vaccinated &#8212; I know it’s a broken record, and I keep saying it &#8212; but to get vaccinated.<br><br>With the Delta variant, we’re seeing a pandemic of the unvaccinated.  Cases and hospitalizations are rising faster in states with low vaccination rates, such as Florida, Texas, Louisiana, Alabama, and Mississippi, which are the states that &#8212; from a hurricane-prone &#8212; they’re the states that are most at risk.<br><br>And so, we don’t wait until it’s too late.  And if, God forbid, a natural disaster strikes, we have to make sure we’re ready to be protected against COVID-19 as well.<br><br>Let me be clear: If you’re in a state where hurricanes often strike &#8212; like Florida or the Gulf Coast or into Texas &#8212; a vital part of preparing for hurricane season is to get vaccinated now.  Everything is more complicated if you’re not vaccinated and a hurricane or a natural disaster hits.<br><br>If you wind up having to evacuate, if you wind up having to stay in a shelter, you don’t want to add COVID-19 to the list of dangers that you’re going to be confronting. <br><br>Get vaccinated now so you’re ready for whatever may come this month.  And it’s likely some serious hurricanes are going to come this month. <br><br>So, go to Ready.gov to make sure that you’re prepared with the hurricane &#8212; with a hurricane plan.  Know your evacuation zones.  Have a plan with your family.  And get your emergency supplies and a go-bag ready, and don’t forget to pack one for your pets as well.  I mean that seriously.<br><br>And if you’ve got older neighbors or people in your community who might need your help, check in to see if you can help them make a plan as well. <br><br>And the bottom line is this: The more we do to prepare, the better off we are when disaster strikes.<br><br>We can’t prevent hurricanes making landfall, but we can prevent people from getting seriously sick and dying from COVID-19.  Get vaccinated and make a plan.<br><br>Thank you, all.  That’s what we’re going to discuss in some detail today with my team.  Thank you all very much.<br><br>4:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting on Hurricane Preparedness During COVID-&#8288;19&#160;Pandemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-on-hurricane-preparedness-during-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 23:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26803</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden met with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Chief Medical Advisor and NIAID Director Dr. Anthony Fauci, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, and COVID-19 Response Coordinator and Counselor to the President Jeff Zients, as well as members of his Homeland Security and COVID-19 Response teams, for a briefing on the state of the COVID-19&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden met with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Chief Medical Advisor and NIAID Director Dr. Anthony Fauci, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, and COVID-19 Response Coordinator and Counselor to the President Jeff Zients, as well as members of his Homeland Security and COVID-19 Response teams, for a briefing on the state of the COVID-19 pandemic in hurricane-prone states in the South and Southeast.  They discussed efforts underway to protect public health, enhance preparedness, and adapt response and recovery operations to meet the challenges of the combined effects of hurricanes and the spread of the Delta variant. </p>



<p>The President was briefed on the data that demonstrates that the most important preparatory step people can take to prepare for peak hurricane season is to get vaccinated to ensure they will be protected from COVID-19 if they have to evacuate their homes. They also discussed how FEMA is innovating during the pandemic by working with partner organizations to enable COVID-safe sheltering, providing vaccination options at shelters and recovery centers, and protecting its workforce so they maintain mission readiness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
