<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:59:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Modi of India Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/11/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-modi-of-india-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:24 A.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Prime Minister Modi, it’s always good to see you.  I’m looking forward to seeing you in Japan, about the 24th of May.  And I was honored to welcome you to the White House last September to discuss U.S.-India relations, to meet with our fellow Quad leaders.   And I&#8217;m pleased to have this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:24 A.M. EDT<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Prime Minister Modi, it’s always good to see you.  I’m looking forward to seeing you in Japan, about the 24th of May.  And I was honored to welcome you to the White House last September to discuss U.S.-India relations, to meet with our fellow Quad leaders.  <br> <br>And I&#8217;m pleased to have this opportunity to speak with you today virtually and with your two ministers and your ambassador here in person.  <br> <br>(Referring to the language interpretation.)  Is it contemporaneous? <br> <br>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Yes, (inaudible).<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>As two vibrant democracies who &#8212; one is learning how to make sure I can do this contemporaneously, but &#8212; two vibrant democracies, we have a &#8212; we take the same concerns about the global challenges we face &#8212; from COVID-19, advancing health security, and tracking the climate crisis &#8212; and we share a strong and growing Major Defense Partnership. <br> <br>At the root of our partnership is a deep connection between our people &#8212; ties of family, of friendship, and of shared values.  <br> <br>On that note, I want to welcome India&#8217;s humanitarian support for the people of Ukraine, who are suffering a horrific assault, including a tragic shelling in a train station last week that killed dozens of innocent children and women and civilians attempting to flee the violence.<br> <br>The United States and India are going to continue our close consultation on how to manage the destabilizing effects of this Russian war.  <br> <br>And I&#8217;m looking forward to our discussions today, Mr. Prime Minister.  Our continued consultation and dialogue are key to ensuring the U.S.-India relationship continues to grow deeper and stronger, delivering our people and our global good &#8212; good that we all are seeking to manage, particularly in your part of the world. <br> <br>And the floor is yours, Mr. Prime Minister.<br> <br>PRIME MINISTER MODI:  (As interpreted.)  President Biden, I would like to, first of all, express my gratitude to you for your warm words.  Our defense and foreign ministers will be meeting today in the 2+2 format in a short while from now.<br> <br>Our meeting before that is very important, as it will provide direction for the discussions.  I also appreciate your initiative to organize today&#8217;s virtual meeting.<br> <br>Excellency, when I was in Washington last year in September &#8212; and you, in fact, mentioned that &#8212; you had said at the time that the India-America partnership can contribute to solving a lot of global problems.  I totally agree with you.<br> <br>As two democracies that are the world’s largest and oldest, we are natural partners.  And the progress that has taken place in our relations in the last few years, the new momentum that has been created would have been hard to even imagine a few decades ago.<br> <br>Excellency, our talks today are taking place at a time when the situation in Ukraine is very worrying.<br> <br>A few weeks ago, over 20,000 Indians were stuck in Ukraine, and most of them were young students.  After a lot of hard work, we were successful in getting them all out safely.  One student, however, lost his life.<br> <br>During this entire process, I spoke several times on the phone to the presidents of both Ukraine and Russia.  I not only appealed for peace, but also suggested that there be direct talks between President Putin and the President of Ukraine.<br> <br>We had extensive discussions on Ukraine in our parliament as well. <br> <br>Recently, the news about the killings of innocent civilians in the Bucha city was very worrying.  We instantly condemned the killings and have called for an independent inquiry.  <br> <br>We hope that the ongoing discussions between Russia and Ukraine will lead to peace.<br> <br>Excellency, we have also emphasized the importance of the security of civilians in Ukraine and the unhindered supply of humanitarian assistance to them &#8212; and you mentioned this, in fact. <br> <br>On our part, we have sent medicines and other relief material to Ukraine and to its neighboring countries.  And on Ukraine&#8217;s request, we will be sending them another consignment of medicines very soon.<br> <br>Excellency, at the beginning of your term in office, you’d used a very important slogan: “Democracies can deliver.”  The India-America partnership and the success of the India-America partnership is the best means to make this slogan meaningful.<br> <br>This year, India is celebrating 75 years of its independence, and we are also celebrating the 75th anniversary of our diplomatic relations as well.  I am confident that our friendship with America will be an integral part of India&#8217;s development journey over the next 25 years.<br> <br>Once again, my thanks to you for organizing this event.<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Thank you, Mr. Prime Minister.  We&#8217;re going to hold for just a moment, Mr. Prime Minister, while the press leaves the room.  <br> <br>11:31 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Lady Jill&#160;Biden Leads Administration Officials in Call for Puerto Rican Families to Sign Up for the American Rescue Plan’s Expanded Child Tax&#160;Credit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/first-lady-jill-biden-leads-administration-officials-in-call-for-puerto-rican-families-to-sign-up-for-the-american-rescue-plans-expanded-child-tax-credit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is committed to creating an economy that works for every American. Part of that agenda is to ensure that families in Puerto Rico are treated fairly in our tax system. Historically, the prior Child Tax Credit (CTC) only applied to families in Puerto Rico with three or more qualifying children, and therefore only&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is committed to creating an economy that works for every American. Part of that agenda is to ensure that families in Puerto Rico are treated fairly in our tax system. Historically, the prior Child Tax Credit (CTC) only applied to families in Puerto Rico with three or more qualifying children, and therefore only 10% of families with children were eligible.<br>&nbsp;<br>That changed when President Biden signed the American Rescue Plan (ARP). It not only provided the largest Child Tax Credit nationwide to the most ever families, it also made sure that, for the first time, families and children in Puerto Rico fully benefited – permanently fixing the credit to give Puerto Rico families equal access. This tax filing season, 97% of Puerto Rico families with children are now eligible for the expanded CTC. The law also <em><u>permanently</u></em> changed the structure of the CTC so that every child in Puerto Rico will get the credit on the same basis as all other American children. This will mean that parents in Puerto Rico will have, as President Biden says, a “little more breathing room” in meeting the costs of raising a family and that there will be fewer children in Puerto Rico living in poverty.<br>&nbsp;<br>The ARP also meant a historic expansion of the federal government’s commitment to expand the Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC) in Puerto Rico. Together, the expanded CTC and EITC could provide an estimated $1 billion annually in critical benefits to hundreds of thousands of low- and moderate-income working people and families in Puerto Rico.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, as part of a final push to encourage families in Puerto Rico to file their taxes and receive both the CTC and EITC, First Lady Dr. Jill Biden, Education Secretary Miguel Cardona, House Chairwoman Nydia Velazquez, Deputy Secretary of Treasury Wally Adeyemo, and American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling are holding a special virtual event with UnidosUS, the Hispanic Federation, the Institute of Youth Development/Instituto del Desarrollo de la Juventud (IDJ), Espacios Abiertos, and United Way of Puerto Rico. The Biden Administration and these leading non-profits are urging families to file their taxes by April 18<sup>th</sup> to take advantage of this critical aid.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>The American Rescue Plan made historic, permanent changes to the Child Tax Credit for Puerto Rico families – making the credit available to 97% of Puerto Rico families this year, compared to 10% before the ARP</strong></p>



<ul><li>Previously, <strong><em><u>only Puerto Rico families with three or more qualifying children or more qualified for any Child Tax Credit benefit</u></em></strong>.<br></li><li>This meant that before the American Rescue Plan, <strong><em><u>only about 10% of Puerto Rico families qualified for any Child Tax Credit.<br></u></em></strong></li><li>The ARP permanently changed that policy to extend the CTC to Puerto Rico families with fewer than three qualifying children who were previously excluded. <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/blog/tax-credit-expansions-expected-to-significantly-reduce-poverty-in-puerto-rico">As a result</a> of the ARP, <strong><em><u>97% of Puerto Rico families with children are eligible for the 2021 Child Tax Credit.<br></u></em></strong></li><li>For 2021, the ARP increased the Child Tax Credit to <strong><em><u>$3,600 per child under 6 and $3,000 per child 6-17</u></em></strong> – and ensured that lower income families could access the full credit.<br></li><li>In addition, the ARP provided the first-ever federal support for Puerto Rico’s local Earned Income Tax Credit – allowing Puerto Rico to <strong><u>more than</u></strong> triple EITC <strong><u>benefits</u></strong> and extend <strong><u>the EITC</u></strong> to more workers for the next 10 years.</li></ul>



<p>Together, the ARP’s expansions of the CTC and EITC are&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/american-rescue-plan-act-provides-critical-permanent-tax-relief-to-puerto-rico">estimated</a>&nbsp;to <strong>provide over $1 billion in tax relief</strong> per year going forward. They stand to benefit hundreds of thousands of Puerto Rico families – with the families of over 500,000 children eligible for the 2021 expanded CTC.<br><br><strong>Today’s event builds on substantial White House-Treasury Department efforts to ensure access to the 2021 Child Tax Credit in Puerto Rico:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>The White House and Treasury Department in collaboration with UnidosUS created a Weekly CTC/EITC Puerto Rico Working Group, with the Youth Development Institute (IDJ), Espacios Abiertos, Hispanic Federation, and others, to increase awareness and take up rates</strong> among newly eligible families in Puerto Rico for the CTC and Local EITC. This group is comprised of representatives of the Puerto Rico government, Hacienda (the local tax authority), Treasury, IRS, and local stakeholders — including community-based organizations and other advocates in Puerto Rico – who work to remove barriers for the implementation of tax credit policies. Collaboration across these groups has already led to the execution or launch of over 35 local community events, navigator trainings and capacity building engagements for local elected officials and municipal staff. More than 240 municipal and state agencies employees were trained to scale and implement integrated outreach strategies and provide free tax preparation services for low-to-middle income communities.<br></li><li><strong>The White House and Treasury Department collaborated closely with the Governor of Puerto Rico, Mayors, foundations and NGOs on the island to increase awareness and CTC sign-ups in Puerto Rico. </strong>The White House ARP Implementation Coordinator, White House Intergovernmental Affairs and Treasury teams met twice at the White House with the Governor of Puerto Rico on CTC outreach strategy and had several meetings with top Puerto Rican mayors. The White House ARP Implementation Team also organized several meetings with foundations on the importance of investing in CTC outreach in Puerto Rico.<br></li><li><strong>The Administration launched a stand-alone section of ChildTaxCredit.gov for Puerto Rico families and outreach partners. </strong><a href="https://www.childtaxcredit.gov/es/puerto-rico/">Childtaxcredit.gov/es/puerto-rico/</a> highlights the unique and unprecedented access for families with children to benefit from the enhanced CTC and provides information on how to claim the credit in plain language, Spanish, and a mobile friendly format.<br></li><li><strong>The Treasury Department and the White House worked to build capacity for Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) Centers and Facilitated Self-Assistance (FSA) Sites</strong>, including through navigator training and volunteer recruitment scale-up for tax prep assistance in low income communities. Currently there are 43 tax assistance sites, including VITA and FSA in the island.<br></li><li><strong>The Administration amplified the island-wide public campaign by the Alliance for Economic Security in Puerto Rico, and garnering support from state/local government. </strong>The Alliance, composed by the Hispanic Federation, Instituto del Desarrollo de la Juventud (IDJ) and Espacios Abiertos coalesced to launch &nbsp;<a href="https://reclamatudineropr.com/">ReclamaTuDineroPR.com</a> to further promote awareness of these tax benefits. In addition, the Administration has helped amplify these efforts and match trained IRS volunteers with Mayors and municipalities to host “Fill-a-thons” (“Llenatones” in Spanish) &#8211; to ensure all families with children learn about the credit and can receive tax filing assistance through a local community event.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Treasury provided training for mayors in Puerto Rico on how to leverage ARP State &amp; Fiscal Recovery Funds (SLFRF) to do CTC and EITC outreach and tax filing assistance outreach </strong>in collaboration with the White House, the Government of Puerto Rico, the Association of Mayors, and the Federation of Mayors of Puerto Rico to maximize critical State and Local ARP funds for local governments in Puerto Rico.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Selection of Special Advisors for the Summit of the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-selection-of-special-advisors-for-the-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. announced that former U.S. Senator Christopher Dodd of Connecticut and former U.S. Representative Debbie Mucarsel-Powell of Florida will serve as special advisors for the Ninth Summit of the Americas that will take place from June 6 through June 10 in Los Angeles, California. Senator Dodd served as a member&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. announced that former U.S. Senator Christopher Dodd of Connecticut and former U.S. Representative Debbie Mucarsel-Powell of Florida will serve as special advisors for the Ninth Summit of the Americas that will take place from June 6 through June 10 in Los Angeles, California.</p>



<p>Senator Dodd served as a member and Chair of the Senate Foreign Relations Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere for over three decades. Senator Dodd and President Biden worked closely together on the Senate Foreign Relations Committee for over 28 years. Senator Dodd’s interest in Latin America began years before his election to the U.S. Congress. In the 1960s, Dodd joined President John Kennedy’s Peace Corps, serving for two years as a volunteer in the Dominican Republic. During his service in the Peace Corps and in the Senate, he traveled extensively and on numerous occasions throughout the hemisphere.</p>



<p>As the first and only Latina Democrat to ever represent a Congressional district in Florida, and the first-ever Member of Congress born in Ecuador, Congresswoman Mucarsel-Powell was a leading voice in the charge to support Venezuelans fleeing their country through securing Temporary Protected Status in the United States and providing humanitarian and other aid to the Venezuelan people and neighboring countries. She served as chair of the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Women’s Task Force and also sponsored environmental and public health legislation.</p>



<p>Senator Dodd and Congresswoman Mucarsel-Powell are confident that President Biden will renew and strengthen the collaboration and respect essential for a bright future for the Americas at the upcoming Summit in Los Angeles this June.</p>



<p>The Summit of the Americas, the only meeting that brings together the leaders of North, South, and Central America and the Caribbean, will play a central role in shaping the future of the Americas at a critical time in our history.&nbsp; The region’s governments, civil society, and private sector will work to develop a shared vision built around the theme for this year’s meeting, “Building a Sustainable, Resilient, and Equitable Future.”</p>



<p>The United States looks forward to welcoming the hemisphere to Los Angeles to work together on strengthening our democracies, building more prosperous and inclusive economies, and better protecting the human rights, health, dignity, and security of our people.  The United States previously hosted the inaugural Summit of the Americas in Miami, Florida, in 1994.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Modi of&#160;India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-modi-of-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 17:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India to inaugurate the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue. Together, they committed to strengthening the U.S.-India relationship through cooperation on clean energy, technology and military cooperation, and expanded economic and people-to-people ties. They also committed to continue cooperation – bilaterally and multilaterally&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India to inaugurate the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue. Together, they committed to strengthening the U.S.-India relationship through cooperation on clean energy, technology and military cooperation, and expanded economic and people-to-people ties. They also committed to continue cooperation – bilaterally and multilaterally – on ending the COVID-19 pandemic, strengthening global health security, advancing global food security, and ensuring a free and open Indo-Pacific. They emphasized their shared commitment, as leaders of the world’s largest democracies, to respect for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all nations in the Indo-Pacific and beyond. The two Leaders also discussed the destabilizing impacts of Russia’s war against Ukraine, with a particular focus on global food supply. President Biden and Prime Minister Modi looked forward to meeting in person later this spring, in Tokyo, for the Quad summit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Education and Sharing Day, USA,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/11/a-proclamation-on-education-and-sharing-day-usa-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we work together to build a better America, we must remember that education is the key to achieving greater opportunity, prosperity, stability, and equality both here and around the world.&#160;&#160;A high-quality education develops the mind, opens the heart, nurtures our talents, and fortifies our character.&#160;&#160;Through education, we learn to recognize ourselves in our neighbors&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As we work together to build a better America, we must remember that education is the key to achieving greater opportunity, prosperity, stability, and equality both here and around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;A high-quality education develops the mind, opens the heart, nurtures our talents, and fortifies our character.&nbsp;&nbsp;Through education, we learn to recognize ourselves in our neighbors and cherish the dignity of our shared human experience.&nbsp;&nbsp;No one understood this better than the man whose life and legacy we celebrate on this day:&nbsp;&nbsp;Rabbi Menachem Mendel Schneerson, the Lubavitcher Rebbe and leader of the Chabad-Lubavitch movement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Rebbe&#8217;s devotion to educating people worldwide and his profound respect for diversity, inclusiveness, and equal justice have set a strong example for generations of Americans and people across the globe.  Having survived one of history&#8217;s cruelest chapters, the Rebbe emerged determined to help heal the soul of humanity.  He left his mark as a thinker, leader, and teacher who recognized the limitless potential of every human being regardless of their background.  His outreach is still felt today in countless houses of worship, centers of education, cultural exchanges, and service communities worldwide.</p>



<p>The Rebbe&#8217;s work reminds us, in the words of the Prophet Amos, to &#8220;hate evil, love good, and establish justice in the gate.&#8221;  We each share a responsibility to live up to those words &#8212; in and out of the classroom &#8212; and to plant the seeds of love, kindness, and empathy in the hearts and minds of every child in America.  </p>



<p>To ensure that our children are provided every opportunity to learn and grow, my Administration provided resources through the American Rescue Plan for schools to safely reopen for in-person instruction.  Today, thanks to our COVID-19 strategy and the resilience of local communities, more than 99 percent of America&#8217;s schools are open again.  But if we are truly going to build a better America, we must continue to make transformational investments in education &#8212; including making high-quality pre-school available to every 3- and 4-year old in America and coming together to address the invisible toll on children&#8217;s mental health that was exacerbated by the pandemic.</p>



<p>Today &#8212; on what would have been the Rebbe&#8217;s 120th birthday &#8212; let us celebrate all the educators, advocates, and pioneers who teach young people the lessons that create caring neighbors and closer communities.  Let us commit to learning together, sharing the best we have to offer, and working in unity for the common good. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 12, 2022, as Education and Sharing Day, USA.&nbsp;&nbsp;I call upon all government officials, educators, volunteers, and all the people of the United States to observe this day with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eleventh day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden Administration Releases Rural Playbook, Launches Building A Better America Rural Infrastructure Tour to Highlight Impact of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law on Rural&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/biden-administration-releases-rural-playbook-launches-building-a-better-america-rural-infrastructure-tour-to-highlight-impact-of-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-on-rural-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House released a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Rural Playbook to help state, local, Tribal and territorial governments in rural areas unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure and launched a rural infrastructure tour led by the President and other senior administration officials to engage rural communities across the country.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House released a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law <a href="https://build.gov/rural">Rural Playbook</a> to help state, local, Tribal and territorial governments in rural areas unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure and launched a rural infrastructure tour led by the President and other senior administration officials to engage rural communities across the country.</p>



<p>The Rural Playbook, found at build.gov/rural, builds on the release of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Guidebook and provides rural communities with information on the “what, when, where, and how to apply” for funding under the law – so no community needs to hire a lobbyist to access their government. The Playbook also identifies over 100 programs funded under the law with federal cost share flexibilities and matching requirement waivers.</p>



<p>During the month of April, Biden Administration officials will travel to dozens of rural communities as part of a Building A Better America rural infrastructure tour to talk about the impact of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments, as well as the President’s broader commitment to ensure federal resources reach all communities in rural America. Agriculture Secretary Tom Vilsack, Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo, Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm, EPA Administrator Michael Regan, Interior Secretary Deb Haaland, Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg and Infrastructure Coordinator Mitch Landrieu will take part in events, along with other senior administration officials.</p>



<p>President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will send billions of dollars to rural communities across the country. Supporting Americans living in rural areas remains a top priority for the Biden Administration, and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers on the President’s promises to provide high speed internet, safe roads and bridges, modern wastewater systems, clean drinking water, reliable and affordable electricity, and good paying jobs in every rural community. As part of this effort, the Biden Administration is also committed to working with communities to help them access federal resources and improving transparency.</p>



<p>“This Rural Playbook and our rural infrastructure tour are a critical part of our extensive outreach to state, local, tribal and territorial governments to ensure the people of America can benefit from this once-in-a-generation investment,” said <strong>Mitch Landrieu, Senior Advisor &amp; Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator.</strong> “Building a better America requires these funds to reach rural communities that have been left behind for far too long.&nbsp; We see you, and major investments are on the way. With these investments in infrastructure in rural communities, President Biden is delivering for rural America.”</p>



<p>Across the month of April, the Biden-Harris administration will announce billions for rural areas including rural water projects, flood mitigation, transportation, healthcare, and tribal community grants, along with new technical assistance programs for rural and tribal communities.&nbsp; Earlier this month, the Department of the Interior <a href="https://doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-420-million-rural-water-funding-president-bidens">announced $420 million for rural water systems</a> across six states: Iowa, Minnesota, Montana, New Mexico, North Dakota and South Dakota. Today, the President is also announcing a $1 billion America the Beautiful Challenge that will leverage Federal conservation and restoration investments with private and philanthropic contributions to accelerate land, water, and wildlife conservation efforts across the country. The America the Beautiful Challenge is anchored by an initial commitment of $440 million of Federal resources over the next five years to a new public-private grant program, administered by the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (NFWF), that will support locally led ecosystem restoration projects that invest in watershed restoration, resilience, equitable access, workforce development, corridors and connectivity, and collaborative conservation, consistent with the America the Beautiful Initiative. The America the Beautiful Challenge will offer states, Tribes, territories, local groups, non-governmental organizations, and others the opportunity to apply for multiple grant programs through a single application that is managed by NFWF.</p>



<p>Since President Biden signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law nearly five months ago, the Biden-Harris Administration has hit the ground running to deliver results. The Administration has made key progress towards implementing the largest long-term investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. More than $100 billion has been announced and allocated to states from formula and competitive programs for roads and highways, bridges, ports, airports, electric vehicle charging stations, water systems, high speed internet, weatherization and clean energy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Rural Infrastructure&#160;Tour</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-rural-infrastructure-tour/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have always believed that for America to succeed, rural America must succeed. Since taking office, my Administration has focused on building pathways to the middle class for rural Americans in rural America – including investing in rural infrastructure and rebuilding the communities that feed and fuel our country. For far too long, opportunity has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I have always believed that for America to succeed, rural America must succeed. Since taking office, my Administration has focused on building pathways to the middle class for rural Americans in rural America – including investing in rural infrastructure and rebuilding the communities that feed and fuel our country.</p>



<p>For far too long, opportunity has been out of reach for rural communities. My Administration is changing that. Through the American Rescue Plan, we supported rural families and provided rural communities with the tools and resources that made them central to America’s strong economic recovery. I also secured historic investments for rural America through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to make sure we revitalize and rebuild rural communities for years to come. These generational infrastructure investments will provide rural communities across America affordable high-speed internet, clean drinking water, reliable electricity, better roads and bridges, and good-paying jobs. Strong infrastructure in rural communities is good for jobs, good for keeping the economy moving, good for lowering prices, and good for America.</p>



<p>I am proud today that my Administration is launching a rural infrastructure tour to double down on our unwavering commitment to building a better America where rural communities thrive. In the coming weeks and beyond, Cabinet members and senior administration officials will crisscross the country to meet with, listen to, and deliver infrastructure investments to rural communities. As we unlock federal resources and generate results for these communities, we are unlocking opportunity – job opportunities, educational opportunities, and the opportunity for a better future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Announces New Actions to Lessen the Burden of Medical Debt and Increase Consumer&#160;Protection</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-announces-new-actions-to-lessen-the-burden-of-medical-debt-and-increase-consumer-protection/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris to announce reforms across four areas to ease the burden of medical debt,&#160;giving more American families the opportunity to thrive Today,&#160;as part of the fight to help Americans deal with high costs,&#160;the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions to protect consumers and lessen the burden of medical debt on American families.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Kamala Harris to announce reforms across four areas to ease the burden of medical debt,</em>&nbsp;<em>giving more American families the opportunity to thrive</em></p>



<p>Today,&nbsp;as part of the fight to help Americans deal with high costs,&nbsp;the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions to protect consumers and lessen the burden of medical debt on American families. Together, these actions will help:</p>



<ul><li>Hold medical providers and debt collectors accountable for harmful practices;</li><li>Reduce the role that medical debt plays in determining whether Americans can access credit – which will open up new opportunities for people with medical debt to buy a home or get a small business loan;</li><li>Help over half a million of low-income American veterans get their medical debt forgiven; and,</li><li>Inform consumers of their rights.</li></ul>



<p>One-in-three adults in the United States have medical debt. It is now the largest source of debt in collections—more than credit cards, utilities, and auto loans combined.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2021/04/who-had-medical-debt-in-united-states.html">Black and Hispanic households</a>&nbsp;are more likely to hold medical debt than white households.</p>



<p>Medical debt is not just a financial issue—it can have negative health effects too. One&nbsp;<a href="https://nmahoney.people.stanford.edu/sites/g/files/sbiybj23976/files/media/file/kaiser_20210831.pdf">study</a>&nbsp;found that almost half of individuals with medical debt intentionally avoided seeking care.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Getting sick or taking care of loved ones should not mean financial hardship for American families. That is why the Administration is taking new action to ease the burden of medical debt and protect consumers from predatory collection policies. These actions build upon the President’s April 5<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/05/executive-order-on-continuing-to-strengthen-americans-access-to-affordable-quality-health-coverage/?msclkid=887ba3d9b67111ec81e80c7ddd11167b">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;on strengthening access to affordable, quality health care coverage, which directed federal agencies to take action to reduce the burden of medical debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, Vice President Harris is announcing reforms in four areas that will lessen the burden of medical debt, protect consumers, and open up new opportunities for Americans looking to buy a home or start a small business.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Holding Providers and Collectors Accountable&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>When families cannot afford to pay the cost of care—often because they are uninsured or underinsured—<a href="https://finhealthnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Medical-Debt-and-Financial-Health-Executive-Summary.pdf">providers have a responsibility</a> to offer non-predatory payment plans or financial assistance to all eligible patients. While many do, far too many eligible patients report not receiving help. Worse, lawsuits against patients over medical bills <a href="https://news.yale.edu/2021/12/06/study-finds-spike-hospitals-suing-patients-over-unpaid-medical-bills?msclkid=a446f5ebb6cc11ecbc00812a3db42912">are on the rise</a>. And when hospitals sell outstanding bills to third party debt collectors, patients can be subjected to persistent and aggressive collections practices. </p>



<p>The federal government pays roughly $1.5 trillion a year into the health care system to provide patients with quality care and services. Providers receiving that funding should make it easy for eligible patients to receive the financial assistance they are entitled to, and should not directly or indirectly subject patients to illegal and harassing debt collection practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, Secretary Becerra is directing the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to evaluate how providers’ billing practices impact access and affordability of care and the accrual of medical debt. HHS will request data from more than 2,000 providers on medical bill collection practices, lawsuits against patients, financial assistance, financial product offerings, and 3<sup>rd</sup>&nbsp;party contracting or debt buying practices.&nbsp;The Department will, for the first time, weigh this information in their grantmaking decisions, publish topline data and policy recommendations for the public, and share potential violations with the relevant enforcement agencies of jurisdiction.</p>



<p>Separately, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) will investigate credit reporting companies and debt collectors that violate patients’ and families’ rights, and hold violators accountable. The CFPB has already issued a&nbsp;<a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.consumerfinance.gov%2Fabout-us%2Fnewsroom%2Fcfpb-issues-bulletin-to-prevent-unlawful-medical-debt-collection-and-credit-reporting%2F&amp;data=04%7C01%7CDiane.Thompson%40cfpb.gov%7C1fafc34fb3d945dfc6ef08da17e3e25d%7Cc817bf69ef414ed6ac5f1f44da3798c0%7C0%7C0%7C637848564786280189%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;sdata=piCtFykML5hUkeNWUupGnfZeQ9utyxObMhdlYbdiVDo%3D&amp;reserved=0">bulletin</a>&nbsp;to prevent unlawful medical debt collection and reporting. The CFPB will target coercive credit reporting and determine whether unpaid medical billing data should ever be included in credit reports.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Improve Government Underwriting Practices</strong></p>



<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Batty-Gibbs-Ippolito-health-insurance-medical-debt-financial-well-being-WP.pdf?x91208">latest research</a>&nbsp;finds that owing medical debt is not a reliable predictor of overall financial health. An&nbsp;<a href="https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201405_cfpb_report_data-point_medical-debt-credit-scores.pdf">analysis</a>&nbsp;of 5 million anonymized credit records found that consumers who owed medical debt paid their bills at the same rate as those who did not. In fact, including paid-off medical debt causes credit scores to&nbsp;<a href="https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201405_cfpb_report_data-point_medical-debt-credit-scores.pdf">underestimate</a>&nbsp;creditworthiness by as much as 22 points. As a result, the inclusion of medical debt on credit reports and in credit scores and loan underwriting can hold American’s back from financial opportunities while failing to improve the accuracy and predictiveness of lending programs.</p>



<p>The private sector has taken important steps to address this problem. Last month, the three largest credit reporting agencies—Equifax, Experian, and Transunion—announced that they will no longer include certain forms of medical debt on credit reports, removing billions of dollars in debt from consumer reports. This change covers borrowers with already paid debts, unpaid debts less than a year old, and debts paid or unpaid under $500.</p>



<p>However, this change leaves out a third of Americans with medical debt over $500. For example, 11 million Americans have medical debt above $2000 and 3 million Americans have debt over $10,000. Further action is needed to help families struggling with medical debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to leading the way. The federal government is one of the largest actors in consumer credit markets, directly providing tens of billions of loans annually to millions of Americans, and guaranteeing or holding up to&nbsp;70% of all mortgages. Government action matters.&nbsp;Americans with medical debt can apply for an FHA-backed mortgage without fear that medical debt will keep them from being able to buy a home. FHA – which&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/Housing/images/FHASFMarketShare2021Q4.pdf">backs over 12 % of new home purchases</a>&nbsp;in America &#8212; has eliminated medical debt from consideration when evaluating a borrower’s creditworthiness.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is why, today, the Administration is announcing actions that&nbsp;go beyond recent private sector announcements.</p>



<p><em><u>The Biden-Harris Administration is providing guidance to all agencies to eliminate medical debt as a factor for underwriting in credit programs</u></em>, whenever possible and consistent with law. Medical debt is not a reliable indicator of credit quality, and its impact should be reduced or eliminated to give more American families the opportunity to thrive:&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Americans with medical debt can apply for USDA rural housing service loans without fear that their medical debt could keep them from getting a mortgage. Today, USDA is announcing that it will discontinue the inclusion of any recurring medical debts into borrower repayment calculations, which measure a borrower’s ability to repay for its homeownership programs—<a href="https://crsreports.congress.gov/product/pdf/R/R47044">over $20 billion</a> in lending activity. <br> </li><li>The Department of Veteran Affairs has taken multiple steps to ensure credit reporting and underwriting regarding medical debt, including finalizing a rule to virtually cease reporting of medical debt for veterans with bills from VA Care. VA will also review its underwriting guidelines to ensure we minimize or eliminate medical debt reporting as a proxy for creditworthiness, wherever possible.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Small Business Administration has a demonstrated commitment to ensuring credit access and a vested interest in accurate credit reporting and underwriting.&nbsp;&nbsp;To further this commitment, SBA will work with its colleagues and partners to lessen the financial burden of medical debt for families and to review SBA lending programs to identify ways to reduce the negative impact of medical debt on small business access to capital.</li></ul>



<ul><li>FHFA is reviewing the credit models that Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac use and looking at ways to ensure that measures of creditworthiness are accurate, reliable, and predictive.</li></ul>



<p>To reinforce these measures, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) will be issuing new guidance to agencies to, whenever possible and consistent with law, eliminate medical debt as a factor for underwriting in credit programs, or reduce its impact.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Support Veterans in Financial Hardship</strong></p>



<p>Since the start of the pandemic, VA has&nbsp;<strong>cancelled or refunded approximately $1 billion in copayments to over 1.5 million veterans.</strong>&nbsp;The&nbsp;American Rescue Plan (ARP) eliminated all out-of-pocket medical cost for veterans enrolled in VA health care and provided much needed financial relief to veterans experiencing economic hardship during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Veterans Affairs (VA) will now make it easier and faster for lower-income veterans to get their VA medical debt forgiven. Currently, veterans in financial hardship who need medical debt relief from VA must fill out a complex, paper form with complicated eligibility requirements. The application process is confusing, time-consuming, and as a result, veterans may be deterred from applying for much-needed relief.&nbsp;To address these problems and ensure that veterans get the relief they deserve, VA will streamline the request process, including offering an online option to apply, and set a simple income threshold to qualify for relief.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5758">VA has also published a final rule</a>&nbsp;under which it will virtually cease reporting unfavorable debt, including medical debt, to consumer reporting agencies. The new rule ensures that debt reported better reflects creditworthiness, while saving veterans from further financial struggles simply because they had to take on medical debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Help Consumers Know Their Rights</strong></p>



<p>The CFPB will ramp-up its consumer education tools aimed at helping American families navigate the complex and often confusing medical billing landscape, including more materials specifically designed to help patients access the financial assistance they are entitled to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CFPB has a wide range of tools available to help patients and their families confronting medical billing and collections, particularly problems relating to debt collection and credit reporting, at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/consumer-tools/">consumerfinance.gov</a>. People experiencing aggressive debt collection, coercive credit reporting, or other problems with a consumer financial product or service related to medical billing and collections can submit a complaint to the CFPB at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/complaint/">consumerfinance.gov/complaint.</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Cracks Down on Ghost Guns, Ensures That ATF Has the Leadership it Needs to Enforce Our Gun&#160;Laws</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-cracks-down-on-ghost-guns-ensures-that-atf-has-the-leadership-it-needs-to-enforce-our-gun-laws/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden and Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco will deliver remarks in the Rose Garden to announce additional steps the Administration is taking to combat gun crime. Ensuring that ATF has the leadership it needs to enforce our commonsense gun laws and fight gun crime. The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden and Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco will deliver remarks in the Rose Garden to announce additional steps the Administration is taking to combat gun crime.</p>



<p><strong>Ensuring that ATF has the leadership it needs to enforce our commonsense gun laws and fight gun crime.</strong></p>



<p>The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) is our top federal law enforcement agency responsible for enforcing our commonsense gun laws. Today, the President is nominating Steve Dettelbach to serve as Director of ATF.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dettelbach is a highly respected former U.S. Attorney and career prosecutor who spent over two decades as a prosecutor at the U.S. Department of Justice. He has received bipartisan praise and support from law enforcement for his work. In 2009, he was unanimously confirmed for his position as U.S. Attorney for the Northern District of Ohio. He has a proven track record of working with federal, state, and local law enforcement to fight violent crime&nbsp;and combat domestic violent extremism and religious violence – including through partnerships with the ATF to prosecute complex cases and take down violent criminal gangs. Dettelbach also worked closely with local law enforcement and community leaders to develop and implement data-driven and neighborhood-based efforts to prevent and fight violent crime. His leadership and his record of innovation in fighting crime and violence make him ready from day one to aggressively and creatively address these pressing issues at the Director of ATF.</p>



<p><strong>Cracking down on ghost guns – the weapon of choice for many violent criminals</strong></p>



<p>Today, the President and Deputy Attorney General will also announce that the U.S. Department of Justice has issued a final rule to rein in the proliferation of “ghost guns” – unserialized, privately-made firearms that law enforcement are increasingly recovering at crime scenes in cities across the country. Last year alone, there were approximately 20,000 suspected ghost guns reported to ATF as having been recovered by law enforcement in criminal investigations – a ten-fold increase from 2016.<a href="//990DAAC7-E8DC-47C2-AECE-F4A3C5AC88E6#_ftn1"><sup>[1]</sup></a>&nbsp;Because ghost guns lack the serial numbers marked on other firearms, law enforcement has an exceedingly difficult time tracing a ghost gun found at a crime scene back to an individual purchaser.</p>



<p>This final rule bans the business of manufacturing the most accessible ghost guns, such as unserialized “buy build shoot” kits that individuals can buy online or at a store without a background check and can readily assemble into a working firearm in as little as 30 minutes with equipment they have at home. This rule clarifies that these kits qualify as “firearms” under the Gun Control Act, and that commercial manufacturers of such kits must therefore become licensed and include serial numbers on the kits’ frame or receiver, and commercial sellers of these kits must become federally licensed and run background checks prior to a sale – just like they have to do with other commercially-made firearms.</p>



<p>The final rule will also help turn some ghost guns already in circulation into serialized firearms. Through this rule, the Justice Department is requiring federally licensed dealers and gunsmiths taking any unserialized firearm into inventory to serialize that weapon. For example, if an individual builds a firearm at home and then sells it to a pawn broker or another federally licensed dealer, that dealer must put a serial number on the weapon before selling it to a customer. This requirement will apply regardless of how the firearm was made, meaning it includes ghost guns made from individual parts, kits, or by 3D-printers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This rule builds on the Biden Administration’s prior executive action to rein in the proliferation of ghost guns. In February 2022, the U.S. Department of Justice launched a National Ghost Gun Enforcement Initiative, which is training a national cadre of prosecutors and disseminating investigation and prosecution tool to help bring cases against those who use ghost guns to commit crimes. As President Biden&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/03/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-gun-violence-prevention-task-force-meeting/">said</a>&nbsp;during an event at the New York Police Department headquarters, if you use a ghost gun to commit a crime “not only are state and local prosecutors going to come after you, but expect federal charges and federal prosecution as well.”&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Additional executive action to reduce gun violence</strong></p>



<p>Today’s final rule includes two additional actions to make our communities safer.</p>



<p>First, the final rule ensures that firearms with split receivers are subject to regulations requiring serial numbers and background checks when purchased from a licensed dealer, manufacturer or importer. Decades ago, ATF issued a regulation defining the “frame or receiver” of a firearm as the part that is regulated by the Gun Control Act – meaning that is the part that triggers federal serialization, background check, and other requirements. At that time, many firearms in the United States were single-framed firearms, like revolvers, that house key components in a single structure. However, we have seen the increasing popularity of firearms using split or multi-part receivers that house key components in multiple structures. Some courts have recently interpreted decades-old regulatory text in a way that, if broadly applied, could mean that as many as 90 percent of firearms in the United States today would not have a frame or receiver subject to federal regulation. The final rule updates the regulatory definitions of “frame” and “receiver” to ensure that firearms using split or multi-part receivers continue to be covered by our common-sense gun laws.</p>



<p>Second, the final rule requires federally licensed firearms dealers to retain key records until they shut down their business or licensed activity. At that time, these dealers must transfer the records to ATF, just as they are currently required to do at the end of licensed activity. Previously, these dealers were permitted to destroy most records after 20 years, making it harder for law enforcement to trace firearms found at crime scenes. According to ATF’s National Tracing Center, on average more than 1,300 firearms a year are untraceable because the federally licensed firearms dealer destroyed the relevant records that were more than 20 years old.</p>



<p><strong>Implementing the President’s comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy</strong></p>



<p>This final rule is part of the President’s comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy. President Biden made more progress on executive actions to reduce gun violence than any other President during their first year in office. You can read more about the Administration’s whole-of-government approach to reduce gun crime&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-bidens-historic-actions-to-make-our-communities-safer-by-reducing-gun-crime/">here</a>.</p>



<p>President Biden’s fiscal year 2023 budget calls on Congress to deliver the funding needed to implement the President’s comprehensive strategy to reduce gun crime and make our communities safer. These additional resources will fund accountable policing, including by putting more police officers on the beat, and making essential investments in crime prevention and community violence intervention.</p>



<p>Congress needs to do its job by passing this budget and other essential legislation to reduce gun crime, including legislation to&nbsp;require background checks for all gun sales, ensure that no terrorist can buy a weapon in the United States, ban the sale and possession of unserialized firearms &#8212; ghost guns, ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and repeal gun manufacturers’ protection from liability.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Virtual Meeting with Prime Minister Modi of&#160;India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/10/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-virtual-meeting-with-prime-minister-modi-of-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will meet virtually with Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India on Monday, April 11 to further deepen ties between our governments, economies, and our people. President Biden and Prime Minister Modi will discuss cooperation on a range of issues including ending the COVID-19 pandemic, countering the climate crisis, strengthening the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will meet virtually with Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India on Monday, April 11 to further deepen ties between our governments, economies, and our people. President Biden and Prime Minister Modi will discuss cooperation on a range of issues including ending the COVID-19 pandemic, countering the climate crisis, strengthening the global economy, and upholding a free, open, rules-based international order to bolster security, democracy, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific. The Leaders will advance ongoing conversations about the development of an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework and delivering high-quality infrastructure. President Biden will continue our close consultations on the consequences of Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine and mitigating its destabilizing impact on global food supply and commodity markets. Biden last spoke to Prime Minister Modi with other Quad Leaders in March. This meeting will precede the U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial between Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin, and External Affairs Minister Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar and Defense Minister Rajnath Singh of India.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
