<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 02:34:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of Joseph R. Biden, Jr.’s Call with President-Elect Yoon Suk-yeol of the Republic of&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/readout-of-joseph-r-biden-jr-s-call-with-president-elect-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 02:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol of the Republic of Korea (ROK) to congratulate him on his election. Together, they affirmed the strength of the U.S.-ROK alliance, which is the linchpin for peace, security and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific. President Biden emphasized the United States’ commitment to the defense of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol of the Republic of Korea (ROK) to congratulate him on his election. Together, they affirmed the strength of the U.S.-ROK alliance, which is the linchpin for peace, security and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific. President Biden emphasized the United States’ commitment to the defense of the ROK and that he looks forward to working together to deepen cooperation on key global challenges, including climate change, the COVID-19 pandemic, and supply chains. The two also committed to maintain close coordination on addressing the threats posed by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s nuclear and missile programs.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in Roundtable With CEOs and Governors in Support of the Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/09/remarks-by-president-biden-in-roundtable-with-ceos-and-governors-in-support-of-the-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 22:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 2:05 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:  All right.  Well, thanks, everybody, for being here.  And for my colleagues that are on the screen, thank you for being here. I’m pleased to be joined by &#8212; by a group of very distinguished people, and particularly by the governor from Indiana, Eric Holcomb; and my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>2:05 P.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  All right.  Well, thanks, everybody, for being here.  And for my colleagues that are on the screen, thank you for being here.<br><br>I’m pleased to be joined by &#8212; by a group of very distinguished people, and particularly by the governor from Indiana, Eric Holcomb; and my good friend, Gretchen Whitmer, from the state of Michigan; and some of America’s world leaders and most important manufacturers in the world and &#8212; Cummins, Hewlett-Packard, Meda- &#8212; Medtronic, Micron, Samsung, Whirlpool.</p>



<p>And just last week, in my State of the Union message, I said that we’re seeing the revitalization of American manufacturing, especially in the Industrial Midwest.</p>



<p>Our economy created <s>432,000</s> [423,000] new manufacturing jobs in America since we took office.  And today, companies are choosing to build new factories here &#8212; here in the United States, when just a few years ago, they would have built them overseas.</p>



<p>What I also said is that companies are ready to do more &#8212; a lot more if Congress passes the Bipartisan Innovation Act.&nbsp; And that’s why we’re here to today to talk about the bipartisan act.</p>



<p>And we have the President and CEO of Micron with us.&nbsp; Sanjay, thanks for being here.&nbsp; Micron is looking to making a multibillion-dollar semiconductor investment here in America if &#8212; if this bill gets passed.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Dr. Choi, the CEO of Samsung, is also on the screen.&nbsp; Thank you for being here.&nbsp; Samsung has committed $17 billion &#8212; its largest-ever U.S. investment &#8212; to build a semiconductor facility in Texas, which I understand is going to create 2,000 good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>Other CEOs that are here are making their own investments in America.&nbsp; But they need Congress to pass the bipartisan innovation bill.</p>



<p>And one of the reasons &#8212; one of the reasons we need to do that is because there is perhaps no production more important than reclaiming America’s leadership and owning our future than semiconductors.</p>



<p>You know, these semiconductors that are the size of a fingertip, power about every day &#8212; almost everything in our everyday life &#8212; smartphones, the Internet, appliances, technologies we haven’t invented yet.</p>



<p>And our nation &#8212; and the semiconductor was invented here in the United States of America.&nbsp; And over 30 years ago, America had 40 percent of the global production of semiconductors.</p>



<p>But since then, something happened.&nbsp; American manufacturing &#8212; the backbone of our economy &#8212; got hollowed out.&nbsp; Companies moved jobs and production overseas, especially from the industrial Midwest.</p>



<p>As a result, today, we barely produce 10 percent of these computer chips, despite being a leader on chip design and research.</p>



<p>This puts us at the mercy of shortages and supply chain bottlenecks.&nbsp; But we have an opportunity &#8212; we have an opportunity to reclaim the position of leadership.</p>



<p>I think it’s a bipartisan consensus.&nbsp; There’s an inno- &#8212; there’s an innovation bill that &#8212; this innovation bill has bipartisan support in both House and Senate now.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It includes billions of dollars for new incentives to produce semiconductors here in America.</p>



<p>And the bill is not just about funding semiconductors; it includes an office at the Department of Commerce that will be tasked with monitoring and strengthening critical supply chains.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And it &#8212; and it expands programs that help manufacturers across the country benefit from our investments, particularly small manufacturers.</p>



<p>It invests in R&amp;D the way we need to so we can invent and make the technologies of the future and in industries like biotechnology, artificial intelligence, telecommunications, and others we can barely imagine today and which we’re going to build a foundation for future jobs and prosperity not just here but around the world.</p>



<p>So today, I’m urging the House and Senate to work out the differences between their ver- &#8212; two versions of this bill and get it to my desk as quickly as you can.</p>



<p>Passing this bill will do four important things:</p>



<p>First, it will send a message to the world that America is back in the game, open for investment, commitment to creating clean energy economy and competing to win in the 21st century.</p>



<p>Second, we’re going to create jobs: good paying, cutting-edge jobs; manufacturing jobs &#8212; many that don’t require a four-year college degree.</p>



<p>Third, making it in America is one of the ways we can address our cost and supply chain challenges.&nbsp; When we build a pr- &#8212; when we build products we need, we don’t have to wait.&nbsp; And we reduce ship- &#8212; shipping costs.&nbsp; And we can get goods moving faster.</p>



<p>And fourthly, we have &#8212; it will be a &#8212; it will mean that we aren’t overly reliant on other countries from risks like wars and pandemics.&nbsp; And I saw it during the pandemic that when we needed it the most, we were in short supply of masks, gowns, gloves, ventilators, and other essential equipment.</p>



<p>We should never be in that position again.&nbsp; And the bottom line is this Bipartisan innovation bill will allow us to stamp more products “Made in America”.&nbsp; And it’s going to bolster our national security and our economic security.</p>



<p>It matters, so let’s get it done.</p>



<p>And now, it’s my honor to turn this over to the governors, and then we’re going to hear from the CEOs.&nbsp; And so, Governors, I’m sure they agree with the Ohio Senator Sherrod Brown, who said, “It’s time to bury the label ‘Rust Belt.’”&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Like, the Industrial Midwest today, you see something special is happening.</p>



<p>Let me start with you, Governor –- Governor Holcomb from Indiana.<br><br>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; And, Madam Secretary, great to be back with you again.&nbsp; I would just echo or underscore the point that &#8212; points that you’ve made.&nbsp; And certainly, the Midwest is no longer the Rust Belt; it is a shining buckle on that belt.&nbsp; And we are just open for business but able to do more.<br><br>This innovation bill &#8212; ultimate bill that comes together is a key part of our futures.&nbsp; It’s a key part of a Midwestern microelectronics corridor, if you will, that has everything to do with economic development and national security.<br><br>For a state like Indiana &#8212; and you could probably say this about a lot of Midwestern states &#8212; but we’re heavy intensive in manufacturing &#8212; number one per capita for a state like Indiana.&nbsp; Five auto OEMs, medical devices, the list just goes on and on and on.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I would &#8212; I would just say that it’s two things.&nbsp; One, it’s been said that speed kills, and in this sense, slow speed kills.&nbsp;&nbsp;We need to get this done.&nbsp; We need to get it on your desk.&nbsp; We need to get it signed so that we cannot just catch up with the competition but lead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know a little something about this in Indiana.&nbsp; We got the Indy 500, and we like to go fast.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible) going fast.&nbsp; A gallon of gas is down 14 percent today.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So I want to make sure they go fast.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And I didn’t mean to interrupt you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; No, so, you know, it&#8217;s speed.&nbsp; We got to get there, and we got to get there yesterday.&nbsp; And then also partnerships.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for us in the Midwest, we have those talent pipelines, Madam Secretary, that we&#8217;ve spent a lot of time talking about: Purdue University, one of the largest engineering schools in the country &#8212; top ranked; Rose-Hulman, number-one undergraduate engineering school.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve got a community college system that is built &#8212; the structure in place &#8212; as well as Naval Surface Warfare Center Crane, with the DOD &#8212; and all the research that goes into it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those &#8212; the federal, the private sector, and the state governments that come together &#8212; those partnerships are in place right now so that we can get it to your desk and get on with business.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll do anything to help if you get me to be able to drive a lead car in the Indy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; Write that down.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not kidding.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; Oh, we know you&#8217;re not kidding.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen you drive a lot of cars in Michigan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; Oh, God, I tell you what &#8212;</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; I think the Secretary is driving the pace car, by the way.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:  Yeah, I know.  I &#8212; I don&#8217;t know, man.  I&#8217;m ready.  Anyway. Gov.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; Yeah, well I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m really glad to be sitting here next to Eric because, in the Midwest, you know, we are proud of what we do.&nbsp; We work hard.&nbsp; We solve problems.&nbsp; We’re not afraid of digging in.&nbsp; And this &#8212; I think this act that we&#8217;re talking about is a huge opportunity for our nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, in places like Michigan, this is about creating good-paying jobs.&nbsp; This is about lowering costs for families.&nbsp; This is about our national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know my fellow governors on both sides of the aisle support getting this to your desk so that you can sign it and make a reality.&nbsp; You know, right now, thousands of jobs up and down the auto supply chain are at risk because we&#8217;re not making chips; we don&#8217;t have access.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I also know &#8212; my friend from Whirlpool here, also from Michigan, is going to remind me it&#8217;s not just the auto industry &#8212; right? &#8212; it&#8217;s appliances as well.&nbsp; It is the smartphones, as you said, Mr. President.</p>



<p>You know, chip shortages have impacted more than 575,000 American jobs.&nbsp; And in 2021 alone, automakers in North America lost production of an estimated 2.2 million vehicles, equaling 3,000 days of work.&nbsp; So, these shortages are driving up costs, they&#8217;re jeopardizing families.&nbsp;&nbsp; And increasing this manufacturing here at home will reduce supply chain delays in transportation, as well as lowering the cost of consumer electronics, et cetera, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we also saw during the pandemic that American manufacturing is crucial to our national security.&nbsp; And when the whole world comes to a halt because swabs are manufactured in Italy or N95 masks are manufactured in China, it is a national security issue.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, doing this important advanced manufacturing where we can stamp it “Made in America” and preferably “Made in Michigan” is a good thing for our whole nation.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s why I think it&#8217;s so important that both sides of the aisle &#8212; we are here, we are eager to throw our support behind getting this bill to your desk, and recognize that critical importance to the people of our states and our nation.</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m excited to be here and eager to jump in wherever we can be helpful.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;re old friends.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard me say many times &#8212; you know, that was something my dear mother, God bless her soul, used to say: “Out of everything bad, something good will happen if you look hard enough for it.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think we&#8217;re in a position now &#8212; we&#8217;re in a real inflection point in history &#8212; not just America, but across the world.&nbsp; There are going to be changes that are going to &#8212; whether &#8212; no matter who&#8217;s in charge, they&#8217;re going to create fundamental &#8212; fundamental change is taking place geographically, politically, economically, technologically.</p>



<p>And, you know, one third of the inflation last year was because of the cost of automobiles, and it was one reason: didn&#8217;t have the computer chips.&nbsp; Rising prices were &#8212; you know, that&#8217;s one third of the inflation.&nbsp; And so, we can solve a lot of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to, with her permission &#8212; Liz, I&#8217;d like to go to you a little bit, speaking of Whirlpool.</p>



<p>And you announced an $80 million investment in a manufacturing plant in Ohio and Oklahoma last year, which are going to create about 250 jobs, if I&#8217;m not mistaken.</p>



<p>My question is that &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; why is domestic production of semiconductors important to Whirlpool?&nbsp; And how will this bipartisan initiative, if it passes it and gets to my desk &#8212; how that&#8217;s going to affect you?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think I know the answer, but I think it&#8217;s important for it to be heard from you.&nbsp; No, I really mean it.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s important.</p>



<p>Look, the one thing we&#8217;ve had as we brought in CEOs and VPs and others the last, I don&#8217;t know, a couple months, right here in this fora, is people go, &#8220;Whoa, this is real,&#8221; when they hear from the companies what they want to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I&#8217;d love to &#8212; you to tell me a little bit about how you see it moving, if you would.</p>



<p>MS. DOOR:&nbsp; Well, first of all, thank you, Mr. President, for inviting Whirlpool Corporation to sit here today at this table with all these leaders.&nbsp; We&#8217;re very, very grateful to be able to be here today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would say is that the $80 million investment in Ohio and Oklahoma, as you said &#8212; you know, that is us supporting the United States.&nbsp; Additionally, we have made an investment, $60 million commitment, in Michigan in our R&amp;D Center.&nbsp; So this is demonstrative of our commitment to the United States.</p>



<p>We have nine factories in the U.S.&nbsp; We sell &#8212; 80 percent of the products that we sell in the U.S. are produced in the U.S.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s definitely a commitment here to the United States.</p>



<p>We have been challenged with the supply chain &#8212; you know, not being able to deliver appliances to each of the consumers in the U.S. every day due to the semiconductor issues.</p>



<p>We see the semiconductors as an essential component to our appliances.&nbsp; They&#8217;re found in almost every one of our appliances, and they&#8217;re absolutely critical because they deliver the technology that delights our consumers, whether it&#8217;s cleaning your laundry or your dishes, or cooking in the home, or using it to store your food and medicine during these very challenging times.</p>



<p>So, semiconductors are absolutely essential for us.&nbsp; And certainly, if we had all the semiconductors, as Governor Whitmer said, we&#8217;d be able to deliver the appliances to all of our customers, which we have been challenged to do so.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are absolutely committed to deliver to our consumers every day.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Do you think your customers and/or even maybe some of your employees who have been around a long time really appreciated how critical a semiconductor was for them to make the products and move?</p>



<p>MS. DOOR:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; I think everyone inside our company &#8212; and I even think if you ask consumers &#8212; and world leaders are very, very familiar now with semiconductors and how critical they are to technology, research and development, upskilling the workforce, and STEM education.&nbsp; So, absolutely.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s interesting.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s been a &#8212; unfortunately, a &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s been a reality that the American public realizing that a semiconductor mattered a great deal whether or not your washing machine functioned, or whether your cellphone functioned, or whether your automobile functioned.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s not that &#8212; I think we &#8212; they just took an awful lot for granted; we all did &#8212; that this was, &#8220;We can do this.&nbsp; It’s not a problem.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the irony of &#8212; I keep reminding everybody of the irony is: We actually invented the semiconductor; we headed to the Moon.&nbsp; So, we also &#8212; I have no parenthetic.&nbsp; We got to be &#8212; start investing a hell of a lot more money in research and development &#8212; pure research and development.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We used to do about 2 percent of our GDP; now we&#8217;re down by 1 percent.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; anyway, but I don&#8217;t want to get off on that and get you going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also like Madam President, Jennifer, I &#8212; you &#8212; at Cummins, you make some pretty big engines.&nbsp; You manufacture &#8212; and &#8212; now &#8212; but now you&#8217;re making battery electric alternative fuel engines, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. RUMSEY:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And so, how has the ship [sic] shortage affected &#8212; chip shortage affected your company and your customers?&nbsp; And as we move toward this energy future, how can this Innovation Act &#8212; and it&#8217;s a shame &#8212; you have to know all about this legislation; I mean, you&#8217;re running the company &#8212; but how can this act help companies like yours remain globally competitive, not just here at home?</p>



<p>MS. RUMSEY:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, first, Mr. President, thank you so much for the opportunity to speak today and talk about Cummins&#8217;s support of both the domestic innovation focus of this legislation as well as funding semiconductor manufacturing.</p>



<p>Cummins is a 100-year-old company headquartered in Columbus, Indiana.&nbsp; We employ 25,000 employees in the United States.&nbsp; And our employees are really focused on driving innovation and producing power solutions, engines, and also, as you said, fuel cell and battery-electric power solutions for commercial and industrial equipment.&nbsp; And those applications serve some of the world&#8217;s most demanding and economically vital applications.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I spent time, prior to my current role, as chief technical officer, so I saw firsthand the need for innovation &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.) (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. RUMSEY:&nbsp; &#8212; yeah, really &#8212; the need for innovation, and the power of government and private sectors coming together to focus on innovation.</p>



<p>Cummins worked closely for a number of years with the Department of Energy &#8212; a 21st Century Truck Program.&nbsp; And in that program, we were able to advance technology and improve fuel efficiency in trucks by 50 percent &#8212; a 50 percent reduction in&nbsp;<a>CO2</a>.&nbsp; And much of that work has now made its way into trucks that are on the road today and are benefiting society.</p>



<p>And I think there&#8217;s never been a more important time than now to continue to focus on domestic innovation when you consider the environmental and the technical challenges that we face as a society.</p>



<p>So, I think it&#8217;s critically important that we can come together.&nbsp; Our industry and other industries are transforming how we will compete as we tackle these challenges &#8212; like, climate change is changing.</p>



<p>And so, I think coming together in a bipartisan way to talk about how we drive and fuel innovation in America is critical to keep us at the leading edge with these advanced technologies and new solutions and bring high-tech and manufacturing jobs to the United States and the future.&nbsp; So, I think it&#8217;s critically important.</p>



<p>In my operational role, I&#8217;ve been spending a lot of time on this semiconductor issue, and it has been a real issue for us for the last 18 months.&nbsp; Our products do not run, in most cases, without semiconductors.&nbsp; They&#8217;re critical for emissions and safety-control systems.&nbsp; And increasingly, we&#8217;re utilizing them as our technology advances.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have not been able to get enough.&nbsp; It has impacted our ability to build and deliver product to our customers.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an issue we continue to deal with today.</p>



<p>So we strongly support the CHIPS Act, really focusing on bringing domestic production of semiconductors here, including some for our industry &#8212; which, by the way, are different than what we use in our cellphone.&nbsp; You know, because of the durability and harsh environment our products operate in, we have specific chips that are critical to continue to invest and fund here in the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we look forward to being a part of the conversation as we move this important work forward.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, you know, the point you&#8217;ve all made is that as everything changes, there&#8217;s a fundamental shift to the reality that we can&#8217;t &#8212; we can&#8217;t keep the combustion engine the way it has been.&nbsp; It&#8217;s even &#8212; you see what&#8217;s happening in locomotives now.&nbsp; You know?&nbsp; And you see what&#8217;s happening just across the board.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; and I think it presents an enormous opportunity &#8212; enormous opportunity to improve the health of the public overall, number one, because we&#8217;re moving in the direction, and we don&#8217;t need to propel most of what we have in the future by &#8212; with regard to oil products or &#8212;</p>



<p>And, you know, I was really pleased to &#8212; and Gina &#8212; or Gretchen and I talked about this a lot.&nbsp; When we met with the CEOs of the automobile companies, particularly Mary Barra &#8212; and she had sued the state of California for having a higher mileage standard than the national standard.&nbsp; And we had a long talk.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not taking credit for her changing her mind, but she ended up calling me and saying that, “We&#8217;re going to go &#8212; we dropped the suit, and we&#8217;re going to go all electric.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll get to halfway there within the next…” &#8212; and then she said a date.&nbsp; And then Ford jumped on and everybody else.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a &#8212; because it is the future.</p>



<p>And it also creates, really, a hell of a lot of jobs too &#8212; good-paying jobs &#8212; and increasing the technological breakthroughs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, at any rate, I think what you&#8217;re doing really matters.&nbsp; And I know we got a lot to talk about.&nbsp; You saw the team over here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure about, you know, anybody but Gina over here on this side, including me.&nbsp; But all kidding aside, we got a lot to do and I think we can get a lot done.&nbsp; I really do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s a little thing going on in Europe right now, and I&#8217;m not going to be able to stay with you the whole time we&#8217;re here.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s not going to in any way diminish the content of what we&#8217;re discussing here.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Brian, I&#8217;m told that you&#8217;re going to run this show here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Yeah, we&#8217;ll give you a chance to depart, and the press as well, and then we’ll continue on here.</p>



<p>2:28 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, March 9,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/09/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-march-9-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 22:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:13 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, so I have a couple of short items at the top.&#160; A lot of paper.&#160; A lot of things to talk about today. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Today, the President will host an event with business leaders and bipartisan governors, including Governor Whitmer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:13 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, so I have a couple of short items at the top.&nbsp; A lot of paper.&nbsp; A lot of things to talk about today.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, the President will host an event with business leaders and bipartisan governors, including Governor Whitmer and Governor Holcomb, to call on Congress to quickly pass competitiveness legislation like the Bipartisan Innovation Act.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During the event, the President, Secretary Raimondo, and the participants will focus in particular on why passing competitiveness legislation is critical for lowering prices for working families on essentials like cars and household appliances by addressing bottlenecks like semiconductor chips, manufacturing more in America, and strengthening our supply chains to make our economy more productive.</p>



<p>As we’ve seen over the past year, global events like the pandemic or Russia’s unprovoked aggression in Ukraine can result in disruptions to global supply chains that lead to higher prices for American consumers, which further underscores the importance of strengthening our economy and making it more resilient to shocks like that in the future.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note that today the President signed an executive order outlining the first-ever whole-of-government approach to addressing the risks and harnessing the potential benefits of digital assets.</p>



<p>Previously, there has been &#8212; never been an organized effort to bring together the expertise and authorities of the entire U.S. government to inform a holistic approach to digital assets.</p>



<p>With this executive order, the President is calling on experts across the federal government to assess and develop policy recommendations that address the implications of growing digital asset sec- &#8212; of the growing digital asset sector across consumer protection, financial stability, national security, and climate risk.</p>



<p>Let me finally say: I heard there was a little kerfuffle in here after the briefing the other day.&nbsp; I just want to say that what we&#8217;re going to do today is we&#8217;re going to try to start with the third and fourth row, and fifth and sixth row; get more people&#8217;s questions answered.&nbsp; We are always happy to answer questions from here.&nbsp; I could go on for hours.&nbsp; Just sit in your seats.</p>



<p>But we also know you all have a lot on your plates.&nbsp; So what we try to do, for everybody&#8217;s knowledge, is balance between all the things reporters and all of you have focused on and trying to be informative in this briefing room.&nbsp; But we also are here as people have follow-up questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, Josh, let me have you start.&nbsp; Kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I know the pool is supposed to gather around 1:45 &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; if that’s still on.</p>



<p>So, one easy question: The U.S. declined to help facilitate the transfer of jets to Ukraine yesterday.&nbsp; Does the U.S. want the Ukraine to get jets?&nbsp; And how urgent a priority is that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, let me give you an update on the status.&nbsp; As of now, the &#8212; Secretary Austin, Chairman Milley, and members of our Defense Department are in touch with Ukrainian counterparts, NATO counterparts, discusting [sic] &#8212; discussing what are clearly logistical challenges here.</p>



<p>And I would note, Josh, that in the statement put out by my colleague at the Pentagon yesterday, he made clear that obviously the proposal from yesterday that fighter jets manned by Americans departing a NATO base to fly into airspace contes- &#8212; contested with Russia raises serious concerns for the United States and NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the logistical questions here, just to put a little fine point on it, are things like how do you get planes into Ukraine in a way that is not escalatory, and what are the logistics and operational details of that.</p>



<p>Those are conversations that are happening between counterparts at the military level, and I would expect any update might come from them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, let&#8217;s go around.&nbsp; Michael, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Two questions on Venezuela.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, obviously, yesterday two Americans were freed and they are now home.&nbsp; Nicolás Maduro has agreed to re-engage in the Mexico City talks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, is the ball in the President&#8217;s court at this point to continue the engagement?&nbsp; And what is the plan (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the &#8212; let me note that the return of two American citizens is certainly welcome news, exciting news.&nbsp; And it would not have happened without the tireless work over the series &#8212; a series of months by a number of our diplomats, including, of course, our Special Envoy for Hostage Affairs, Roger Carstens, who worked on this for months over the course of time.</p>



<p>You know, we are &#8212; we&#8217;ll continue to discuss a range of issues, including, first and foremost, Americans unjustly held.&nbsp; Unfortunately, they&#8217;re not the only individuals held there &#8212; the individuals who returned.&nbsp; So that will be something that we will look to have ongoing discussions about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that Maduro said he will resume talks with Venezuela&#8217;s interim president in Mexico.&nbsp; So that is an encouraging sign.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there were a range of issues discussed on this trip.&nbsp; There are a range of issues to discuss moving forward.&nbsp; But right now, we&#8217;re just celebrating the return of two Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just to follow up: Are there concrete plans for continued engagement for another round of talks?&nbsp; And is there &#8212; you know, you mentioned, I think on Monday, that energy security was part of the conversation.&nbsp; What can Venezuela contribute to energy security?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of additional talks or rounds of talks.&nbsp; But again, we are &#8212; we are very pleased to have these two Americans returned home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; if there are opportunities to continue to discuss that, that&#8217;s something we are open to.&nbsp; There are obviously ongoing concerns about the health and wellbeing of anyone detained, whether it&#8217;s there or in Venezuela or Russia or Afghanistan, Syria, China, Iran, and elsewhere.&nbsp; Those are conversations we are always going to want to engage in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, it is facts- &#8212; factual &#8212; you all know &#8212; that Venezuela is a large producer of oil.&nbsp; But in terms of any decisions or discussions or where that may go from here, I have no &#8212; nothing to preview or predict for you on that front.</p>



<p>Nadia, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Many American companies declared yesterday that they&#8217;re shutting down in Russia, including Visa card, Masters, and McDonald&#8217;s, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Russians say that they&#8217;re going to confiscate their assets there.&nbsp; How would the White House react to that?&nbsp; I know they’re all private companies, but basically declaring that they&#8217;re going to nationalize these assets, according to the Russians.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And second &#8212; not exactly related: Do you &#8212; there are some reports indicating that Russia is delaying the signing of the Iran agreement and delaying the negotiation in Vienna from taking place for their own interests because they don&#8217;t want, obviously, oil to be released to make up for the shortage.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me take the second one first.&nbsp; I would say that our team &#8212; we&#8217;re continuing to engage with Iran deal partners, including Russia, on Iran nuclear negotiations.&nbsp; We believe Russia shares a common interest in ensuring Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In our view, there&#8217;s nothing that should be required of or will be offered from the United States as it relates to Russia sanctions &#8212; that is related to their invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, we believe we share an objective here.&nbsp; Always in the final stages, there are details to be worked through, and we will continue to work through those.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of your first question on the seizing &#8212; I think it was on the potential seizing of private sector assets in Russia for companies that have decided to pull back and pull out of the country &#8212; obviously, we have not &#8212; while we have applauded the actions of a number of companies, that is not something we have been pushing from behind the scenes, if that makes sense.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If they were to take those actions, I&#8217;m certain there would be steps we would take, but nothing has happened at this point in time.&nbsp; So let me talk to our economic team and see if there&#8217;s anything more we can predict for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; First, about the Florida bill that just passed restricting the speaking about homosexuality and gender identity after third grade.&nbsp; And then I have a question about surveillance matters that have been in the news.</p>



<p>Regarding the Florida bill: In 1994, when many of us in this room were in school, President Biden actually voted for a much broader restriction that banned federal funds from being used for, quote, &#8220;the promotion of homosexuality as a positive lifestyle alternative.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why did he do that?&nbsp; And can you describe how his thinking has evolved over the years?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that you have seen the President speak passionately about his view that a bill like this &#8212; a bill that would discriminate against families, against kids, put these kids in a position of not getting the support they need at a time where that&#8217;s exactly what they need &#8212; is discriminatory.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a form of bullying.&nbsp; It is horrific.&nbsp; I mean, the President has spoken to that.</p>



<p>In terms of his views and comments from 25 years ago, I think the most important question now is: Why are Florida leaders deciding they need to discriminate against kids who are members of the LGBTQI community?&nbsp; What prompts them to do that?&nbsp; Is it meanness?&nbsp; Is it wanting to make kids have more difficult times in school, in their communities?&nbsp; I would pose that question to them, and we can talk about it more tomorrow if you get an answer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there a reason he supported the same policy, though, in the &#8217;90s when we were all in school?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what&#8217;s important to note here is how outspoken the President has been against discrimination against kids, against members of the LGBTQI+ community.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re looking at here is a bill that would propagate misinformed, hateful policies and impact children…</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s the question I hope &#8212; maybe you can pose that to some of the leaders in Florida.&nbsp; Maybe they&#8217;ll return your phone calls.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll look forward to having a conversation with you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow up on that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, perhaps Chris could follow up afterwards.&nbsp; But I&#8217;d like to ask about the surveillance matters as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senators Wyden and Heinrich, who are Democrats, recently alleged that the CIA is conducting a mass surveillance program that implicates American data and that it&#8217;s outside of the statutory bounds that people think it&#8217;s within.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, could you say anything about that to reassure Americans regarding their data?</p>



<p>And secondly, according to a recent court filing by Special Counsel Durham, there was a technology executive who was, quote, “mining” the Executive Office of the President&#8217;s DNS traffic and other data.&nbsp; CISA, the federal agency for cybersecurity, said in a 2020 document that DNS data can be sensitive and that&#8217;s important to secure.</p>



<p>There are competing narratives, of course, about what data was actually implicated.&nbsp; So could you share with us what data was implicated in this and whether the White House has any security or privacy concerns regarding this alleged review?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have nothing further to comment on your questions.&nbsp; Obviously, this is an investigation.&nbsp; I point you to the Department of Justice, members of Congress.&nbsp; Obviously, we have serious respect for people&#8217;s privacy in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; A quick follow-up.&nbsp; You mentioned the logistical challenges about flying planes &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to Ukraine, through contested airspace.&nbsp; Why can&#8217;t the United States put those planes on trains or automobiles?&nbsp; I guess, are we really to believe that when we&#8217;re sending &#8212; or preparing to send billions in aid, that, you know, this is the logistical bottleneck that is stopping us from getting them those planes?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it is a serious logistical bottleneck, right?&nbsp; Obviously &#8212; there&#8217;s obvious concerns that the Department of Defense has spoken to about flying planes from U.S. airbases &#8212; right? &#8212; that they spoke to yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These planes &#8212; carting them down the street, I think, is not as easy as you may think it is.&nbsp; Planes &#8212; if they have to be taken apart and put back together, you have to have people who are able to put those planes back together.&nbsp; You have to ensure that there&#8217;s &#8212; they can be safely moved through the course of a contested country, or not &#8212; you know, a country where there is a war going on with the Russians, you know, who implemented that war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there are a range of logistical and operational challenges.&nbsp; Those are important conversations to happen between military experts and our Defense Department leaders and officials &#8212; Secretary Austin, Chairman Milley, and their counterparts.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, should we expect that the U.S. Export-Import Bank is going to continue to underwrite loans that would support commerce with Russian companies and corporations, given the tranche of sanctions that we&#8217;ve seen against (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to check and see how these sanctions are implemented.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re going to abide by all of our &#8212; our own sanctions.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve tried to implement them as quickly as possible, but I can see if there&#8217;s any specific impact on them.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, John Kirby&#8217;s line is that transferring the planes &#8212; or the latest iteration &#8212; was not &#8220;tenable.&#8221;&nbsp; Can you say: Is what&#8217;s not tenable the arming of the Ukrainians with jet fighters?&nbsp; Or is it merely the logistical things you&#8217;re speaking to?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the Defense Department spoke primarily to this, and they were very specific, Geoff.&nbsp; They said fighter jets manned by Americans departing a NATO base to fly into airspace contested with Russia raises serious concerns for the United States and for the NATO Alliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have provided a billion dollars in military assistance.&nbsp; I would say the $350 billion that was announced just &#8212; less than two weeks ago, I believe the Defense Department has conveyed almost all of that has been delivered.&nbsp; We have not held back on providing weapons, anti-missile systems, tank systems at all at any point in this process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there are important operational, logistics concerns here and steps &#8212; conversations that should happen between military experts.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what&#8217;s happening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, in principle, it&#8217;s a policy that the White House would support or like to find a way to solve?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;re having discussions about it, but there are operational and logistical questions that are important ones that we will leave to our Defense Department colleagues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick one.&nbsp; You know, there was another round of arrests in Russia &#8212; it was, like, estimated at 5,000 &#8212; over the weekend.&nbsp; Is the &#8212; protesting the war.&nbsp; What is the assessment of the White House as far as how this has all affected regime stability over there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t think we assess that President Putin thought that there would be such an outpouring of objection in his own country.&nbsp; He would probably not have cut off access to media, access to social media, access to basic information for the people of his country if that were the case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we have seen people across Russia bravely, courageously protest, speak out against a war that they believe is unjust, is unwarranted.&nbsp; And, you know, that is incredibly powerful.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, unfortunately, as you know and many of you know from working for these networks and news organizations, there have been tough decisions that news organizations have had to make, whether &#8212; about whether they&#8217;re going to keep a presence in Russia because of the restrictions.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not just &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s not just the speaking out of President Putin.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about fines.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about the threat of arrest.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about safety and security that organizations have to consider.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in terms of stability, I don’t have any assessment for that other than to tell you that it&#8217;s pretty clear he didn&#8217;t bet on the opposition from within his own country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Shrish, why don’t you go in the back?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; One, if I could follow up on the earlier</p>



<p>questions about the jet fighters.&nbsp; Is this a difference of kind or a difference of degree?&nbsp; I mean, is the objection that it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s an airplane, or because, as you point out, we&#8217;re sending them things that destroy tanks, things that shoot down airplanes?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I mean, if it can be done without &#8212; I mean, they would know where they came from and &#8212; I don&#8217;t even see if there&#8217;s plausible deniability or anything like that.&nbsp; What is the hang-up exactly?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s pretty clear.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t require a military expert to understand why having planes fly from a U.S. airbase into a contested part of a country where there is a war is not in our interest and not in NATO interests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there are logistical and operational challenges to consider and discuss.&nbsp; It isn&#8217;t that easy to move military planes around &#8212; maybe not as easy as some of you may suspect it is.&nbsp; And those are conversations, again, that are happening between military experts.&nbsp; And I would point you to the Department of Defense for the status of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And more broadly, is there any concern that making the lives of average Russians miserable &#8212; you know, with all these companies pulling out and things that are designed to hurt the economy, as opposed to Putin personally, as opposed to his oligarchs personally &#8212; is there a worry that that&#8217;s going to consolidate his support within the country rather than make him &#8212; rather than diminishing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that our view and the view of our global partners is that when a president like President Putin, you know, launches a war of choice where he is brutally killing, injuring people in a sovereign country, there have to be consequences.&nbsp; Those consequences are economic and significant, no question about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our target is not to hurt the Russian people; it is to squeeze President Putin and the leadership around him.&nbsp; But what the impact is, is certainly having a devastating impact on the Russian economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our view is that over the over the medium and long term, that that is not going to be sustainable for President Putin and the team around him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Ed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I’m starting to hear the administration talk about gas prices &#8212; as a way to speed up the lowering of gas prices, to speed up the transition to those clean energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gas prices have risen month over month, every month since the President has been in office.&nbsp; So, is the feeling then from the President that the American people just have to wait until 2030 when the President set his goal for zero emissions &#8212; or to have cars being sold with zero emissions &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible) higher gas prices.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s never been our theory or our belief.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say that since President Putin began his military buildup on Ukrainian borders, the price of gas at the pump in America has gone up 75 cents, which is significant, of course.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There is widespread consensus that the sharp runup of energy prices since January was called by &#8212; caused by the building of Putin&#8217;s troops at Ukraine&#8217;s border.&nbsp; The reality, as we know, is that Russia is the world&#8217;s third-largest oil producer.&nbsp; And energy supply disruptions and market volatility are a result of his aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Don&#8217;t &#8212; you don’t have to take my word for that.&nbsp; There have been a number of assessments.&nbsp; Back in January, Federal Chair &#8212; Fed Chair Powell warned that there was a risk to our economy based on, quote, “what&#8217;s going on in Eastern Europe.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In early February, JP Morgan analysts projected that disruptions of oil flows from Russia could push oil prices to $120 per barrel, which is what has happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our approach has always been twofold.&nbsp; One, we need to ensure the supply meets the demand out there in the marketplace.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a couple of ways to do that.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re engaging with big global oil producers around the world to meet that demand.&nbsp; But there are also, as we&#8217;ve talked about a few times in here, 9,000 unused oil leases that oil companies could certainly tap into, and we&#8217;ve encouraged them to do that.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s certainly a way to address.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the price of gas on February 14th was at a high &#8212; highest level since 2014.&nbsp; So it was already at an elevated level.</p>



<p>I want to ask you &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And the build-up of troops was even before that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to ask you about tomorrow.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to get a CPI inflation number that&#8217;s expected to be pretty big.&nbsp; It&#8217;s supposed to rise from the 7.5 percent that it was month over month.&nbsp; So gas prices are part of that.&nbsp; I want to know what specifically the administration has done, they&#8217;ve been working on that has worked to bring down inflation.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first because while we don&#8217;t have the data at this point yet, but as we&#8217;re looking ahead, we certainly assess that &#8212; that we expect to see a high headline in &#8212; headline inflation in tomorrow&#8217;s February inflation data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A key reason, as you touched on, are energy prices.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen the price of gas increase, as I noted, 75 cents since the beginning of the year as Putin built up his military near Ukraine and took increasingly aggressive measures that were felt in the markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also expect some increases in pandemic-affected sectors given our strong recovery from Omicron in February.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a positive sign for our economy and for Americans who are going out again, traveling, going to restaurants, and getting back to normal.&nbsp; And we also expect to see continued moderation in used car prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what our prediction, our assessment is at this point in time.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of steps we have taken to address inflation &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what has worked?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What has &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What has worked?&nbsp; So October 13th is when you announced the port initiative.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What specifically can you point to that has worked to bring down inflation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there are a number of steps we&#8217;ve taken.&nbsp; If you&#8217;ve seen &#8212; if you compare a month-to-month, we&#8217;ve seen inflationary pressure &#8212; or inflationary numbers go down month to month &#8212; even as we looked at the year-to-year numbers go up, which we entirely predicted.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One, we&#8217;ve taken steps to address bottlenecks in the supply chain, to reduce those bottlenecks.&nbsp; Those are steps we&#8217;ve taken not just since October but since earlier this year.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question that we&#8217;ve seen impacts as it relates to getting goods and supplies out to the American public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also taken steps to address what we see as shortages and issues in the semiconductor space.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We &#8212; I just opened this briefing by pressing for the passing of the competitiveness legislation that the President would love to sign into law, because we know that one of the big pressures is, of course, from the car and manufacturing sector or the car sector.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, third, we know that because of the pressures on the energy sector that that has been an area where we&#8217;ve continued to see have an impact on inflationary pressure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We believe in the last few months that has been because of President Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; But as I&#8217;ve noted, there are a number of steps working to address that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t you go ahead in the yellow?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, there’s &#8212; is there an assessment by the White House for the losses on the Russian side, like financial, economy losses?&nbsp; Because every time a new or fresh wave of sanctions is imposed, the response from Moscow would be, “It was expected.”&nbsp; So, is there, like, an assessment of the losses as a result of all the sanctions that have been imposed?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, another question on EU.&nbsp; As you know, President Zelenskyy asked for an accelerated push to join the EU.&nbsp; And EU leaders or, I think, representatives are meeting today in Brussels.&nbsp; Does the White House support Ukraine in EU?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the last question, that&#8217;s really up to the EU and Ukraine to determine together.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the &#8212; on the first question, I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s what they&#8217;re saying anymore.&nbsp; They have had &#8212; their stock market has been closed for days.&nbsp; The ruble is worth a penny.&nbsp; They&#8217;re headed toward what many outside economists have described as a recession.&nbsp; They have had a huge strain on their financial markets and systems.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think the facts bear out if that is the claim anyone is making, and I have not seen that claim be made, much less.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, go ahead in the middle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Does the White House believe there&#8217;s an opportunity to convince China to play an effective role in resolving the crisis in Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve seen China do to date:&nbsp; We have seen them speak out at the Munich Security Conference or have a public comment, I should say, about the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen them abstain from U.N. Security Council votes.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen them largely abide by the sanctions that have been put in place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would note, though, that if any country tries to evade or work around our economic measures, they will experience the consequences of those actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So our assessment right now is that they&#8217;re abiding by the requirements that have been put in place, but we would continue to encourage any country to think a lot about what place they want to &#8212; what role they want to play in history as we all look back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let me go to the front.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; A couple questions on the future leadership of NATO.&nbsp; What is the White House thinking on Jens Stoltenberg stepping down in just a few months as the leader of the Alliance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that NATO has not been more united, in the last several months, in decades.&nbsp; And while no one wanted that to be prompted by the invasion of a dictator, like President Putin, into a foreign country, that unity among NATO partners and the strength of that unity is certainly something that has been a direct impact of his aggression.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of future leadership, obviously, that would be for NATO partners to determine.&nbsp; But we certainly recognize and value the leadership that has been displayed by NATO &#8212; NATO leaders and the Alliance over the course of the last few months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Follow-up on that: Have you, as a NATO member, ruled out asking Stoltenberg to continue in this time of the biggest crisis since World War Two?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you in terms of the future of NATO leadership from here.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you started the search for a new leader of NATO?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, it&#8217;s up to NATO leaders and partners to determine that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not a spokesperson for the NATO Alliance, so I would certainly point you to them to speak to that in any further detail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to go back to Venezuela, if we can.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s a few here you&#8217;re probably going to not be able or just not answer &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but we’re going to ask them anyway.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gustavo Cárdenas and Jorge Alberto Fernández &#8212; do we know why they were released?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more details on that I can provide.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; U.S. officials who were part of that delegation &#8212; are they all back from Venezuela?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I believe, yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will confirm that for you, though.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we anticipate the imminent release of any other Americans who are being held there right now?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, as we are working on bringing any unjustly detained Americans home from any country in the world &#8212; whether it&#8217;s Venezuela, Russia, Afghanistan, Syria, China, Iran, and elsewhere &#8212; we typically don&#8217;t discuss that because it puts at risk the potential for bringing individuals home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But yes, we would still &#8212; we are still going to work on bringing others home who have &#8212; who did not return on the plane last night.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A high-ranking member of Juan Guaidó’s team told the Miami Herald this week, quote, “It is foolish to think that Maduro will quit Russia when a great deal of the corruption funds have been deposited in Russia and when Russia, furthermore is its greatest ally…This is a mistake.&nbsp; To buy oil from Maduro is the same as buying oil from Putin.”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two things.&nbsp; I think I know where you&#8217;ll go on the first one, but I want to give you the opportunity to respond.&nbsp; If the United States &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We spend so much time together, Ed.&nbsp; I appreciate it.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If the United States recognizes Guaidó as the leader of Venezuela, why did the U.S. feel it necessary to negotiate with the Maduro regime?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And was the Guaidó team made aware of the plans for U.S. officials to go to Venezuela to meet with the Maduro government before they went?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the last, I just don&#8217;t have anything more to convey to you about private diplomatic conversations.&nbsp; I would note that one of the steps that was announced yesterday was Maduro saying he was willing to resume talks with Venezuela’s interim president.&nbsp; Certainly, we would note that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, obviously, we &#8212; part of our effort here, as you now know, was related to the health and wellbeing of American citizens detained in Venezuela, hence we had discussions with those who are detaining them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one, because there were so many questions &#8212; good ones &#8212; about the planes &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; going from Poland to Ukraine and whether we&#8217;d be the interlocutor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Sunday, when the Secretary of State was asked about this possibility of a plane swap, he said, quote, “That gets a green light,” and we&#8217;re working with Poland on possibly backfilling their military equipment.&nbsp; What changed between him saying that on Sunday and Tori Nuland and others yesterday at the Pentagon saying, “Actually, that&#8217;s not tenable”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s exactly how I would see how the events transpired.&nbsp; I believe that Tony &#8212; Secretary Blinken was asked about Poland’s giving planes to the Ukrainians.&nbsp; That&#8217;s certainly a choice they make as a sovereign country.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never opposed that, never stood in the way of that; we still do not today.</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re talking about here though is &#8212; the proposal yesterday, as you know, was for these planes to fly from a U.S. air base in Germany.&nbsp; And we have understandable concerns about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what we&#8217;re talking about now, through military channels, is the operational concerns: how this could work, the logistics of it.&nbsp; And those conversations are ongoing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Why did you guys decide to rebrand the rise in gas prices as the “#PutinPriceHike”?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I mean, if you want to use that on Fox, I welcome that.&nbsp; But &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I think it&#8217;ll get a lot of airtime because we have heard the President warn for months that gas prices were rising because of the supply chain and because of post-pandemic demand.&nbsp; If you guys knew for months that this was going to be the #PutinPriceHike, why are we just hearing that now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, if we go back to six months ago, I don&#8217;t think anybody was predicting we would be exactly where we are as it relates to Russia and Ukraine, as you know that events in the world, including the invasion by Russia of a foreign country, does prompt instability and volatility in the global oil markets.&nbsp; And there are all sorts of different issues that can impact that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing now.</p>



<p>Outside economists and analysts have conveyed and said publicly that Russia&#8217;s invasion, Russia&#8217;s buildup of troops, President Putin&#8217;s decision to do that very early this year led to a lot of the instability and volatility in the oil markets.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t have to take my word for it.</p>



<p>So, therefore, if President Putin&#8217;s buildup of military troops is leading to volatility and an increase in oil &#8212; in prices, hence you have “Putin pump &#8212; gas price pump &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; You and the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; rise.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You and the President are both talk &#8212; thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You and the President are both talking about &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Spit that out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You and the President are both talking about producing energy here, saying that oil and gas companies “have 9,000 permits to drill now.&nbsp; They could be drilling right now.”&nbsp; Would President Biden cut red tape to make that possible?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What red tape needs to be cut when they have the permits, they have the capacity to do it?&nbsp; What&#8217;s holding them up?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does President Biden think that each of these 9,000 leases that are available have oil or gas in them?&nbsp; Because industry experts are saying that “that accusation is a complete red herring”; “some permits are viable and some are not”; and that when you say that, “This represents a fundamental misunderstanding as to how this process works.”</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, the &#8212; nearly 60 percent of leased acres remain non-producing &#8212; that&#8217;s a lot &#8212; in the range of 20 million acres.&nbsp; So there are 9,000 unused approved permits to drill in.&nbsp; They should not require &#8212; that should not require us inviting them to do that.&nbsp; They should do that themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you said they can&#8217;t get the additional permits.&nbsp; So would the President &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What additional permits do they need?&nbsp; There&#8217;s no &#8212; they have &#8212; the leases are there.&nbsp; The permits are there. I don&#8217;t think they need an embroidered invitation to drill.&nbsp; That is their oil companies.&nbsp; What is &#8212; what is happening &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s not an embroidered invitation, it’s a federal permit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What is happening &#8212; what is ha- &#8212; but what was is &#8212; the permits have been granted, Peter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s not just one permit though.&nbsp; Would you &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What is happening here is that we are seeing &#8212; these are private sector companies.&nbsp; We recognize that.&nbsp; Many of them are making record profits.&nbsp; We see that that.&nbsp; That is all publicly available data.&nbsp; They have pressure to return cash to investors and their shareholders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re saying right now is: There is a war.&nbsp; We&#8217;re asking them to go use the approved permits, use the unused space, and go get more supply out of the ground in our own country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just a quick yes-or-no, because there&#8217;s a lot of gray area here.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is a restart of the Keystone XL construction completely off the table as long as Joe Biden is President?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, why don&#8217;t you tell me what that would help address.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking you if it is an option.&nbsp; You guys say, “All options are on the table.”&nbsp; Is restarting Keystone construction one of them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; If we&#8217;re trying to bring about more supply, that does not address any problem.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s supply from Canada, a friendly ally, instead of Saudi Arabia or Iran or Venezuela.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That &#8212; that’s already &#8212; we’re already getting that oil, Peter.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; the pipeline is just the delivery mechanism.&nbsp; It is not an oil field.&nbsp; So it does not provide more supply into the system.&nbsp; It does not address &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it off the table?&nbsp; Is it possible that Joe Biden will ever say, “You guys can go ahead with construction of Keystone XL”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no plans for that, and it would not address any of the problems we&#8217;re having currently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you help us &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And we’re going to have to wrap up soon, but we’ll try to get to MJ.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you help us understand what exactly would have transpired for the Polish government to publicly propose this idea of getting the fighter jets to Ukraine that the U.S. would then publicly reject?&nbsp; Was there, at any point, a breakdown in communication between the two countries?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I think as our Undersecretary of State, Tori Nuland, testified yesterday, we were not made aware of their plans to make that announcement yesterday.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t call that a breakdown in &#8212; I guess it&#8217;s a temporary breakdown in communication, but we have a strong and abiding relationship with Poland.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President spoke with President Duda just last Friday.&nbsp; Obviously, the Vice President is on her way there, not &#8212; not related to this particular issue, which will be worked through military channels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it was more about the mechanism for how it would be delivered.&nbsp; And that is the issue that is operational, and we&#8217;re still discussing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it safe to say that the U.S. was caught off guard by the initial announcement from the Polish government?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we said that yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On gas prices &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; quickly.&nbsp; The President said yesterday, “I&#8217;m going to do everything I can to minimize Putin’s price hike here at home.”&nbsp; And then hours later as he was getting off the Air Force One, he said, I “can&#8217;t do much about that right now.”&nbsp; “Can&#8217;t do much right now.”&nbsp; That was the exact words from the President.</p>



<p>For anyone that might have been confused seeing the two statements from the President within a couple of hours, what would be your explanation?&nbsp; Does the President believe there is action that he can take to address gas prices, or does he believe there&#8217;s not much that can be done?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the short gaggles when the President is getting off the plane and getting into a car are not always super comprehensive, as I think many of you have experienced.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not always extensive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what the President said yesterday in his lengthy remarks before his trip and what we have said many times is that there are a range of steps that we will continue to take, including coordinating with the global community about ensuring the supply in the marketplace meets the demand.&nbsp; That includes the release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve that he announced a second one just a few weeks ago.&nbsp; That includes continuing to work and coordinate with global oil suppliers around the world, something that his national security team and he is engaged in, in a nearly daily basis.&nbsp; And that includes considering a range of domestic options.</p>



<p>But the oil markets &#8212; oil markets are global.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And it is all about meeting the supply demands that are out there.&nbsp; And clearly, given the invasion and given the impact of that, we need to look at a range of options, but we&#8217;ve already taken a number of steps and we will continue to.&nbsp; And he said that all yesterday morning in the same day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, to clarify &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, I got to &#8212; this may have to be the last one.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to clarify on the military planes &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and the Vice President’s trip.&nbsp; You said that what&#8217;s going on now are discussions with military officials.&nbsp; So this issue is not a priority, is not going to be part of the Vice President&#8217;s discussions with the Polish leader tomorrow?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would expect it&#8217;s going to happen through military channels.&nbsp; Those conversations have on- &#8212; been ongoing, and I would expect they would continue to happen through those channels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, not &#8212; not a priority?&nbsp; Not a central part of the Vice President&#8217;s discussions tomorrow (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m never going to say it&#8217;s not a priority, but I would just say that the appropriate channels for it &#8212; because they&#8217;re about the operational movement of military equipment &#8212; are through military channels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A quick follow-up?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a clarification.&nbsp; Just a clarification on the &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know we’re going to have to wrap up in a minute here because you guys have to go to the event.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick reaction to the Russian airstrikes reportedly striking a children’s hospital in the Ukrainian city of Mariupol?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have &#8212; we have certainly seen those reports.&nbsp; And as a mother &#8212; I know a number of you are mothers yourself &#8212; it is horrifying to see the type of &#8212; the barbaric use of military force to go after innocent civilians in a sovereign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, I know we&#8217;ve seen the reports on all &#8212; that you have all been broadcasting over the last couple of hours.&nbsp; Unfortunately, I don&#8217;t have more details than that at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just for clarification &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You all have to go to an event with the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just for clarification on the question &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the U.S. recognize Juan Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela?&nbsp; Because I think that was a direct question from Ed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That we had &#8212; that’s how we’ve &#8212; we have referred to him, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, no, but you didn’t say.&nbsp; Does the U.S. recognize Juan Guaidó &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s how we refer to him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone, so much.&nbsp; Have a good rest of your day.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:50 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe&#160;Biden’s Roundtable with CEOs and Bipartisan Governors in Support of the Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-roundtable-with-ceos-and-bipartisan-governors-in-support-of-the-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 21:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. joined by Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo and Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese, met with business leaders and a bipartisan pair of governors to call on Congress to take swift action and deliver competitiveness legislation like the Bipartisan Innovation Act to the President’s desk. The governors and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. joined by Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo and Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese, met with business leaders and a bipartisan pair of governors to call on Congress to take swift action and deliver competitiveness legislation like the Bipartisan Innovation Act to the President’s desk.<br> <br>The governors and business leaders—which included some of the world’s leading manufacturing and semiconductor firms—discussed how the bill will foster domestic semiconductor manufacturing, create more resilient supply chains, invest in basic research and set a course for America’s innovation agenda while lowering costs for the middle class. Business leaders discussed their plans to reshore manufacturing and make more in America, building on the momentum of 423,000 manufacturing jobs created since President Biden took office. They discussed how their companies are trying to build more resilient supply chains, leading them to re-locate production in America, and how the bill would result in quicker innovation in American manufacturing and more investments in worker training. They also discussed how domestic production can help Americans by addressing bottlenecks that are raising the costs of household goods like appliances, air conditioners, and washing machines.  And the group discussed how, as we’ve seen over the past years, global events like the pandemic or Russia’s unprovoked aggression in Ukraine can result in higher prices for American consumers, which further underscores the importance of strengthening our economy and making it more resilient to these types of shocks.<br> <br>Indiana Governor Eric Holcomb and Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer, spoke to the economic imperative of passing this bipartisan legislation for the economies of their states. Governor Holcomb said “Slow speed kills—we need to get this done and get it to your desk” and Governor Whitmer explained “Chip shortages have impacted more than 575,000 American jobs…These shortages are driving up costs, are jeopardizing families, and increasing the manufacturing here at home will reduce supply chain delays in transportation as well as lowering the costs of consumer electronics.”<br> <br><strong>Participants include:</strong><br>Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer<br>Indiana Governor Eric Holcomb<br>Dr. Siyoung Choi*, President and GM, Device Solutions Division, Samsung<br>Elizabeth Door, Senior Vice President, Global Strategic Sourcing, Whirlpool<br>Enrique Lores*, President and CEO, Hewlett-Packard<br>Geoff Martha, CEO, Medtronic<br>Sanjay Mehrota, President and CEO, Micron<br>Jennifer Rumsey, President and COO, Cummins<br> <br>*Denotes virtual participant</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy on EPA’s Reinstatement of the California&#160;Waiver</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/statement-by-national-climate-advisor-gina-mccarthy-on-epas-reinstatement-of-the-california-waiver/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For more than 30 years, the Clean Air Act has provided California with an ability to set standards that control of emissions from new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines. And since that time, California has worked hand-in-hand with the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to drive life-saving air pollution reductions, while spurring invention&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For more than 30 years, the Clean Air Act has provided California with an ability to set standards that control of emissions from new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines. And since that time, California has worked hand-in-hand with the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to drive life-saving air pollution reductions, while spurring invention and investment in technologies and materials that enable the next generation of motor vehicles.<br><br>Building on the momentum from California’s 2020 Framework Agreement on Clean Cars, the EPA set the most ambitious motor vehicle emissions standards in history and today, reinstated the California Waiver. Together, these steps provide the opportunity for the Biden-Harris Administration and the State of California under Governor Newsom’s leadership, to once again move forward in the direction of a harmonized national program that will benefit families all across America.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 16:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48728</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Shereef Elnahal, Nominee for Under Secretary for Health, Veterans Health Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs Ray Jefferson, Nominee for Under Secretary for Benefits, Veterans Benefits Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs Rita Landgraf, Nominee&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Shereef Elnahal, Nominee for Under Secretary for Health, Veterans Health Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Ray Jefferson, Nominee for Under Secretary for Benefits, Veterans Benefits Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Rita Landgraf, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Aging, Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Roselyn Tso, Nominee for Director of the Indian Health Service, Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Patrick Murphy, Nominee for Chair of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Jonathan Woodson, Nominee for Vice Chair of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>William Blake, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Michael Blecker, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Christine Hill, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Joyce Johnson, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Lucretia McClenney, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>José Ramos, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Shereef Elnahal, Nominee for Under Secretary for Health, Veterans Health Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Shereef Elnahal is a physician leader who has served as President and Chief Executive Officer of University Hospital in Newark, NJ since 2019. Prior to this role, Elnahal served as New Jersey’s 21st Health Commissioner, appointed by Governor Phil Murphy and confirmed unanimously by the New Jersey Senate. He was the first Muslim member of New Jersey&#8217;s Cabinet in state history. He also served as Assistant Deputy Under Secretary for Health for Quality, Safety, and Value at the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs from 2016 through 2018, overseeing quality of care for the Veterans Health Administration (VHA). He co-founded the VHA Innovation Ecosystem, a program that continues to foster the spread of innovation and best practices that improve veteran care across the nation.</p>



<p>Elnahal led University Hospital through the COVID-19 public health emergency, and also set up one of the first COVID-19 vaccination sites in NJ, vaccinating the state&#8217;s first health care worker on December 15th, 2020. In addition, Elnahal has overseen improvements in care quality and patient safety at the hospital. He has brought his public health background to bear in community-based programming, including a recently announced partnership with a developer and the NJ Housing and Mortgage Financing Authority to provide supportive housing to homeless patients; a hospital-based violence intervention program that has served as a national model; and a program that deploys trusted chaplains as community health workers.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ray Jefferson, Nominee for Under Secretary for Benefits, Veterans Benefits Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Ray Jefferson is the President of Jefferson Group, a global leadership development consultancy, as well as the Chair and Co-Founder of the Service Academies Global Summit. Earlier in his career, Jefferson served as a White House Fellow and worked as a Special Assistant to the U.S. Secretary of Commerce. Additionally, he served as a Fulbright Fellow in Singapore; as the Deputy Director for Hawaii’s Department of Business, Economic Development and Tourism; and as a Leadership Consultant with McKinsey &amp; Company based in Singapore. In 2009, President Barack Obama appointed Jefferson as the Senate-confirmed U.S. Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training at the U.S. Department of Labor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jefferson graduated from the U.S. Military Academy at West Point in 1988 and served as an Army Officer with the infantry, Rangers, and Special Forces. Jefferson lost all five fingers on his left hand while attempting to protect his teammates from a hand grenade detonating prematurely during training. He attended Harvard&#8217;s Kennedy School of Government, earning an MPA in Strategic Management, and went on to earn an MBA from Harvard Business School. Jefferson’s commitment to service has been recognized throughout his career, including when he was selected by then-Secretary of State Colin Powell as one of the two inaugural recipients of the Harrison H. Schmitt Fulbright Alumni Leadership Award for dedication to public service. Jefferson is a member of the Asia Society, Council on Foreign Relations (life member), Fulbright Association, HBS African-American Alumni Association, NAACP, Special Forces Association, 75th Ranger Regiment Association, and Young Presidents’ Organization. Born and raised in Guilderland, New York, he now considers home to be Honolulu, Hawaii.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rita Landgraf, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Aging, Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Rita Landgraf joined the University of Delaware’s College of Health Sciences in 2017 as Professor of Practice and Distinguished Health and Social Services Administrator in Residence. She also serves as Director of the UD Partnership for Healthy Communities, a cross-college, cross-state initiative. Landgraf serves as a leader within the Dean’s Office and supports a variety of activities including community engagement and outreach, development of a Master’s level degree in public health, and the college’s pipeline program. Landgraf’s focus is concentrated on the social, economic, and environmental conditions that support and sustain healthy communities and the relationship of these conditions to promote equity in health, a cost-effective health system, and the advancement of policy.</p>



<p>From 2009 to 2017, Landgraf served as Cabinet Secretary of the Delaware Department of Health and Social Services under Governor Jack Markell. As Secretary, she led the principal agency charged with keeping Delawareans healthy, ensuring they get the health care they need, and providing children, families, individuals with disabilities and seniors with the essential services. She managed one of the largest departments in Delaware’s government that included Medicaid, aging and disability services, with an annual budget of over $2 billion. Under Landgraf’s leadership, Delaware expanded community-based services to help older adults age in place, and people with disabilities live, work and participate in their communities.&nbsp; Landgraf is the former President of AARP Delaware, the former Executive Director of the National Alliance on Mental Illness Delaware, and the former Executive Director of the Arc of Delaware.</p>



<p><strong><u>Roselyn Tso, Nominee for Director of the Indian Health Service, Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Roselyn Tso is an enrolled member of the Navajo Nation. Tso began her career with the Indian Health Service (IHS) in 1984. She previously served in various roles in the Portland Area IHS and IHS Headquarters. Currently, Tso serves as the Area Director for the Navajo Area IHS. The Navajo Area IHS delivers health services to a user population of over 244,000 American Indians; the Navajo Nation is one of the largest Indian reservations in the United States consisting of more than 25,000 contiguous square miles and three satellite communities, and extends into portions of the states of Arizona, New Mexico, and Utah. In her leadership position, she was responsible for the implementation of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Act and worked directly with tribes and direct service tribes.</p>



<p>Tso holds a Bachelor of Arts in interdisciplinary studies from Marylhurst University in Portland, Oregon and a master’s degree in organizational management from the University of Phoenix, Portland, Oregon.</p>



<p><strong><u>Patrick Murphy, Nominee for Chair of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Patrick Murphy, a Pennsylvania native, was the first Iraq War Veteran to serve in Congress. He received a Bronze Star for his service in Iraq as paratrooper with the 82nd Airborne Division. While in Congress, Murphy led the signing of two landmark bills into law, including the repeal of Don’t Ask Don’t Tell and the 21st Century GI Bill. As Under Secretary of the Army during the Obama-Biden Administration, Murphy oversaw the management and operation of the Army – a Fortune 10-sized organization and the nation’s second largest employer of over 1.3 million individuals. Murphy led the expansion of the Soldier for Life initiative, which saved $340M in FY16, and helped the Army reach recruitment goals for the first time in five years with over 130,000 millennials hired.</p>



<p>In 2019, Murphy chaired the Cyberspace Solarium Commission which generated more than 100 recommendations for improving the United States’ approach to digital security issues, many of which became law through multiple defense bills and a high-profile infrastructure package. For the last several years, Murphy has been working across the public and private sector to invest in veteran-owned businesses, advocate for stronger healthcare policy, and recruiting young people and veterans to run for public office.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jonathan Woodson, Nominee for Vice Chair of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Jonathan Woodson is the Lars Anderson Professor in Management and Professor of the Practice at the Boston University Questrom School of Business, and holds joint appointments as Professor of Surgery at the School of Medicine, and Professor of Health Law, Policy, and Management at the School of Public Health. He established and led the University-wide Institute for Health System Innovation and Policy.</p>



<p>From 2010-2016, Woodson was the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs and Director of the Tricare Management Activity in the United States Department of Defense (DOD). He was the principal advisor to the Secretary of Defense for all health and force health protection related issues, and ensured the effective execution of the DOD medical mission. He exercised authority, direction, and control over the Defense Health Agency, Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, Armed Forces Radiobiology Research Institute, Defense Center of Excellence for Psychological Health and Traumatic Brain Injury, and the Tricare Health Plan serving 9.5 million beneficiaries. Woodson holds the rank of Major General, United States Army, Reserve, and is Commander of the United States Army Reserve Medical Command, Pinellas Park, Florida.</p>



<p><strong><u>William Carl Blake, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Carl Blake is the Executive Director for Paralyzed Veterans of America (PVA), a position he has served in since January 2018. He is responsible for exercising administrative control, as directed by the President of PVA, of all offices and functions of the organization, including overseeing all efforts devoted to financial management, development and fundraising, strategic communications, and service programs executed by PVA. Blake previously served as the Associate Executive Director of Government Relations for PVA. He has represented PVA to federal agencies and has frequently testified before committees of the U.S. House of Representatives and Senate.</p>



<p>Blake was raised in Woodford, Virginia. He attended the United States Military Academy at West Point, New York. He received a Bachelor of Science Degree from the Military Academy in May 1998. He was assigned to the 2nd Battalion, 504th Parachute Infantry Regiment (1st Brigade) of the 82nd Airborne Division at Fort Bragg, North Carolina. He graduated from Infantry Officer Basic Course, U.S. Army Ranger School, U.S. Army Airborne School, and Air Assault School. His awards include the Army Commendation Medal, Expert Infantryman’s Badge, and German Parachutist Badge. Blake retired from the military in October 2000 due to injuries suffered during a parachute training exercise. He completed spinal cord injury rehabilitation at the Richmond VA Medical Center in Virginia. Blake received his Master’s in Public Administration from Old Dominion University with a concentration in Nonprofit Management. Blake lives in Fredericksburg, VA, with his wife Venus, son Jonathan, and daughter Brooke.</p>



<p><strong><u>Michael Blecker, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Michael Blecker served in the U.S. Army from 1967 to 1970, with combat infantry service in Vietnam from 1968 &#8211; 1969. Upon finishing law school, he joined Swords to Plowshares in 1976 to help veterans navigate the complex VA disability system. In 1982, he became Executive Director of Swords to Plowshares, and has over the past 45 years guided the agency from its small grassroots origins to one with a continuum of specialized services and an annual budget of over $35 million.</p>



<p>Blecker has a nationwide reputation for dedicated service and as an authority on veterans’ services and veterans’ rights. He is co-founder of the National Coalition for Homeless Veterans and the California Association of Veterans’ Service Agencies. He has served on the Congressional Commission on Service Members and Veterans Transition Assistance, the California Senate Commission on Homeless Veterans, the San Francisco Mayor’s Homeless Planning Committee, the National Agent Orange Settlement Advisory Board, the Agent Orange Information Center, and the Veterans Speakers Alliance. From 2015 to 2016, Blecker served on the federal Commission on Care, examining veteran access to VA care.</p>



<p><strong><u>Christine Hill, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Christine Hill currently serves as the Republican Staff Director for the House Committee on Veterans’ Affairs Subcommittee on Health. Prior to this position, she was the Executive Vice President, Government Affairs for Wounded Warrior Project (WWP). In the Bush Administration, Hill was Senate-confirmed as the Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Legislative Affairs for the Department of Veterans Affairs. Prior to her appointment, Hill was Director, Congressional and Intergovernmental Affairs for the 2005 Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission. Before joining this congressionally mandated commission, Hill was the military legislative assistant to Senator Elizabeth Dole.</p>



<p>A 1983 graduate of the United States Air Force Academy, Hill held numerous positions as a KC-135 instructor navigator and senior standardization/evaluation navigator. During this time, she flew combat support during the U.S. intervention in Panama, and was deployed to Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, flying in support of Desert Storm as the chief of tanker air operations. Following an assignment to Headquarters Air Combat Command, Hill was hand-picked to become the first woman assigned to fly the B-1B Bomber. She completed qualification as both an offensive and defensive systems officer and was the first initial qualification student combat qualified as a weapons system officer and instructor. During this time, she also held various Squadron- and Wing-level leadership positions. Hill concluded her military career at the Pentagon with assignments in Air Force plans and budget, and in the weapon systems division of the Air Force Office of Legislative Liaison. She retired as a Lieutenant Colonel.</p>



<p><strong><u>Joyce Johnson, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Rear Admiral Dr. Joyce M. Johnson, DO, MA is a physician with senior public health leadership experience in the civilian and military sectors. Her last active duty assignment was with the U.S. Coast Guard as Director, Health and Safety and she retired at the rank of Rear Admiral, Upper Half (08). As a physician, she is board certified in Public Health/Preventive Medicine and Psychiatry, and is also a board-certified Clinical Pharmacologist and Certified Addiction Specialist. She is a Doctor of Osteopathic Medicine, earning a D.O. degree; prior to that she earned a master’s degree in Hospital and Health Administration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Based on her previous experiences, Johnson understands the clinical needs of veterans from both provider and patient perspectives, and recognizes the many contributions the VA health care system makes to patients, their families, and the overall community in meeting the needs of America’s veterans. For many years, she was a surveyor for a national accreditation body, surveying both inpatient and ambulatory care facilities. At the Department of Veterans Affairs, Johnson served as a Senior Research Resident, and more recently on has been appointed to the VA Commission on Care, the Advisory Committee on Disability Compensation, and the Advisory Committee on Women Veterans. In addition, Johnson served on the Board and chaired several committees of the Military Officers Association of America (MOAA). Johnson has been awarded eight honorary doctoral degrees, and has extensive on-site disaster relief experience, and has provided clinical care and/or medical consultation on all seven continents.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lucretia McClenney, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Lucretia M. McClenney has dedicated her professional life to our nation’s men and women who have served and are serving in uniformed armed services, and their families. She served with distinction for 30 years in the Army in various medical treatment facilities and staffs worldwide, and retired as a Colonel in November 2001. Immediately following McClenney’s retirement from the Army, she joined the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) as Special Assistant to the Assistant Secretary for Policy, Planning, and Preparedness. She also served as Director of the VA’s Center for Minority Veterans, where she was the principal advisor to the Secretary of the VA on policies and programs affecting minority veterans. As an outcome of her efforts in this role, the VA established an Office of Health Equity to ensure health equity for all veterans.</p>



<p>Her dedication and passion for the health care of veterans led to her selection in 2015 to serve on the congressionally mandated Commission on Care that provided recommendations for transforming veterans’ health care. She served as a consultant with the DOD Vietnam War Commemoration. Currently, McClenney is a member of the Military Officers Association of America (MOAA) Board of Directors, VA’s Former POW Advisory Committee, a Life Member of The ROCKS, Inc., and a Life Member of Alpha Kappa Sorority, Inc. She received a BSN from Murray State University, and an MSN in Psychiatric/Mental Health Nursing from Catholic University. She lives in Alexandria, VA.</p>



<p><strong><u>José Ramos, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>José R. Ramos is the Vice President of Government and Community Relations for the Wounded Warrior Project (WWP). Ramos grew up in El Paso, TX and joined the Navy as a Hospital Corpsman, spending his entire career serving alongside Marines as a platoon “Doc”. He served one tour in Afghanistan and two tours in Iraq. In 2004, while serving as a member of a Sniper Team, he was hit by a rocket and was severely injured. His injuries were nearly fatal and included a left arm amputation, lung contusions, nerve damage to the left leg, bulged discs in the lumbar region, and numerous shrapnel wounds which led to his retirement from service in November 2005. Ramos used adaptive sports through his recovery, running the New York City Marathon, cycling with other injured troops from Washington, D.C. to the Hamptons, N.Y. in seven days, and competed in endurance events as a way of raising awareness for those with disabilities.</p>



<p>In 2007, Ramos was appointed by President Bush to serve on the President’s Commission on Care for America’s Returning Wounded Warriors, tasked to conduct a review of the care America is providing wounded servicemen and women returning from the battlefield. Ramos graduated from George Mason University, <em>summa cum laude</em>, with a B.A. in Government and International Politics and a Minor in Islamic Studies. Earlier in Ramos’ career, he worked at the Center for Strategic and International Studies, sat on the Peer Reviewed Orthopedic Research Program Integration Panel for the Department of Defense, and served as a Special Assistant at the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Legislative Affairs. Ramos resides in Great Falls, VA with his wife Jodie, their sons Donovan and Luke, and their Labrador Scout.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the President&#8217;s New Digital Assets Executive&#160;Order</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/09/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-presidents-new-digital-assets-executive-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 14:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (March 8, 2022) 6:21 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; Good evening, everyone.&#160; Thank you for joining today&#8217;s press call to discuss President Biden&#8217;s new executive order on ensuring responsible innovation in digital assets. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; As a reminder, this call will be on background, attributed to a senior administration official, and the contents of this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(March 8, 2022)</p>



<p>6:21 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you for joining today&#8217;s press call to discuss President Biden&#8217;s new executive order on ensuring responsible innovation in digital assets.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a reminder, this call will be on background, attributed to a senior administration official, and the contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Wednesday, March 9th, at 6:00 a.m.&nbsp; By joining the call, you agree to these ground rules.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Prior to this call, I also shared a factsheet that is also under embargo until tomorrow at 6:00 a.m.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For everyone&#8217;s awareness but not for reporting, our speakers today are [senior administration official], [senior administration official], and [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>After we hear from our speakers, we will open up the call for Q&amp;A.&nbsp; And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks to all of you for joining us late in the day.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ensuring responsible innovation and evolution of the digital asset ecosystem is essential to our national security, financial stability, economic competitiveness, and continued global leadership.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You all know that cryptocurrencies have seen explosive growth in recent years, reaching a $3 trillion market cap last November.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without oversight, the explosive growth in cryptocurrency use would pose risks to Americans and to the stability of our businesses, our financial system, and our national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The absence of sufficient oversight can also provide opportunities for criminals and other malicious actors to leverage cryptocurrencies to launder the proceeds of their crimes or circumvent justly-applied sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the same time, however, digital assets can also provide opportunities for American innovation and competitiveness, and promote financial inclusion.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Innovation is central to America&#8217;s story and powers our economy, generating jobs and opportunities, creating and building new industries, and sustaining our global competitive edge and leadership.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This innovation is also a critical factor in ensuring the long-term strength of key national security tools, like sanctions and anti-money laundering frameworks as well as other strategic benefits we reap from the role of the United States in the global financial system.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also want to underscore the significant international leadership role the United States has already played in the digital asset ecosystem, just as we have in technological and financial standard-setting throughout our history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States also has the world’s oldest and most comprehensive regulatory framework for digital asset activities, which has enabled us to take leading roles in international fora and supporting key partners in building their own digital asset capacity.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States led global efforts to adopt the first international standards on digital assets during our presidency of the Financial Action Task Force &#8212; FATF.&nbsp; And we continue to drive implementation of those standards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Under our G7 presidency, we established the G7 Digital Payments Expert Group to discuss Central Bank Digital Currencies, stablecoins, and other digital payment issues.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To reinforce this leadership, the EO directs relevant departments and agencies to initiate research into the merits of a U.S. central bank digital currency, including an assessment of possible risks and benefits to consumers, investors, payment systems, implications for national security, human rights, and financial inclusion.&nbsp; That effort will also lay out the measures that are needed to establish a central bank digital currency, or CBDC, should there be a determination that doing so is in the national interest.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For context, over 100 countries are currently exploring or piloting central bank digital currencies for both cross-border and domestic use.&nbsp; Many of these countries are also working together to set standards for CBDC design and cross-border systems, with implications for domestic and international priorities including the centrality of the U.S. dollar in the global financial system.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This EO will help make sure we have a leadership role and a seat at the table.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now I&#8217;ll turn it over to my colleague.&nbsp; As you just heard, they are [redacted].&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Over to you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Good evening everyone, and thank you again for your time this evening.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, innovation is not only critical for our economic security but also for our national security, enabling us to maintain our technological and economic edge to compete and win in the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But innovation must benefit all Americans, and that extends to innovation in the digital asset ecosystem.&nbsp; The benefits and risks of digital asset systems are fundamentally dependent on their design and governance, so we must take steps to ensure this serves Americans’ interests.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This executive order seeks to promote digital asset innovation while balancing their benefits and associated risk, and it does so in several ways.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, the EO establishes a comprehensive federal framework to ensure the United States continues to play a leading role in the innovation and governance of digital assets at home and abroad, consistent with our democratic values and to the benefit of U.S.&nbsp;global competitiveness.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, the EO directs relevant departments and agencies to initiate research into the merits of a U.S. Central Bank Digital Currency, as [senior administration official] mentioned previously.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This research, along with the framework we will develop for international engagement and competitiveness, will help ensure we preserve the critical role of the United States in the global financial system.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is critical for ensuring the strength of U.S.&nbsp;national security tools that we need to combat illicit actors, like rogue states and cybercriminals.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, the EO calls for the development of a plan to mitigate the illicit finance and national security risks posed by the misuse of digital assets.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The White House has already demonstrated leadership in this space by aligning departments and agencies to combat misuse of digital assets enabling the rise and spread of ransomware.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The insufficiency of international implementation of anti-money laundering network and frameworks for digital assets is the greatest vulnerability of these ecosystems that criminals are currently exploiting.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Most current digital asset systems were not designed with critical controls in mind like identity, sanctions screening, and revocability of illicit transactions.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Similar to our efforts to secure software development under the cyber executive order, this executive order is a signal to industry on the need to build in the critical protections needed for financial systems so we can leverage these innovative technologies for our benefit.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The U.S. government will be developing action plans and frameworks to drive this objective.<a></a></p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In sum, the executive order recognizes and reinforces U.S. leadership in the global financial system, safeguards the long-term efficacy of critical national security tools like sanctions and anti-money laundering frameworks, ensuring the digital asset ecosystem evolves in a manner consistent with our democratic values and protects businesses, consumers, and the integrity of the global financial system.</p>



<p>This EO is represents a continuation of U.S. leadership on financial and technological standard-setting at home and abroad. We remain committed to working with allies in the broader digital asset community to shape the future of digital assets systems in a manner that&#8217;s inclusive, consistent with our democratic values, and safeguards the integrity of the global financial system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to my colleague, [senior administration official], to follow up and continue.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Over to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>As [senior administration officials] said, today&#8217;s announcement marks a necessary step forward in our efforts to promote responsible innovation in the digital asset space, leveraging technology, and working with the private sector to help build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out.</p>



<p>Fundamentally, an American approach to digital assets is one that encourages responsible innovation by decisively mitigating the risks, in particular the financial stability and consumer protection risks.</p>



<p>We need to be clear-eyed that certain earlier forms of financial innovation have ended up hurting American families while making a small group of people very rich.&nbsp; That underscores the need for robust consumer and investor protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As digital assets have grown, investors have poured in.&nbsp; Around 16 percent of adult Americans &#8212; approximately 40 million people &#8212; have ever invested in, traded, or used crypto currency based on recent surveys.&nbsp; But some asset prices are volatile, regularly skyrocketing and sinking with real downsides for investors.&nbsp; Bitcoin, for example, began the pandemic at $7,300, peaked at around $68,000 before falling back down to about $39,000.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has put forward a holistic whole-of-government approach to understand and address not only the macroeconomic risks, but also the micro risk &#8212; that is the risk to each individual consumer, investor, and business that engages with these assets.</p>



<p>I want to emphasize why this executive order is significant in two key ways.&nbsp; First, it reflects an extensive process informed by stakeholders across the federal government and many outside of government.&nbsp; This process has identified key areas of present and future concern, and questions about the potential promise of these assets and their underlying technology.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chief among those is the need to guard individual consumers, investors, and businesses, as well as the financial system writ large, from the risks posed by the substantial growth in digital assets.&nbsp; This includes the disparate impact risks that may arise from disparities in digital asset ownership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, it recognizes that our assessments of the risks and potential benefits of digital assets must include an understanding of how our financial system does and does not meet the current needs of consumers in a manner that is equitable, inclusive, and efficient.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Antiquated payment infrastructure leaves the United States and its consumers with options that are slow, costly, or altogether inaccessible.&nbsp; That&#8217;s particularly true of cross-border payments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is why this executive order directs a report on the future of money and payment systems, including discussion of the conditions that drive broad adoption of these assets and the implications for the U.S. financial system and consumers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The executive order also places the highest urgency on research and potential development of the U.S. central bank digital currency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The government alone does not solve these problems, and definitely not a government that stays in its silos.&nbsp; Therefore, we’ll continue to partner with all stakeholders &#8212; including industry, labor, consumer, and environmental groups, international allies and partners &#8212; to identify actions we can take to foster responsible innovation in the digital asset ecosystem, while mitigating the very real risk.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, this executive order signals the beginning, not the conclusion, of this administration&#8217;s work around digital assets.&nbsp; As this ecosystem evolves, so will our approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I will give it back to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I just am looking at a map that shows nine countries have already started &#8212; you know, launched a currency.&nbsp; There&#8217;s 15 pilots underway; 16 countries have them in development.&nbsp; Is the United States kind of getting to this market and this sector too late?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you are now launching a 180-day study, you know, don&#8217;t you even put it off any further?&nbsp; So how quickly can you go after the &#8212; after these reports come in?&nbsp; And is there a risk of being at a competitive disadvantage to China and others?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Maybe I’ll start on that, Andrea.&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; I think the first thing to note from the EO is we&#8217;re placing the highest urgency on the effort to assess the potential benefits and the risks of a digital dollar on payment systems, on financial stability, on national security, on the implications for human rights, and financial inclusion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these are critical design &#8212; all of these implications lead to critical design decisions.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve got to be very &#8212; very deliberate about that analysis because the implications of our moving in this direction are profound for the country that issues the world&#8217;s primary reserve currency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, we can move quickly, but we can also move in a way that&#8217;s smart and that&#8217;s inclusive of the stakeholders both within our government and certainly outside our government.</p>



<p>Oh, I should say also on your second question, you know, on the digital one: I mean, here I want to be &#8212; I want to be very, very direct with my answer.  The primacy of the dollar &#8212; the U.S. dollar &#8212; it&#8217;s underpinned by fundamental advantages that the United States has held for a long time and continues to hold: credible and longstanding commitments to transparency, our rule of law, the contractual obligations and rights that everyone enjoys, the deepest and most liquid financial markets in the world, sound economic governance, and the full independence of our Federal Reserve system.  So those are the institutional features, the competitive advantages that give the dollar its primacy. <br><br>     And really, the dollar’s role has been and will continue to be crucial to the stability of the international monetary system as a whole.  Foreign central bank digital currencies &#8212; I mean, their introduction by themselves do not threaten this dominance. <br><br>     But, you know, we are &#8212; we are constantly assessing and monitoring any developments that relate to a core policy objective of ours, which is to maintain the centrality of the dollar in global financial markets and in the global economy.<br><br>     Q    Hi.  My first question is just logistical.  What is the timeline for some of the reports to be delivered or action to be taken?<br><br>     The second one is: What has your conversation been like with industry in developing this executive order?  You know, how have those conversations gone?  What’s the tenor of them?  And do you expect that they will be on board with the principles that you’ve laid out?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  So I’m happy to start on that and then invite my colleagues to join.<br><br>     So on the timeframes, the executive order includes various timeframes consistent with the complexity of the particular reports and how much work has been done.<br><br>     So one of the key parts of the executive order is we want to fully leverage innovation while managing the risks.  And that means taking a careful look at both of those components and really bringing together stakeholders so that we make these decisions &#8212; as [senior administration official] noted, these are important decisions and we make them in a way that really sets us up for the long-term benefits and implications.<br><br>     So the EO will have a range of timeframes &#8212; some shorter, some 60 to 90 days; some longer, 180 days &#8212; in order to allow for that.<br><br>     And with regard to the engagement with industry, we’ve done a number of what we call “Crypto Sundays” where we brought in innovators on the technology side, individuals on the financial side to really understand the different elements of cryptocurrencies &#8212; for example, the types of services it will enable, like cross-country remittances &#8212; bringing down the cost of that, enabling the speed of that &#8212; as well as innovation in financial markets and, on the flip side, how the governance and design can be &#8212; and the technology of that can be navigated to ensure we manage some of the risks as well.<br><br>     So we’ve done extensive engagement to both be informed and also to test out ideas in the development, which was extensive, of this EO.<br><br>     Q    Hey.  I wanted to ask about next steps once these reports come in.  Is there a timeline for when you would want to maybe start thinking about regulation on some of these topics?<br><br>     And then my other question is &#8212; you mentioned sanctions at the top of the call.  I don’t see them mentioned in the fact sheet.  But are the sanctions and the concerns that have been raised about crypto being a workaround &#8212; are those going &#8212; is that going to be mentioned in this executive order?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  [Senior administration official], you want to speak to that?  Or &#8212;<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  I don’t know.  [Senior administration official], do you want to talk about the sanctions aspect?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah.  Maybe, [senior administration official], if you want to start on regulation and then [senior administration official] and I can do sanctions?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sure.  So, look, I &#8212; we don’t want to pre-judge what we’re going to do before we’ve &#8212; the agencies have had time to do their work and produce their reports and analysis that we are asking them to do.<br><br>     That said, I think the entire premise of this executive order and the spirit behind it is that this is a growing area, an area that is presenting increasing risks and also potential opportunities, and that it’s important that we very quickly fully document and understand what those are and move quickly to address them.<br><br>     So my expectation would be that once the reports are finished on the accelerated timeline that the executive order requires that we would move quickly to try to act on the recommendations that they are providing &#8212; that they provide.<br><br>     [Senior administration official], do you want to talk about sanctions?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sure.  [Senior administration official], I’ll start on this, and if there’s anything I miss, please add onto mine.<br><br>     So, first thing to say here is the U.S. government has long taken actions, including under law enforcement and existing Treasury authorities to combat the use of cryptocurrency to evade sanctions.  And right now, the administration is driving a priority effort on combatting the misuse of virtual currency.<br><br>     This was launched as part of the U.S. counter-ransomware strategy that has been underway for several months.  And the administration will continue to aggressively combat the misuse of cryptocurrency, including the use of it to evade U.S. sanctions.  And that stance equally applies to the &#8212; to the Russia-Ukraine crises, as it does to any other nation or regime or non-state actor that seeks to undermine U.S. national security.<br><br>     I will say, on Russia, in particular, the use of cryptocurrency we do not think is a viable workaround to the set of financial sanctions we’ve imposed across the entire Russian economy and, in particular, to its central bank.<br><br>     And, [senior administration official], over to you for anything I missed.<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  No, I think you really covered it all, [senior administration official].  We’re building on work that’s been underway over the last six to nine months really to counter use of cryptocurrency as part of ransomware and &#8212; including working with international partners on anti-money laundering.<br><br>     And hopefully, while we don’t see it in the current context in terms of Russia itself, the current crisis is a good opportunity for us to double down on that international work and help our partners build capacity to actually implement that anti-money laundering or cryptocurrency rules that we very much want to have in place.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing the call.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t mean to be facetious here, but I&#8217;d love to know sort of how you characterize the importance of this executive order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It strikes me looking at it that a lot of this is ground that’s been trod before, particularly when it comes to central bank digital currency.&nbsp; We just saw the report &#8212; the initial report from the Board of Governors, the subsequent report from the Reserve Bank of Boston, and it just seems like they&#8217;ve begun to dig into these issues in much the same way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, as you talk about the kind of cross-agency work on cybersecurity, certainly the Deputy Attorney General has talked a lot about the role the Justice Department is going to play looking into these issues, I just wonder if you see this as a reset or something more than that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, I&#8217;ve listened to the CFTC chairman, the FCC chairman talk about what they see as their regulatory role here.&nbsp; And I guess I&#8217;m just struggling, looking at the factsheet, to understand how this advances the work that has been done by the administration thus far.&nbsp; Is it, again, to reset it, or to pull it under one agency or umbrella?&nbsp; Just how would you convey the importance of this to somebody who is wondering what the notional progress is from seeing this EO.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Please go ahead, [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’ll follow you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I’m happy to.&nbsp; And then we’ll work this &#8212; you can tell the close partnership among the three of us on this work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, first, there hadn&#8217;t previously been an organized effort to bring together the expertise and authorities of the entire U.S. government to inform a holistic approach to digital assets.&nbsp; And, in this case really, the partnership &#8212; the White House and specifically the National Security Advisor, the Economic Adviser chair &#8212; they’ll share this effort to ensure that we&#8217;re bringing together our national security and our economic policy in a coordinated way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you&#8217;re correct.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been work done by Treasury, there&#8217;s been work done by financial regulators, but really pulling together the questions around consumer and investor protection, financial stability, and systemic and disparate risk &#8212; bringing that together and then, with a common approach, laying out a coordinated path is really the game changer here.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Yeah, I mean, just to add to what you said, I think the implications &#8212; we know the implications of potentially issuing a digital dollar are profound.&nbsp; They&#8217;re extraordinarily wide-ranging.</p>



<p>So, this EO pulls together the expertise from across the U.S. government.&nbsp; It also pulls &#8212; pulls in expertise views and perspectives from a range of stakeholders in our &#8212; in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, this is all about &#8212; this is all about the future of the payments system in this country, the future of credit creation, commercial banking.&nbsp; We know the implications for national security, our ability to show leadership in setting global payment standards for privacy and security, but also reinforcing the efficacy of sanctions or potentially influencing the growth of private cryptocurrencies that we know are growing to a material scale and, in some cases, have facilitated illicit finance and financial stability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of these issues are tied up in the question of whether to issue a digital currency, and, if so, how to do so in a way that advances our strategic objectives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so this &#8212; this is a way to organize ourselves with urgency so that we have a coherent and coordinated view on digital assets and that it&#8217;s articulated at the very highest level of our government.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doing it.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, this is [senior administration official].&nbsp; I would just add to what [senior administration officials] have said: that it&#8217;s notable because this is the President articulating his views about what our interests and concerns are in this space.&nbsp; In fact, that is notable in and of itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think it&#8217;s also important that &#8212; the emphasis that this document places on potential risks and the need to mitigate those risks.&nbsp; You know, in a world &#8212; we live in a world where, you know, approaching 20 percent of Americans have invested in or traded or used cryptocurrencies.&nbsp; This is not a niche issue anymore.&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s profoundly important that we have the right tools to mitigate the risks to consumers, to investors, and, frankly, to the entire financial system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as [senior administration officials] said, getting &#8212; articulating those interests, getting all the work that has already been happening at agencies, getting that organized, getting the agencies talking with each other as appropriate to adequately address these issues &#8212; all of that is very important.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, folks.&nbsp; Thanks for taking this.&nbsp; I guess &#8212; some of my questions have been answered.&nbsp; I guess I wanted to circle back on, I think, the Crypto Sundays that [senior administration official] mentioned.&nbsp; How many of those did you guys do?&nbsp; And was it only sort of innovators and industry representatives present?&nbsp; Or did you also have, you know, some of the academics who have studied, you know, financial stability risks, consumer protection risks, governance issues that are present in the crypto market?&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Academics and other &#8212; you know, other &#8212; other, I guess, experts and stuff.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, the less I share, you know, how often we work Sundays &#8212; I won’t go into how many Sundays there were, but will go into the question about who was included.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There were &#8212; you know, our goal was noting this is a new space and really wanting to learn from as broad a space as possible and test those ideas.&nbsp; It did include academics, innovators, to your point, as well as individuals from the sector as well.</p>



<p>And I want to emphasize, as well, the points that [senior administration officials] made.&nbsp; You know, you see as well we tasked a number of studies in the EO to emphasize that we &#8212; this is an area needs some deep reflection to ensure that we can move out quickly following that and making some key decisions, both from a policy and an implementation perspective.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I would just add that there&#8217;s also meetings with consumer groups and other groups that are focused on some of those risks and that, you know, we purposefully tried to solicit views from experts and academics who have a diversity of viewpoints about the potential risks and benefits of cryptocurrency.&nbsp; So, we tried to really get the full spectrum of the user.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I don’t &#8212; I can’t recall, just to be sure &#8212; I think, [senior administration official], you mentioned it just now &#8212; but we also heard quite a bit from those who want to solve the problems associated with financial inclusion.&nbsp; You know, we know as recently as 2020, I think, over 5 percent of American households were unbanked.&nbsp; That’s if not the highest, among the highest percentage among G7 countries.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a multiple of that share that&#8217;s underbanked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so we heard quite a bit about the reasons why those who are unbanked or underbanked are facing issues with financial inclusion, and many of them relate to high minimum balances or high fees they have to face in the existing architecture.&nbsp; And so, it was important to hear their perspective and to understand how this effort can help solve that problem.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for taking my questions.&nbsp; The last comment actually was very helpful because I&#8217;m interested in the comments that were made about how the current financial system doesn&#8217;t serve many Americans.&nbsp; And I was hoping you could provide a bit more information from the surveys that you talked about regarding unbanked individuals investing in cryptocurrency.&nbsp; Is there &#8212; are there numbers that you might have regarding that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then one other question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve heard from sources &#8212; quite a few sources that say that this EO has not a lot to do with the current war in Ukraine, but I am curious about the timing of the executive order and if that was factored in whatsoever to it&#8217;s being released now.&nbsp; Any information on that would also be helpful.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Maybe I&#8217;ll start.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure &#8212; I&#8217;m sure both [senior administration officials] would like to add perspective.</p>



<p>First, on your last question, we&#8217;ve been working on this EO for many, many months, updating well before early November when Russia began to amass troops on Ukraine&#8217;s border.</p>



<p>In terms of the problems we&#8217;re trying to solve &#8212; and I&#8217;ll come to &#8212; I think [senior administration official] should speak to the financial inclusion issue.&nbsp; But, you know, the payment system right now is quite costly in this country and, in some cases, quite slow, especially for payments across borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, you can look to a number of objective analyses that show Americans pay over, I think, 2 percent of GDP in payment services.&nbsp; And a lot of that has to do with high fees for credit cards.&nbsp; And the primary payment source, which is bank deposits, they tend to get compensated with relatively low interest rates compared to wholesale money market rates, for example.</p>



<p>And, you know, it takes a long time for checks to clear, and wire transfers sometimes take even longer.&nbsp; And so these are problems that are worth solving, worth understanding.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of this effort.</p>



<p>You know, you referenced the financial inclusion surveys.&nbsp; A lot &#8212; the numbers I was citing come from the FDIC, and I think they cite that over 5 percent of American households are unbanked and about 18 percent of households are underbanked.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, just to add to what [senior administration official] said.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, we &#8212; we have a clear problem with lack of access to basic banking services, as [senior administration official] has detailed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our payment system for consumers, in many cases, is quite slow, and it takes a while for a check to actually be deposited into your account.&nbsp; And that delay can end up being quite costly to people who need that payment for &#8212; to pay the rent, or pay utility bills, and so on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, what we are trying &#8212; one of the things that we are trying to do here is to fully understand how can digital assets help, if at all, in solving those problems.&nbsp; I think that just the very fact that they are digital does not, you know, magically solve these problems.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not &#8212; based on what we know so far, it&#8217;s not the case that these assets completely eliminate transaction costs.&nbsp; There are a variety of costs associated with holding and transferring them that resemble some of the problems that we have in our current payment system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the point is, there&#8217;s at least potential here to try to address a very serious problem that mainly affects, you know, lower-income, middle-class Americans.&nbsp; And so we really want to try to get to the bottom of what we can do and how it would be possible to nurture innovation so it does help those folks rather than &#8212; rather than hurt them.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone, for joining our call this evening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, the contents of this call are under embargo until 6:00 a.m. tomorrow morning, and the contents of this call should be attributed to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p> 6:53 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Ensuring Responsible Development of Digital&#160;Assets</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/09/executive-order-on-ensuring-responsible-development-of-digital-assets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 14:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows: Section 1.&#160; Policy.&#160; Advances in digital and distributed ledger technology for financial services have led to dramatic growth in markets for digital assets, with profound implications for the protection&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows:<br><br>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; Advances in digital and distributed ledger technology for financial services have led to dramatic growth in markets for digital assets, with profound implications for the protection of consumers, investors, and businesses, including data privacy and security; financial stability and systemic risk; crime; national security; the ability to exercise human rights; financial inclusion and equity; and energy demand and climate change.&nbsp; In November 2021, non‑state issued digital assets reached a combined market capitalization of $3 trillion, up from approximately $14&nbsp;billion in early November 2016.&nbsp; Monetary authorities globally are also exploring, and in some cases introducing, central bank digital currencies (CBDCs).&nbsp;<br>While many activities involving digital assets are within the scope of existing domestic laws and regulations, an area where the United States has been a global leader, growing development and adoption of digital assets and related innovations, as well as inconsistent controls to defend against certain key risks, necessitate an evolution and alignment of the United States Government approach to digital assets.&nbsp; The United States has an interest in responsible financial innovation, expanding access to safe and affordable financial services, and reducing the cost of domestic and cross-border funds transfers and payments, including through the continued modernization of public payment systems.&nbsp; We must take strong steps to reduce the risks that digital assets could pose to consumers, investors, and business protections; financial stability and financial system integrity; combating and preventing crime and illicit finance; national security; the ability to exercise human rights; financial inclusion and equity; and climate change and pollution.<br><br>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Objectives.&nbsp; The principal policy objectives of the United States with respect to digital assets are as follows:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;We must protect consumers, investors, and businesses in the United States. &nbsp;The unique and varied features of digital assets can pose significant financial risks to consumers, investors, and businesses if appropriate protections are not in place.&nbsp; In the absence of sufficient oversight and standards, firms providing digital asset services may provide inadequate protections for sensitive financial data, custodial and other arrangements relating to customer assets and funds, or disclosures of risks associated with investment.&nbsp; Cybersecurity and market failures at major digital asset exchanges and trading platforms have resulted in billions of dollars in losses.&nbsp; The United States should ensure that safeguards are in place and promote the responsible development of digital assets to protect consumers, investors, and businesses; maintain privacy; and shield against arbitrary or unlawful surveillance, which can contribute to human rights abuses.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;We must protect United States and global financial stability and mitigate systemic risk.&nbsp; Some digital asset trading platforms and service providers have grown rapidly in size and complexity and may not be subject to or in compliance with appropriate regulations or supervision. &nbsp;Digital asset issuers, exchanges and trading platforms, and intermediaries whose activities may increase risks to financial stability, should, as appropriate, be subject to and in compliance with regulatory and supervisory standards that govern traditional market infrastructures and financial firms, in line with the general principle of &#8220;same business, same risks, same rules.&#8221; &nbsp;The new and unique uses and functions that digital assets can facilitate may create additional economic and financial risks requiring an evolution to a regulatory approach that adequately addresses those risks.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;We must mitigate the illicit finance and national security risks posed by misuse of digital assets.&nbsp; Digital assets may pose significant illicit finance risks, including money laundering, cybercrime and ransomware, narcotics and human trafficking, and terrorism and proliferation financing. &nbsp;Digital assets may also be used as a tool to circumvent United States and foreign financial sanctions regimes and other tools and authorities.&nbsp; Further, while the United States has been a leader in setting international standards for the regulation and supervision of digital assets for anti‑money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism (AML/CFT), poor or nonexistent implementation of those standards in some jurisdictions abroad can present significant illicit financing risks for the United States and global financial systems.&nbsp; Illicit actors, including the perpetrators of ransomware incidents and other cybercrime, often launder and cash out of their illicit proceeds using digital asset service providers in jurisdictions that have not yet effectively implemented the international standards set by the inter-governmental Financial Action Task Force (FATF). &nbsp;The continued availability of service providers in jurisdictions where international AML/CFT standards are not effectively implemented enables financial activity without illicit finance controls. &nbsp;Growth in decentralized financial ecosystems, peer-to-peer payment activity, and obscured blockchain ledgers without controls to mitigate illicit finance could also present additional market and national security risks in the future. &nbsp;The United States must ensure appropriate controls and accountability for current and future digital assets systems to promote high standards for transparency, privacy, and security &#8212; including through regulatory, governance, and technological measures &#8212; that counter illicit activities and preserve or enhance the efficacy of our national security tools.&nbsp; When digital assets are abused or used in illicit ways, or undermine national security, it is in the national interest to take actions to mitigate these illicit finance and national security risks through regulation, oversight, law enforcement action, or use of other United States Government authorities.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;We must reinforce United States leadership in the global financial system and in technological and economic competitiveness, including through the responsible development of payment innovations and digital assets.&nbsp; The United&nbsp;States has an interest in ensuring that it remains at the forefront of responsible development and design of digital assets and the technology that underpins new forms of payments and capital flows in the international financial system, particularly in setting standards that promote: &nbsp;democratic values; the rule of law; privacy; the protection of consumers, investors, and businesses; and interoperability with digital platforms, legacy architecture, and international payment systems. &nbsp;The United States derives significant economic and national security benefits from the central role that the United States dollar and United States financial institutions and markets play in the global financial system.&nbsp; Continued United States leadership in the global financial system will sustain United States financial power and promote United States economic interests.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;We must promote access to safe and affordable financial services.&nbsp; Many Americans are underbanked and the costs of cross-border money transfers and payments are high. &nbsp;The United States has a strong interest in promoting responsible innovation that expands equitable access to financial services, particularly for those Americans underserved by the traditional banking system, including by making investments and domestic and cross-border funds transfers and payments cheaper, faster, and safer, and by promoting greater and more cost-efficient access to financial products and services. &nbsp;The United States also has an interest in ensuring that the benefits of financial innovation are enjoyed equitably by all Americans and that any disparate impacts of financial innovation are mitigated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;We must support technological advances that promote responsible development and use of digital assets.&nbsp; The technological architecture of different digital assets has substantial implications for privacy, national security, the operational security and resilience of financial systems, climate change, the ability to exercise human rights, and other national goals.&nbsp; The United States has an interest in ensuring that digital asset technologies and the digital payments ecosystem are developed, designed, and implemented in a responsible manner that includes privacy and security in their architecture, integrates features and controls that defend against illicit exploitation, and reduces negative climate impacts and environmental pollution, as may result from some cryptocurrency mining.<br><br>Sec. 3.&nbsp; Coordination.&nbsp; The Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (APNSA) and the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy (APEP) shall coordinate, through the interagency process described in National Security Memorandum 2 of February 4, 2021 (Renewing the National Security Council System), the executive branch actions necessary to implement this order.&nbsp; The interagency process shall include, as appropriate: &nbsp;the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Domestic Policy Council, the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, the Director of the National Science Foundation, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.&nbsp; Representatives of other executive departments and agencies (agencies) and other senior officials may be invited to attend interagency meetings as appropriate, including, with due respect for their regulatory independence, representatives of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, and other Federal regulatory agencies.<br><br>Sec. 4.&nbsp; Policy and Actions Related to United States Central Bank Digital Currencies.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The policy of my Administration on a United States CBDC is as follows:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sovereign money is at the core of a well-functioning financial system, macroeconomic stabilization policies, and economic growth.&nbsp; My Administration places the highest urgency on research and development efforts into the potential design and deployment options of a United States CBDC. &nbsp;These efforts should include assessments of possible benefits and risks for consumers, investors, and businesses; financial stability and systemic risk; payment systems; national security; the ability to exercise human rights; financial inclusion and equity; and the actions required to launch a United States CBDC if doing so is deemed to be in the national interest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;My Administration sees merit in showcasing United States leadership and participation in international fora related to CBDCs and in multi‑country conversations and pilot projects involving CBDCs. &nbsp;Any future dollar payment system should be designed in a way that is consistent with United States priorities (as outlined in section 4(a)(i) of this order) and democratic values, including privacy protections, and that ensures the global financial system has appropriate transparency, connectivity, and platform and architecture interoperability or transferability, as appropriate.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;A United States CBDC may have the potential to support efficient and low-cost transactions, particularly for cross‑border funds transfers and payments, and to foster greater access to the financial system, with fewer of the risks posed by private sector-administered digital assets.&nbsp; A United States CBDC that is interoperable with CBDCs issued by other monetary authorities could facilitate faster and lower-cost cross-border payments and potentially boost economic growth, support the continued centrality of the United States within the international financial system, and help to protect the unique role that the dollar plays in global finance. &nbsp;There are also, however, potential risks and downsides to consider. &nbsp;We should prioritize timely assessments of potential benefits and risks under various designs to ensure that the United&nbsp;States remains a leader in the international financial system.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall submit to the President a report on the future of money and payment systems, including the conditions that drive broad adoption of digital assets; the extent to which technological innovation may influence these outcomes; and the implications for the United&nbsp;States financial system, the modernization of and changes to payment systems, economic growth, financial inclusion, and national security. &nbsp;This report shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section&nbsp;3 of this order.&nbsp; Based on the potential United States CBDC design options, this report shall include an analysis of:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the potential implications of a United States CBDC, based on the possible design choices, for national interests, including implications for economic growth and stability;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;the potential implications a United States CBDC might have on financial inclusion;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;the potential relationship between a CBDC and private sector-administered digital assets;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;the future of sovereign and privately produced money globally and implications for our financial system and democracy;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the extent to which foreign CBDCs could displace existing currencies and alter the payment system in ways that could undermine United States financial centrality;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;the potential implications for national security and financial crime, including an analysis of illicit financing risks, sanctions risks, other law enforcement and national security interests, and implications for human rights; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(vii) &nbsp;an assessment of the effects that the growth of foreign CBDCs may have on United States interests generally.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;The Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Chairman of the Federal Reserve) is encouraged to continue to research and report on the extent to which CBDCs could improve the efficiency and reduce the costs of existing and future payments systems, to continue to assess the optimal form of a United States CBDC, and to develop a strategic plan for Federal Reserve and broader United&nbsp;States Government action, as appropriate, that evaluates the necessary steps and requirements for the potential implementation and launch of a United States CBDC. &nbsp;The Chairman of the Federal Reserve is also encouraged to evaluate the extent to which a United States CBDC, based on the potential design options, could enhance or impede the ability of monetary policy to function effectively as a critical macroeconomic stabilization tool.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Chairman of the Federal Reserve, shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;within 180 days of the date of this order, provide to the President through the APNSA and APEP an assessment of whether legislative changes would be necessary to issue a United States CBDC, should it be deemed appropriate and in the national interest; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;within 210 days of the date of this order, provide to the President through the APNSA and the APEP a corresponding legislative proposal, based on consideration of the report submitted by the Secretary of the Treasury under section 4(b) of this order and any materials developed by the Chairman of the Federal Reserve consistent with section 4(c) of this order.<br><br>Sec. 5.&nbsp; Measures to Protect Consumers, Investors, and Businesses.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The increased use of digital assets and digital asset exchanges and trading platforms may increase the risks of crimes such as fraud and theft, other statutory and regulatory violations, privacy and data breaches, unfair and abusive acts or practices, and other cyber incidents faced by consumers, investors, and businesses.&nbsp; The rise in use of digital assets, and differences across communities, may also present disparate financial risk to less informed market participants or exacerbate inequities.&nbsp; It is critical to ensure that digital assets do not pose undue risks to consumers, investors, or businesses, and to put in place protections as a part of efforts to expand access to safe and affordable financial services.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Consistent with the goals stated in section 5(a) of this order:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the heads of other relevant agencies, including, as appropriate, the heads of independent regulatory agencies such as the FTC, the SEC, the CFTC, Federal banking agencies, and the CFPB, shall submit to the President a report, or section of the report required by section&nbsp;4 of this order, on the implications of developments and adoption of digital assets and changes in financial market and payment system infrastructures for United States consumers, investors, businesses, and for equitable economic growth.&nbsp; One section of the report shall address the conditions that would drive mass adoption of different types of digital assets and the risks and opportunities such growth might present to United&nbsp;States consumers, investors, and businesses, including a focus on how technological innovation may impact these efforts and with an eye toward those most vulnerable to disparate impacts.&nbsp; The report shall also include policy recommendations, including potential regulatory and legislative actions, as appropriate, to protect United States consumers, investors, and businesses, and support expanding access to safe and affordable financial services.&nbsp; The report shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Chief Technology Officer of the United&nbsp;States, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Chairman of the Federal Reserve, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall submit to the President a technical evaluation of the technological infrastructure, capacity, and expertise that would be necessary at relevant agencies to facilitate and support the introduction of a CBDC system should one be proposed.&nbsp; The evaluation should specifically address the technical risks of the various designs, including with respect to emerging and future technological developments, such as quantum computing.&nbsp; The evaluation should also include any reflections or recommendations on how the inclusion of digital assets in Federal processes may affect the work of the United&nbsp;States&nbsp;Government and the provision of Government services, including risks and benefits to cybersecurity, customer experience, and social‑safety‑net programs.&nbsp; The evaluation shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii)&nbsp; &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the President a report on the role of law enforcement agencies in detecting, investigating, and prosecuting criminal activity related to digital assets.&nbsp; The report shall include any recommendations on regulatory or legislative actions, as appropriate.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;The Attorney General, the Chair of the FTC, and the Director of the CFPB are each encouraged to consider what, if any, effects the growth of digital assets could have on competition policy.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Chair of the FTC and the Director of the CFPB are each encouraged to consider the extent to which privacy or consumer protection measures within their respective jurisdictions may be used to protect users of digital assets and whether additional measures may be needed.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(vi)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;The Chair of the SEC, the Chairman of the CFTC, the Chairman of the Federal Reserve, the Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Comptroller of the Currency are each encouraged to consider the extent to which investor and market protection measures within their respective jurisdictions may be used to address the risks of digital assets and whether additional measures may be needed.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(vii)&nbsp; &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, the Assistant to the President and National Climate Advisor, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall submit a report to the President on the connections between distributed ledger technology and short-, medium-, and long-term economic and energy transitions; the potential for these technologies to impede or advance efforts to tackle climate change at home and abroad; and the impacts these technologies have on the environment.&nbsp; This report shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.&nbsp; The report should also address the effect of cryptocurrencies&#8217; consensus mechanisms on energy usage, including research into potential mitigating measures and alternative mechanisms of consensus and the design tradeoffs those may entail.&nbsp; The report should specifically address:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(A)&nbsp; potential uses of blockchain that could support monitoring or mitigating technologies to climate impacts, such as exchanging of liabilities for greenhouse gas emissions, water, and other natural or environmental assets; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(B)&nbsp; implications for energy policy, including as it relates to grid management and reliability, energy efficiency incentives and standards, and sources of energy supply.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(viii)&nbsp; Within 1 year of submission of the report described in section 5(b)(vii) of this order, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall update the report described in section&nbsp;5(b)(vii) of this order, including to address any knowledge gaps identified in such report.<br><br>Sec. 6.&nbsp; Actions to Promote Financial Stability, Mitigate Systemic Risk, and Strengthen Market Integrity.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Financial regulators &#8212; including the SEC, the CFTC, and the CFPB and Federal banking agencies &#8212; play critical roles in establishing and overseeing protections across the financial system that safeguard its integrity and promote its stability.&nbsp; Since 2017, the Secretary of the Treasury has convened the Financial Stability Oversight Council (FSOC) to assess the financial stability risks and regulatory gaps posed by the ongoing adoption of digital assets.&nbsp; The United States must assess and take steps to address risks that digital assets pose to financial stability and financial market integrity.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Within 210 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury should convene the FSOC and produce a report outlining the specific financial stability risks and regulatory gaps posed by various types of digital assets and providing recommendations to address such risks. &nbsp;As the Secretary of the Treasury and the FSOC deem appropriate, the report should consider the particular features of various types of digital assets and include recommendations that address the identified financial stability risks posed by these digital assets, including any proposals for additional or adjusted regulation and supervision as well as for new legislation. &nbsp;The report should take account of the prior analyses and assessments of the FSOC, agencies, and the President&#8217;s Working Group on Financial Markets, including the ongoing work of the Federal banking agencies, as appropriate.<br><br>Sec. 7.&nbsp; Actions to Limit Illicit Finance and Associated National Security Risks.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Digital assets have facilitated sophisticated cybercrime‑related financial networks and activity, including through ransomware activity. &nbsp;The growing use of digital assets in financial activity heightens risks of crimes such as money laundering, terrorist and proliferation financing, fraud and theft schemes, and corruption.&nbsp; These illicit activities highlight the need for ongoing scrutiny of the use of digital assets, the extent to which technological innovation may impact such activities, and exploration of opportunities to mitigate these risks through regulation, supervision, public‑private engagement, oversight, and law enforcement.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Within 90 days of submission to the Congress of the National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other relevant agencies may each submit to the President supplemental annexes, which may be classified or unclassified, to the Strategy offering additional views on illicit finance risks posed by digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, stablecoins, CBDCs, and trends in the use of digital assets by illicit actors.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;Within 120 days of submission to the Congress of the National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other relevant agencies shall develop a coordinated action plan based on the Strategy&#8217;s conclusions for mitigating the digital‑asset-related illicit finance and national security risks addressed in the updated strategy.&nbsp; This action plan shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.&nbsp; The action plan shall address the role of law enforcement and measures to increase financial services providers&#8217; compliance with AML/CFT obligations related to digital asset activities.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d)&nbsp; Within 120 days following completion of all of the following reports &#8212; the National Money Laundering Risk Assessment; the National Terrorist Financing Risk Assessment; the National Proliferation Financing Risk Assessment; and the updated National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing &#8212; the Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the relevant agencies through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order on any pending, proposed, or prospective rulemakings to address digital asset illicit finance risks.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury shall consult with and consider the perspectives of relevant agencies in evaluating opportunities to mitigate such risks through regulation.<br><br>Sec. 8.&nbsp; Policy and Actions Related to Fostering International Cooperation and United States Competitiveness.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The policy of my Administration on fostering international cooperation and United States competitiveness with respect to digital assets and financial innovation is as follows:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Technology-driven financial innovation is frequently cross-border and therefore requires international cooperation among public authorities. &nbsp;This cooperation is critical to maintaining high regulatory standards and a level playing field. &nbsp;Uneven regulation, supervision, and compliance across jurisdictions creates opportunities for arbitrage and raises risks to financial stability and the protection of consumers, investors, businesses, and markets. &nbsp;Inadequate AML/CFT regulation, supervision, and enforcement by other countries challenges the ability of the United States to investigate illicit digital asset transaction flows that frequently jump overseas, as is often the case in ransomware payments and other cybercrime-related money laundering.&nbsp; There must also be cooperation to reduce inefficiencies in international funds transfer and payment systems.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;The United States Government has been active in international fora and through bilateral partnerships on many of these issues and has a robust agenda to continue this work in the coming years. &nbsp;While the United States held the position of President of the FATF, the United&nbsp;States led the group in developing and adopting the first international standards on digital assets. &nbsp;The United States must continue to work with international partners on standards for the development and appropriate interoperability of digital payment architectures and CBDCs to reduce payment inefficiencies and ensure that any new funds transfer and payment systems are consistent with United States values and legal requirements.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;While the United States held the position of President of the 2020 G7, the United&nbsp;States established the G7 Digital Payments Experts Group to discuss CBDCs, stablecoins, and other digital payment issues.&nbsp; The G7 report outlining a set of policy principles for CBDCs is an important contribution to establishing guidelines for jurisdictions for the exploration and potential development of CBDCs. &nbsp;While a CBDC would be issued by a country&#8217;s central bank, the supporting infrastructure could involve both public and private participants. &nbsp;The G7 report highlighted that any CBDC should be grounded in the G7&#8217;s long-standing public commitments to transparency, the rule of law, and sound economic governance, as well as the promotion of competition and innovation.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;The United States continues to support the G20 roadmap for addressing challenges and frictions with cross-border funds transfers and payments for which work is underway, including work on improvements to existing systems for cross-border funds transfers and payments, the international dimensions of CBDC designs, and the potential of well-regulated stablecoin arrangements.&nbsp; The international Financial Stability Board (FSB), together with standard-setting bodies, is leading work on issues related to stablecoins, cross‑border funds transfers and payments, and other international dimensions of digital assets and payments, while FATF continues its leadership in setting AML/CFT standards for digital assets. &nbsp;Such international work should continue to address the full spectrum of issues and challenges raised by digital assets, including financial stability, consumer, investor, and business risks, and money laundering, terrorist financing, proliferation financing, sanctions evasion, and other illicit activities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;My Administration will elevate the importance of these topics and expand engagement with our critical international partners, including through fora such as the G7, G20, FATF, and FSB. &nbsp;My Administration will support the ongoing international work and, where appropriate, push for additional work to drive development and implementation of holistic standards, cooperation and coordination, and information sharing.&nbsp; With respect to digital assets, my Administration will seek to ensure that our core democratic values are respected; consumers, investors, and businesses are protected; appropriate global financial system connectivity and platform and architecture interoperability are preserved; and the safety and soundness of the global financial system and international monetary system are maintained.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) In furtherance of the policy stated in section 8(a) of this order:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 120 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall establish a framework for interagency international engagement with foreign counterparts and in international fora to, as appropriate, adapt, update, and enhance adoption of global principles and standards for how digital assets are used and transacted, and to promote development of digital asset and CBDC technologies consistent with our values and legal requirements.&nbsp; This framework shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.&nbsp; This framework shall include specific and prioritized lines of effort and coordinated messaging; interagency engagement and activities with foreign partners, such as foreign assistance and capacity-building efforts and coordination of global compliance; and whole‑of‑government efforts to promote international principles, standards, and best practices.&nbsp; This framework should reflect ongoing leadership by the Secretary of the Treasury and financial regulators in relevant international financial standards bodies, and should elevate United States engagement on digital assets issues in technical standards bodies and other international fora to promote development of digital asset and CBDC technologies consistent with our values.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 1 year of the date of the establishment of the framework required by section 8(b)(i) of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the heads of other relevant agencies as appropriate, shall submit a report to the President on priority actions taken under the framework and its effectiveness. &nbsp;This report shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall establish a framework for enhancing United States economic competitiveness in, and leveraging of, digital asset technologies.&nbsp; This framework shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 90 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit a report to the President on how to strengthen international law enforcement cooperation for detecting, investigating, and prosecuting criminal activity related to digital assets.<br><br>Sec. 9.&nbsp; Definitions.&nbsp; For the purposes of this order:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; The term &#8220;blockchain&#8221; refers to distributed ledger technologies where data is shared across a network that creates a digital ledger of verified transactions or information among network participants and the data are typically linked using cryptography to maintain the integrity of the ledger and execute other functions, including transfer of ownership or value.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The term &#8220;central bank digital currency&#8221; or &#8220;CBDC&#8221; refers to a form of digital money or monetary value, denominated in the national unit of account, that is a direct liability of the central bank.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c)&nbsp; The term &#8220;cryptocurrencies&#8221; refers to a digital asset, which may be a medium of exchange, for which generation or ownership records are supported through a distributed ledger technology that relies on cryptography, such as a blockchain.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d)&nbsp; The term &#8220;digital assets&#8221; refers to all CBDCs, regardless of the technology used, and to other representations of value, financial assets and instruments, or claims that are used to make payments or investments, or to transmit or exchange funds or the equivalent thereof, that are issued or represented in digital form through the use of distributed ledger technology.&nbsp; For example, digital assets include cryptocurrencies, stablecoins, and CBDCs. &nbsp;Regardless of the label used, a digital asset may be, among other things, a security, a commodity, a derivative, or other financial product.&nbsp; Digital assets may be exchanged across digital asset trading platforms, including centralized and decentralized finance platforms, or through peer-to-peer technologies.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e)&nbsp; The term &#8220;stablecoins&#8221; refers to a category of cryptocurrencies with mechanisms that are aimed at maintaining a stable value, such as by pegging the value of the coin to a specific currency, asset, or pool of assets or by algorithmically controlling supply in response to changes in demand in order to stabilize value.<br><br>Sec. 10.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>March 9, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NEC Director Brian Deese and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on New Digital Assets Executive&#160;Order</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/statement-by-nec-director-brian-deese-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-new-digital-assets-executive-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to establish the first-ever comprehensive federal digital assets strategy for the United States. The E.O. will help position the U.S. to keep playing a leading role in the innovation and governance of the digital assets ecosystem at home and abroad, in a way that protects consumers, is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to establish the first-ever comprehensive federal digital assets strategy for the United States. The E.O. will help position the U.S. to keep playing a leading role in the innovation and governance of the digital assets ecosystem at home and abroad, in a way that protects consumers, is consistent with our democratic values and advances U.S. global competitiveness.</p>



<p>This E.O. marks an intensification of our efforts to promote responsible innovation in the digital assets space – innovation that works for all Americans, protects our national security interests, and contributes to our economic competitiveness and growth. Fundamentally, an American approach to digital assets is one that encourages innovation but mitigates the risks to consumers, investors, and businesses, broader financial stability, and the environment. We are clear-eyed that “financial innovation” of the past has too often not benefited working families, while exacerbating inequality and increasing systemic financial risk. This history underscores the need to build robust consumer and economic protections into digital asset development.</p>



<p>The approach outlined in the E.O. will reinforce U.S. leadership in the global financial system and safeguard the long-term efficacy of critical national security tools like sanctions and anti-money laundering frameworks. To these ends, the Order identifies the Administration’s policy priorities, both for cryptocurrencies and any future U.S. central bank digital currency, to help guide the evolution of the digital asset ecosystem in a way that is consistent with our values. Governments alone cannot solve these problems, and definitely not a government that operates in siloes. This E.O. is the product of months of work with stakeholders across government, industry, advocacy, academia, and international allies and partners – to identify actions we can take to foster responsible innovation in the digital asset ecosystem. Its implementation will leverage the knowledge and distinct expertise of a broad range of stakeholders across the White House and Executive departments and agencies, and regulatory agencies. We remain committed to working with allies, partners, and the broader digital asset community to shape the future of digital asset systems in a manner that is safe, inclusive, and consistent with our democratic values. As this ecosystem evolves, so too will our approach.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Sign Executive Order on Ensuring Responsible Development of Digital&#160;Assets</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-sign-executive-order-on-ensuring-responsible-innovation-in-digital-assets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Outlines First Whole-of-Government Strategy to Protect Consumers, Financial Stability, National Security, and Address Climate Risks Digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, have seen explosive growth in recent years, surpassing a $3 trillion market cap last November and up from $14 billion just five years prior. Surveys suggest that around 16 percent of adult Americans – approximately 40&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Outlines First Whole-of-Government Strategy to Protect Consumers, Financial Stability, National Security, and Address Climate Risks</em></p>



<p>Digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, have seen explosive growth in recent years, surpassing a <a href="https://time.com/6115300/cryptocurrency-value-3-trillion/">$3 trillion</a> market cap last November and up from $14 billion just five years prior. Surveys suggest that around 16 percent of adult Americans – approximately 40 million people – have invested in, traded, or used cryptocurrencies. Over 100 countries are exploring or piloting Central Bank Digital Currencies (CBDCs), a digital form of a country’s sovereign currency.<br><br>The rise in digital assets creates an opportunity to reinforce American leadership in the global financial system and at the technological frontier, but also has substantial implications for consumer protection, financial stability, national security, and climate risk. The United States must maintain technological leadership in this rapidly growing space, supporting innovation while mitigating the risks for consumers, businesses, the broader financial system, and the climate. And, it must play a leading role in international engagement and global governance of digital assets consistent with democratic values and U.S. global competitiveness.<br><br>That is why today, President Biden will sign an Executive Order outlining the first ever, whole-of-government approach to addressing the risks and harnessing the potential benefits of digital assets and their underlying technology. The Order lays out a national policy for digital assets across six key priorities: consumer and investor protection; financial stability; illicit finance; U.S. leadership in the global financial system and economic competitiveness; financial inclusion; and responsible innovation.</p>



<p>Specifically, the Executive Order calls for measures to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect U.S. Consumers, Investors, and Businesses </strong>by directing the Department of the Treasury and other agency partners to assess and develop policy recommendations to address the implications of the growing digital asset sector and changes in financial markets for consumers, investors, businesses, and equitable economic growth. The Order also encourages regulators to ensure sufficient oversight and safeguard against any systemic financial risks posed by digital assets.<br></li><li><strong>Protect U.S. and Global Financial Stability and Mitigate Systemic Risk </strong>by encouraging the Financial Stability Oversight Council to identify and mitigate economy-wide (i.e., systemic) financial risks posed by digital assets and to develop appropriate policy recommendations to address any regulatory gaps.<br></li><li><strong>Mitigate the Illicit Finance and National Security Risks Posed by the Illicit Use of Digital Assets </strong>by directing an unprecedented focus of coordinated action across all relevant U.S. Government agencies to mitigate these risks. It also directs agencies to work with our allies and partners to ensure international frameworks, capabilities, and partnerships are aligned and responsive to risks.<br></li><li><strong>Promote U.S. Leadership in Technology and Economic Competitiveness to Reinforce U.S. Leadership in the Global Financial System </strong>by directing the Department of Commerce to work across the U.S. Government in establishing a framework to drive U.S. competitiveness and leadership in, and leveraging of digital asset technologies. This framework will serve as a foundation for agencies and integrate this as a priority into their policy, research and development, and operational approaches to digital assets.<br></li><li><strong>Promote Equitable Access to Safe and Affordable Financial Services </strong>by affirming the critical need for safe, affordable, and accessible financial services as a U.S. national interest that must inform our approach to digital asset innovation, including disparate impact risk. Such safe access is especially important for communities that have long had insufficient access to financial services.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury, working with all relevant agencies, will produce a report on the future of money and payment systems, to include implications for economic growth, financial growth and inclusion, national security, and the extent to which technological innovation may influence that future.<br></li><li><strong>Support Technological Advances and Ensure Responsible Development and Use of Digital Assets </strong>by directing the U.S. Government to take concrete steps to study and support technological advances in the responsible development, design, and implementation of digital asset systems while prioritizing privacy, security, combating illicit exploitation, and reducing negative climate impacts.<br></li><li><strong>Explore a U.S. Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC) </strong>by placing urgency on research and development of a potential United States CBDC, should issuance be deemed in the national interest. The Order directs the U.S. Government to assess the technological infrastructure and capacity needs for a potential U.S. CBDC in a manner that protects Americans’ interests. The Order also encourages the Federal Reserve to continue its research, development, and assessment efforts for a U.S. CBDC, including development of a plan for broader U.S. Government action in support of their work. This effort prioritizes U.S. participation in multi-country experimentation, and ensures U.S. leadership internationally to promote CBDC development that is consistent with U.S. priorities and democratic values.</li></ul>



<p>The Administration will continue work across agencies and with Congress to establish policies that guard against risks and guide responsible innovation, with our allies and partners to develop aligned international capabilities that respond to national security risks, and with the private sector to study and support technological advances in digital assets.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
