<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 15:39:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Applications to NATO by Finland and&#160;Sweden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-applications-to-nato-by-finland-and-sweden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 15:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I warmly welcome and strongly support the historic applications from Finland and Sweden for membership in NATO and look forward to working with the U.S. Congress and our NATO Allies to quickly bring Finland and Sweden into the strongest defensive alliance in history. Sweden and Finland have made the important decision to seek NATO membership&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I warmly welcome and strongly support the historic applications from Finland and Sweden for membership in NATO and look forward to working with the U.S. Congress and our NATO Allies to quickly bring Finland and Sweden into the strongest defensive alliance in history.</p>



<p>Sweden and Finland have made the important decision to seek NATO membership after thorough and inclusive democratic processes in each country. NATO guarantees the security of one billion people in Europe and North America—united by our shared commitment to democratic principles and our vision of peace and prosperity in Europe and around the world. And my commitment to NATO and Article 5 is ironclad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finland and Sweden are longtime, stalwart partners of the United States. By joining NATO, they will further strengthen our defense cooperation and benefit the entire Transatlantic Alliance. Together with our NATO Allies, the United States will maintain its robust exercise activity and presence in the Baltic Sea region. While their applications for NATO membership are being considered, the United States will work with Finland and Sweden to remain vigilant against any threats to our shared security, and to deter and confront aggression or the threat of aggression.</p>



<p>I look forward to welcoming President of Finland Sauli Niinistö and Prime Minister of Sweden Magdalena Andersson to Washington tomorrow so that we can further consult on their NATO applications and European security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Phone Call with Politburo Member Yang&#160;Jiechi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-phone-call-with-politburo-member-yang-jiechi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 14:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi by phone. This phone call, which followed their March 14 meeting in Rome, focused on regional security issues and nonproliferation. Mr. Sullivan and Director Yang also discussed Russia’s war against&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><br>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi by phone. This phone call, which followed their March 14 meeting in Rome, focused on regional security issues and nonproliferation. Mr. Sullivan and Director Yang also discussed Russia’s war against Ukraine and specific issues in U.S.-China relations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Kosovo Prime Minister Albin&#160;Kurti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/statement-from-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-kosovo-prime-minister-albin-kurti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Prime Minister Albin Kurti of Kosovo. Mr. Sullivan thanked the Prime Minister for Kosovo’s willingness to host Afghan evacuees. They exchanged views on Russia’s military aggression against Ukraine, including Kosovo’s provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine and imposition of sanctions against Russia. They also&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Prime Minister Albin Kurti of Kosovo. Mr. Sullivan thanked the Prime Minister for Kosovo’s willingness to host Afghan evacuees. They exchanged views on Russia’s military aggression against Ukraine, including Kosovo’s provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine and imposition of sanctions against Russia. They also discussed stability in the Western Balkans, with Mr. Sullivan expressing U.S. support for the EU-facilitated Dialogue to reach a comprehensive normalization agreement between Kosovo and Serbia and the need for further progress on key outstanding issues. Mr. Sullivan welcomed plans by Kosovo to transition away from its dependence on lignite coal to cleaner energy and to ensure a stable supply of electricity. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan&#160;Grisham</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-new-mexico-governor-michelle-lujan-grisham/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 02:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden called New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham today to discuss the wildfires that have burned hundreds of thousands of acres across the State, resulted in the evacuation of tens of thousands, and destroyed hundreds of homes.  Governor Lujan Grisham underscored the impacts of the fires on New Mexico communities and the need for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden called New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham today to discuss the wildfires that have burned hundreds of thousands of acres across the State, resulted in the evacuation of tens of thousands, and destroyed hundreds of homes.  Governor Lujan Grisham underscored the impacts of the fires on New Mexico communities and the need for ongoing partnership with the Federal Government as New Mexico recovers and rebuilds from some of the most devastating wildfires on record in the State.  The President reaffirmed that the people of New Mexico will have the full support of the Federal Government, and that every effort will be made to provide immediate help to people in the impacted communities and support the State throughout its recovery.  The President expressed his gratitude to all of the first responders, firefighters, and other federal, state, and local personnel who are battling the blazes and have come to the aid of those who have been impacted by the fires.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden call with President Guillermo Lasso of the Republic of&#160;Ecuador</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/readout-of-president-biden-call-with-president-guillermo-lasso-of-the-republic-of-ecuador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 02:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke today with President Guillermo Lasso of the Republic of Ecuador to discuss their vision for the Americas ahead of the Summit of the Americas and the importance of the U.S.-Ecuador relationship.  They discussed strengthening economic, security, and migration cooperation.  President Biden and President Lasso also discussed COVID-19 pandemic response and recovery and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke today with President Guillermo Lasso of the Republic of Ecuador to discuss their vision for the Americas ahead of the Summit of the Americas and the importance of the U.S.-Ecuador relationship.  They discussed strengthening economic, security, and migration cooperation.  President Biden and President Lasso also discussed COVID-19 pandemic response and recovery and supporting regional priorities.  The leaders committed to upholding democratic values and advancing the Summit of the Americas objectives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid&#160;bin Salman </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-saudi-vice-minister-of-defense-khalid-bin-salman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 01:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud.  They underscored the longstanding partnership between our two nations, as exemplified by the U.S.-Saudi Arabia Strategic Joint Planning Committee, which the Vice Minister is co-chairing this week at the Department of Defense.  Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s commitment&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud.  They underscored the longstanding partnership between our two nations, as exemplified by the U.S.-Saudi Arabia Strategic Joint Planning Committee, which the Vice Minister is co-chairing this week at the Department of Defense.  Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s commitment to help Saudi Arabia defend its territory, and expressed appreciation for Saudi Arabia’s leadership in securing a UN-brokered truce in Yemen.  They also discussed the importance of coordinating efforts to ensure global economic resilience.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris at a Reception to Celebrate AANHPI Heritage&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/17/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-a-reception-to-celebrate-aanhpi-heritage-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 22:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 4:23 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Ambassador Tai.&#160; It is true, there is something we all know: that we must always honor the mothers, the aunties, the chithis, all of them.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And, of course, the husbands and the fathers and the grandfathers.&#160; (Laughter.) It is good to be with everyone.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>4:23 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Ambassador Tai.&nbsp; It is true, there is something we all know: that we must always honor the mothers, the aunties, the <em>chithis</em>, all of them.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And, of course, the husbands and the fathers and the grandfathers.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>It is good to be with everyone.&nbsp; I think this is, Mr. President, one of the biggest groups that we&#8217;ve had since we&#8217;ve been in office, and it&#8217;s quite a beautiful sight to see.</p>



<p>So good afternoon to everyone.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>And as you all know, my mother arrived in the United States at the age of 19, from India.&nbsp; And when I think about the work that we are all doing, the work we are doing as an administration, led by our President, in terms of not only living the values but standing on the shoulders of so many who imagined that we would all be here and who know that when we talk about the beauty of who we are as a nation, as the United States of America, it is represented by all of the people who are here today and all those who are proud that we stand here today together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Joe Biden, Dr. Jill Biden, Mr. Second Gentleman &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and members of our Cabinet, it is good again to be gathered with all of you today and to be joined by the members of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a former member of the caucus, I will take a few moments to talk about a friend to so many of us, a mentor to so many of us, one who helped found CAPAC and became its first chair.&nbsp; And, of course, I&#8217;m talking about the amazing Secretary Norman Mineta, who devoted his career to public service.</p>



<p>For all of those who knew Norm, he worked tirelessly to make our nation stronger, safer, and more just.&nbsp; And in so doing, he inspired a generation of leaders, including me.</p>



<p>Secretary Mineta’s family is here with us today.&nbsp; And from my family to yours, please know that he is deeply missed.</p>



<p>Today, yes, it is a great celebration for so many reasons of so many things.&nbsp; But it is also impossible to ignore that we gather mere days after a horrific act of hate in Buffalo, New York, targeting Black Americans.</p>



<p>And, you know, it was only last year, as the Ambassador said &#8212; only last year that we &#8212; that I was with the President in Atlanta, mourning the murder of eight people, including six who were Asian American women.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, sadly, what I said then remains true now: Racism is real in America. &nbsp;It has always been.&nbsp; Xenophobia is real in America. &nbsp;It has always been.&nbsp; Sexism too.</p>



<p>I said last year and I sadly say again today: We have had people in positions of incredible power in our country scapegoating, people with the biggest pulpits spreading this kind of hate.</p>



<p>This requires &#8212; these moments &#8212; sadly, tragically require us to ask, “Who are we as a nation?&nbsp; And what do we stand for?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is yet again a moment to remember and talk about and reflect on how we treat people and do we live to the greatest and best of our ideals, which means treating people &#8212; all people &#8212; with dignity and respect, remembering the history of our nation and who built our nation and honoring the diversity of all who have contributed to who we are today.</p>



<p>And, of course, that is what this month requires us to do.&nbsp; And I know, looking around at the leaders here, we remember it every day of the year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we also know in tragic moments like this that we are committed collectively to saying: A harm against any one of us, is a harm against all of us, and it is all harm against our nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the President and I, and all of us as leaders, will not be silent.&nbsp; We will not stand by.&nbsp; We must always speak out against violence, against hate crime and discrimination, whenever and wherever it occurs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we must do everything in our power to end this epidemic of hate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We feel great pride, based on good reason and fact and history, in what we celebrate today.&nbsp; And we know that those who allowed us to be here, and paved the path for us to be present at this moment, expect great things from us, including that we are not only clear-eyed but that we are optimistic about our future &#8212; collectively about our future as a nation.&nbsp; That we remain committed to the ideals that make this nation great.&nbsp; That we remain committed to the notion that a harm against any one of us is a harm against all of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that is an extension of a most profound belief, which is that we are in this together as one nation undivided.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So today we celebrate all those ideals when we celebrate the great people of this nation who have paved a path for so many of us to be where we are today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, finally, to quote then a great American, Norm Mineta &#8212; I quote: “If we will act together, then we are strong enough to withstand any evil, internal or external, that threatens to unravel” &#8212; and this is key &#8212; “this beautiful tapestry that is America.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now it is my great honor to introduce a man who ran for President because he knows that no one should be in this fight alone: President Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You’ve got to admit, I have got good taste in picking people, don’t you?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Way above my pay grade.</p>



<p>Kamala, thank you, and Ambassador Tai; and Doug, the Second Gentleman, out there hiding behind everybody out there, I know. (Laughter).&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, Jill and I are honored to welcome all of you here to celebrate the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, Pacific Islander Heritage Month here in the Rose Garden.</p>



<p>You know, it’s wonderful to see so many friends: U.S. Senator Mazie Hirono.&nbsp; Where &#8212; where’s Mazie?&nbsp; I see &#8212; was told she’s here.&nbsp; I’m looking.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;Mazie, wherever you are, you’re the best.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Tammy Duckworth.&nbsp; Tammy &#8212; Tammy is here, I’m told.&nbsp; Or &#8212; (applause) &#8212; going to be here.&nbsp; No?&nbsp; Any rate &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the Chair of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, Representative Judy Chu, is here as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there’s several other representatives here today who represent the community in Congress that is growing each election.</p>



<p>As Katherine mentioned, I’m proud to have re-established</p>



<p>the White House Initiative on Asian American, Native Ameri- &#8212; Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islanders.&nbsp; Several members are here today along with members of the community across the administration at every level.</p>



<p>Also joining are mayors and local leaders, and leaders of business and philanthropy, leaders of civil rights, the arts, the fashions and culture.</p>



<p>And this is a reception that follows on the &#8212; the great honor Jill and I, Kamala and Doug had in hosting Team USA, including the Amer- &#8212; the Asian American athletes who so honorably represented America in the Olympics.</p>



<p>Not too long ago, that included one of the most decorated &#8212; the most decorated figure skater in U.S. history &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and also worked on my campaign &#8212; also worked on my campaign and is now my nominee to be Ambassador to Belize: Michelle Kwan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Michelle, you’re the best, kid.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You’re the best.&nbsp; You do things backward better than most people can do them forward.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you represent a simple truth: There is no single Asian Am- &#8212; as Jill pointed out much more articulately than I have &#8212; there is no single Asian American, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander identity.&nbsp; It doesn’t exist.&nbsp; The diversity of cultures, the breadth and achievement that has shaded and shaped so many, strengthened the fabric of this country in ways that you can’t measure.&nbsp; I don’t think &#8212; I don’t know how you can measure it.</p>



<p>The fastest-growing demographic in the United States that has also gotten us through the pandemic as frontline and essential workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you have powered our economic recovery: An unemployment rate in a community that’s fallen from 6.6 percent since we got in office to 3.1 percent &#8212; for Asian Americans.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Entrepreneurship in the community has risen &#8212; with you all, it’s risen the fastest rate in over a decade.</p>



<p>Where members of the community were once tokenized as villains on the movie screens, you now light them up as superheroes.</p>



<p>And today, I’ll be traveling &#8212; on Thursday, excuse me, I’ll be traveling to the Republic of Korea and Japan to affirm the importance of our Indo-Pacific alliances.&nbsp; Folks &#8212; and to celebrate the indispensable partnerships that are strengthening by the deep family ties and heritage and the values reflected in the AAN- &#8212; NH &#8212; PI &#8212; aye, aye, aye, aye, aye &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; community here in the United States.&nbsp; As they say in Claymont, Delaware, “All youse guys.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But, look, we know that for the generations of progress, racism, harassment, and hate crimes persist, as was pointed out by my friends behind me.&nbsp; And today we know that maybe you are one of them who don’t feel safe walking American streets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A shooting near Atlanta a year ago is still fresh, as been mentioned, in the hearts of so many.&nbsp; And Kamala and I went to vi- &#8212; down to visit.&nbsp; Just as we’ve seen hate crime shootings in Orange County, California; Dallas, Texas, just last week.</p>



<p>Jill and I just got back from Buffalo &#8212; Buffalo, New York &#8212; where another lone gunman with a hate-filled soul shot and killed Black people at a grocery store on a Saturday afternoon.</p>



<p>You know, I probably shouldn’t be saying this now, but I’m going to say it anyway: We have to not only talk about how we’re going to end the hate, but who’s responsible for generating it.&nbsp; Who is responsible for generating it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I’ve said many times: Hate can have no safe harbor in America.&nbsp; And every person deserves to be treated with dignity and respect.</p>



<p>But, you know, you have folks on television stations talking about the “replacement theory,” scaring the living hell out of people who don’t have a whole lot of emotional stability, taking advantage of &#8212; on the Internet and other means by talking about how we’re going to be “overtaken.”<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why, one year ago, with the help of many of you, I signed into law the bipartisan COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act.&nbsp; And with your continued help &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, with your continued help &#8212; our commitment to advance equality across the board in everything from healthcare, to education, to housing, to LGBTQ rights.</p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;re working to fix our immigration system to reflect our values and the truth that legal immigration defines who we are as a nation &#8212; who we are as a nation.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so darn strong.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bottom line is we&#8217;re doing the work to make real the promise of America for every American &#8212; a promise that holds that every person is created equal and deserves to be treated equally throughout their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve never fully lived up to that promise, but we&#8217;ve never, ever before walked away from it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never walked away from it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we acknowledge during this month: building a legacy of strength and resilience for people like you and almost all of our forebears.</p>



<p>You know, you were telling the story &#8212; Jill is going to get mad at me for &#8212; it reminded me.&nbsp; I happen to be Irish.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That’s the problem sometimes with Jill.&nbsp; But anyway, I&#8217;m only joking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; That’s not true.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m teasing.&nbsp; But my mother used to always say on birthdays, “The mother should get the gift, not the child.”&nbsp; So I didn&#8217;t realize it was both Asian and Irish &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; at least in my house.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And speaking of friends, the late Norm Mineta, whom Kamala just spoke about, was one of my close friends &#8212; for real.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you all know, Norm was born in 1931 in San Jose, California, an immigrant &#8212; to immigrant parents from Japan.&nbsp; As an 11-year-old, he spent three years in an incarceration camp, among 120,000 Japanese Americans across the country.</p>



<p>But with every reason to be angry and resentful &#8212; with every reason to be angry and resentful, Norm chose to believe in himself, to believe in America, and to believe in his country.</p>



<p>He served in the United States Army, elected the first Asian American mayor of a major city in his hometown of San Jose.&nbsp; Elected and served two decades as a congressman.&nbsp; We were &#8212; we spent a lot of time together and traveled together, serving with pioneers and dear friends like Danny Inouye and Danny Akaka.&nbsp; They both taught me, by the way, not only about Asian Americans, they taught me that it is “Native Americans,” not “Indian Tribes.”&nbsp; “Native Americans.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Danny was the first guy &#8212; I don’t want to ruin his reputation, God bless his soul &#8212; but Danny was the first guy to convince me to run for president and be my national campaign chairman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then Norm became the first American of Asian descent to serve as a Cabinet Secretary.&nbsp; Norm passed away earlier this month, as we all know.&nbsp; In the days after, I signed a bill into law naming the U.S. Department of Transportation headquarters in his honor.</p>



<p>Today, we’re honored to be joined by two of his sons, David and Bob.&nbsp; Where are you guys?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Come up here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’re a good man &#8212; you’re both good men.&nbsp; Thank you very, very much.&nbsp; And I want to tell you, he was one of hell of a man.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let’s all follow in the power of Norm’s example.</p>



<p>I thank you all for being here, and I want you to enjoy the rest of the reception.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, though: This fight that we’re &#8212; for equality, we&#8217;re just starting here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just the wackos who go out there with those guns and get talked into doing something.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the people who fill their brains with false ideas.&nbsp; It’s the people who make them &#8212; convince them, for their power and their prestige and their money, to be able to go out and do these terrible things.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not who we are.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not who we are.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll be darned, as long as I&#8217;m President of the United States, I&#8217;m going to fight like hell, and we&#8217;re going to expose everybody.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to make sure that this &#8212;</p>



<p>And my &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a hymn in my &#8212; based on the 91st Psalm, and it says &#8212; in my church &#8212; “May He raise you up on Eagle&#8217;s wings and Bear you on the breath of dawn, and let the sun shine upon you until…”&nbsp; And then it goes on to talk about that we all &#8212; all &#8212; that God will hold you in the palm of his hand.</p>



<p>That’s how we’ve got to think about our fellow Americans.&nbsp; The reason we are strong, the reason we’re who we are is because we’re diverse with so many talents.&nbsp; So many.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know this group will never forget it.&nbsp; But I’m going to spend the rest of my term and as long I’m in office reminding the rest of America they should understand it too.</p>



<p>God bless you all, and enjoy the night &#8212; the day.&nbsp; And thank you for being here.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;</p>



<p>4:41 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to&#160;the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 21:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Andrew G. Biggs, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2024, vice Lanhee J. Chen, term expired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Stacy Lynn Dean, of the District of Columbia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Andrew G. Biggs, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2024, vice Lanhee J. Chen, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stacy Lynn Dean, of the District of Columbia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services, vice Kevin W. Concannon.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Alexis Taylor, of Iowa, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs, vice Ted McKinney.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calvin Smyre, of Georgia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Commonwealth of The Bahamas.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; David Pressman, of New York, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Hungary.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Heide B. Fulton, of West Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Oriental Republic of Uruguay.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yohannes Abraham, of Virginia, to be Representative of the United States of America to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Alice Hill, of the District of Columbia, to be Deputy Administrator for Resilience, Federal Emergency Management Agency, Department of Homeland Security, vice Daniel J. Kaniewski, which was sent to the Senate on February 7, 2022.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calvin Smyre, of Georgia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Dominican Republic, which was sent to the Senate on October 4, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; William J. Valdez, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security, vice Claire M. Grady, which was sent to the Senate on July 28, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Prime Minister Mitsotakis of&#160;Greece</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-prime-minister-mitsotakis-of-greece/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of Greece following his address to a joint meeting of Congress.  The Vice President offered her congratulations on Greece’s 201 years of independence and reaffirmed the strong alliance between the United States and Greece, as well as our shared commitment to democratic values, international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of Greece following his address to a joint meeting of Congress.  The Vice President offered her congratulations on Greece’s 201 years of independence and reaffirmed the strong alliance between the United States and Greece, as well as our shared commitment to democratic values, international norms, and the rule of law.  She also thanked the Prime Minister for Greece’s robust support to Ukraine and solidarity in the face of Russian aggression and for Greece’s contributions to Europe’s efforts to diversify its energy supplies. The two leaders also discussed security issues in the Eastern Mediterranean and wider Middle East.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and First Lady Biden Honoring the Lives Lost in Buffalo, New York, and Calling on All Americans to Condemn White&#160;Supremacy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/17/remarks-by-president-biden-and-first-lady-biden-honoring-the-lives-lost-in-buffalo-new-york-and-calling-on-all-americans-to-condemn-white-supremacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 20:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Delavan Grider Community CenterBuffalo, New York 12:21 P.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY:&#160; I just wanted to say thank you to the families for opening up your hearts to us and for letting us be with you today.&#160; So God bless you, and thank you for allowing us to be with you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; (Applause.) THE&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Delavan Grider Community Center<br>Buffalo, New York</p>



<p>12:21 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; I just wanted to say thank you to the families for opening up your hearts to us and for letting us be with you today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So God bless you, and thank you for allowing us to be with you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; To Majority Leader &#8212; Leader Schumer and Senator Gillibrand and Congressman Higgins.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Gov, thank you for taking my call when I called.&nbsp; And I’ll never forget what she said.&nbsp; I said, “I’d like to maybe come up if it’s okay.”&nbsp; She said, “This is a big Scranton.&nbsp; Come.&nbsp; Come.”&nbsp; And I think you’re doing a heck of a job.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for your heart as well as your head.</p>



<p>And, Mayor Brown, you’ve been a &#8212; you’ve been wonderful.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And I know this is a lot of &#8212; when a vice presidential or a presidential trip shows up, it&#8217;s &#8212; there’s all kinds of paraphernalia and people, and I know it&#8217;s not easy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank your law enforcement officers for not just what they did in this crisis, but for accommodating us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all the elected officials, and law enforcement officers, first responders, and faith leaders that are here today: Jill and I have come to stand with you.</p>



<p>And to the families: We’ve come here to grieve with you.&nbsp; It’s not the same, but we know a little bit of what’s like to lose a piece of your soul when you lose a son, a daughter, a husband, a wife, a mother, a father.&nbsp; The feeling of having that &#8212; as I said to some of you when we talked privately: You feel like there’s a black hole in your chest you’re being sucked into and you’re suffocating, unable to &#8212; unable to breath.&nbsp; That’s what it felt like, at least to us.&nbsp; And I’m sure some version of that &#8212; it feels that way to you.&nbsp; The anger.&nbsp; The pain.&nbsp; The depth of a loss that’s so profound.</p>



<p>You know, we know it’s hard to believe, and you’re probably not going to believe it, but I can tell you now from our personal experience and many others who we’ve met: The day is going to come &#8212; it will come &#8212; when your loved one brings a smile as you remember him or her &#8212; as you remember her; it’s going to bring a smile to your lip before it brings a tear to your eye.&nbsp; It takes a while for that to happen.&nbsp; It takes a while.&nbsp; It might take more than a season, but our prayer for you is that time comes sooner or later, but I promise you it will come.</p>



<p>As a nation, I say to the families: We remember them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve been reading about them.&nbsp; We visited the memorial where &#8212; the show of the love for them, and you’ve all shown, by the supermarket.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Celestine Chaney, 65 years old.&nbsp; Brain cancer survivor.&nbsp; Churchgoer.&nbsp; Bingo player.&nbsp; Went to buy strawberries to make her favorite shortcake.&nbsp; A loving mother and a grandmother.</p>



<p>Roberta Drury, 32.&nbsp; Beloved daughter and sister.&nbsp; Moved back home to help take care of her brother after his bone marrow transplant.&nbsp; She went to buy groceries for dinner.&nbsp; The center of attention who made everyone in the room laugh and smile when she walked in.</p>



<p>Andrei Mackneil &#8212; excuse me, Andre Mackneil, 53.&nbsp; Worked at a restaurant.&nbsp; Went to buy his three-year-old son a birthday cake.&nbsp; His son <s>celing</s> [celebrating] a birthday, asking, “Where is Daddy?”</p>



<p>Katherine Massey, 72.&nbsp; A writer and an advocate who dressed up in costumes at schools and cut the grass in the park</p>



<p>and helping local elections.&nbsp; The glue of the family and the community.</p>



<p>Margus Morrison, 52.&nbsp; School bus aide.&nbsp; Went to buy snacks for weekly movie night with the family.&nbsp; Survived by his wife and three children and his stepdaughter.&nbsp; The center of their world.</p>



<p>Heyward Patterson, 67.&nbsp; Father.&nbsp; Church deacon.&nbsp; Fed the homeless at the soup kitchen.&nbsp; Gave rides to the grocery store to neighbors who needed help.&nbsp; Putting food in the trunk of others when he took his final breath.</p>



<p>Aaron Salter, 55.  Retired Buffalo police officer for three decades.  Three decades.  Loved electric cars.  A hero who gave his life to save others on a Saturday afternoon.  And had that man not been wearing that vest that he purchased &#8212; bulletproof vest &#8212; a lot of lives would have been saved.  A beloved father and husband.</p>



<p>Geraldine Talley, 62.&nbsp; Expert <s>banker</s> [baker].&nbsp; And known for her warm, gentle personality.&nbsp; A friend to everybody.&nbsp; Devoted mother and grandmother.</p>



<p>Ruth Whitfield, 88.  Beloved wife, mother, grandmother, great-grandmother who sang in the church choir.  A caretaker of her husband, bringing him clean clothes, cutting his hair, holding his hand every day she visited him in the nursing home.  Heart as big as her head.</p>



<p>Pearl Young, 77.&nbsp; A mother, grandmother, missionary of God.&nbsp; Public school teacher who also ran a local food pantry.&nbsp; Loved singing, dancing, and her family.</p>



<p>And all three are injured: Zaire Goodman, 20.&nbsp; Shot in the neck but fighting through it.&nbsp; Jennifer Warrington, 50.&nbsp; Christopher Braden, 55.&nbsp; Both treated with injuries, on a long road to recovery.</p>



<p>Individual lives of love, service, and community that speaks to the bigger story of who we are as Americans.&nbsp; A great nation because we’re a good people.</p>



<p>Jill and I bring you this message from deep in our nation’s soul: In America, evil will not win &#8212; I promise you.&nbsp; Hate will not prevail. &nbsp;And white supremacy will not have the last word.</p>



<p>For the evil did come to Buffalo, and it’s come to all too many places, manifested in gunmen who massacred innocent people in the name of hateful and perverse ideology rooted in fear and racism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s taken so much. &nbsp;Ten lives cut short in a grocery store, three other wounded &#8212; three other wounded by a hate-filled individual who had driven 200 miles from Binghamton &#8212; in that range &#8212; to carry out a murderous, racist rampage that he would livestream &#8212; livestream to the world.</p>



<p>What happened here is simple and straightforward: terrorism.&nbsp; Terrorism.&nbsp; Domestic terrorism.&nbsp; Violence inflicted in the service of hate and a vicious thirst for power that defines one group of people being inherently inferior to any other group.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A hate that through the media and politics, the Internet, has radicalized angry, alienated, lost, and isolated individuals into falsely believing that they will be replaced &#8212; that’s the word, “replaced” &#8212; by the “other” &#8212; by people who don’t look like them and who are therefore, in a perverse ideology that they possess and being fed, lesser beings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I and all of you reject the lie.&nbsp; I call on all Americans to reject the lie.&nbsp; And I condemn those who spread the lie for power, political gain, and for profit.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because that’s what it is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have now seen too many times the deadly and destructive violence this ideology unleashes.</p>



<p>We heard the chants, “You will not replace us,” in Charlottesville, Virginia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wasn’t going to run, as the Senator knows, again for President.&nbsp; But when I saw those people coming out of the woods &#8212; of the fields of &#8212; in Virginia, in Charlottesville, carrying torches, shouting “You will not replace us,” accompanied by white supremacists and carrying Nazi banners &#8212; that’s when I said, “No.”&nbsp; “No.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I, honest to God &#8212; those who know me &#8212; Chuck &#8212; you know I wasn’t going to run for certain.  But I was going to be darned if I was going to let &#8212; anyway.  Don’t want to get going. </p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;ve seen the mass shootings in Charleston, South Carolina; El Paso, Texas; in Pittsburgh; last year in Atlanta; this week in Dallas, Texas; and now in Buffalo &#8212; in Buffalo, New York.&nbsp;</p>



<p>White supremacy is a poison.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a poison &#8212; (applause) &#8212; running through &#8212; it really is &#8212; running through our body politic.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s been allowed to fester and grow right in front of our eyes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No more.&nbsp; I mean, no more.&nbsp; We need to say as clearly and forcefully as we can that the ideology of white supremacy has no place in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; None.</p>



<p>And, look, failure for us to not say that &#8212; failure in saying that is going to be complicity.&nbsp; Silence is complicity.&nbsp; It’s complicity.&nbsp; We cannot remain silent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our nation&#8217;s strength has always come from the idea &#8212; it&#8217;s going to sound corny, but think about it: What&#8217;s the idea of our nation?&nbsp; That we&#8217;re all children of God.&nbsp; All chil- &#8212; life, liberty, our universal goods &#8212; gifts of God.&nbsp; We didn&#8217;t get it from the government, we got it from &#8212; because we exist, and we’re called upon to defend them.</p>



<p>The venom of the haters and their weapons of war, the violence in the words and deeds that &#8212; that stalk our streets, our stores, our schools &#8212; this venom, this violence cannot be the story of our time.&nbsp; We cannot allow that to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I&#8217;m not naïve.&nbsp; I know tragedy will come again.&nbsp; It cannot be forever overcome.&nbsp; It cannot be fully understood either.&nbsp; But there are certain things we can do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can keep assault weapons off our streets.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done it before.&nbsp; I did it when we passed the crime bill last time.&nbsp; And violence went down, shootings went down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can&#8217;t prevent people from being radicalized to violence, but we can address the relentless exploitation of the Internet to recruit and mobilize terrorism.&nbsp; We just need to have the courage to do that, to stand up.</p>



<p>Look, the American experiment in democracy is in a danger like it hasn&#8217;t been in my lifetime.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in danger this hour.&nbsp; Hate and fear are being given too much oxygen by those who pretend to love America but who don&#8217;t understand America.</p>



<p>To confront the ideology of hate requires caring about all people, not making distinctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reverend, the Scripture is seeing that we&#8217;re all part of the Divine.&nbsp; “Love thy neighbor as thyself.”&nbsp; That&#8217;s the America I know, that Jill knows.&nbsp; And most deserve the most &#8212; we &#8212; look, we are the most multiracial, most dynamic nation in the history of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now is the time for the people of all races, from every background, to speak up as a majority in America and reject white supremacy.</p>



<p>These actions we’ve seen in these hate-filled attacks represent the views of a hate-filled minority.&nbsp; We can’t allow them to distort America &#8212; the real America.&nbsp; We can’t allow them to destroy the soul of the nation.</p>



<p>As President of the United States, I travel the world all the time, and other nations ask me &#8212; heads of state and other countries ask me, “What’s going on?&nbsp; What in God’s name happened on January 6th?&nbsp; What happened in Buffalo?&nbsp; What happ-…”&nbsp; They ask.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have to refuse to live in a country where Black people going about a weekly grocery shopping can be gunned down by weapons of war deployed in a racist cause.</p>



<p>We have to refuse to live in a country where fear and lies are packaged for power and for profit.</p>



<p>We must all enlist in this great cause of America.</p>



<p>This is work that requires all of us &#8212; presidents and politicians, commentators, citizens.&nbsp; None of us can stay in the sidelines.&nbsp; We have to resolve here in Buffalo that from the tragedy &#8212; this tragedy &#8212; will come hope and light and life.&nbsp; It has to.&nbsp; And on our watch, the sacred cause of America will never bow, never break, never bend.&nbsp; And the America we love &#8212; the one we love &#8212; will endure.</p>



<p>So, to the families: From your pain, may we find purpose to live a life worthy of the loved ones you lost.</p>



<p>From a hymn based on the 91st Psalm, sung at my church: “May He raise you up on Eagle’s wings and Bear you on the breath of dawn, make you to shine like the sun, and hold you in the palm of His hand.”&nbsp; That’s my wish for us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can do this if we resolve to do it, if we take on the haters and those who don’t even care &#8212; it’s just about profit and politics.</p>



<p>May the soul of the fallen rest in peace and rise in glory.&nbsp; And may God guide the United States of America, now and always.</p>



<p>To the families: As my grandpop used to say when I walked out of his home in Scranton &#8212; he’d say, “Joey, spread the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandma would yell, “No, Joey.”&nbsp; I mean, he said, “Keep the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandma would say, “No, Joey, spread the faith.”</p>



<p>We’re thinking of you.&nbsp; Hold on to each other tightly.&nbsp; Stick together.&nbsp; You’ll get through this.&nbsp; And we’ll make Buffalo and the United States a better place to live than it is today.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p> 12:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
