<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 22:16:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of Meeting with Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond and Key Business Groups on Historic Infrastructure Investments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/readout-of-meeting-with-senior-advisor-cedric-richmond-and-key-business-groups-on-historic-infrastructure-investments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 22:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond hosted a virtual roundtable with key business groups, including those representing Black, LGBTQ+, Hispanic, AAPI, women and small business leaders. Director Richmond discussed the historic investments proposed in President Biden’s American Jobs Plan and updated business leaders on the status of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond hosted a virtual roundtable with key business groups, including those representing Black, LGBTQ+, Hispanic, AAPI, women and small business leaders. Director Richmond discussed the historic investments proposed in President Biden’s American Jobs Plan and updated business leaders on the status of the negotiations with the bipartisan group of Senators. He also reiterated the President’s commitment to not raise taxes on people making less than $400,000 a year and thanked the business leaders for their leadership and support.<br> <br>The business leaders spoke of the urgent need for investments in infrastructure, including roads, bridges, ports, seaports and broadband. They also emphasized their support for programs to help businesses recover from the economic impacts of the pandemic and expanding federal contracting opportunities for small businesses. The group discussed how access to paid leave and child care resources will support their employees and allow small businesses to better compete. The leaders reiterated the need for additional capital investment in order to create jobs and compete in the 21st century economy.<br> <br>Richmond also thanked participants for joining and said that he looks forward to continued dialogue about how the Biden &#8211; Harris Administration can continue its support for small businesses. This meeting is part of Director Richmond’s outreach to small businesses. To date, Richmond has organized nearly 150 meetings with the private sector that were attended by over 95,000 people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Seven Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/president-biden-announces-seven-key-nominations-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 22:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles: Bathsheba Nell Crocker, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Office of the United Nations and Other International Organizations in Geneva, with the rank of Ambassador Claire A. Pierangelo, Nominee for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Bathsheba Nell Crocker, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Office of the United Nations and Other International Organizations in Geneva, with the rank of Ambassador</li><li>Claire A. Pierangelo, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Madagascar and to the Union of the Comoros</li><li>Julia Gordon, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Housing, Federal Housing Commissioner, Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Dave Uejio, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Sara Bronin, Nominee for Chair of the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation</li><li>Fagan Harris, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</li><li>Alvin Warren, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps </li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Bathsheba Nell Crocker, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Office of the United Nations and Other International Organizations in Geneva, with the rank of Ambassador</u></strong></p>



<p>Bathsheba Nell Crocker is currently a Senior Advisor at the Department of State and served on the Biden-Harris Transition team.&nbsp; From 2017-2020, she was a Vice President covering humanitarian issues at CARE USA.&nbsp; Ms. Crocker was the Assistant Secretary of State for International Organization Affairs from 2014-2017.&nbsp; She previously served as a Senior Advisor to the Secretary of State, as the Principal Deputy Director in the State Department’s Office of Policy Planning, and as Chief of Staff to the Deputy Secretary of State.&nbsp; Earlier in her career, Ms. Crocker was an Attorney-Adviser in the State Department’s Office of the Legal Adviser; Deputy U.S. Special Representative for Southeast Europe Affairs; and Executive Assistant to the Deputy National Security Advisor at the White House.&nbsp; She also held senior roles at the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, the United Nations, the UN Development Program, and the Center for Strategic and International Studies.&nbsp;&nbsp; Ms. Crocker served as a Fellow at the University of Pennsylvania and the Brookings Institution; at the School of Foreign Service at Georgetown University; and at the Council on Foreign Relations, as an International Affairs Fellow.&nbsp; She taught at Johns Hopkins University, George Washington University, and American University.&nbsp; A native of Washington, D.C., Ms. Crocker received a B.A. from Stanford University, an M.A. from the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, and a J.D. from Harvard Law School.</p>



<p><strong><u>Claire A. Pierangelo, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Madagascar and to the Union of the Comoros</u></strong></p>



<p>Claire A. Pierangelo, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the Principal Officer at the U.S. Consulate General, Lagos Nigeria. Previously, Pierangelo was an Assistant Professor at the National Defense University and prior to that, the Director of the Office of Performance Evaluation in the State Department’s Bureau of Human Resources. Earlier, she was the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Hanoi, Vietnam in addition to other positions, including multiple assignments in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs in the State Department and service as Principal Officer at the U.S. Consulate General, Surabaya, Indonesia. Pierangelo earned an M.S. degree in National Security and Resource Strategy from the Industrial College of the Armed Forces, National Defense University, an M.A. degree from the Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies and a B.A. degree from the University of California, Santa Cruz.&nbsp; She speaks Italian, Indonesian, Vietnamese and French.</p>



<p><strong><u>Julia Gordon, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Housing, Federal Housing Commissioner, Department of Housing and Urban Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Julia Gordon is the president of the National Community Stabilization Trust (NCST), a nonprofit organization that supports neighborhood revitalization and affordable homeownership through facilitating the rehabilitation of residential properties in underserved markets. In addition to managing NCST’s programmatic work, Gordon specializes in federal policy related to homeownership, community development, and the nation’s housing finance system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Previously Gordon has served as the senior director of housing and consumer finance at the Center for American Progress, manager of the single-family policy team at the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and senior policy counsel at the Center for Responsible Lending. She also has worked in the civil legal aid sector and as a litigation associate and pro bono coordinator at the law firm of WilmerHale. Gordon received her bachelor&#8217;s degree in government from Harvard College and her J.D. from Harvard Law School. She resides in Silver Spring, Maryland with her husband, Geoffrey Berman, and her daughter, Rochelle.</p>



<p><strong><u>Dave Uejio, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, Department of Housing and Urban Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Dave Uejio was announced as the Acting Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., on January 20, 2021. As the Bureau’s Acting Director, Mr. Uejio oversees a $600 million budget and a 1,600-member workforce dedicated to protecting consumers from unfair, deceptive, and abusive practices, in the financial marketplace, through the enforcement of federal consumer financial law. Currently, the Bureau supervises over 150 depository institutions with assets totaling more than $10 billion. The Bureau also supervises mortgage originators and servicers and payday lenders, as well as companies from the consumer reporting, consumer debt collection, student loan servicing, international money transfer, and automobile financing financial marketplaces.</p>



<p>Prior to becoming Acting Director, Mr. Uejio served the Bureau as Acting Chief of Staff, as Lead for Talent Acquisition, and, most recently, as the Bureau’s Chief Strategy Officer. As Chief Strategy Officer, Acting Director Uejio led the development of an integrative approach to strategic planning, policy prioritization, enterprise risk management, organizational performance, and program evaluation. Acting Director Uejio utilized this integrative approach to improve the strategic advice provided to the Director and to better translate the Director’s priorities into tangible, reportable, and auditable programs and initiatives.</p>



<p>In addition, to his experience at the Bureau, Acting Director Uejio has served in Human Resources capacities at the National Institutes of Health, the Office of Personnel Management, and the Office of the Secretary of Defense. Acting Director Uejio began his career in government service in 2006, when he joined the NIH as a Presidential Management Fellow.</p>



<p>Acting Director Uejio is devoted to public service both as a profession and a calling. He co-chairs the Federal Innovation Council, which is a leading federal government interagency body to drive public sector innovation. He also co-founded the largest event to connect, develop, and inspire emerging public service leaders, the Next Generation of Government Summit. Acting Director Uejio received a master’s degree in public policy from the University of Minnesota and a Bachelor of Arts degree from the University of California, Santa Barbara.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sara Bronin, Nominee for Chair of the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation</u></strong></p>



<p>Sara Bronin is a Mexican-American architect, attorney, and policymaker specializing in historic preservation, property, land use, and climate change. &nbsp;She is an incoming Professor at the Cornell College of Architecture, Art, and Planning and an Associated Faculty Member of the Cornell Law School, and she has held visiting positions at the Yale School of Architecture, University of Pennsylvania, and the Sorbonne, among other places.&nbsp; Among other scholarly service, Bronin is an elected member of the American Law Institute and a past chair of the State &amp; Local Government Section of the American Association of Law Schools.</p>



<p>Bronin’s interdisciplinary research focuses on how law and policy can foster more equitable, sustainable, well-designed, and connected places.&nbsp; She has published books and articles on historic preservation law and currently leads the research team behind the groundbreaking Connecticut Zoning Atlas. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Active in public service, Bronin is a board member of Latinos in Heritage Conservation and an advisor for the National Trust for Historic Preservation and the Sustainable Development Code.&nbsp; As the founder of Desegregate Connecticut, she leads a coalition that successfully advanced the first major statewide zoning reforms in several decades. Previously, she chaired Preservation Connecticut, served on the city of Hartford historic preservation commission, and led Hartford’s nationally-recognized efforts to adopt a climate action plan and city plan, and to overhaul the zoning code.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bronin won several design awards for the rehabilitation of her family’s National-Register-listed 1865 brownstone.&nbsp; She holds a J.D. from Yale Law School (Harry S Truman Scholarship), M.Sc. from the University of Oxford (Rhodes Scholarship), and B.Architecture/B.A. from the University of Texas.&nbsp; While in law school, she clerked for then-Judge Sonia Sotomayor on the Second Circuit Court of Appeals.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Fagan Harris, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</u></strong></p>



<p>Fagan Harris is a social entrepreneur, writer, and researcher who has dedicated his career to advancing impact career opportunities for underestimated communities.<br><br>As the co-founder and CEO of Baltimore Corps, Fagan has led his team to re-imagine recruiting, hiring, and career advancement for underestimated communities. In 2020, Baltimore Corps played a leading role in the Baltimore Health Corps, a $12M initiative that enlisted hundreds of city residents in Baltimore&#8217;s pandemic response as full-time public health professionals. The Health Corps earned national attention as a model for centering racial equity in large-scale workforce development. Since its inception, Baltimore Corps has engaged thousands in public service and social entrepreneurship. In 2021, Baltimore Corps launched citycorps.us, which will deploy the organization&#8217;s model in cities across the United States.<br><br>Fagan is an active civic leader. He currently serves as the Assistant American Secretary for the Rhodes Trust where he helps to oversee the scholarships annual recruitment and selection process. He is a Trustee at the Johns Hopkins Hospital at Bayview and the Enoch Pratt Free Library. He serves as the national Board President of Lead for America. Fagan is also a board member at several Baltimore-based social enterprises including B-360, Infinite Focus, and H.O.P.E (Helping Oppressed People Excel). Fagan chairs an impact consultancy that guides leading institutions to integrate &#8220;ESG&#8221; into their core practices and operations.<br><br>Previously, Fagan co-directed the Impact Careers Initiative at The Aspen Institute where he led a team of researchers to publish scholarship on talent pipelines in the public and social sectors. He started his career at College Track where he helped build its College Success strategy and program. In 2011, Fagan staffed the White House Council for Community Solutions in the Obama Administration.<br><br>For his work in social entrepreneurship, Fagan was named a Fellow at Ashoka and Echoing Green. In 2020, he was awarded the Dial Fellowship by the Emerson Collective. Fagan has given the keynote address at several national conferences including CEO for Cities Conference and MCON.<br><br>Fagan is a writer who elevates stories of Black excellence. He has worked with several New York Times best-selling authors, including Wes Moore. He is currently co-authoring several memoirs with leading Black luminaries.<br><br>Fagan is a proud graduate of Maryland Public Schools. He is an Honors graduate of Stanford University where he was the recipient of its top undergraduate honor. He has a Master in Philosophy from the University of Oxford where he was a Rhodes scholar.</p>



<p><strong><u>Alvin Warren, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</u></strong></p>



<p>Alvin is a member of Santa Clara Pueblo where he lives with his wife Pamela, an Isleta Pueblo tribal member, and their children. He’s vice president of Career Pathways and Advocacy for the LANL Foundation in Espanola, NM. In this role he’s responsible for expanding students&#8217; access to academic and technical opportunities by supporting the growth of college and career readiness in districts, schools, communities and Native American Pueblos, Tribes and Nations. He leads the foundation’s work with secondary schools, universities, colleges, industry leaders and government representatives to develop and support a seamless educational continuum of well-articulated steps, cradle to career, coupled with strong supports and connections to employment opportunities. Alvin is a former cabinet secretary of Indian Affairs for the State of New Mexico, lieutenant governor of Santa Clara, program officer for the W.K. Kellogg Foundation, national Tribal Lands Program director for The Trust for Public Lands and land claims / water rights coordinator for Santa Clara.</p>



<p>During his career Alvin has helped tribes across the United States regain and protect traditional lands; ensured that over $120 million in state dollars flowed to tribes to build essential infrastructure; enacted state legislation establishing a framework for collaborative state-tribal governmental relations; developed and sustained tribal immersion and dual language schools and positively transform public narratives about indigenous peoples. Alvin is the president of the Kha’p’o Community School Board; co-chair of the New Mexico Broadband Collective, an advisory committee member for the Native American Relief Fund; and on the board of directors for the International Funders for Indigenous Peoples. He’s a longtime farmer who’s actively involved in the cultural life of his tribal community. Alvin earned a BA in History from Dartmouth College and a Master of Public Administration from Harvard University’s John F. Kennedy School of Government.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/24/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-deal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:03 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Please, please be seated.&#160; I got my notes here.&#160; Well, good afternoon.&#160; If you hear a little noise in the background, it&#8217;s because I&#8217;m supposed to be getting on a helicopter to head to North Carolina, which I&#8217;m going to be doing short- &#8212; right after this.&#160; And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>2:03 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Please, please be seated.&nbsp; I got my notes here.&nbsp; Well, good afternoon.&nbsp; If you hear a little noise in the background, it&#8217;s because I&#8217;m supposed to be getting on a helicopter to head to North Carolina, which I&#8217;m going to be doing short- &#8212; right after this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the Vice President and I, though, want to lay out what we&#8217;ve just settled, at least for the moment, with our friends &#8212; the bipartisan group of senators.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I said many times before: There&#8217;s nothing our nation can&#8217;t do when we decide to do it together, do it as one nation.&nbsp; Today is the latest example of that truth, in my view.&nbsp; I&#8217;m pleased to report that a bipartisan group of senators &#8212; five Democrats, five Republicans &#8212; part of a larger group &#8212; have come together and forged an agreement that will create millions of American jobs and modernize our American infrastructure to compete with the rest of the world and own the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank them for working together and for raising their ideas and concerns with me and with the Vice President, as well as with our Jobs Cabinet: Secretaries Buttigieg is here &#8212; good to see you, Mr. Secretary.&nbsp; Secretary Fudge.&nbsp; Secretary Granholm.&nbsp; Secretary &#8212; there you are &#8212; okay, you guys to make sure I &#8212; I &#8212; I thought everybody was on this side.&nbsp; I was &#8211;(laughs).&nbsp; Secretary Raimondo and Secretary Walsh.</p>



<p>I also want to thank Senator Shelley Capito for her earlier work on an infrastructure agreement.&nbsp; We didn&#8217;t reach an agreement, but she tried her best to get something done.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure it helped produce the final agreement we have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact is, investment in jobs and infrastructure have often had bipartisan support in the past.&nbsp; Matter of fact, when I first got to the United States Senate, it was probably the least difficult thing to do &#8212; is pass infrastructure plans.&nbsp; But even so, it&#8217;s been a very long time since the last time our country was able to strike a major bipartisan deal on American infrastructure &#8212; which is so badly needed, I might add.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We devoted far too much energy to competing with one another and not nearly enough energy competing with the rest of the world to win the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The investments we&#8217;ll be making as a result of this deal are long overdue.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll put Americans to work in good-paying jobs repairing our roads and our bridges.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll deliver high-speed Internet to every American home, bringing down the price that people pay now for Internet service.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ll close the American digital divide &#8212; as been driven home by every mother and father with a child at home during the COVID crisis, that is, thank God, abating.&nbsp; And kids not being able to be in school.</p>



<p>This is going to put plumbers and pipefitters to work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to replace 100 percent of the nation&#8217;s lead water pipes so that every child and every American could turn on the faucet at home or at school and drink clean water, including in low-income communities and communities of color that have been disproportionately affected by lead pipes and the consequences of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This still makes key investments to put people to work all across the country building transmission lines, upgrading the power grid to be more ener- &#8212; more energy efficient and resilient in extreme weather &#8212; to be able to sustain extreme weather and the &#8212; and the climate crisis.&nbsp; It also builds our natural infrastructure &#8212; our coastlines and our &#8212; and our levees &#8212; to be more resilient as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>American workers will be installing electric vehicle charging stations and undertaking critical environmental cleanups.&nbsp; This bipartisan agreement represents the largest investment in public transit in American history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I might add that &#8212; the largest investment in rail, since the creation of Amtrak.&nbsp; You all know I have nothing but affection for Amtrak, having traveled over a million miles on it, commuting every day.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s a big deal.</p>



<p>This agreement is going to create a new financing authority that&#8217;s going to leverage private capital and infrastructure and clean energy projects that will provide folks with good-paying jobs that can&#8217;t be outsourced &#8212; the kinds of jobs that provide middle-class &#8212; a middle-class life with a little bit of breathing room &#8212; a little bit of breathing room for American families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My dad used to say, &#8220;Being in the middle class is just being able to take that extra breath.&#8221;&nbsp; I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; Think about all the people who can&#8217;t take that breath because they don&#8217;t &#8212; they have no margin for error.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re &#8212; and we&#8217;re &#8212; and we&#8217;re going to do it all without raising a cent from earners below $400,000.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no gas tax increase, no fee on electric vehicles.&nbsp; And the fact is, we&#8217;re going to help ensure that &#8212; we&#8217;re going to make sure that everybody in America is in a position to be able to do what need be done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so what I&#8217;ve &#8212; because &#8212; and let me be clear: We&#8217;re in a race with China and the rest of the world for the 21st century.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not waiting.&nbsp; They&#8217;re investing tens of billions of dollars across the board.&nbsp; Tens of billions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just came back from Europe with &#8212; meeting with the G7, as well as with NATO, as well as the EU, and as well as with Mr. Putin &#8212; all separately.&nbsp; There&#8217;s massive investment going on in the &#8212; among the autocrats.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the underlying questions is: Can democracies compete with autocratic enterprises in the 21st century?&nbsp; And this is a big move toward that, being able to compete.&nbsp; We have to move, and we have to move fast.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this agreement singles &#8212; signals to the world that we can function, deliver, and do significant things.&nbsp; These investment rep- &#8212; these investments represent the kind of national effort that, throughout our history, has literally &#8212; not figuratively &#8212; literally transformed America and propelled us into the future.&nbsp; The transcontinental railroad, the Interstate Highway System &#8212; investments that we made together that only our government was in a position to make.</p>



<p>Now we&#8217;re poised to add a new chapter in that American tradition.&nbsp; Let me be clear: Neither side got everything they wanted in this deal, and that&#8217;s what it means to compromise.&nbsp; And it reflects something important: It reflects consensus.&nbsp; The heart of democracy requires consensus.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s time a true &#8212; this time a true bipartisan effort, breaking the ice that too often has kept us frozen in place and prevented us from solving the real problems facing the American people.</p>



<p>This deal &#8212; this deal means millions of good-paying jobs, and fewer burdens felt at the kitchen table and across the country, and safer and healthier communities.&nbsp; But it also signals to ourselves and to the world that American democracy can deliver.&nbsp; And because of that, it represents an important step forward for our country.</p>



<p>I want to be clear about something else: Today is a huge day for one half of my economic agenda, the American Jobs Plan.&nbsp; It delivers on clean transportation, clear water and clean water, universal broadband, clean power infrastructure, and environmental resilience.</p>



<p>In these areas, it invests two thirds of the resources that I proposed in my American Jobs Plan.&nbsp; Two thirds of what I called for in those areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I’m getting to work with Congress right &#8212; right away on the other half of my economic agenda as well &#8212; the American Family Plan &#8212; to finish the job on childcare, education, the caring economy, clean energy tax cuts &#8212; clean energy, and tax cuts for American families, and much more.</p>



<p>For me, investment in our physical and human infrastructure are inextricably intertwined.&nbsp; Both make us better off and stronger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The case for these investments is clear.&nbsp; Economists &#8212; left, right, and center &#8212; independent Wall Street forecasters, they all say that these kinds of public investments mean more jobs, more workers participating in the labor force, higher productivity, and higher growth for our economy over the long run.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Both need to get done, and I’m going to work closely with Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer to make sure that both move through the legislative process promptly and in tandem.&nbsp; Let me emphasize that: and in tandem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need physical infrastructure, but we also need the human infrastructure as well.&nbsp; They’re a part of my overall plan.&nbsp; What we agreed on today is what we could agree on: the physical infrastructure.&nbsp; There was no agreement on the rest.&nbsp; We’re going to have to do that through the budget process.</p>



<p>And we need a fairer tax system to pay for it all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m not going to rest until it all &#8212; both get to my desk.</p>



<p>And lastly, I know there are some of my party who discouraged me from seeking an agreement with our Republican colleagues, who said that we should, “Go bigger and go alone.”</p>



<p>To them, I say this: I have already shown, in my young presidency, that I am prepared to do whatever needs to get done to move the country forward.&nbsp; That’s what I did with the American Rescue Plan, which was $1.9 trillion.</p>



<p>But let me say this: When we can’t &#8212; when we can find common ground, though, working across party lines, that is what I will seek to do.</p>



<p>The reason why is because broader support for a proposal has &#8212; the broader support a proposal has in Congress, the stronger its prospects for passage.&nbsp; Working together when we can allows us to make bipartisan process [progress] whenever possible without foreclosing the right and the necessity of moving forward on a &#8212; on a major &#8212; on a majority basis when we are at deep odds with one another.&nbsp; So-called “reconciliation progress &#8212; process.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for the &#8212; for the deal being announced today, there is plenty of work ahead to bring this home.&nbsp; It’s going to require hard work and collaboration.&nbsp; The committee chairs and the ranking members are going to play a major part.&nbsp; There are going to be disagreements to resolve and more compromise to be forged along the way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this group of senators and all of the American people can be proud today because we have reaffirmed, once again, that we are the United States of America.&nbsp; There’s not a single thing beyond our capacity that we aren’t able to do when we do it together.</p>



<p>I know a lot of you in the press, particularly, doubt that unity is possible, that anything bipartisan is possible.&nbsp; It’s hard, but it’s necessary.&nbsp; And it can get done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I want to thank you all.&nbsp; And God bless you.&nbsp; And now I’ll take a few questions, before the helicopter leaves without me, from the press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what assurances do you have at this point that you have sufficient Democratic support, both in the Senate and the House, to move both on this bipartisan deal and on the reconciliation package?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You always ask me those things.&nbsp; Nobody knows for certain.&nbsp; It’s your job, but you know it’s not a reasonable question.&nbsp; And the reason I say that &#8212; I (inaudible) being critical &#8212; the idea of my telling you now that I know what every senator &#8212; how they’re going to vote is just not &#8212; I don’t know that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do know that among the roughly 20 bipartisan groups of senators and congr- &#8212; senators that I met with &#8212; only 10 were here today, but that group &#8212; that we had an agreement.</p>



<p>For example, you know &#8212; and you know, they talk about, “Well, why would Biden compromise?”&nbsp; Well, when’s the last time &#8212;</p>



<p>If you had asked me whether or not I&#8217;d be able to get passenger rail service or 66 billion dollars’ worth &#8212; largest investment ever since Amtrak came about.&nbsp; I asked for $90 [billion] and got $66 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Talk about public transit: $49 billion &#8212; $49 billion for public transit.&nbsp; When I raised that before, some of you looked at me like, “Where have you been, Biden?&nbsp; You&#8217;ve been spending too much in China or something.”&nbsp; I hadn&#8217;t been to China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, electric buses &#8212; $7.5 billion.&nbsp; I asked for $15 [billion].&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t get all of it, but I &#8212; we compromised.&nbsp; Electric infrastructure &#8212; that is charging stations along the roads.&nbsp; I got &#8212; I asked for fifteen; I got seven and a half.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These are significant down payments on things that we finally got after negotia- &#8212; skillful negotiation on the part of my Cabinet and my team, led by Mr. Ricchetti.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, when you ask me what guarantee do I have that I have all the votes I need: I don&#8217;t have any guarantee, but what I do have is a pretty good read, over the years, of how the Congress and the Senate works.&nbsp; And the idea that we&#8217;re not going &#8212; because someone is not going to be able to get every single thing they want, they&#8217;re going to vote against some of the things that I just named with nothing in here that&#8217;s, quote, “bad” for the environment, “bad” for the economy, “bad” for the transportation is unlikely.&nbsp; But I can&#8217;t guarantee it.&nbsp; You know that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, talk a little more about your interactions with Republicans specifically.&nbsp; You said earlier, “They&#8217;ve given me their word.&nbsp; Where I come from, that’s good enough for me.”&nbsp; To skeptics in your own party, what is it about the conversations you&#8217;ve had recently with Republicans that gives you so much hope?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, secondly, you had said earlier you might have more to say about the situation down in South Beach, in Miami.&nbsp; Just curious &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to stick to &#8212; I will, at the end, answer your South Beach question.&nbsp; But let me &#8212; so we have some coherence here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number one, I&#8217;ve worked with a lot of these people who are in the room.&nbsp; I know them.&nbsp; Everybody knows and you guys know: When certain senators tell you something, they mean it.&nbsp; Snd others you take &#8212; you discount.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Where I come from and the &#8212; in my years in the Senate, the single greatest currency you have is your word &#8212; keeping your word.&nbsp; Mitt Romney has never broken his word to me.&nbsp; You know, the senator from Alaska and the senator of New Hampshire, they&#8217;ve never broken their wor- &#8212; I &#8212; from Maine &#8212; they&#8217;ve never broken their word.&nbsp; They&#8217;re friends.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the people I was with today are people that I trust.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t agree with them on a lot of things, but I trust them when they say, “This is a deal.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll stick to the deal.” Just like I doubt that you&#8217;ll find any one of them who say they don&#8217;t trust me when I said, “Okay, this is the deal &#8212; on these issues, this is a deal we&#8217;ll stick with.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, for example, there&#8217;s &#8212; and I made it clear today &#8212; there&#8217;s other things in the environment I want to get done.&nbsp; I think we should have the $300 billion tax credit for dealing with the environment.&nbsp; It (inaudible) giant tax cuts for corporations, but it’ll also be a giant move toward weatherizing every building in America and all the things that we need to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there are things &#8212; and so, when I said, “We agree,” I&#8217;m not going to go back and renegotiate the Amtrak piece, but I am going to fight for trying to get $300 billion more for tax credits for the environment.&nbsp; That&#8217;s about as best that I can answer the question.</p>



<p>Yes, ma&#8217;am.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, can you answer a ques- &#8212; thank you so much.&nbsp; My question is on the timeline.&nbsp; There are families who are looking at the Families Plan and wondering when the help is coming.&nbsp; Can you talk &#8212; I know you said they&#8217;re going to be “promptly and in tandem,&#8221; but can you say anything more about that?</p>



<p>And what does this signal for future deals?&nbsp; There&#8217;s still things like voting rights and policing reform that are not able to get bipartisan deals.&nbsp; What does this tell you?&nbsp; What have you learned in talking to Republicans about what would happen in the future?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me take &#8212; you asked three essay questions &#8212; and legitimate questions, but you asked three of them.&nbsp; The first one related to what, again?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The first one is on the timeline.&nbsp; When do you think this two-track (inaudible)?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Timeline.&nbsp; And you said, “when people are waiting for relief.”</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I got them &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; $1.9 trillion in relief so far.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be getting checks in the mail that are consequential, this week, for childcare.&nbsp; A lot has been happened already.&nbsp; Number one.</p>



<p>Number two, I&#8217;m going to fight like heck to get them the rest of what I think has to be done.&nbsp; On education, for example, my proposal was, in the Family Plan, early education and free community college.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to fight like the devil to get that done, but it&#8217;s not going to be with Republican help.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to have to get every Democrat and do it through reconciliation if it gets done.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s number one.</p>



<p>The &#8212; I think, based on my being out on the street and polling data, I think the people who need the help the most trust me to be fighting to get them the help they need.&nbsp; They know who I am, and they know my record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to the issue of what &#8212; what about voting rights &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Voting rights is maybe the most consequential thing, I think, with &#8212; I&#8217;m going to be going around the country, spending time making the case to the American people that this just isn&#8217;t about iden- &#8212; showing an identification that, &#8220;This is who I am when I vote.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This isn&#8217;t just about whether or not &#8212; excuse me &#8212; you can provide water for someone standing in line while they&#8217;re waiting to vote.&nbsp; This is about who gets to judge whether your vote counted after it&#8217;s been cast.&nbsp; Think about it.</p>



<p>Up to now, every state and the federal government has assumed that there would be officials who were appointed and/or elected in states where the election commissioners &#8212; bound by an oath that they would uphold certain requirements to make sure the vote was honest and fair.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What these guys are trying to do now, in ro- &#8212; rough approximation, is say that, “If we don’t like the vote turned out and we control the state legislature, we&#8217;re going to say the vote didn&#8217;t count and we&#8217;re going to recount.&#8221;&nbsp; That&#8217;s never happened before.&nbsp; It&#8217;s wrong.&nbsp; &#8220;Who in God&#8217;s name,&#8221; as my mother would say, &#8220;died and left them boss?&#8221;&nbsp; Your vote has to count when you cast it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a lot of ancillary pieces of this legislation that I strongly support.&nbsp; I strongly support the idea that there&#8217;s no &#8212; there&#8217;s no prior &#8212; if I had my way, there&#8217;d be no private contributions to see who gets elected &#8212; how much money you raise.&nbsp; If I had my way &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s really important &#8212; that every Election Day would be a day off because people can&#8217;t go to &#8212; people who work certain shifts can&#8217;t make it to the election.&nbsp; I would make sure there&#8217;s automatic registration when you turn 18.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what I think everybody thinks this fight is about, and it&#8217;s a worthy fight, but it&#8217;s much more profound than that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about saying that the legislature in Georgia could decide, if it&#8217;s a Republican legislature, &#8220;You know, on reflection, we don&#8217;t think that election was fair.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to vote to say it didn&#8217;t count.&#8221;&nbsp; It&#8217;s just simply wrong.&nbsp; It&#8217;s wrong.&nbsp; And in my view, it borders on being immoral.</p>



<p>This is the sacred right to vote.&nbsp; As John Lewis said, &#8220;It is the &#8212; the &#8212; the most important right you have.&#8221;&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m going to be making the case across the country and, as best I can, to see (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you support critical &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me go to this side.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, you said you want both of these measures to come to you &#8220;in tandem.&#8221;&nbsp; Did you receive any assurances that that would happen?&nbsp; And how do you anticipate &#8212; what will you do if &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I control that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; they don&#8217;t get to you in time?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If they don&#8217;t come, I&#8217;m not signing.&nbsp; Real simple.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, but I expect &#8212; I expect that in the &#8212; the coming months this summer, before the count &#8212; the fiscal year is over, that we will have voted on this bill, as well &#8212; the infrastructure bill &#8212; as well as voted on the budget record [sic] &#8212; resolution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s when they&#8217;ll &#8212; but if only one comes to me, I&#8217;m not &#8212; and if this is the only thing that comes to me, I&#8217;m not signing it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in tandem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you support, then, Speaker Pelosi&#8217;s stated plan to hold the bipartisan deal in the House until the Senate also passes reconciliation?&nbsp; Do you support that sequencing on her part?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, Mr. President, your own party is not on the same page about the reconciliation package.&nbsp; So, by moving forward with this two-track system, are you putting the bipartisan bill in jeopardy?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sure, the bipartisan bill was &#8212; look, the bipartisan bill, from the very beginning, was understood there was going to have to be the second part of it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not just signing the bipartisan bill and forgetting about the rest I &#8212; that I proposed.&nbsp; I proposed a significant piece of legislation in three parts.&nbsp; And all &#8212; all three parts are equally important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, my party &#8212; you keep &#8212; everybody tell &#8212; tells me my party is &#8212; my party is divided.&nbsp; Well, my party is divided.&nbsp; My party is divided, but my party is also rational.&nbsp; If they can&#8217;t get every single thing they want, but all that they have in the bill is that &#8212; before them is good, are they going to vote &#8220;no&#8221;?&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you &#8212; 48 hours ago, it seemed like this deal was kind of in a rough place or didn&#8217;t necessarily have a path forward.&nbsp; What clinched it?&nbsp; What changed the dynamic that you saw?&nbsp; And also, would you be willing to include a debt ceiling increase in either of the two vehicles you&#8217;re talking about?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re probably going (inaudible) be debt ceiling.&nbsp; Whether it&#8217;s included in either of these bills is not relevant.&nbsp; It depends on what the &#8212; the leadership in the House and Senate thinks how they should proceed, number one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, you notice, I didn&#8217;t have that bleak view you all had.&nbsp; You said, 48 hours ago, it didn&#8217;t look good.&nbsp; It looked good to me 48 hours ago.&nbsp; It looked good to our team 48 hours ago.&nbsp; Seventy-two hours ago, it looked good, too.&nbsp; It wasn’t there yet.</p>



<p>But you guys know me too well.&nbsp; And it’s &#8212; I’m going to drive you crazy the next four years because I’m going to tell you the truth as I see it.&nbsp; I know the Senate and the House better than most of you know it.&nbsp; I’ve been &#8212; my whole life, that’s what I’ve done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It doesn’t mean I’m going to turn out to be right all the time, but I&#8217;m not going to negotiate with the press while I&#8217;m negotiating with the &#8212; privately with my colleagues.&nbsp; And these are really tough decisions senators have got.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t, in any way, dismiss what Senator Murphy says about the environment.&nbsp; I don’t dismiss it at all.&nbsp; Especially (inaudible).&nbsp; I wrote the bill on the environment.&nbsp; Why would I not be for it?</p>



<p>The question is: How much can we get done?&nbsp; And the bottom line is: When all is said and done, does what you agree to preclude, forever, you getting the things you really want?&nbsp; Well, I’m not for that.&nbsp; I’m not going to vote for one of those deals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secondly, do you get all of what you wanted?&nbsp; Or do you come back and fight another day?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve been President about 150 days.&nbsp; I think we’ve done fairly well so far.&nbsp; Not because of me, but because of the way the system works.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s not &#8212; I mean, I &#8212; I know that doesn’t answer any of your questions about, “Can you tell me when?” and “How are you going to do it?”&nbsp; I just feel that the best way to get a senator or a congressperson who supports the essence of what&#8217;s already there, but says, “I don&#8217;t have enough of what&#8217;s there, of other things” &#8212; the best way to get that message across is go to the constituents, and say, “Here&#8217;s &#8212; here&#8217;s what&#8217;s on the table.&nbsp; Do you think your senator, your congressman should vote for that?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you campaign.&nbsp; The campaign doesn&#8217;t stop; the partisan piece stops, in terms of, “I’m against Charlie Smith or Harry Wilson.”&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t stop &#8212; I mean, that stops.&nbsp; But what doesn&#8217;t stop is to the saying, “You&#8217;re…” &#8212; it&#8217;s like on a &#8212; last example I&#8217;ll give.&nbsp; I promise I won&#8217;t do this to you again. But remember: In 2018, everybody said, “Well, you know, we&#8217;re going to lose.&nbsp; The Democrats are going to lose.&nbsp; You know, the House and Senate, they&#8217;re not going to make &#8212; the House is not going to make gains.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I went into over 60 congressional districts.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t go after the individual congresspersons who were against making sure that we kept the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; But I went to their constituents and said, “The Affordable Care Act is really important.”&nbsp; We had large crowds show up.&nbsp; And I’d say, “Here&#8217;s why I think you should do it.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why, if I were you, I&#8217;d take a look at what Charlie Smith says and Harry Wilson says.&nbsp; He&#8217;s for it.&nbsp; She&#8217;s not.”&nbsp; Or &#8220;She&#8217;s for it; he&#8217;s not.&#8221;&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; We won, what, 40 some seats?</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s not just convincing this particular congressperson.&nbsp; It&#8217;s making a rational case, if you can, in their communities why this is important to get done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the fact that I didn&#8217;t get everything now at this moment &#8212; for example, a lot of our housing pieces didn&#8217;t get passed.&nbsp; We&#8217;re coming back at it though.&nbsp; We’re coming back at it.&nbsp; We’re going to make the case.&nbsp; And if I make the case to the public at large &#8212; the one thing I can say for all of you, you do accurately report what I say.&nbsp; The problem is I disappoint you because I can&#8217;t answer all your questions and negotiate with you before I negotiate with my colleagues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I really think we &#8212; the public understands and they&#8217;re seeing the proof is in what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; It’s now projected our economy is going to grow above 7 percent this year.&nbsp; Projections from Wall Street to the Fed: It’s going to continue to grow.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to increase more &#8212; and guess what?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember you were asking me &#8212; and I&#8217;m not being critical of you all; I really mean this.&nbsp; It was legitimate questions you were asking me &#8212; asking me, “Well, you know, guess what?&nbsp; Employers can&#8217;t find workers.”&nbsp; I said, “Yeah.&nbsp; Pay them more.”&nbsp; This is an employee&#8217;s &#8212; employee’s bargaining chip now what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to have to compete and start playing [sic] hardworking people a decent wage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way &#8212; talking inflation &#8212; the overwhelming consensus is it’s going to pop up a little bit and then go back down.&nbsp; No one is talking about, “This great, great deal.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, again, if it turns out that what I&#8217;ve done so far &#8212; what we&#8217;ve done so far is a mistake, it&#8217;s going to show.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to show.&nbsp; The economy is not going to grow, like it wasn&#8217;t before.&nbsp; People aren&#8217;t going to have jobs with increased pay, like it was before.&nbsp; People are going to be out of work, like it was before, with no options.&nbsp; Unemployment is going to continue to climb, instead of continue to go down.&nbsp; If that happens, then my policies didn’t make a lot of sense, but I&#8217;m counting on it not.&nbsp; That&#8217;s my counting how it&#8217;s working.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve got to get a helicopter (inaudible).&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, will you travel to Florida, sir?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we ask you about Florida &#8212; what you&#8217;ve learned and what you&#8217;ve (inaudible)?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, yes.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; Yes, thank you. (Inaudible) President.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken with, coincidentally, the mayor of Miami-Dade, who was in my office yesterday.&nbsp; And I talked to her today &#8212; not about that, obviously &#8212; and so I had a long discussion with her today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve also spoken with &#8212; we&#8217;ve been in contact with the Congresswoman Debbie Wasserman Schultz, who has that district.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gotten in touch with FEMA.&nbsp; They&#8217;re ready to go.&nbsp; The governor is going to have to &#8212; we can&#8217;t &#8212; they&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re down inspecting in what is &#8212; what they think is needed.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m waiting for the governor to ask for &#8212; declare an emergency if &#8212; and especially as we learn more about what the rest &#8212; might happen with the rest of the building.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are on top of it.&nbsp; We are ready to move, from the federal resources, immediately &#8212; immediately, if in fact we’re asked for it.&nbsp; But we can&#8217;t go in and do it &#8212; but the &#8212; FEMA is down there taking a look at what&#8217;s needed, and &#8212; including from everything from &#8212; if the rest of those buildings have to be evacuated as well; finding housing for those people; making sure they have the capacity to both have a place to &#8212; to shelter, and food to eat, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s underway now, and I&#8217;m &#8212; my Chief of Staff has been deeply involved in this from the very beginning.&nbsp; We got the Cabinet involved in it now, in terms of dealing with FEMA.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I made it clear that I say to the people of Florida: Whatever help you want that the federal government can provide, we&#8217;re waiting.&nbsp; Just ask us; we&#8217;ll be there.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you so much.&nbsp; I appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, one quick que- &#8212; what are you hoping the Vice President can do at the border tomorrow?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; She&#8217;s done a great job so far.&nbsp; And the reason why it&#8217;s important that she go down: She&#8217;s now set up the criteria, having spoken with the President of Mexico and Guatemala, visited the region to know what we need to do.</p>



<p>Thank you very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know anything on these reports about moving Afghan nationals to other countries who helped during the war?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to come.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already begun the process.&nbsp; Those who helped us are not going to be left behind.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know what country they&#8217;re going to move to first?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don’t know that.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be meeting with the &#8212; with Ghani tomorrow, the head &#8212; he&#8217;s coming to my office.&nbsp; That will be a discussion.&nbsp; But they&#8217;re welcome here, just like anyone else who risked their lives to help us.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.</p>



<p>2:33 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Bipartisan House Members on USICA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-bipartisan-house-members-on-usica/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 20:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with a bipartisan group of House members – led by Foreign Affairs Committee Chairman Meeks and Ranking Member McCaul – at the White House to discuss the vital importance of investing in domestic sources of strength that will allow us to grow our economy, bolster the middle&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This morning, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with a bipartisan group of House members – led by Foreign Affairs Committee Chairman Meeks and Ranking Member McCaul – at the White House to discuss the vital importance of investing in domestic sources of strength that will allow us to grow our economy, bolster the middle class, and out-compete China and the rest of the world.<br><br>During the meeting – which also included Rep. Gallagher, Rep. Matsui, Rep. Bera, Rep. Slotkin, and Rep. Turner – National Security Advisor Sullivan discussed a range of issues, including the success of the President’s recent trip to Europe in rallying democracies around a shared agenda.<br><br>Sullivan also stressed the importance of linking our foreign policy objectives with making vital investments to grow our economy, including through passing bipartisan legislation like the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act (USICA) and the National Science Foundation for the Future Act – which incorporates key components of the vision the President laid out through the American Jobs Plan, including in bolstering R&amp;D in areas like climate technology, and strengthening advanced manufacturing, supply chain resiliency, and the American semiconductor industry.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the Fourth National Climate Task Force Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/readout-of-the-fourth-national-climate-task-force-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 19:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21915</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration Mounts Whole-of-Government Response to Address Extreme Heat Impacting Nearly Half of U.S. and Boosting Climate Resilience Today, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the fourth National Climate Task Force meeting where she was joined by Cabinet members and senior leadership from 17 federal agencies. During the meeting, Biden Administration officials discussed the whole-of-government&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration Mounts Whole-of-Government Response to Address Extreme Heat Impacting Nearly Half of U.S. and Boosting Climate Resilience</em></p>



<p>Today, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the fourth National Climate Task Force meeting where she was joined by Cabinet members and senior leadership from 17 federal agencies. During the meeting, Biden Administration officials discussed the whole-of-government effort taking place to address historic and severe climate impacts currently facing communities across the United States, including record breaking heat waves, unprecedented drought and water scarcity, and devastating wildfires. Task Force members discussed a sobering summer outlook, identified near-term readiness plans in the face of extreme weather risks, and laid out long-term resilience measures that will help the nation fend off the worst impacts of climate change.</p>



<p>Additionally, agency leadership shared the climate-related challenges they are working to address:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Health and Human Services Secretary Xavier Becerra</strong>&nbsp;emphasized that record-breaking heat waves across the nation’s Western States pose a severe public health threat to tens of thousands of Americans, particularly in disadvantaged or vulnerable communities. The Center for Disease Control’s National Syndromic Surveillance Program data show that cases of heat related emergency room hospital visits increased from 857, in the first week of May, to 5313 in the week of June 13-19 – a six-fold increase.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Interior Secretary Deb Haaland</strong>&nbsp;discussed how climate-related impacts are displacing certain coastal communities, especially tribal and indigenous communities, in regions already dramatically influenced by climate change.&nbsp; More and more Alaska Native villages, for example, are experiencing increasingly dire impacts from climate change, including receding summer sea ice; storm-fueled coastal erosion; and thawing permafrost, which presents a risk to food security. President Biden’s American Jobs Plan includes a $2B investment for transition and relocation assistance to support community-led transitions in the most vulnerable communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Agriculture Secretary Tom Vilsack</strong>&nbsp;spoke about ongoing efforts to combat wildfire and drought, including a focus on forest management and natural solutions. He emphasized the Agriculture Department’s focus on building resilience to these challenges through climate-smart agriculture and forestry management. This approach is mirrored in President Biden’s American Job’s Plan, which includes an investment of more than $50B in resilience in the face of a changing climate.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Housing and Urban Development Deputy Secretary Adrianne Todman</strong>&nbsp;noted that our nation’s low-income families and communities of color are particularly susceptible to the impacts of climate change due to historic disinvestment, aging infrastructure, and the legacy of residential segregation. For example, historically the nation’s public housing stock has not been built to withstand extreme temperatures, thereby exacerbating health risks and resulting in crippling energy costs for residents. To address this need, HUD’s FY22 budget request proposes $800 million in energy, resilience, and healthy retrofits for federally subsidized housing and housing in Native American communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>White House Council on Environmental Quality Chair Brenda Mallory&nbsp;</strong>noted that one of the most powerful and cost-effective strategies for combatting climate change and protecting communities from its impacts is through the conservation and restoration of natural lands and waters. Chair Mallory provided an update on the work that Federal agencies are doing through the Administration’s America the Beautiful initiative to support locally-led, voluntary stewardship efforts and to pursue the first-ever national conservation goal.</li></ul>



<p>To ensure resilient federal operations and physical footprints, agencies are preparing Climate Action Plans, per President Biden’s Executive Order 14008. These plans parallel many of the nation’s climate related vulnerabilities, including natural resources such as land and water resources; financial risk &#8212; including risks to assets, supplies, and services; and the health, safety, and availability of the Federal workforce.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Acting Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and&nbsp;Sustainment Stacy Cummings&nbsp;</strong>emphasized that around the world, climate change is a destabilizing force, creating new missions and impacting the operational environment. At the same time, climate-related extreme weather can affect military readiness and drain resources. For these reasons, the Department of Defense focused their Climate Adaptation Plan on building resilience across the entire Department in alignment with warfighting requirements.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Deputy Transportation Secretary Polly Trottenberg</strong>&nbsp;spoke about how the Department of Transportation is using their Climate Action Plan to explore a range of strategies that will guide decision making to make our transportation infrastructure more resilient. These strategies include building stronger or better by retrofitting existing infrastructure, adding network redundancy, relocating transportation assets to less vulnerable locations, and improving maintenance and operational strategies to respond to disruptions.</li></ul>



<p>As outlined by President Biden’s January 27 executive order on tackling the climate, the Task Force is chaired by the National Climate Advisor and includes Cabinet-level leaders from 21 federal agencies and senior White House officials to mobilize the Biden-Harris Administration’s implementation of a whole-of-government approach.</p>



<p><em>Task Force membership is comprised of the following government officials:</em></p>



<ul><li>National Climate Advisor (Chair)</li><li>Secretary of the Treasury</li><li>Secretary of Defense</li><li>Attorney General</li><li>Secretary of the Interior</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Commerce</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Health and Human Services</li><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Secretary of Transportation</li><li>Secretary of Energy</li><li>Secretary of Homeland Security</li><li>Administrator of General Services</li><li>Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality</li><li>Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration</li><li>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs</li><li>Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism</li><li>Assistant to the President for Economic Policy</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 19:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Ismael N. Ahmed, of Michigan, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2024, vice Olga Viso, term expired. &#160; &#160; &#160;Kinan Azmeh, of New York, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Ismael N. Ahmed, of Michigan, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2024, vice Olga Viso, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kinan Azmeh, of New York, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2024, vice Charlotte P. Kessler, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Stacey Michelle Brandenburg, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Harry S Truman Scholarship Foundation for a term expiring December 10, 2025, vice Steven H. Cohen, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Laura Daniel-Davis, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Interior, vice Joseph Balash, resigned.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Hampton Y. Dellinger, of North Carolina, to be an Assistant Attorney General, vice Beth Ann Williams.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kamilah Forbes, of New York, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2026, vice Lee Greenwood, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Robert Garcia, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Harry S Truman Scholarship Foundation for a term expiring December 10, 2023, vice James L. Henderson, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Christi A. Grimm, of Colorado, to be Inspector General, Department of Health and Human Services, vice Daniel R. Levinson, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Cathy Ann Harris, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Merit Systems Protection Board for the term of seven years expiring March 1, 2028, vice Anne Marie Wagner, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Cathy Ann Harris, of Maryland, to be Chairman of the Merit Systems Protection Board, vice Susan Tsui Grundmann.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Raymond A. Limon, of Nevada, to be a Member of the Merit Systems Protection Board for the term of seven years expiring March 1, 2025, vice Mark A. Robbins, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Huascar Medina, of Kansas, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2026, vice Irvin M. Mayfield, Jr., term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Christopher Kaui Morgan, of Maryland, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2024, vice David Masumoto, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Fiona Whelan Prine, of Tennessee, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2024, vice Diane Helen Rodriguez, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jake Shimabukuro, of Hawaii, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2024, vice Rick Lowe, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Xochitl Torres Small, of New Mexico, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development, vice Lisa Afua Serwah Mensah.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;M. Camille Calimlim Touton, of Nevada, to be Commissioner of Reclamation, vice Brenda Burman.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;David Uejio, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, vice Anna Maria Farias.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Max Vekich, of Washington, to be a Federal Maritime Commissioner for a term expiring June 30, 2026, vice Michael A. Khouri, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Homer L. Wilkes, of Mississippi, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Natural Resources and Environment, vice James E. Hubbard.</p>



<p>     Constance Hess Williams, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2026, vice Barbara Ernst Prey, term expired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President Biden Announces Support for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-support-for-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 17:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden and Vice President Harris announced their support for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century – an investment that will make our economy more sustainable, resilient, and just. The President came into office promising to find common ground to get things done&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden and Vice President Harris announced their support for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century – an investment that will make our economy more sustainable, resilient, and just.</p>



<p>The President came into office promising to find common ground to get things done – and he’s delivering on that promise.</p>



<p>The $1.2 trillion Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework is a critical step in implementing President Biden’s Build Back Better vision. The Plan makes transformational and historic investments in clean transportation infrastructure, clean water infrastructure, universal broadband infrastructure, clean power infrastructure, remediation of legacy pollution, and resilience to the changing climate. Cumulatively across these areas, the Framework invests two-thirds of the resources that the President proposed in his American Jobs Plan.</p>



<p>President Biden believes that we must invest in our country and in our people, creating good-paying union jobs, tackling the climate crisis, and growing the economy sustainably, and equitably for decades to come. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework is a critical step in accomplishing these objectives.</p>



<p>President Biden believes that we are at inflection point between democracy and autocracy. At this moment in our history, President Biden believes we must demonstrate to the world that American democracy can deliver for the American people. Today, the President is showing that democracy can deliver results. The Framework will position American workers, farmers, and businesses – small and large alike – to compete and win in the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century.</p>



<p>Still, there is more work to do – to grow our economy, create jobs, improve living standards, reduce climate pollution, and ensure more Americans can participate fully and equally in our economy. President Biden remains committed to the comprehensive agenda laid out in the American Jobs Plan and American Families Plan. He will work with Congress to build on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework in legislation that moves in tandem, and he is encouraged that both the House and Senate are working on budget plans that would do so.</p>



<p>But democracy requires compromise. The historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework will make life better for millions of Americans, create a generation of good-paying union jobs and economic growth, and position the United States to win the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century, including on many of the key technologies needed to combat the climate crisis. That’s what President Biden and Vice President Harris were elected to do.</p>



<p>The President calls on Congress to pass the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and send it to his desk, and pass a budget resolution and legislation that makes his full Build Back Better vision a reality.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework will:</p>



<ul><li>Improve healthy, sustainable transportation options for millions of Americans by modernizing and expanding transit and rail networks across the country, while reducing greenhouse gas emissions. The Plan is the largest federal investment in public transit in history and is the largest federal investment in passenger rail since the creation of Amtrak.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Repair and rebuild our roads and bridges with a focus on climate change mitigation, resilience, equity, and safety for all users, including cyclists and pedestrians. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework is the single largest dedicated bridge investment since the construction of the interstate highway system.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Build a national network of electric vehicle (EV) chargers along highways and in rural and disadvantaged communities. The largest investment in EV infrastructure in history, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework will accomplish the President’s goal of building 500,000 EV chargers.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Electrify thousands of school and transit buses across the country to reduce harmful emissions and drive domestic manufacturing of zero emission vehicles and components.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Eliminate the nation’s lead service lines and pipes, delivering clean drinking water to up to ten million American families and more than 400,000 schools and child care facilities that currently don’t have it, including in Tribal nations and disadvantaged communities. The Plan is the largest investment in clean drinking water and waste water infrastructure in American history.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Connect every American to reliable high-speed internet, just as the federal government made a historic effort to provide electricity to every American nearly one hundred years ago. The Framework will also drive down prices for internet service and close the digital divide.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Upgrade our power infrastructure, including by building thousands of miles of new, resilient transmission lines to facilitate the expansion of renewable energy, including through a new Grid Authority. The Plan is the single largest investment in clean energy transmission in American history.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Create a first of its kind Infrastructure Financing Authority that will leverage billions of dollars into clean transportation and clean energy.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Make the largest investment in addressing legacy pollution in American history, a cleanup effort that will create good-paying union jobs and advance environmental justice.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Prepare more of our infrastructure for the impacts of climate change, cyber attacks, and extreme weather events. The Framework is the largest investment in the resilience of physical and natural systems in American history.</li></ul>



<p>The Framework, which will generate significant economic benefits and returns, is financed through a combination of closing the tax gap, redirecting unspent emergency relief funds, targeted corporate user fees, and the macroeconomic impact of infrastructure investment.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework</u></strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis:100%">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:100%">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:100%">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:100%">
<figure class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes"><table><tbody><tr><td>&nbsp;</td><td><strong>Amount (billions)</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Total</strong></td><td><strong>$579</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Transportation</span></strong></td><td><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">$312</span></strong></td></tr><tr><td>Roads, bridges, major projects</td><td>$109</td></tr><tr><td>Safety</td><td>$11</td></tr><tr><td>Public transit</td><td>$49</td></tr><tr><td>Passenger and Freight Rail</td><td>$66</td></tr><tr><td>EV infrastructure</td><td>$7.5</td></tr><tr><td>Electric buses / transit</td><td>$7.5</td></tr><tr><td>Reconnecting communities</td><td>$1</td></tr><tr><td>Airports</td><td>$25</td></tr><tr><td>Ports &amp; Waterways</td><td>$16</td></tr><tr><td>Infrastructure Financing</td><td>$20</td></tr><tr><td><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Other Infrastructure</span></strong></td><td><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">$266</span></strong></td></tr><tr><td>Water infrastructure</td><td>$55</td></tr><tr><td>Broadband infrastructure</td><td>$65</td></tr><tr><td>Environmental remediation</td><td>$21</td></tr><tr><td>Power infrastructure incl. grid authority</td><td>$73</td></tr><tr><td>Western Water Storage</td><td>$5</td></tr><tr><td>Resilience</td><td>$47</td></tr></tbody></table><figcaption><em>*New spending + baseline (over 5 years) = $973B</em><br><em>*New spending + baseline (over 8 years) = $1,209B</em></figcaption></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Proposed Financing Sources for New Investment</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Reduce the IRS tax gap<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Unemployment insurance program integrity<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Redirect unused unemployment insurance relief funds<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Repurpose unused relief funds from 2020 emergency relief legislation<br>&nbsp;</li><li>State and local investment in broadband infrastructure<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Allow states to sell or purchase unused toll credits for infrastructure<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Extend expiring customs user fees<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Reinstate Superfund fees for chemicals<br>&nbsp;</li><li>5G spectrum auction proceeds<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Extend mandatory sequester<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Strategic petroleum reserve sale<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Public-private partnerships, private activity bonds, direct pay bonds and asset recycling for infrastructure investment<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Macroeconomic impact of infrastructure investment</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Hong Kong’s Apple Daily</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-hong-kongs-apple-daily/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 17:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is a sad day for media freedom in Hong Kong and around the world. Intensifying repression by Beijing has reached such a level that Apple Daily, a much-needed bastion of independent journalism in Hong Kong, has now ceased publishing. Through arrests, threats, and forcing through a National Security Law that penalizes free speech, Beijing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>It is a sad day for media freedom in Hong Kong and around the world. Intensifying repression by Beijing has reached such a level that Apple Daily, a much-needed bastion of independent journalism in Hong Kong, has now ceased publishing. Through arrests, threats, and forcing through a National Security Law that penalizes free speech, Beijing has insisted on wielding its power to suppress independent media and silence dissenting views.<br> <br>Independent media play an invaluable role in resilient and prosperous societies. Journalists are truth-tellers who hold leaders accountable and keep information flowing freely—and that is needed now more than ever in Hong Kong, and in places around the world where democracy is under threat. Beijing must stop targeting the independent press and release the journalists and media executives that have been detained. The act of journalism is not a crime. <br> <br>People in Hong Kong have the right to freedom of the press. Instead, Beijing is denying basic liberties and assaulting Hong Kong’s autonomy and democratic institutions and processes, inconsistent with its international obligations. The United States will not waver in our support of people in Hong Kong and all those who stand up for the basic freedoms all people deserve.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Announces Initiatives to Promote Housing Stability By Supporting Vulnerable Tenants and Preventing Foreclosures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 15:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Across America, a strong economic recovery is taking hold. Since President Biden took office, more than two million jobs have been created. The American Rescue Plan is working, jumpstarting the economy and getting Americans back to work. And critically, 70% of Americans ages 30 and older have received at least one dose of the COVID-19&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Across America, a strong economic recovery is taking hold. Since President Biden took office, more than two million jobs have been created. The American Rescue Plan is working, jumpstarting the economy and getting Americans back to work. And critically, 70% of Americans ages 30 and older have received at least one dose of the COVID-19 vaccine. In every state, jobs are up, the pandemic is in retreat, and American workers and families are looking ahead to a brighter future.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a number of steps to keep people in their homes by protecting renters and homeowners who are still experiencing shocks from the pandemic and its economic fallout. Following the CDC’s decision to extend the eviction moratorium for one final month through July 31, 2021, the Administration is announcing a series of actions to help state and local governments prevent evictions. The Administration is also taking action to stabilize homeowners and support a return to a more stable housing market, including by extending the foreclosure moratorium for federally-backed mortgages by a final month, until July 31st.<br><br><strong><u>Biden-Harris Administration Actions to Help State and Local Governments Prevent Evictions</u></strong><br><br>The American Rescue Plan allocated an additional $21.5 billion for Emergency Rental Assistance (ERA) that can be used by renters to cover arrears and make landlords whole. This is on top of $25 billion allocated under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021, bringing the total amount of ERA available to more than $46 billion and creating an economic and moral imperative for state and local governments to rise to the challenge of building a new infrastructure for getting emergency rental assistance to vulnerable renters and landlords. The Biden-Harris Administration’s&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/FACT_SHEET-Emergency-Rental-Assistance-Program_May2021.pdf">May 7<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;guidance</a>&nbsp;has helped state and local governments move more funds to more renters in need. But state and local governments must do better. Money is available in every state to help renters who are behind on rent and at risk of eviction.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a series of actions to help state and local governments prevent evictions and promote housing stability. The Administration is also calling for the acceleration of ERA funds to renters and landlords in need in addition to an all hands-on-deck effort by local governments, courts, community organizations, and the legal community to create alternatives to evictions.<br><br>Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration is providing the following support and guidance to:<br><br><strong>Urge State and Local Courts to Participate in Eviction Diversion Efforts.</strong>&nbsp;Today, Associate Attorney General Vanita Gupta is sending a letter to state courts encouraging them to adopt anti-eviction diversion practices that will benefit families, tenants, landlords, and the courts themselves. Establishing diversion programs will help landlords and tenants reach agreement and access emergency rental assistance in addition to other available resources to keep families hard-pressed by the COVID crisis in their homes while helping make landlords whole. Avoiding legal action helps tenants and landlords avoid the costs of such action and relieves strain on the courts themselves. The Justice Department letter points to actions that courts can implement immediately to help confront this problem. The letter also directs courts to federal resources they can use to support diversion programs and to tools developed by the National Center for State Courts that can help judges ensure landlords and tenants have an opportunity to tap into available resources and mediate their dispute.<br><br><strong>Highlight that American Rescue Plan Funds for State and Local Governments and for Emergency Rental Assistance Can Be Used to Fund Eviction Diversion Plans, Including&nbsp;Counseling, Navigator, and Legal Services.</strong>&nbsp;The American Rescue Plan delivered critical and historic support to states and localities to help them address the COVID-19 public health emergency and its economic fallout. Today, the Treasury Department is making clear that states and localities, in partnership with their court systems, can tap two sources of Federal support for funding their eviction diversion efforts: the $350 billion Coronavirus State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds and billions of additional dollars available for housing stability services through the Emergency Rental Assistance Program.<br><br><strong>Convene a White House Summit for Immediate Eviction Prevention Plans.&nbsp;</strong>Effective prevention of unnecessary evictions through deployment of ERA funds requires local strategies that strongly encourage alternatives to evictions. Eviction diversion strategies, where local legal systems require landlords and tenants to seek mediation—a process that is particularly likely to be successful with the deployment of ERA funds—are among the most effective strategies for accomplishing that goal.&nbsp; The White House, in collaboration with the American Bar Association (ABA), Legal Services Corporation (LSC), and National Conference of Bar Presidents (NCBP), is convening local government, judicial, legal, and community leaders from 50 cities to develop community-specific solutions to provide vulnerable families access to counsel, divert evictions, and connect renters and landlords to available resources. Drawing on local leaders from across the court system, legal services and legal advocacy communities, philanthropy, non-profit services, and local government, the White House will support and facilitate coordination among these stakeholders in developing locally-tailored solutions that incentivize the use of emergency rental assistance and keep tenants stably housed, while also providing a model for the coordination required in communities across the country to fully address the eviction crisis.<br><br><strong>Accelerate and Broaden State and Local Delivery of Emergency Rental Assistance by Providing Clarity on Bulk Payments, Aiding Americans Experiencing Homelessness, and Overcoming Language and Disability Barriers.&nbsp;</strong>Building off the enhanced policies&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/FACT_SHEET-Emergency-Rental-Assistance-Program_May2021.pdf">announced</a>&nbsp;on May 7, today, Treasury is highlighting promising practices of communities implementing effective rental assistance programs, as well as releasing new guidance to support states’ and localities’ rapid deployment of Emergency Rental Assistance to protect vulnerable families from the threat of eviction. Treasury’s guidance:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Strongly encourages partnerships with courts to actively prevent evictions and develop eviction diversion programs.</u></strong>&nbsp;Emergency rental assistance can be used to help families at-risk of eviction remain in their homes, especially when programs work with courts to connect such families and their landlords with mediation and emergency rental assistance resources, engage providers of housing stability services for active support, and enter into agreements with courts to cover the costs of eviction diversion activities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Helps families experiencing homelessness gain access to assistance.</u></strong>&nbsp;For vulnerable families without a current rental obligation—necessary for emergency rental assistance eligibility—Treasury is creating a commitment letter process to help those families gain access to assistance. ERA can help families who have lost, or are at imminent risk of losing, their housing, to get stably housed by paying for relocation assistance, prospective rent, security deposits, and temporary hotel accommodations.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Drives towards equal access by removing language and cultural barriers in securing emergency rental assistance.</u></strong>&nbsp;Treasury is strongly encouraging grantees to provide culturally and linguistically-relevant housing stability services and to conduct outreach in multiple languages so that eligible families do not face unnecessary barriers to access. Grantees who cannot provide such services themselves should be engaging partners with the capacity to do so to ensure equal access to emergency rental assistance for all eligible households.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Provides a streamlined payment option for&nbsp;</u></strong><strong><u>utility providers and large landlords to make accessing emergency rental assistance on behalf of multiple tenants easier and more attractive.</u></strong>&nbsp;Treasury is clarifying how grantees may achieve economies of scale by obtaining information in bulk from utility providers and landlords with multiple units to help speed determination of eligibility of households and to bundle, in a single payment, approved amounts for the benefit of multiple tenants.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Pushes grantee coordination to reduce the confusion, burdens, and delays in providing assistance created by differences in locally-imposed requirements among programs operating in the same regions</u></strong>.&nbsp;Grantees providing services to overlapping or neighboring areas should collaborate to develop consistent or complementary policies to avoid unnecessary confusion or burdens for families or landlords seeking aid.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Lifts up grantees implementing effective practices to ensure that assistance quickly reaches the renters who need it most.</u></strong>&nbsp;Treasury is highlighting promising practices from the field, including successful examples of partnership with local court systems and legal services to divert evictions and prevent housing insecurity as well as programs taking advantage of options to reduce documentation barriers that keep eligible families from benefiting from ERA. This could include automating application processing and approaches for verifying income to simplify and speed eligibility determinations, such as leveraging fact-specific proxies like area median incomes.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensure that the 30-day Eviction Notice Requirement for Federally-Backed Properties is Enforced</strong>. HUD/FHA and USDA will ensure that no landlord (public or private) whose underlying financing is backed by the federal government (e.g., HUD/FHA or USDA), purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) or the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), or that is receiving assistance from the federal government may require a tenant to vacate their unit for non-payment of rent until 30 days after the landlord has provided the tenant with a notice to vacate.<br><br><strong>Make Clear the Fair Housing Act Must Be Followed.&nbsp;</strong>Evictions disproportionately affect communities of color, people with disabilities, women, and other members of protected classes. Tenants with disabilities who are facing eviction are entitled to reasonable accommodations in the eviction process. In some cases, in bringing eviction actions, housing providers may also engage in practices that violate the federal Fair Housing Act. The Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) is providing guidance to help prevent Fair Housing Act violations and collaborating with DOJ to publicize this guidance. Landlords and renters can visit hud.gov/fairhousing for details on guidance.<br><br><strong>Leverage Government Information Channels to Reach Vulnerable Tenants and Landlords:&nbsp;</strong>The administration is implementing a whole-of-government effort to raise awareness about emergency rental assistance, including tapping multiple federal agencies to take actions to inform tenants and landlords of available emergency rental assistance including:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Publishing on Treasury’s website a list of more than 590 links to state, local and tribal government ERA programs.&nbsp;</u></strong>Treasury’s&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/emergency-rental-assistance-program/program-index">website</a>&nbsp;will also link to the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau’s (CFPB) interagency housing hub, where CFPB has published information about ERA designed to be easily accessible to consumers.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Lifting up</u></strong><strong><u>&nbsp;consumerfinance.gov/housing.</u></strong>&nbsp;The website is a one-stop, go-to resource for up-to-date information on their relief options, protections, and key deadlines for renters. Visit&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cfpb.gov/housing">cfpb.gov/housing</a>&nbsp;to learn more.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Conducting outreach to HUD grantees, HUD-assisted households, and housing providers who receive HUD assistance.</u></strong>&nbsp;HUD is working to encourage housing providers who receive HUD assistance to send information on the emergency rental assistance program in their community to tenants, ensuring HUD grantees are collaborating with the emergency rental assistance program in their community, and continuing to provide guidance that explains how the emergency rental assistance program can help HUD-assisted households.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Sharing program information with the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s SNAP beneficiaries and the Social Security Administration’s SSI recipients</u></strong><strong>.&nbsp;</strong>USDA will encourage State Departments of Social Services to share information on Treasury’s ERA and HUD’s Emergency Housing Vouchers with SNAP recipients. The Social Security Administration will support external outreach efforts by directly sharing information with SSI recipients as well as elevating awareness through their websites and social media platforms.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Conducting targeted outreach to vulnerable tenants.</u></strong>&nbsp;HUD is working closely with the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to step up outreach efforts to vulnerable tenants and inform them of federal assistance available to avoid eviction through extensive earned and paid media campaigns, close collaboration with state and local housing offices and public housing authorities, and the promotion of resources—such as toolkits and renter-oriented materials—for tenants and guidance to housing providers about eviction prevention best practices and emergency rental assistance.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Aligning philanthropic supports.</u></strong>&nbsp;Philanthropy can play a key role in supporting outreach efforts to vulnerable tenants and helping communities stand up new programs. HUD is developing a Memorandum of Understanding with Melville Charitable Trust (MCT) to build the capacity of community-based organizations, cities, states, and Tribes to administer federal relief dollars efficiently and equitably. MCT is the largest foundation in the U.S. devoted exclusively to preventing and ending homelessness. In this new collaborative partnership, MCT will coordinate the philanthropic sector to target new capacity building resources in communities disproportionately impacted by the pandemic to fill gaps in service of new federal programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Biden-Harris Administration Actions to Prevent Foreclosures</u></strong><br><br>In addition to the actions outlined to support tenants and landlords, today, the Biden-Harris Administration is also announcing efforts to support homeowners. Three federal agencies that back mortgages – the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), and Department of Agriculture (USDA) – will extend their respective foreclosure moratorium for one, final month, until July 31, 2021. The Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) will also announce that it has extended the foreclosure moratorium for mortgages backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac until July 31, 2021.<br><br>Once the moratoria end, HUD, VA, and USDA will take additional steps to prevent foreclosures on mortgages backed by those agencies until borrowers are reviewed for COVID-19 streamlined loss mitigation options that are affordable, while FHFA will continue to work with Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to ensure that borrowers are evaluated for home retention solutions prior to any referral to foreclosure. <br><br>In addition, HUD, VA, and USDA will also continue to allow homeowners who have not taken advantage of forbearance to date to enter into COVID-related forbearance through September 30, 2021, while homeowners with Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac-backed mortgages who have COVID-related hardships will also continue to be eligible for COVID-related forbearance. Finally, HUD, VA, and USDA will be announcing additional steps in July to offer borrowers payment reduction options that will enable more homeowners to stay in their homes.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: New U.S. Government Actions on Forced Labor in Xinjiang</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-new-u-s-government-actions-on-forced-labor-in-xinjiang/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the recent G7 Summit in Cornwall, United Kingdom, the world’s leading democracies stood united against forced labor, including in Xinjiang, and committed to ensure global supply chains are free from the use of forced labor. The United States is translating these commitments into action. The Biden-Harris administration is taking additional steps to hold those&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>At the recent G7 Summit in Cornwall, United Kingdom, the world’s leading democracies stood united against forced labor, including in Xinjiang, and committed to ensure global supply chains are free from the use of forced labor. The United States is translating these commitments into action. The Biden-Harris administration is taking additional steps to hold those who engage in forced labor accountable and ensure that we continue to remove goods made with forced labor from our supply chains through actions by the Department of Homeland Security’s U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Department of Commerce, and the Department of Labor.<br><br>These actions demonstrate our commitment to imposing additional costs on the People’s Republic of China (PRC) for engaging in cruel and inhumane forced labor practices and ensuring that Beijing plays by the rules of fair trade as part of the rules-based international order. The United States believes that state-sponsored forced labor in Xinjiang is both an affront to human dignity and an example of the PRC’s unfair economic practices. The PRC’s use of forced labor in Xinjiang is an integral part of its systematic abuses against the Uyghur population and other ethnic and religious minority groups, and addressing these abuses will remain a high priority for the Biden-Harris administration. The systematic abuses go beyond forced labor to include sexual violence and large-scale forced detentions, and the PRC continues to commit genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang.<br><br>The PRC’s forced labor practices run counter to our values as a nation and expose American consumers to unethical practices. They also leave American businesses and workers to compete on an uneven playing field by allowing firms to gain advantage over their competitors by exploiting workers and artificially suppressing wages. The United States will not tolerate forced labor in our supply chains and will continue to stand up for our values and for U.S. workers and businesses. This includes maintaining support for the development of transparent and diverse clean energy supply chains at home free of forced labor — and supporting President Biden’s commitment to bold climate action, the domestic solar industry, and the jobs this vital industry creates.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Issues Withhold Release Order (WRO): </strong>CBP has issued a WRO on silica-based products made by Hoshine Silicon Industry Co., Ltd., a company located in Xinjiang, and its subsidiaries. This WRO is based on information reasonably indicating that Hoshine used forced labor to manufacture silica-based products. As a result, personnel at all U.S. ports of entry have been instructed to immediately begin detaining shipments that contain silica-based products made by Hoshine or materials and goods derived from or produced using those silica-based products. CBP investigates allegations of forced labor in U.S. supply chains and will continue investigating allegations in the polysilicon industry and other industries in Xinjiang and elsewhere.<br><br>CBP’s forced labor investigations have produced six Withhold Release Orders in Fiscal Year 2021, including one on cotton and tomato products from the Xinjiang region, another on cotton products originating from the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps (XPCC), and one on the Dalian Ocean Fishing Co., Ltd. As demonstrated by the Dalian WRO, the United States is also taking action to combat the PRC’s use of forced labor beyond Xinjiang – including in the seafood industry. Currently, 35 of 49 active WROs are on goods from the PRC, and 11 WROs are on goods made by forced labor from Xinjiang.<br><br><strong>Department of Commerce Updates its Entity List: </strong>The Department of Commerce&#8217;s Bureau of Industry and Security added to the Entity List five PRC entities: Hoshine Silicon Industry (Shanshan); Xinjiang Daqo New Energy; Xinjiang East Hope Nonferrous Metals; Xinjiang GCL New Energy Material Technology, and XPCC— for participating in the practice of, accepting, or utilizing forced labor in Xinjiang and contributing to human rights abuses against Uyghurs and other minority groups in Xinjiang. This action, which follows the 48 PRC entities previously added to the Entity List for their connections to human rights abuses in Xinjiang, restricts the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of commodities, software, and technology subject to the Export Administration Regulations where such entities are a party to the transactions (e.g., end-user, purchaser, intermediate or ultimate consignee).<br><br><strong>Department of Labor Updates the “List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor”: </strong>The Department of Labor has published a Federal Register Notice updating its “List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor,” to include polysilicon produced with forced labor in the PRC. Every two years, the Department of Labor publishes an updated list of goods produced by child labor or forced labor in violation of international standards. This update is the first time a good has been added outside of that two-year cycle, highlighting its strong response to the severity of the ongoing human rights abuses against Uyghurs and other minority groups in Xinjiang. The report currently includes other products from the PRC that have links to forced labor in Xinjiang or by Uyghur workers transferred to other parts of the PRC, including cotton, garments, footwear, electronics, gloves, hair products, textiles, thread/yarn, and tomato products.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
