<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 12:17:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe&#160;Biden’s meeting on Hurricane Preparedness and Actions to Ensure Equitable&#160;Recovery</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-meeting-on-hurricane-preparedness-and-actions-to-ensure-equitable-recovery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On May 18, President Biden met with leaders of his Federal emergency preparedness and response team to receive the annual briefing on the Atlantic Hurricane Season Outlook and to review progress on his directive to enhance equity and access to Federal disaster support and resources. He was briefed by Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Administrator Deanne&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On May 18, President Biden met with leaders of his Federal emergency preparedness and response team to receive the annual briefing on the Atlantic Hurricane<s> </s>Season Outlook and to review progress on his directive to enhance equity and access to Federal disaster support and resources. He was briefed by Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Administrator Deanne Criswell, Administrator of the National Oceanographic and Atmospheric Administration Richard Spinrad, Director of the National Hurricane Center Kenneth Graham, Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marica Fudge, Small Business Administrator Isabella Guzman, U.S. Coast Guard Vice Commandant Admiral Linda Fagan, and Homeland Security Advisor Dr. Liz Sherwood-Randall.</p>



<p>The President was briefed on the projected hurricane activity for the upcoming season and how lessons learned from past years have improved accuracy in analysis and forecasting. &nbsp;Following this overview, the President had the opportunity to discuss the actions that FEMA, the Small Business Administration, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development have taken to ensure more equitable outcomes for underserved communities following a disaster.</p>



<p>The President also met with the brave men and women who fly into hurricanes and perform high-risk missions to provide early warning and real time analysis of severe storms in order to save American lives.&nbsp; He toured the aircraft with specialized technologies that are used to predict hurricane tracks and spoke with U.S. Coast Guard members who conduct search and rescue missions during hurricanes and other extreme weather events.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, May 18,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/18/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-may-18-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 23:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:11 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Sorry we’re starting a little late.&#160; We had to finish for the President to complete his remarks, and that was a request that we got from WHCA, so we wanted to make sure we adhered to it. As you all know,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:11 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Sorry we’re starting a little late.&nbsp; We had to finish for the President to complete his remarks, and that was a request that we got from WHCA, so we wanted to make sure we adhered to it.</p>



<p>As you all know, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan is here.&nbsp; He’s going to take your questions, preview Asia.&nbsp; And he has a hard out at 2:30, so we’re going to try and get him out of here.</p>



<p>Okay, all yours.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; And I have 20 minutes of remarks, so &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I hope you guys will bear with me.</p>



<p>I actually do have a number of things to get through because we have quite a stretch ahead here with respect to the President’s foreign policy and national security priorities.</p>



<p>Very good to be back with you guys today.</p>



<p>Today, Finland and Sweden submitted their applications for NATO membership.&nbsp; President Biden has welcomed those applications, and he looks forward to working with NATO Allies and with Congress on a swift accession process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Audio playback of press briefing interrupts.)</p>



<p>Oh, sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s all happening again.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Not a problem.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We got the audio.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Small interruption of the accession process right there.&nbsp; But everything will be on track just fine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Tomorrow morning, the President will welcome the President of Finland and the Prime Minister of Sweden to the White House to coordinate on the path forward.&nbsp; And the three leaders will also have the chance to compare notes on our united efforts to support Ukraine in its defense against Russia&#8217;s brutal invasion.</p>



<p>They will also have the opportunity to speak to the press and the public to affirm our shared vision for a peaceful and secure Euro-Atlantic region.</p>



<p>This is a historic event, a watershed moment in European security.&nbsp; Two nations with a long tradition of neutrality will be joining the world&#8217;s most powerful defensive alliance.&nbsp; And they will bring with them strong capabilities and a proven track record as security partners.&nbsp; And President Biden will have the opportunity to mark just what a historic and watershed moment this is when he meets with them tomorrow.</p>



<p>After that meeting concludes, President Biden will board Air Force One for a trip to the Republic of Korea and Japan.&nbsp; This will be his first trip as President to the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And it comes at a pivotal moment.</p>



<p>President Biden has rallied the free world in defense of Ukraine and in opposition to Russian aggression.&nbsp; He remains focused on ensuring that our efforts in those missions are successful.&nbsp; But he also intends to seize this moment &#8212; this pivotal moment &#8212; to assert bold and confident American leadership in another vital region of the world: the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>That began last week with his hosting of the U.S.-ASEAN Summit here at the White House, where he welcomed nine leaders from Southeast Asia for a substantive set of meetings that covered a diverse agenda from economics and security to technology and energy.</p>



<p>President Biden made a series of significant announcements to show that when it comes to engagement with ASEAN, we&#8217;re not just talking the talk, we&#8217;re walking the walk as well.</p>



<p>This week, the President turns his attention to Northeast Asia.&nbsp; And on this trip, he&#8217;ll have the opportunity to reaffirm and reinforce two vital security alliances, to deepen two vibrant economic partnerships, to work with two fellow democracies to shape the rules of the road for the 21st century, and to thank his allies in Korea and Japan for their remarkable and in some ways unexpected contributions to the effort to support Ukraine and to hold Russia accountable.</p>



<p>In Korea, President Biden will meet with the newly inaug- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; the newly inaugurated Korean President, President Yoon, who campaigned on the platform of strengthening the U.S.-ROK alliance and on improving relations between the ROK and Japan.</p>



<p>President Biden will engage with technology and manufacturing leaders in Korea who are mobilizing billions of dollars in investment here in the United States to create thousands of good-paying American jobs.</p>



<p>He will see American and Korean troops standing shoulder to shoulder in defense of our collective security and consult on the challenge posed by the DPRK’s nuclear and missile programs.</p>



<p>And he will highlight the truly global nature of the U.S.-ROK alliance, from climate and energy and technology to economic growth and investment.</p>



<p>In Japan, President Biden will meet with Prime Minister Kishida and his team.&nbsp; And we believe that the U.S.-Japan alliance, at this moment, under these two leaders, is at an all-time high.&nbsp; This visit can take us even higher.</p>



<p>The two leaders will consult on the broad and deep economic relationship between our two countries, as well as on a range of regional and global security issues.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll also cover the DPRK as well as a number of other security issues both in the Indo-Pacific and more broadly around the world.</p>



<p>The U.S.-Japan alliance is the cornerstone of peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific, and Japan&#8217;s contributions as a security partner are rightly growing as the regional security picture becomes more challenging and dynamic.</p>



<p>President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida will also be able to compare notes on the G7 agenda as the G7 Summit approaches next month in Germany.</p>



<p>In Japan, President Biden won’t just have a bilateral program, he&#8217;ll also have the opportunity to participate in the second in-person Quad Summit, following on the summit he hosted here in Washington last September.</p>



<p>He will do this alongside the Prime Minister of Japan, the Prime Minister of India, and the Prime Minister of Australia.&nbsp; And we believe that this summit will demonstrate, both in substance and in vision, that democracies can deliver and that these four nations working together will defend and uphold the principles of a free and open Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>While he&#8217;s in Tokyo, President Biden will also launch a new, ambitious economic initiative for the region: the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp; &#8220;IPEF,&#8221; as we affectionately call it, is a 21st century economic arrangement, a new model designed to tackle new economic challenges &#8212; from setting the rules of the digital economy, to ensuring secure and resilient supply chains, to managing the energy transition, to investing in clean, modern, high-standards infrastructure.</p>



<p>President Biden will be joined in person by the Prime Minister of Japan for the launch of IPEF and virtually by leaders from a number of Indo-Pacific partners, from Down Under to Southeast Asia to Northeast Asia.</p>



<p>On security and economics, on technology and energy, on investment in infrastructure, we think this trip is going to put on full display President Biden&#8217;s Indo-Pacific strategy and that it will show, in living color, that the United States can at once lead the free world in responding to Russia&#8217;s war in Ukraine and at the same time chart a course for effective, principled American leadership and engagement in a region that will define much of the future of the 21st century.</p>



<p>And with that, I&#8217;d be happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Can you talk to us about Turkey and what the administration is doing and what conversations you might be having with Turkey about their plans to block Finland and Sweden&#8217;s applications?&nbsp; Is there a deal to be struck with Turkey?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We&#8217;re confident that, at the end of the day, Finland and Sweden will have an effective and efficient accession process, that Turkey’s concerns can be addressed.</p>



<p>Finland and Sweden are working directly with Turkey to do this, but we&#8217;re also talking to the Turks to try to help facilitate.&nbsp; I spoke with my counterpart today; Secretary Blinken is meeting with his counterpart perhaps as we speak, in New York.&nbsp; And we feel very good about where this will track to.</p>



<p>And President Biden will express that confidence as we believe the President of Finland and Prime Minister of Sweden will express that confidence tomorrow.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Korean media is reporting that President Biden will meet with former President Moon Jae-in during his visit to Seoul.&nbsp; Is that accurate?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a meeting scheduled with President Moon at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have there been any discussions between U.S. officials and Korean officials about Moon Jae-in potentially taking on a “Special Envoy to North Korea”-like role?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not familiar with any discussions along those lines.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the statement today welcoming Finland and Sweden&#8217;s application to NATO, at the very &#8212; or almost at the very end, it said that “While their applications for NATO membership are being considered, the [U.S.] will work with Finland and Sweden to remain vigilant against any threats to our shared security, and…deter and confront aggression…”</p>



<p>Does that mean that the U.S. is extending, like, the NATO security umbrella to them while their applications are in process?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Article 5 only kicks in once all 30 Allies have ratified the accession protocols and they become full-fledged members of the Alliance.</p>



<p>But the United States is prepared to send a very clear message, as are all of our European allies, that we will not tolerate any aggression against Finland or Sweden during this process.&nbsp; And there are practical measures that we can take along those lines that Secretary Austin will coordinate with his counterparts in both Finland and Sweden.<br><br>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, two questions.&nbsp; One on the accession and one on your trip.<br><br>So, when the initial NATO expansion happened, of course, there was a huge debate in Washington about whether it was a good idea or not.&nbsp; I remember Kennan himself wrote in the New York Times that he wasn&#8217;t in favor of it.&nbsp; Was there any similar debate that went underway here about whether or not bringing Finland and Sweden in was a good idea, or whether it would further corner Putin?<br><br>And on the trip, tell us a little bit about what you know on the evidence that North Korea may attempt either a nuclear test &#8212; hard to imagine what they would accomplish by a seventh test, but &#8212; the seventh test &#8212; or a missile launch, and what your preparations are if that happens during the trip?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; On the first question, President Biden posed the question to his national security team, to his Cabinet principals who cover national security, as to whether they supported the accession of Finland and Sweden, and for them to consider the risks as well as the benefits of bringing Finland and Sweden into the Alliance.<br><br>Unanimously, President Biden&#8217;s national security team emphatically supported the entry of Finland and Sweden into the NATO Alliance on the grounds that they have already proven themselves as highly capable security partners.&nbsp; In the parlance, we say “net security contributors,” meaning they give a heck of a lot more than they take when it comes to a security partnership or an alliance.&nbsp; And that we believe that Russian aggression has only reinforced the argument for the kind of defensive alliance that &#8212; that NATO presents and poses.<br><br>And finally, we have the principle of the open door.&nbsp; And the open door says that if countries meet the criteria of NATO membership and display that they can be net contributors to the Alliance and to overall European security, they should be admitted.&nbsp; That is a principle that President Biden has believed since long before he occupied the Oval Office.&nbsp; And Finland and Sweden are two cases that are pretty clear-cut when it comes to meeting those terms.<br><br>With respect to the issue of North Korea, we&#8217;ve said from this podium, we&#8217;ve said at the State Department, and we&#8217;ve indicated in quite clear terms that our intelligence does reflect the genuine possibility that there will be either a further missile tests &#8212; including a long-range missile test or a nuclear test or, frankly, both &#8212; in the days leading into, on, or after the President&#8217;s trip to the region.<br><br>We are preparing for all contingencies, including the possibility that such a provocation would occur while we are in Korea or in Japan.&nbsp; We are coordinating closely with our allies in both Korea and Japan on this.&nbsp; We have spoken with counterparts in China.&nbsp; I met &#8212; I spoke with my Chinese counterpart this morning and covered this issue of the DPRK.&nbsp;<br><br>And we are prepared, obviously, to make both short- and longer-term adjustments to our military posture as necessary to ensure that we are providing both defense and deterrence to our allies in the region and that we&#8217;re responding to any North Korean provocation.<br><br>Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, thank you.&nbsp; Two questions on different topics.&nbsp; One, could you update us on the situation with the Russian blockade on grains?&nbsp;<br><br>And also, on Haiti: What happens with the Title 42 with the Haitian migrants and maybe migrants of South America as well in the Caribbean when it comes to the end of Title 42 on May 23rd, if that happens?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, it is Russia&#8217;s war of aggression against Ukraine and nothing else that is stopping tens of millions of tons of food from getting out of the breadbasket of Europe &#8212; Ukraine &#8212; and onto the world market to feed people in Africa, the Americas, Asia, and everywhere else.&nbsp;<br><br>And that is true in two critical respects: First, Russia is bombarding Odessa, which is the port from which that food departs on large cargo ships bound through the Black Sea and then on to the world market.&nbsp; Second, Russian ships are engaged in an effective blockade of commercial ship traffic that would &#8212; could leave Odessa Port, were not under this bombardment, and head out to the world.<br><br>So we have publicly called upon Russia to end its attacks on Odessa and to end the blockade and to permit the traffic &#8212; the commercial and humanitarian traffic of ships into and out of Odessa Port.<br><br>We are working closely with both Ukraine and the United Nations on this issue, as well as other allies and partners.&nbsp; And we are supporting efforts to facilitate the delivery of that grain to the world market so that it can alleviate food prices everywhere.<br><br>And we would like to see an outcome in which the facts &#8212; not just the rhetoric &#8212; the facts bear out the actual permission by Russia of large numbers of ships moving through the Black Sea and onto the world market.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Russia responding to that request?&nbsp; And also the question I asked you about Title 42.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There are ongoing intensive diplomatic conversations.&nbsp; The United Nations Secretary-General is involved in this, the Ukrainians are involved in this, some of our other partners are involved in this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of those discussions.&nbsp; I&#8217;m only going to say that the United States stands ready in any way to help facilitate and deliver on that diplomacy to try to produce an outcome in which food is getting to the world stage.<br><br>With respect to Haiti, we will have to see.&nbsp; Obviously, there are a number of issues bound up in the courts right now.&nbsp; But with the end of Title 42, the United States has put in place a process by which those individuals who claim asylum and have legitimate asylum claims can stay and those who come and don&#8217;t will go through the process &#8212; the legal process that exists and has existed for some time.<br><br>Even when Title 42 was in effect, large numbers of individuals were not subject to Title 42; they were subject to the standard legal process by which we deal with claims at our border for people who want to come and stay here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on Ukraine again: U.S. intelligence chiefs recently offered assessments that Putin continues to bank on the fracturing of Western resilience to continue this war.&nbsp; Is Turkey&#8217;s concern about Finland and Sweden joining up perhaps an example of that?&nbsp;<br><br>And what about the, I guess, also congressional pushback, or the growing congressional pushback, to Ukrainian aid?&nbsp; What are you guys doing, sort of, in both regards to make sure that that doesn&#8217;t continue to happen?&nbsp; I know you’ve described some of it, but it does seem now that there are examples of these growing concern or criticism resistance.<br><br>And then I got one other on another part of the world.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, growing congressional pushback, to me, is a strange premise for a circumstance in which the House of Representatives voted overwhelmingly not just in favor of approving what the President sent up, which was $33 billion, but actually adding $7 billion to it to make a $40 billion package.&nbsp; And we expect a similar overwhelming bipartisan vote in the Senate once the final procedural hurdle &#8212; hurdles are cleared over the next 24 to 48 hours.<br><br>So there are some voices against this, but the chorus of voices on both sides of the aisle, from all sides of the political spectrum, in favor of standing up in defense of Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty and freedom and independence &#8212; it’s quite powerful and, frankly, in a way, quite moving.&nbsp; And it sends a clear message to the world that the United States can pull together behind the brave people of Ukraine in their hour of need.</p>



<p>What was your other question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, just Turkey’s continued concern here and whether there might be others who are going to raise concern about NATO expansion.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Look, the great thing about the free world &#8212; about the Western alliance, about NATO &#8212; is that you’ve got a raucous collection of states that all have opinions, that all have perspectives, that all have interests.&nbsp; But they also know how to and when to pull together and how to settle any differences.&nbsp; And I expect these differences will be settled.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I expect that NATO will speak with one voice in support of Finland and Sweden at the end of the day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the remarkable unity you&#8217;ve seen with respect to sanctions coming out of the EU, the United States, and our Indo-Pacific partners; the support that we have provided Ukraine in terms of military and humanitarian assistance &#8212; it&#8217;s only grown stronger over the course of the last 12 weeks, and we expect that that momentum will continue, and it&#8217;s having a major impact on the battlefield.</p>



<p>Ukraine won the Battle of Kyiv.&nbsp; Ukraine has now beaten Russia back from Kharkiv.&nbsp; And Ukrainian defenders are putting the military assistance we provided to good use in defending territory in the Donbas as well.</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a little bit about the challenges of trying to focus on the Indo-Pacific &#8212; a priority for you all to get-go &#8212; given just &#8212; I mean, look, a bulk of the questions even here today have focused on other parts of the world.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, Finland and Sweden are going.&nbsp; Just the juxtaposition of what is going on in the world right now as you all are trying to focus (inaudible).</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; And, you know, it&#8217;s interesting, we actually don&#8217;t regard this as a tension between investing time, energy, and attention in Europe and time, energy, and attention in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; We regard this as mutually reinforcing.</p>



<p>First, look at the Indo-Pacific partners that have stepped up to help make these sanctions and export controls as effective as they are: Korea, Japan, Australia, even Singapore.</p>



<p>Second, look at the extent to which European countries are increasingly invested in the Indo-Pacific, in helping ensure that our vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific is actually realized.&nbsp; We see that with the AUKUS partnership, where you&#8217;ve got the United Kingdom alongside Australia and the United States.&nbsp; We see it with the way the European Union has, for the first time ever, put out an Indo-Pacific strategy.</p>



<p>And so, actually, we think that there is something quite evocative about going from meeting with the President of Finland and the Prime Minister of Sweden to reinforce the momentum behind the NATO Alliance and the free world’s response in Ukraine, and getting on a plane and flying out to the Indo-Pacific not just to deal with security issues, but to unveil a new far-reaching economic initiative, to host a Quad summit that will cover climate and cyber and emerging technologies, and to deal with Korea and Japan on issues that actually affect working people here in the United States, including major investments that will create jobs in states across the country.</p>



<p>So, for us, there is a certain level of integration and a symbiosis in the strategy we are pursuing in Europe and the strategy we&#8217;re pursuing in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And President Biden&#8217;s unique capacity to actually stitch those two together is, I think, going to be a hallmark of his foreign policy presidency.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can you provide an update on when the President will visit Israel?</p>



<p>And secondly, can you elaborate further on the specific security guarantees that the United States has made Finland and Sweden in the interim period?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, on Israel, we are actively working with the Israelis to fix a date for the visit at some point in the not-too-distant future.&nbsp; The President is very much looking to go.&nbsp; But unfortunately, I don&#8217;t have an announcement of a trip or a timetable for it standing here today, other than to say the President is excited to get the opportunity to go to reaffirm the strength of the U.S.-Israel relationship.</p>



<p>With respect to the specifics on security commitments or assurances or actions that we will take with Finland and Sweden, those are ongoing conversations that are happening at an operational and technical level between our Department of Defense and their ministries of defense, and also with other NATO Allies and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I&#8217;ll leave it in those channels for now &#8212; only to say that the U.S. stands ready to ensure that deterrence and defense for Finland and Sweden will be there should they need it, even though they don&#8217;t get the full benefits of the Article 5 Alliance until the accession process is properly complete, as is required, frankly, under our Constitution, where we need to get advice and consent from the Senate for that treaty.</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERE:&nbsp; Last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Regarding the trip, to what extent is the message on this trip going to be like a cautionary tale delivered to China to say, “Look what happened in Ukraine.&nbsp; Look how we&#8217;ve responded.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t do anything similar”?&nbsp; Is that going to be part of the messaging during the President’s trip?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The message we&#8217;re trying to send on this trip is a message of an affirmative vision of what the world can look like if the democracies and open societies of the world stand together to shape the rules of the road, to define the security architecture of the region, to reinforce strong, powerful, historic alliances.</p>



<p>And we think putting that on display over four days &#8212; bilaterally with the ROK and Japan, through the Quad, through the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework &#8212; it will send a powerful message.&nbsp; We think that message will be heard everywhere.&nbsp; We think it will be heard in Beijing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it is not a negative message, and it&#8217;s not targeted at any one country.&nbsp; It&#8217;s targeted at an audience the world over about what American leadership, working flanked by allies and like-minded partners, can deliver for people everywhere.</p>



<p>And we think we go into this trip very much with the wind at our back, with a strong case to make that we have what it takes to be able to deliver against the security and economic challenges of our time.</p>



<p>And President Biden will head into the Indo-Pacific with a spring in his step, and we&#8217;re very much looking forward to this visit.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the President visit the DMZ, Jake?&nbsp; Will the President visit the DMZ?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; You can ask Karine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He will not visit the DMZ.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He will not.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He will not.&nbsp; He will not.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not?&nbsp; Why not visit the DMZ?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Just not on this trip.&nbsp; He will not.&nbsp; He will go to South Korea, as you know.&nbsp; They will have an agenda to talk about a lot of things, including North Korea.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s not going to the DMZ.</p>



<p>And just to &#8212; just to reiterate here is that, as Vice President, he has been there before.&nbsp; But on this trip &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But now he&#8217;s President, and his predecessor went &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He’s just not &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; former President Obama went.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But he&#8217;s just not going to go on this trip.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to go to South Korea.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to show his support for the region.&nbsp; And &#8212; but he&#8217;s not going to go to South Korea on this trip &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, the DMZ on this trip.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; We all love Jake.&nbsp; Thank you so much for your patience.&nbsp; And I have one topper, and then we&#8217;ll get to it.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; The Senate took an important step today with the bipartisan agreement announced by Chair Tester and Ranking Member Moran to advance their vision of the Hon- &#8212; of the Honoring Our Promise to Address Comprehensive Toxics Act of 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden has championed legislation to deliver the benefits and healthcare services that veterans impacted by toxic exposures have earned.&nbsp; This historic comprehensive bill will do just that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The PACT will not only help deliver more timely access to benefits and services for veterans and their survivors, it will also ensure that the Department of Veterans Affairs can act more nimbly to add future presumptive conditions when the evidence warrants.&nbsp; And the legislation will help the VA provide our veterans the level of service they deserve.</p>



<p>President Biden believes that we have a sacred obligation to support veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why as part of this first state of the &#8212; of his first State of the Union address, he identified supporting veterans as a key pillar of his Unity Agenda and an issue that can unite the country, Republicans and Democrats.</p>



<p>Passing the PACT Act would be a welcome and long-awaited achievement for the veterans who have served us well.</p>



<p>Darlene, you have the floor.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wanted to ask Jake this question, but I&#8217;ll ask you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about the Quad summit.&nbsp; And there is a possibility that Saturday&#8217;s election in Australia will not produce a winner in time for someone to go to Tokyo to participate in the Quad summit.&nbsp; So what contingencies are there?&nbsp; Will the one meeting go ahead if Australia cannot participate?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I believe that the Quad meeting will go ahead.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more specifics than that about the &#8212; you know, how that&#8217;s going to affect any further, deeper.</p>



<p>But from what I understand, and even Jake said this, that there&#8217;s going to be a Quad summit.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp; We can &#8212; we can talk more about the specifics of what will &#8212; you know, what it will look like with Australia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, the First Lady&#8217;s Office informed us that Ashley Biden, the President&#8217;s daughter, is positive for COVID.&nbsp; Can you tell us when was the last time the President tested negative?&nbsp; Is he testing today in preparation for travel?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp; So, the President tests regularly throughout the week as part of a cadence determined by his doctor.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve &#8212; as we&#8217;ve communicated, the President is not a close contact with Ashley.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been several days that they last &#8212; he and the First Lady last saw Ashley; I think about a week is what I&#8217;ve been told.</p>



<p>If his testing were to change because of a close contact, we’d let all of you know.&nbsp; But his cadence has not changed.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have when he last tested.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one final question on the church attack in California over the weekend.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t seen the President comment on that at all.&nbsp; Is he concerned that what happened there could somehow destabilize relations between Taiwan and China?&nbsp; Does he have any plans to call or reach out to Taiwan or China, or anything like that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any calls to preview of &#8212; calls with Chinese and Taiwan as it relates to this particular case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our thoughts are with all those affected by gun violence, including the incidents &#8212; the other incidents that at &#8212; that happened this weekend in Houston, in Milwaukee, in Chicago, and, as we know, in Buffalo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Federal law enforcement is supporting as needed.&nbsp; And the White House has been in touch with local leaders.&nbsp; These shootings and, of course, the one in Buffalo, as the President and the First Lady went to offer &#8212; went to grieve with the community yesterday, as all of you know, are a sad reminder of how important it is to redouble our eff- &#8212; our fight against gun violence and violent crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as part of the President&#8217;s comprehensive strategy to fight gun crime, we&#8217;re putting more cops on the beat, as you&#8217;ve heard us say this past year and a half; as we’re &#8212; talked about a gun comprehensive approach here, cracking down on firearms trafficking, investing through the art and community programs to prevent crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have any more to share on any calls that may have had occurred.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, I&#8217;m going to go to people who haven’t asked a question.&nbsp; Go ahead, Ashley.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; Following up on Darlene, on Ashley Biden having COVID: She&#8217;s in good company in this White House in that the Vice President had it, the Second Gentleman had it, you had it, Jen Psaki had it twice, a number of top Cabinet officials had it, a number of other aides in the West Wing.&nbsp; And no one so far that I can remember has been deemed a close contact of the President.&nbsp; Why are none of these people close contacts of the President &#8212; and his sister, actually &#8212; including family members?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, are there steps that the President is taking beyond the CDC guidelines that you could lay out?&nbsp; Are meetings in the Oval being kept &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; under 15 minutes?&nbsp; Is everyone masked?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m glad to be &#8212; said I was in good company.&nbsp; Appreciate that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But &#8212; so it is &#8212; we take extra precautions, to your last question &#8212; I&#8217;ll answer that first &#8212; here at the White House.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve said this before: When we&#8217;re in a meeting &#8212; I was in a meeting with the President earlier today.&nbsp; I got tested first.&nbsp; I put my mask on, and we socially distanced.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those are the extra protocols that we do take with the President and all the principals, not just him, just to make sure that we just take that extra added step there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, you know, the close contact is as it&#8217;s deemed by CDC. And he hasn&#8217;t seen Ashley in several days.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s also &#8212; there&#8217;s a time component to how long that person was in the room.&nbsp; We all wear masks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, yeah, I mean, the way we &#8212; if he &#8212; if he is &#8212; if there was a close contact or he&#8217;s a close contact of someone, we would let you know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on guns: Yesterday, when he was leaving Buffalo, the President said, “I&#8217;ve got to convince the Congress that we should go back to what I passed years ago.”&nbsp; I just want to confirm that he was referring to the 1994 assault weapons ban.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And my question is: You know, when he was the point person for President Obama after Sandy Hook, Manchin-Toomey &#8212; which went far less far than an assault weapons ban &#8212; failed.&nbsp; What makes him think that he could get that through when, so far, no meaningful legislation has gone through in the past decade?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, this is what the President said yesterday.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; He understands it&#8217;s not going to be easy, but he knows that there&#8217;s more to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, our country is facing an epidemic that is very real, as we have seen this past weekend, as gun violence is costing lives every single day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, when he was in Buffalo, we saw examples of that.&nbsp; He talked to the family &#8212; talked to them in a very personal way.&nbsp; And this is a top priority for the President, as it&#8217;s been throughout his career.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you just mentioned, he mentioned his own legislation that he passed.&nbsp; Look, the President continues to urge Congress to act to pass universal background checks, to keep guns out of the wrong hands, and to renew a ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines to keep weapons off our streets.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not going to be easy.&nbsp; He understands that.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s going to continue to work very hard to make that happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I do want to add, Ashley, is that this administration has done more on gun violence reform via executive action than any other President in its first year in their administration. So that is the &#8212; his commitment and what he&#8217;s &#8212; what he&#8217;s done just this year and a half.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Jake mentioned his conversation with his Chinese counterpart.&nbsp; This morning, the readout you guys gave was pretty sparse, and so I was wondering if you can give any more details of that conversation, and particularly, sort of, an update on how the White House has seen China&#8217;s actions towards Russia in light of Ukraine.&nbsp; I know that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any more to read out outside of what you &#8212; what was put out by us earlier today.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to keep it to that readout.&nbsp; And &#8212; and, you know, Jake has spoken to this before, about China and their relationship with Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We haven&#8217;t seen any evidence of any, like, material that has been provided to Russia.&nbsp; That continues to be the case.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more to add on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask about a pair of bills on Capitol Hill right now &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; both being forwarded by House Democrats.&nbsp; One is a Consumer Fuel Price gauging &#8212; Gouging Prevention Act, and the other is this domestic terrorism legislation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I haven&#8217;t seen statements of administration policy on either, and I&#8217;m wondering how supportive the President is, particularly on the domestic terrorism legislation.&nbsp; He kind of &#8212; on the tarmac yesterday, he seemed to say that he didn&#8217;t think it was necessary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on the &#8212; the price &#8212; the gas price gouging legislation that you just mentioned: Look, the President welcomes all ideas to protect consumers and to make sure that oil companies aren&#8217;t taking advantage of Putin&#8217;s war and are competing fairly.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been very clear on that.</p>



<p>President Biden has been also very clear that no company should be engaging in unfair practices to hike prices on American consumers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President has said, President Putin&#8217;s actions are what is driving the price increase at the pump.&nbsp; The President is focused on doing everything in his power to address the Putin price hike, including the largest-ever release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, as we&#8217;ve talked about here at this podium, and working around the clock diplo- &#8212; to diplomatically build a coalition of countries for the largest release in foreign reserves ever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know that there are a number of ideas being suggested by our allies and in Congress, and look forward to engaging on this issue so we can get Americans some relief, especially as we&#8217;re in this particular time right now with high prices.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one last on the Dow.&nbsp; It’s down 1,100 points so far today.&nbsp; Chairman Powell did an interview with the Wall Street Journal in which he said he’d push forward on additional rate hikes, even if it resulted in unemployment coming up.&nbsp; Also, presumably baked into that is that the stock market &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen the stock market do poorly as the Fed hikes rates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, do you still, I guess, stand behind Chairman Powell’s vision on rate hikes?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And broadly, you guys have said that you&#8217;re not following day-to-day market tribulations, but we&#8217;re now getting to a point where some of the gains that defined the President&#8217;s tenure are being erased.&nbsp; And so, is there a new level of alarm within the White House about the stock market?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know &#8212; and we say this all the time, Josh &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s &#8212; Justin &#8212; the Fed chair &#8211;you know, the Federal Reserve is independent.&nbsp; We leave them to make their own policy decisions.&nbsp; We do not get involved in that.&nbsp; And nothing has changed on how we see the stock market. We do not &#8212; that&#8217;s not something that we keep an eye on every day.&nbsp; And so, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to comment about that from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do want to touch base on the domestic terrorism and what the President said yesterday about the &#8212; about domestic terrorism.&nbsp; Look, it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a growing and evolving threat and one that the Biden administration has taken very seriously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since our first day in office, we have said we have been studying the details of different proposals.&nbsp; And there are a range of ideas that have been proposed in Congress that could improve our ability to detect and respond to these threats.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What the President was specifically referring to yesterday when he was on the tarmac was the set of existing laws on the &#8212; on the books that provide law enforcement with authorities to investigate and prosecute domestic terrorism and hold those who commit hate-filled attacks accountable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As part of our National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism, we increased our support for federal, state, and local law enforcement as they address domestic terrorism nationwide, including increasing resources and providing traines [sic] &#8212; trainings to thousands of law enforcement entities.</p>



<p>DOJ has made domestic terrorism-related investigation and prosecution a top priority at the national and local level.&nbsp; And plus, DOG [sic] &#8212; DOJ, earlier this year, announced the creation of a new domestic terrorism unit with the counterterrorism section &#8212; sec- &#8212; section of the National Security Division that will enforce the expertise and experience on these issues available to federal prosecutors nationwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there is a commitment there. &nbsp;And that&#8217;s what he was talking about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re about three weeks away from the Summit of the Americas.&nbsp; You got Chris Dodd down in Mexico today &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; trying to convince President López Obrador to come. What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s level of optimism that Mexico will attend this Summit of the Americas?&nbsp; And, well, is the guest list finalized?&nbsp; Has the President decided who to invite?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The guest list is not finalized.&nbsp; Hopefully that will happen soon.&nbsp; And I promise, once we have it, we will share it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, the President is optimistic.&nbsp; You know, we don&#8217;t have anything to share at this moment.&nbsp; Again, once we have it, we&#8217;ll be happy to share it with all of you.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; DHS said today that they&#8217;ll be pausing the Disinformation Governance Board.&nbsp; Did the White House play a role at all in perhaps expressing frustration on how it was rolled out or expressed any &#8212; involvement in how it &#8212; whether or not it should be paused?</p>



<p>And then also, some experts have said that it was sort of set up to fail the way it was rolled out.&nbsp; Do you have a response to that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the board has never convened.&nbsp; It &#8212; so that&#8217;s &#8212; it never convened, and the board is &#8212; yes, the board is pausing in the sense that it will not convene while former Secretary Chertoff and former Deputy AG Gorelick do their assessment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the Department&#8217;s work across several administrations to address disinformation that threatens the security of our country is critical, and that will indeed continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, neither Nina Jankowicz nor the board have anything to do with the censorship or with removing content from anywhere.&nbsp; Their role is to ensure that national security officials are updated on how misinformation is affecting the trea- &#8212; the threat &#8212; the threat environment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She has strong credentials and a history of calling out misinformation from both the left and the right.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s &#8212; and that&#8217;s our focus.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So did the White House &#8212; did the White House play a role at all in whether it should be paused or what should happen with &#8212; with the board?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; First of all, like I said, this &#8212; this is what&#8217;s happening: There is a pause.&nbsp; We did not have an involvement in this at all.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just another quick question.&nbsp; Congressman Schrader, who received a rare endorsement from the President in a Democratic primary, is on track to lose.&nbsp; What does that say about the power of the President&#8217;s endorsement?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, I &#8212; as it comes to &#8212; you know, I have to be careful about what I can say here.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; But we &#8212; you know, the race in Oregon was focused on just how much each candidate support the President &#8212; supported the President.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we saw in this particular race.&nbsp;<br><br>His &#8212; his counterpart in the race, McLeod-Skinner, ran on a &#8212; an agenda of President Biden&#8217;s priorities, including lowering the price of prescription drugs and tackling climate change and the fossil fuel pledge.&nbsp;<br><br>Her support for President Biden extends back to 2020 election, when she said, “He&#8217;s the guy.&nbsp; He knows how to choose a great team.”&nbsp; On the campaign trail, McLeod-Skinner has sought to tie herself to President Biden and paused &#8212; and praised his presidency.<br><br>Even on day one President Biden endorsed Representative Schrader, McLeod-Skinner wrote, “I respect Biden&#8217;s work to tackle COVID-19 and rebuild our economy.” &nbsp;In February, McLeod-Skinner praised President Biden&#8217;s effort at diplomacy around the situation in Ukraine.&nbsp; McLeod praised President Biden&#8217;s plan to lower health and &#8212; care costs, eldercare costs, childcare costs, and prescription drug costs as a transform- &#8212; formative &#8212; “transformative investment in the future of Oregon&#8217;s families.”<br><br>So, that&#8217;s how we see it.&nbsp; We think it’s both &#8212; both sides were very much supportive of the President.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Karine, just to follow up though, I mean, the question is &#8212; this &#8212; both of them had similar platforms, to your point.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yep.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yet President Biden endorsed one of them, and that candidate is on track to lose.&nbsp; So are there concerns within the President &#8212; and I know you can&#8217;t speak to politics of this &#8212; is the President concerned &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Not at all.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that he doesn&#8217;t have enough juice heading into these critical midterms?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, not at all.&nbsp; Because, again, both candidates were running on a platform that supported, embraced the President&#8217;s pla- &#8212; the President&#8217;s agenda.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President reached out to any of the Democratic winners overnight, particularly John Fetterman, who is still in the hospital?&nbsp; Cheri Beasley?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any calls to read out, but I do believe the one thing that I can say here is that he spoke &#8212; last night, the President did speak to Gisele Fetterman, and wished the governor &#8212; wished the lieutenant governor a speedy recovery.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And the President said of Fetterman’s win and of the Republicans who were still locked in a pretty tight battle in Pennsylvania: “[W]hoever emerges will be too dangerous, too craven, and too extreme to represent Pennsylvania” and the United States.&nbsp; Do the Democrats run the risk of underestimating the Republican Senate nominee in Pennsylvania &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and gubernatorial nominee?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, the President remains really focused on delivering for the American people.&nbsp; And what you see from congressional Republicans and what you see from the GOP is &#8212; the plan for American people is to raise taxes to &#8212; in the middle class, to sunset Social Security and Medicare, and to take away a woman&#8217;s right to reproductive healthcare.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to speak against that.&nbsp; He is going to continue to speak for the American public.&nbsp; And so, he&#8217;s not going to stay quiet.&nbsp;<br><br>And that &#8212; and this is something that is incredibly important to make sure that the American people and &#8212; and what he&#8217;s doing to &#8212; for the American people is &#8212; is &#8212; you know, is made sure that it&#8217;s &#8212; it happens, right?&nbsp; What the &#8212; what the other side is trying to do is trying to stop us from trying to lower costs for &#8212; for folks, as we &#8212; as I just laid out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, just very quickly, Senator Raphael Warnock is saying that he&#8217;s coming to the White House to meet with the President today.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about that, about student loans?&nbsp; And is the President open to increasing the forgiveness rate?&nbsp; It seems like he&#8217;s in the $10,000 range.&nbsp; Senator Warnock wants it to be closer to $50,000.&nbsp; Would the President come up?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we meet with members of Congress on a variety of issues.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he going to meet with Senator Warnock today?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; These are senators who have been leaders on college affordability and sent- &#8212; and student debt.&nbsp; The President values their perspective and looks forward to the discussion this afternoon.&nbsp; So, yes.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have more to read on that.<br><br>There&#8217;s &#8212; we &#8212; you know, I&#8217;ve said this a couple of times: We don&#8217;t &#8212; a decision hasn&#8217;t been made yet.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there timeline yet for &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a timeline.&nbsp; A decision hasn&#8217;t been made yet.</p>



<p>Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; A follow-up to the disinformation board.&nbsp; Last week, you guys said that you needed this Disinformation Governance Board at DHS to make sure that freedom of speech is protected across the country and that these platforms are not used for forms of disinformation.&nbsp; So what changed?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, the Department of &#8212; of Homeland Security, they began their statement report- &#8212; repeating that the board had been intentionally mischaracterized, which is a little bit of what you were asking me, and they were explicit about what it does and doesn&#8217;t &#8212; it does not do.<br><br>It was never about censorship, poli- &#8212; policing speech, or removing content from anywhere.&nbsp; Its function was to keep Homeland Security officials aware of how bad actors &#8212; including human smugglers, transnational criminal organization, and foreign adversaries &#8212; could use disinformation to advance their goals.<br><br>As Secretary Mayorkas said, he has asked former DHS Secretary Michael Chertoff and former DO- &#8212; DAG Jamie Gorelick to lead a thorough review &#8212; this is the pause that I was talking about &#8212; and assessment as members of the bipartisan Homeland Security Council &#8212; Advisory Council.<br><br>The board will not convene during that period.&nbsp; But the department&#8217;s work across several administrations to address disinformation that threatens the security for our country is critical and will continue.&nbsp; So that work is going to continue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So if it&#8217;s pausing because you think the board was mischaracterized, then the disinformation board is being shut down because of disinformation?&nbsp; Is that what&#8217;s happening here?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I mean, the &#8212; the board was put forth for a purpose &#8212; right? &#8212; to make sure that we really did &#8212; really did address what was happening across the country when it came to disinformation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s okay to wait now at 75 days to address &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, no, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s just &#8212; it&#8217;s going to pause.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a mischaracterations [sic] from outside &#8212; outside forces.&nbsp; And so, now what we’re going to do is going to &#8212; we’re going to pause it and we&#8217;re going to do an assessment.&nbsp; But the work does &#8212; the work doesn&#8217;t stop.&nbsp; We&#8217;re still going to continue the work.&nbsp; The DHS is still going to continue the work.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a bulletin now that DHS is worried if Roe v. Wade is overturned, there could be violence against the Supreme Court building or Supreme Court justices.&nbsp; Are these threats from pro-abortion activists or anti-abortion activists?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, the President is clear on this question.&nbsp; He believes the right to peace- &#8212; to peacefully protest in this country is fundamental, but he also believes that violence, threats, and intimidation have no place in political discourse anywhere.&nbsp; That is true whether it is in front of a courthouse or in front of a healthcare clinic.<br><br>And that&#8217;s the thing.&nbsp; I feel &#8212; it seems like, to us, it is very one-sided on what we call out as &#8212; as intimidation or as violence.&nbsp; So we want to make sure we&#8217;re calling out on &#8212; on ei- &#8212; on both sides of what is happening and what we&#8217;re seeing.<br><br>While protests &#8212; but while protests have been peaceful to date, the Department of Justice has U.S. Marshals providing support to support [the Supreme] Court Marshal, and the Pres- &#8212; and the President believes Congress should pass the legislation to fund increased security for Court and judges as soon as possible.<br><br>Yesterday, in reference to this, the Department of Homeland Security said they are “committed to protecting Americans’ freedom of speech and other civil rights and civil liberties, including the right to peacefully protest.&nbsp; DHS is also committed to working with our partners across every level of government and the private sector to share timely information and intelligence, prevent all forms of violence, and to support law enforcement &#8212; enforcement efforts to keep our communities safe.”</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, final question, on gas prices: Americans are now spending $5,000 a year on gasoline.&nbsp; That&#8217;s almost double what they did a year ago.&nbsp; Where are people supposed to go to get all that extra cash?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; To get the extra cash to pay for gas?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I mean, one of the things that we&#8217;ve been very clear about is to do everything in our power to make sure that we lower costs.&nbsp; You know, it is important &#8212; we see it.&nbsp; The President understands what the American people is &#8212; are &#8212; is going through.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doing everything that we can.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made multiple announcements in the past several &#8212; several months of what we&#8217;re doing &#8212; whether it&#8217;s just the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, whether it&#8217;s the ethanol 15, to make sure that that &#8212; that the American people are not feeling Putin&#8217;s price hike.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is where this is coming from.&nbsp; Sixty to seventy percent of the current price hike that we have seen has come from Putin&#8217;s aggression against Ukraine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the President announces on March 31st that he&#8217;s got all these steps to lower gas prices, and it&#8217;s still Putin&#8217;s fault, seven weeks later?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, because &#8212; what I&#8217;m saying is, since the war &#8212; since Putin&#8217;s war &#8212; aggression against Ukraine started back in February &#8212; we did see a spike.&nbsp; But before then, it had &#8212; the price &#8212; the &#8212; the price per gallon had fallen down about 10 cents or more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then Putin started his aggression on Ukraine &#8212; his violent aggression on Ukraine &#8212; against their democracy, against their &#8212; against their sovereignty.&nbsp; And we saw about &#8212; I mean, the facts show it went up about 60 to 70 percent.&nbsp; So it is Putin’s tax hike.&nbsp; This is what we&#8217;re talking about.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that same subject &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would you come to the back &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on inflation &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; at some point?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The inflation concerns are now rubbing off on quarterly earnings, reports for a lot of big companies &#8212; Target, for example, today says it missed its estimates because of increased costs of transportation, in gas.&nbsp; That&#8217;s part of what&#8217;s driving this at least 1,100-point drop in the Dow so far.&nbsp; What would you say, what does the White House say to investors and everyday Americans who are concerned that there&#8217;s no end in sight to these price hikes?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, you know, I&#8217;m not &#8212; again, I&#8217;m not going to speak to the stock market.&nbsp; But, you know, this is something that is very important to the President, when it comes to inflati- &#8212; inflation and making sure that we lower costs for the American people.<br><br>Last week, we announced new steps with private sector to lower the price of high-speed Internet for ten &#8212; tens of millions of Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President traveled to Illinois to announce new actions to give farmers the tools and resources so &#8212; they need to boost production, lower prices, and &#8212; and feed the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The nonpartisan Congressional Budget Office found that the deficit fell by $1.5 trillion this year, putting us on track for the fastest deficit reduction in any year on record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These actions build on other actions the President has taken to lower costs in recent weeks.&nbsp; Again, you know, this is to &#8212; this is to address Putin&#8217;s price hike at the pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President, as I was saying, and allies and partners around the world &#8212; they came together.&nbsp; And he was talking about the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, the 1 million barrels of oil per day for the next six months, in addition to a &#8212; to the 60 million barrels of oil from other countries’ reserve.&nbsp; I talked about the E15 gasoline that we have allowed to happen so that it could be sold this summer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President also announced administrative actions to save hundreds of thousands of families hundreds of dollars per month by fixing the Affordable Care Act&#8217;s family glitch.&nbsp; These are the things that we have been working on &#8212; this President has been working on for the past several months, understanding that it is important to lower the cost of &#8212; the costs for American families.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to try and go to the back.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; You, sir.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Oh, sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thanks a lot, Karine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about President Biden&#8217;s long-term thinking on Ukraine?&nbsp; There&#8217;s a possibility this war could go on for months or years.&nbsp; And what is the President&#8217;s commitment to supplying weapons to Ukraine in the long term?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, there is a &#8212; there is a supplemental &#8212; there is a funding &#8212; a Ukraine funding that&#8217;s in the Senate right now for about $40 billion that we are encouraging the Senate to pass.&nbsp; And so, that is going to be part of helping &#8212; continuing to help Ukraine with material, with defense material and humanitarian aid.</p>



<p>Look, this is something that&#8217;s incredibly important to the President, but also to our partners and allies, that we make sure that Ukraine is able to defend their democracy.&nbsp; It is important for us as a country, as a leader in this &#8212; in this world to make sure that we&#8217;re doing everything that we can so that happens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What hap- &#8212; what is happening in Ukraine &#8212; defending their democracy, defending their territorial integrity, defending their sovereignty &#8212; affects us all.&nbsp; So, this is something that we are going to continue to be partners with &#8212; with our allies, our partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The &#8212; Jake was talking about the NATO Alliance and how strong they are, how unified, how they&#8217;re speaking in one voice in a &#8212; in a way that we have not seen in years.&nbsp; And so, this is something that we need to be &#8212; continue to be a leader on, and that&#8217;s what he believes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s important to make sure that we protect our country&#8217;s democracy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What preparations is the President making if Putin escalates after the &#8212; after Finland and Sweden join NATO?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to go into hypotheticals.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to focus on what&#8217;s happening here and now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, again, I think one of the things that we have to remember: This is a war that Putin started.&nbsp; This is a war &#8212; his aggression, his violent &#8212; very violent war that we have seen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Ukraine &#8212; Ukrainians and their government have fought very bravely.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen that with Kharkiv.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that &#8212; what they&#8217;ve done in Kyiv.&nbsp; It is remarkable what they have been able to do in fighting back this aggression against their &#8212; against their country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that is going to be our focus, to make sure that they have everything that they need to be &#8212; to have a &#8212; to strengthen their &#8212; kind of their table when it comes to hopefully having some diplomacy and getting to an end of this war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in the meantime, we have to support them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jonathan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; In the wake of the Buffalo shooting, there been several civil rights groups who have expressed some unhappiness at the lack of outreach from the Biden White House and frustration about a lack of progress on hate crimes, gun violence, and so on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ll just read you one: The Reverend Al Sharpton, who has visited the White House several times, says, quote, “This administration has met less with civil rights and civil liberty groups than previous administrations in a formal substantive way.”&nbsp; He goes on to say that they even asked for meeting here in the wake of this shooting, and, quote, “We&#8217;ve got no response from the White House.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Can you give an update on this?&nbsp; And will there be a meeting with civil rights groups?&nbsp; And can you address his frustrations?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have any meetings to read out for you or any meetings scheduled at this time.&nbsp; You know, we respect the Reverend.&nbsp; He has been here many times before, as you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Are you talking about the letter that the &#8212; that the &#8212; from gun &#8212; gun rights groups have written?&nbsp; There were about 40-plus that &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He says &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think it was in your &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, that &#8212; that &#8212; there’s that, but &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; he says civil rights groups have also asked the White House for a meeting (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, we’ve met with civil rights groups over the last year and a half.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any meetings to read out to you at this time.</p>



<p>Look, the one thing I do want to say is that, you know, the President agrees with these groups on the urgency of acting, and he applauds the work that they&#8217;re doing to rally support around the country for a commonsense agenda to fight the epidemic of gun crime.&nbsp; He understands that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the reasons he went to Buffalo &#8212; to have that conversation, to grieve with the family.&nbsp; And he spoke to them in a very personal way.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>There&#8217;s a couple of things from that letter that I do want to just &#8212; just talk about a little bit, since it was in your publication.&nbsp; He agrees that innovative, neighborhood-based crime prevention programs like community violence intervention need to be at the core of our toolkit to make our <s>common sense</s> [communities] safer.&nbsp; </a>That’s why the President has unlocked existing money within the government to invest in community violence intervention.&nbsp; That’s why he secured more than &#8212; more money for that in his 2022 budget.&nbsp; And that’s why he’s calling for a significance increase in funding in his 2023 budget.&nbsp; He is calling for a $5 billion investment over 10 years.</p>



<p>The President also is going to continue to call on Congress &#8212; he talked about this yesterday when he was in Buffalo &#8212; to pass commonsense gun violence legislation that would keep weapons off our streets and keep guns out of the hands of criminals.&nbsp; We’re working closely with Leader Schumer and Speaker Pelosi on this and other issues, and will defer to their judgment on legislative mechanics, give them space to work on that and to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, on the question of a gun violence coordinator &#8212; I was asked that yesterday; I think I was asked specifically about an office.&nbsp; You know, Ambas- &#8212; we have Ambassador Susan Rice here, who is the Chair of the Domestic Policy Council, as you all know.&nbsp; And she is coordinating the President’s whole-of-government approach to reducing gun violence, leading a 12-person team that connects violence reduction to broader resources, like mental health supports, workforce development opportunities, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She has decades of experience coordinating interagency process in the federal government.&nbsp; There’s no one who is better at bringing stakeholders to the table to drive progress, and we know that’s so &#8212; that’s important because tackling an issue as complex, and gun vi- &#8212; and gun violence requis [sic] &#8212; requires a multidisciplinary approach.&nbsp; And we’re talking about housing, mental health, community support, all of the things &#8212; apprenticeship &#8212; all of the things that are so important in order to deal with this issue.</p>



<p>I’m trying to &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>Oh, my gosh.&nbsp; I’m trying to call on people I haven’t gotten yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, we have to go?&nbsp; All right, guys, I’m so sorry.&nbsp; We have to go.&nbsp; But we will &#8212; we will &#8212; hopefully I’ll see some of you in Asia.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have a good trip.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Bye.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re all the way back here in Siberia.&nbsp; You can visit anytime.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; I &#8212; next time.&nbsp; Next time, I promise.&nbsp; I did call somebody back there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>3:08 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Roundtable with&#160;Nurses</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-nurses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 23:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, in recognition of Nurses Appreciation Week, the White House hosted a roundtable with nurses to thank them for their efforts on the frontlines of the pandemic, providing essential health care and ensuring patients receive the care they deserve.&#160;&#160;The roundtable, which was convened by White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein, brought together nurses&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, in recognition of Nurses Appreciation Week, the White House hosted a roundtable with nurses to thank them for their efforts on the frontlines of the pandemic, providing essential health care and ensuring patients receive the care they deserve.&nbsp;&nbsp;The roundtable, which was convened by White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein, brought together nurses from across the country who work in various specialties – including maternal health and mental health – and with populations including youth, pregnant and postpartum women, military service members and their families, as well as veterans.<br>&nbsp;<br>Participants discussed the devastating impact the pandemic has had on nurses and other health care workers, as well as patients, families, and communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;They underscored the importance of addressing the pandemic-related burnout, advancing gender equity in health care, including through supporting women’s health care, and tackling the national mental health crisis.&nbsp;&nbsp;Participants also highlighted the need to sustainably grow and support the nursing workforce.&nbsp;&nbsp;Administration officials reaffirmed the White House’s commitment to recognizing, supporting, and strengthening America’s nurses and underscored President Biden’s support for emergency COVID-19 funds to ensure we continue to have the vaccines, tests, and treatments we need to protect the American people, keep America moving forward safely and prepare for potential surges to come.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>External participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Dr. Lucinda Canty, CN.M.&nbsp;Assistant Professor of Nursing and&nbsp;certified nurse-midwife&nbsp;</li><li>Joshua Holt, ICU Registered Nurse, American Federation of Teachers</li><li>Catherine Kennedy, Registered Nurse, Vice President, National Nurses United&nbsp;</li><li>Dr. Adrianna Nava,&nbsp;Chief Nurse of Quality and Systems Improvement (QSI) at the Edward Hines Medical Center, President of National Association of Hispanic Nurses.&nbsp;</li><li>Colonel Dr. Kathy Spangler DNP, RN, Director of Fort Belvoir Community Hospital, DOD</li><li>Dr. Jennifer Strawn, Acting Deputy Chief Nursing Officer Nursing Services, Department of Veterans Affairs&nbsp;</li><li>Yvette Zebaze, RN, Registered Nurse, SEIU Member Local 512&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under the Defense Production Act to Ensure an Adequate Supply of Infant&#160;Formula</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/18/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-the-defense-production-act-to-ensure-an-adequate-supply-of-infant-formula/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 22:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential Determination No.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;2022-13 MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES SUBJECT: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegating Authority Under the Defense Production Act to Ensure an Adequate Supply of Infant Formula By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;101 of the Defense Production&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right">Presidential Determination<br> No.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;2022-13</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</p>



<p>SUBJECT: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegating Authority Under the Defense Production Act to Ensure an Adequate Supply of Infant Formula</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;101 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the &#8220;Act&#8221;) (50 U.S.C. 4511), it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Policy and Findings. &nbsp;On February 17, 2022, the largest infant formula manufacturer in the country &#8212; Abbott Nutrition &#8212; initiated a voluntary recall of several lines of powdered infant formula made at its Sturgis, Michigan facility, following concerns about bacterial contamination at the facility after four infants fell ill.&nbsp; This incident has combined with supply chain stress associated with effects of the coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic to cause an acute disruption in the supply of infant formula in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Adequate supply of infant formula is critical to the health and safety of the millions of children who depend on the formula for essential nutrition.&nbsp; The Federal Government has worked in the last several months to address the shortfall in infant formula, but additional measures are needed to ensure an adequate supply of infant formula in the United States and thereby protect the health and well-being of our Nation&#8217;s children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This disruption threatens the continued functioning of the national infant formula supply chain, undermining critical infrastructure that is essential to the national defense, including to national public health or safety.&nbsp; As the Abbott Nutrition recall shows, closure of a single formula-producing facility can severely disrupt the supply of formula nationwide.&nbsp; Accordingly, I hereby determine, pursuant to section 101 of the Act, that the ingredients necessary to manufacture infant formula meet the criteria specified in section 101(b) of the Act (50 U.S.C. 4511(b)).</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Ensuring the Continued Supply of Formula<em>.</em>&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Notwithstanding Executive Order 13603 of March 16, 2012 (National Defense Resources Preparedness),the authority of the President conferred by section 101 of the Act to require performance of contracts or orders (other than contracts of employment) to promote the national defense over performance of any other contracts or orders, to allocate materials, services, and facilities as deemed necessary or appropriate to promote the national defense, and to implement the Act in subchapter III of chapter 55 of title 50, United States Code (50 U.S.C. 4554, 4555, 4556, 4559, 4560), is delegated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to all health resources, including the ingredients necessary to manufacture infant formula.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; The Secretary of Health and Human Services may use the authority under section 101 of the Act to determine, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the heads of other executive departments and agencies as appropriate, the proper nationwide priorities and allocation of all ingredients necessary to manufacture infant forumla, including controlling the distribution of such materials (including applicable services) in the civilian market, for responding to the shortage of infant formula within the United States.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter from President&#160;Biden to Secretary Xavier Becerra and Secretary Thomas Vilsack on  Addressing Infant Formula&#160;Shortage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/letter-from-president-biden-to-secretary-xavier-becerra-and-secretary-thomas-vilsack-on-addressing-infant-formula-shortage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 22:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Secretary Becerra and Secretary Vilsack, The Departments of Agriculture and Health and Human Services, including the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), have taken significant action over the last several months to boost the production and availability of infant formula after the voluntary recall and subsequent shutdown of one of the largest infant formula production&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Secretary Becerra and Secretary Vilsack,</p>



<p>The Departments of Agriculture and Health and Human Services, including the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), have taken significant action over the last several months to boost the production and availability of infant formula after the voluntary recall and subsequent shutdown of one of the largest infant formula production facilities in the country in February. &nbsp;This shutdown was needed to ensure the highest safety standards were being met but resulted in a decline in production of formula that American families rely on. &nbsp;Your departments have worked closely with manufacturers to help them increase formula production and availability, which resulted in more formula produced in April than before the recall. &nbsp;By working with States and retailers to create flexibilities around the types of formula WIC recipients can purchase, we are helping all families access the formula they need.</p>



<p>This week, the FDA reached an agreement with Abbott, the formula manufacturer whose product was pulled from shelves. &nbsp;This agreement will enable Abbott to restart production safely so more infant formula will be produced and distributed over the coming weeks and months. &nbsp;The FDA also announced an expedited process for manufacturers who do not normally sell infant formula in the United States to begin to sell it here safely and efficiently. &nbsp;This additional, high-quality formula should begin to hit shelves within weeks.</p>



<p>Imports of baby formula will serve as a bridge to this ramped up production, therefore, I am requesting you take all appropriate measures available to get additional safe formula into the country immediately.</p>



<p>Specifically, I request that you work expeditiously to identify any and all avenues to speed the importation of safe infant formula into the United States and onto store shelves.&nbsp; I&nbsp;further request that over the next week you work with the Department of Defense to utilize contracted aircraft to accelerate the arrival of infant formula into the United States that meets our Government&#8217;s health and safety standards. &nbsp;This will ensure that we are using every available tool to get American families swifter access to the infant formula they need.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                       <br>JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces New Actions to Address Infant Formula&#160;Shortage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-new-actions-to-address-infant-formula-shortage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 22:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the infant formula shortage caused by Abbott Nutrition’s voluntary recall, the President has directed his team to do everything possible to ensure that there is enough safe infant formula in the country and available for families that need it. Today, President Biden is announcing additional actions to get more formula into the United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>During the infant formula shortage caused by Abbott Nutrition’s voluntary recall, the President has directed his team to do everything possible to ensure that there is enough safe infant formula in the country and available for families that need it.</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing additional actions to get more formula into the United States and onto store shelves.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Invoking the Defense Production Act.</strong> To ensure that manufacturers have the necessary ingredients to make safe, healthy infant formula here at home, President Biden is invoking the Defense Production Act (DPA). The President is requiring suppliers to direct needed resources to infant formula manufacturers before any other customer who may have ordered that good. Directing firms to prioritize and allocate the production of key infant formula inputs will help increase production and speed up in supply chains.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Launching Operation Fly Formula.</strong> To speed up the import of infant formula and get more formula to stores as soon as possible, President Biden has directed the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) and U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) to use Department of Defense (DOD) commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. DOD will use its contracts with commercial air cargo lines, as it did to move materials during the early months of the COVID pandemic, to transport products from manufacturing facilities abroad that have met Food and Drug Administration (FDA) safety standards. Bypassing regular air freighting routes will speed up the importation and distribution of formula and serve as an immediate support as manufacturers continue to ramp up production.</li></ul>



<p>Earlier this week, FDA and Abbott agreed on next steps to reopen Abbott’s facility in Sturgis, Michigan, which was closed due to concerns about bacterial contamination after four infants fell ill. FDA also announced guidance that will allow major formula manufacturers to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. The Administration continues to urge states to cut red tape and implement WIC flexibility, as USDA wrote to states in a letter last week. The Administration remains in close touch with manufacturers and retailers to identify transportation and logistical needs to increase the amount and speed of FDA approved formula being shipped into the country, and ensure that formula is quickly moving from factories to retailers.</p>



<p>Today’s steps further underscore the Administration’s commitment to addressing the formula shortage quickly and safely, and the Administration will continue working overtime to get more formula to stores as soon as possible.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at United&#160;States Coast Guard Academy&#8217;s 141st Commencement&#160;Address</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-united-states-coast-guard-academys-141st-commencement-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 21:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United States Coast Guard AcademyNew London, Connecticut 11:50 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning, Bears.  (Applause.)  Good morning to all.  Secretary Mayorkas, thank you for your steadfast leadership on so many of our nation’s most pressing issues.  I am grateful for your dedication to public service for our country and to the safety and wellbeing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>United States Coast Guard Academy<br><em>New London, Connecticut</em></em></p>



<p>11:50 A.M. EDT <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning, Bears.  (Applause.)  Good morning to all.  Secretary Mayorkas, thank you for your steadfast leadership on so many of our nation’s most pressing issues.  I am grateful for your dedication to public service for our country and to the safety and wellbeing of our country.<br>                                                                      <br>Admiral Schultz, Rear Admiral Kelly, congratulations to you both.  I was honored to have some time to talk with you both before we came out.  And we truly have a gift in your life of service.  Thank you for that.<br><br>Governor Lamont, faculty and staff, family and loved ones: It is an honor to be with you this morning.<br><br>I am also proud to be joined today by my Military Aide, Lieutenant Commander Lauren Milici, who graduated from this academy in 2009.  She is &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes.  She has traveled around the world with me, and this is her last trip.  Lauren, I am so thankful for your service.<br><br>And to the Class of 2022: Congratulations on this tremendous achievement.<br><br>All you have been through, from that first 5:00 a.m. wake-up call during Swab Summer to dipping your rings in the waters of the seven seas at the Ring Dance, you have traveled on this remarkable journey together.<br><br>I hope you look to your left and look to your right and know you have made lifelong friendships.  You have dedicated yourselves to relationships that will last throughout your career.<br><br>And you made it through, together, in such a demanding military training and a rigorous academic program in order to serve your country in the world’s greatest Coast Guard. <br> <br>A Coast Guard, I should note, that has been strengthened, of course, under the leadership of Admiral Schultz, and a Coast Guard, as Admiral Schultz mentioned, that will soon be led by Admiral Fagan, the first woman in history to lead a United States military service.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And to all the parents and loved ones who are here: I know  you are feeling an immense sense of pride in these Cadets today.  And it is a pride that I share, especially when I talk about them, which I do, with other world leaders.<br><br>President Joe Biden and I, well, we view our Cadets as our eyes and ears and hands and hearts wherever you serve, at home or abroad.  You are doing the critical work &#8212; you will be doing the critical work to protect our country, to advance our interests, and to shape the trajectory of world affairs.<br> <br>We applaud you all for all you have done &#8212; as families, as loved ones &#8212; to develop the Cadets that they are today.<br><br>I have had the personal honor of working closely with the Coast Guard over the years, from my time as Attorney General of California to being Vice President of the United States.  And I know who you all are.  I know that you Cadets possess highest level of training, professionalism, and excellence.  <br> <br>And, Cadets, I will then share with you my perspective on where I believe we are in the world today, the work of the Coast Guard, and your role in both.<br> <br>I will start with how I see the world.<br> <br>You all graduate into a world that’s going to need your leadership &#8212; one that is full of possibility and the promise of progress. <br> <br>At the same time, the world you graduate into is unsettled.  It is a world where long-established principles now stand on shaky ground, where the rule of law in places is strained, where rules and norms are under question.<br> <br>We see this in Russia’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, where fundamental principles are under threat – principles that are well grounded in the belief that sovereignty and territorial integrity of all nations must be respected, the belief that<br>all people have a right to peacefully choose their own leaders, and that borders must not be changed by force. <br> <br>For a time, it seemed as though these rules and norms<br>would prevail.  Now, they are being called into question.<br> <br>And the challenges we face are broader than Russia.<br> <br>Around the world, we see additional attempts to undermine the rules-based order: nations that threaten the freedom of the seas, criminal gangs and traffickers who skirt the rule of law and fuel corruption and violence, those that manipulate and undermine the foundations of international commerce.<br> <br>When I think about protecting the security of the United States and the world, I am clear-eyed.  One of our defining missions is to strengthen the international rules-based order &#8212; to defend it, to promote it, and to build on it.<br> <br>Over time, this order has been tried and this order has been tested.  And far too often, I will share with you, I think we have taken it for granted.  Frankly, sometimes we forget how rare it is in human history to have a period of relative peace and stability among nations.<br> <br>We must remember, upholding a system of laws, institutions, and common understandings &#8212; this is how we ensure the safety and security and prosperity of the United States.  And this is how we preserve stability in the world.<br> <br>Cadets, this is where you come in.<br> <br>In addition to the work you will do at home, you will serve a vital role in advancing our nation’s interests abroad.<br> <br>For example, just last week, in Washington, D.C., I chaired a meeting with nine leaders from Southeast Asia.  I spoke with them about the United States Coast Guard &#8212; about you &#8212; with pride.<br> <br>I informed them that we are sending a new cutter to Southeast Asia to serve as a training platform; that we are sending additional Coast Guard personnel to help them build their law enforcement capacity; and that we are launching new initiatives to crack down on illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing in the region.<br> <br>(Bells begin to chime.)<br> <br>These leaders have told me before, and they said again: Ours is a vital partnership.  And what I will tell you, as the bells ring, is the presence of the United States Coast Guard is a reminder to the world that we, as the United States, are committed to a free and open Indo-Pacific and that it is a priority for our own national security.<br> <br>Of course, your influence abroad extends far beyond Southeast Asia.  The Coast Guard has more than 60 bilateral and multilateral agreements around the world.  When you partner with these foreign governments, you strengthen our global standing.<br> <br>And to be clear, if our nation is to be strong abroad, we must also be strong at home.  And every single American, in addition to you, Cadets, has a role to play in bettering our nation.<br> <br>Today is a joyous occasion, but it is impossible to ignore that we gather mere days after a horrific act of hate in Buffalo, New York &#8212; another despicable attack in the epidemic, I fear that may be happening, of hate that we must condemn. <br> <br>I spoke earlier about international rules and norms.  But there are also rules and norms that what &#8212; we must, as Americans, hold on to as each other, as Americans &#8212; rules and norms founded in the belief that a harm against any one of us is a harm against all of us; that hate and violence have no place here in America; and that we are &#8212; we are all in this together as one nation, undivided.<br> <br>I look out at you, Cadets, and I see the very best of America.  I see a group of individuals, each with your own life experience &#8212; a group who came together to become a strong, cohesive unit in service of the greater good; a group bound by shared values and the belief that out of many, one.  Enter as many, leave as one.<br> <br>As a nation, we&#8217;re going to count on you to hold us to that ideal. <br> <br>Now, as officers in our Coast Guard, you will work together as a unit, of course, to better our nation.  And your work every day is going to help ensure the safety, security, and prosperity of the American people.<br> <br>When you serve on a cutter in the Western Pacific, you will protect the sea and the sea lanes, where billions of dollars of trade flow.  And you will support the jobs and livelihood of millions of Americans. <br> <br>When you serve at port &#8212; a port like Savannah or Long Beach &#8212; you will ensure that families have access to the goods they need, when they need them, at a price they can afford. <br> <br>This is the connection between the work you do and all that happens around the world, right into what happens in the households of American families. <br> <br>When you patrol the American shores, looking for drug traffickers, you will help prevent harmful products from reaching our communities. <br> <br>When you work on critical and emerging areas like cybersecurity and the climate crisis, you will help push our country forward into new frontiers. <br> <br>In everything you do, you will embody America&#8217;s values and you will enhance our strength as a nation, which is why your role in both the world and the Coast Guard is so important.<br> <br>Class of 2020, your lived experience makes you uniquely suited for the task at hand.  I don&#8217;t have to tell you: You are a generation that grew up online.  In fact, your class, of course, includes the first graduates in the history of this institution that will have a degree in cyber systems.   (Applause.)  That&#8217;s very impressive. <br> <br>You came of age in a post-9/11 era defined by threats like the climate crisis and a global health pandemic.<br> <br>You are familiar with a world that, frankly, feels strange and new to so many of us. <br> <br>And I believe you have the ability to see what can be, unburdened by what has been; to learn from the past, but not be limited by it; to identify new opportunities for our Coast Guard to lead both in today&#8217;s unsettled world and far into the bright, beautiful future. <br> <br>We need your perspective, and we need your expertise.  In just a few short minutes, you will take an oath and become officers in the United States Coast Guard.  And as you do, I ask you: Remember how you feel right now &#8212; your excitement about this journey, your excitement about the world, about your service, about your future.  Remember how you feel in this moment, because that will help guide you in each of your assignments ahead. <br> <br>President Biden and I have great faith in your ability.  We know you are ready &#8212; ready to serve.  And your country is so proud of you. <br> <br>Congratulations again.  May God bless you.  And may God bless the United States of America.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END            12:06 P.M. EDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Briefing on Interagency Efforts to Prepare for and Respond to&#160;Hurricanes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/18/remarks-by-president-biden-before-briefing-on-interagency-efforts-to-prepare-for-and-respond-to-hurricanes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 20:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George’s County, Maryland 2:02 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, folks, first of all, concluding this tour with Admiral Linda Fagan, Vice Commander of Coast Guard &#8212; soon to be the Commander of the Coast Guard; and Administrator Spinrad of NOAA, it &#8212; it really is amazing what &#8212; what you all do&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George’s County, Maryland</p>



<p>2:02 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, folks, first of all, concluding this tour with Admiral Linda Fagan, Vice Commander of Coast Guard &#8212; soon to be the Commander of the Coast Guard; and Administrator Spinrad of NOAA, it &#8212; it really is amazing what &#8212; what you all do to protect us, and it&#8217;s astounding.&nbsp; I still marvel at the idea that somebody jumps out of a perfectly good helicopter in the middle of the ocean to save people.&nbsp; But it really is amazing what you all do.</p>



<p>You know, I met with some of these brave women and men who perform these high-risk missions &#8212; and they are &#8212; trying to help not only deal with but predict the hurricanes &#8212; the severity of them, where they&#8217;re going to land, and flying right into the heart of them.</p>



<p>I &#8212; including the dedicated personnel from the Air Force, NOAA, the Coast Guard, who help warn about hurricanes that are forming and predict their strength, what they&#8217;re likely to be, and &#8212; and keep Americans safe.</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s not going to &#8212; this job is not going to slow up anytime soon.&nbsp; It&#8217;s likely to get &#8212; I&#8217;m here to get a read on what&#8217;s going to happen, what the hurricane season this year is going to look like.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re prepared for the upcoming hurricane season.</p>



<p>My message to all Americans is straightforward: We know hurricanes are coming our way.&nbsp; They grow more extreme every season thus far.&nbsp; Pay attention to the hurricane warnings.&nbsp; And, and, and &#8212; follow &#8212; follow the guidance of your local authorities.</p>



<p>While you do everything you can to protect yourself and your families, I promise you we &#8212; all of us here &#8212; are going to do everything we can to protect you.</p>



<p>Our top priority is to help Americans prevent, prepare, and respond in every community to what we&#8217;re going to &#8212; what&#8217;s going to happen.</p>



<p>And our &#8212; you know, one of our charges is &#8212; well, put another way, one the changes I directed is that &#8212; to ensure that the piles of paperwork and the bureaucratic excuse &#8212; excuses we&#8217;ve &#8212; been used in the past sometimes don&#8217;t stand in the way of getting to help the most disadvantaged communities as fast as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know it&#8217;s not preventing but, in the aftermath, you know, you&#8217;ve done an incredible job.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve done an incredible job of making sure we&#8217;re not leaving anybody behind.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>And I &#8212; unfortunately, I&#8217;ve visited too many devastated areas with you &#8212; hurricanes, tornadoes, floods, et cetera.&nbsp; You do an incredible job.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why HUD and Marcia Fudge, Secretary of HUD; and the SBA Administrator Isabel Guzman is &#8212; briefed me today, along with FEMA and &#8212; and Administrator Criswell.</p>



<p>In 2021, it was the third-most active hurricane season ever recorded, including the first hurricane to hit the Northeast in 30 years, killing more than 100 people and causing billions &#8212; billions of dollars in damage. </p>



<p>And given the climate crisis, it’s likely to &#8212; we expect another tough hurricane season.&nbsp; And storms are going to be more intense, and we’re going to have shorter notice, as we saw last year with Hurricane Ida.<br><br>That’s why the work of these women and men is so important.&nbsp; And we’re going to continue to ensure Hurricane Hunters and their partners have what they need to get their job done.</p>



<p><br>It’s about &#8212; this isn’t about red states and blue states; it’s about helping communities prepare, having their back when the hurricane strikes, and being there to help, being the &#8212; there to help clear the roads, rebuild the Main Streets so families can get back to their lives.<br><br>And so, we don’t have a moment to lose.&nbsp; But I want to thank the leaders and the personnel assembled here for all the work you do, and I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; And I look forward to hearing from you.<br><br>And I&#8217;ve had the opportunity to, with notable exception &#8212; I can only think of one &#8212; visit every serious area that has been affected by fires, hurricanes, tornadoes.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, as I was talking to Deanne, our Administrator, yesterday, you know, we&#8217;ve lost more territory burned to the ground because of fires &#8212; forest fires than the entire state of New Jersey, from the New York border all the way down to the end of New Jersey, more has been lost.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an enormous amount of damage.&nbsp; And the firefighters are risking their lives and losing them sometimes.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I wish everybody &#8212; I think they do know, but I wish they knew how serious, how prepared, and how much risk all of your folks take in order to get things done.<br><br>So, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m ready to be briefed on all you have to tell me.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re going to tell me, “No hurricanes this year.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how will you convince Turkey to support Sweden and Finland’s NATO bid?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I’m going to say one thing.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to be &#8212; I got a call months ago from the President of Finland, wanted to come and see me.&nbsp; I saw him.&nbsp; He told me what he was thinking about.&nbsp; And then I got a call that both the leader of Finland and Sweden are coming to see me on Thursday.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to be okay.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can convince Turkey to accept their bid?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I &#8212; I think &#8212; I’m not going to Turkey, but I think we’re going to be okay.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>2:08 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Bipartisan Senate Agreement to Advance Toxic Exposure&#160;Legislation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/statement-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-bipartisan-senate-agreement-to-advance-toxic-exposure-legislation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 19:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Senate took an important step today&#160;with the bipartisan agreement announced by Chair Tester and Ranking Member Moran to advance the Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson Honoring Our PACT Act of 2022, their version of the&#160;Honoring Our Promise to Address Comprehensive Toxics (PACT) Act of 2022.&#160;President Biden has championed legislation to deliver the benefits and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Senate took an important step today&nbsp;with the bipartisan agreement announced by Chair Tester and Ranking Member Moran to advance the <em>Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson Honoring Our PACT Act of 2022, </em>their version of the&nbsp;Honoring Our Promise to Address Comprehensive Toxics (PACT) Act of 2022.&nbsp;President Biden has championed legislation to deliver the benefits and health care services that veterans impacted by toxic exposures have earned. This historic, comprehensive bill will do just that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The PACT Act will not only help deliver more timely access to benefits and services for veterans and their survivors, it will also ensure that the Department of Veterans Affairs can act more nimbly to add future presumptive conditions when the evidence warrants. And, the legislation will help VA provide our veterans the level of service they deserve.</p>



<p>President Biden believes that we have a sacred obligation to support veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors. That’s why, as part of his first State of the Union address, he identified supporting veterans as a key pillar of his Unity Agenda and an issue that can unite the country — Republicans and Democrats. Passing the PACT Act would be a welcome and long-awaited achievement for the veterans who have served us so well. &nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health Officials &#124; May 18,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/18/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-may-18-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 17:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:52 A.M. EDT DR. JHA:&#160; All right.&#160; Good morning, everybody.&#160; My name is Ashish Jha, and I&#8217;m the White House COVID-19 Response Coordinator.&#160; Welcome to the COVID-19 Response Team update.&#160; Sorry for the delay.&#160; We had some technical issues, but we have solved them, I&#8217;m hoping. I am joined today by two people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:52 A.M. EDT<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; My name is Ashish Jha, and I&#8217;m the White House COVID-19 Response Coordinator.&nbsp; Welcome to the COVID-19 Response Team update.&nbsp; Sorry for the delay.&nbsp; We had some technical issues, but we have solved them, I&#8217;m hoping.<br><br>I am joined today by two people who don&#8217;t need introductions: Dr. Rochelle Walensky and Dr. Tony Fauci.&nbsp; And I will turn to both of them in a minute.<br><br>I want to start off by just taking about five minutes to talk about where we are in this pandemic, what&#8217;s going on, the things that are doing &#8212; going well, things that are challenges ahead.<br><br>So if we take a step back and begin with where we are as a country, we have more than 200 million Americans vaccinated, more than 100 million Americans boosted.&nbsp; We have a pretty high degree of immunity in our population.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re also seeing, at this moment, a lot of infections across the country.&nbsp; Depending on which tracker you use, we&#8217;re at about 100,000 infections of &#8212; cases a day.&nbsp; And we know that the number of infections is actually substantially higher than that &#8212; hard to know exactly how many, but we know that a lot of people are getting diagnosed using home tests.<br><br>Home tests are great, by the way.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been a huge fan of home tests for the last two years.&nbsp; But what that means is we&#8217;re clearly undercounting infections &#8212; undercounting cases.<br><br>There&#8217;s a lot of infections across America.&nbsp; What&#8217;s driving that?&nbsp; What is primarily driving that is these incredibly contagious subvariants.<br><br>We were hit with the BA.1 &#8212; .1 &#8212; wave of infections in December, January.&nbsp; We saw BA.2.&nbsp; And now we&#8217;re seeing, in a large chunk of the country, BA.2.12.1.&nbsp; They are more contagious with more immune escape, and they are driving a lot of the increases in infection that we&#8217;re seeing across the nation right now.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; that is a huge challenge.<br><br>So how are we thinking about this moment?&nbsp; And you&#8217;ll hear, by the way, more on all of that both from Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci.<br><br>So how are we thinking about that?&nbsp; Very broadly &#8212; and we can get into more details later &#8212; very broadly, the way we&#8217;re thinking about this is: We&#8217;ve got to do what we can to prevent infections.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to do what we can to &#8212; to ensure that infections don&#8217;t turn into severe illness.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to continue being on the lookout for new variants, new subvariants; continue to do that surveillance. &nbsp;<br><br>And then last, but certainly not least, is we&#8217;ve got to take a very glo- &#8212; much a global footing, a global strategy, because we know that there is no only &#8212; “domestic-only” strategy to a global pandemic.&nbsp; And that means remaining deeply globally engaged and doing what we can &#8212; we&#8217;ve done an extraordinary job of &#8212; of acquiring vaccines and making sure they&#8217;re widely available for the world, we&#8217;ve now got to continue that work by making sure that we&#8217;re getting vaccines into people&#8217;s arms.<br><br>All right.&nbsp; So I want to talk about two major things, two recent developments that have happened over the last few weeks.&nbsp; And then I also want to talk about funding and Congress.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;m going to wrap up and turn it over to Dr. Walensky first and then Dr. Fauci after.</p>



<p>So, two major developments.&nbsp; If you&#8217;ve been watching, we have launched a third round of tests that you can get from COVIDTests.gov. &nbsp;<br><br>What&#8217;s that about?&nbsp; Why are we doing that?&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing that because the administration has put in a lot of work and resources from &#8212; that we had from ARP to &#8212; to acquire tests and make sure we had adequate number of tests.<br><br>Given the &#8212; the spread of infections that&#8217;s happening across the country, we know use of rapid tests is a very effective way of keeping infections down.&nbsp; You can test yourself before you go to a large gathering, before you go visit someone vulnerable. &nbsp;<br><br>It is an important way of reducing spread of the virus.&nbsp; There’s very good evidence that the use of rapid tests can reduce the amount of infections that&#8217;s happening out there.&nbsp; So this is one of the tools we have, one of the capabilities we have.<br><br>We opened that up on Monday to a third round.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen really impressive demand.&nbsp; As of about 20 minutes ago, when we got the latest set of numbers &#8212; this opened up on Monday &#8212; about almost eight and a half million households across the country have ordered that next round of tests.<br><br>We have made eight tests available per order.&nbsp; The reason is &#8212; in the past, we were able to do four.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve expanded that because of the &#8212; the testing that we&#8217;ve been able to obtain.&nbsp; We know there are multi-generational households.&nbsp; We know that there are households with more than four people.&nbsp; And we want to make sure that we make as many tests as we can possibly make available.<br><br>And so that&#8217;s getting out there.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s going to be an important part of how we keep infections down.<br><br>On the issue of how do we make sure that infections don&#8217;t turn into severe illness: When I came into this job about five, six weeks ago &#8212; again, under Jeff Zients’s leadership &#8212; the administration, I think, had done an extraordinary job of obtaining and acquiring Paxlovid and other therapeutics.</p>



<p>And yet six weeks ago, despite acquiring all that, the Paxlovid had not started really getting out there.&nbsp; We put in a series of steps.&nbsp; We made it much more widely available by letting pharmacies order directly from &#8212; from the federal government.&nbsp; We expanded test-to-treat sites.&nbsp; There&#8217;s going to be more on that coming in the days and weeks ahead.&nbsp; We did a big effort to connect with providers and simplify the ordering and prescription process, making sure they understood what drug &#8212; drug interactions really mattered, who was eligible. &nbsp;<br><br>And then we talked more broadly to the media &#8212; all of us did.&nbsp; And what we have seen, I think, is a dramatic increase in the use of Paxlovid &#8212; about fourfold increase just in the last month.&nbsp; And our latest estimates are that about 20,000 prescriptions of Paxlovid are being given out every single day.<br><br>I think that is actually a really important reason why, despite this very substantial increase in infections, we have not seen a commensurate increase in deaths.&nbsp; We have seen hospitalizations rise but, again, not as much as one would have expected at this point, despite the fact that hospitalizations do lag.&nbsp; When you look at ICU care, the rate of ICU hospital admissions is much lower than one &#8212; what one would expect with infections.&nbsp; And then death numbers continue to be low.&nbsp; Obviously, we want to continue to drive that lower.<br><br>But I really think that, beyond the vaccinations and boosting, which are making a very big difference, I think Paxlovid is making a very big difference as well.<br><br>Okay.&nbsp; Just a little bit about Congress and where we are with Congress.&nbsp; As you may have heard, we&#8217;ve been spending a lot of time with our friends in Congress on making sure that we have the resources we need to continue to protect the American people.<br><br>As I have laid out, the key tools, the key capabilities that we know prevent infections and reduce severity &#8212; masking, testing, vaccinations, therapeutics, ventilation, and filtration, of course, as well &#8212; those are the major tools.&nbsp; And we want to make sure that as this virus continues to evolve, as we go into the fall and winter, that we&#8217;re able to continue to protect Americans.<br><br>Again, you&#8217;ll hear more about this from Dr. Fauci, but they &#8212; we’re in the middle of developing new vaccines, potentially bivalent vaccines; FDA is going to be looking at the data on this, making decisions.&nbsp; Our expectation is that we&#8217;ll probably get a new generation of vaccines, or certainly we need to plan for that. &nbsp;<br><br>And I want to make sure we have enough resources that we can buy enough vaccines for every American who wants more.&nbsp; I think that is absolutely critical.&nbsp; We do not have the resources to do that right now. &nbsp;So without additional funding from Congress, we will not be able to buy enough vaccines for every American who wants one once these new generation of vaccines come out in the fall and winter.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re using therapeutics to save lives; we&#8217;ve got to continue doing that.&nbsp; At some point, we&#8217;re going to run out of the treatments we have.&nbsp; And without additional resources, we will find ourselves in the fall or winter with people getting infected and no treatments available for them because we will have run out.&nbsp; There are new generations of treatments that are coming online, companies that are making them with some very promising data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. government and no one in the United States is in negotiations with these companies for these treatments because we don&#8217;t have the resources; the companies know that.&nbsp; And therefore, we can&#8217;t ensure that Americans get access to the next generation of therapies that will also be available.</p>



<p>And what &#8212; if we don&#8217;t get more resources from Congress, what we will find in the fall and winter is we will find a period of time where Americans can look around and see their friends in other countries &#8212; in Europe and Canada &#8212; with access to these treatments that Americans will not have. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Last, but certainly not least, is on the issue of testing: We&#8217;ve done a lot of work to build up domestic manufacturing capacity to purchase tests.&nbsp; Obviously, demand for tests falls when infection numbers drop.&nbsp; As that happened, it was really important for us to step in and keep that demand high enough so that companies could continue manufacturing.&nbsp; Without additional resources, we&#8217;ve already started seeing this.&nbsp; Companies and domestic manufacturers are laying off workers, they&#8217;re shutting down production lines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the upcoming weeks, we&#8217;re going to see them sell off their equipment and get out of this business.&nbsp; And we may very well find ourselves without additional resources in the fall, without enough tests, no domestic manufacturing capability, and us having to rely on other countries and other manufacturers outside the United States to make sure that we can get tests for the American people. &nbsp;</p>



<p>All of this is incredibly preventable.&nbsp; We should be doing everything we can to make sure that that scenario does not come to be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are planning for all sorts of contingencies, but I remain very, very confident that Congress will step up and protect the American people. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me just finish off by saying that we&#8217;re more than two years into this pandemic.&nbsp; People are tired.&nbsp; People want to move on. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The good news is we&#8217;re in a way better place than where we were two years ago, largely because of the capabilities that science has delivered for us: vaccines, boosters, therapeutics, testing, masks &#8212; all of that make an enormous difference.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve got to keep using that as the virus evolves and as the virus continues to do what it&#8217;s doing.</p>



<p>We have always had &#8212; the administration has always had a strong partnership with Congress, and I&#8217;m hopeful that Congress will continue to play that critical role of providing the resources and leadership so we can continue protecting the American people. &nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, I&#8217;m going to stop.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to turn it over to Dr. Rochelle Walensky, our CDC director, for her comments.</p>



<p>Dr. Walensky, over to you. &nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Dr. Jha.&nbsp; And good morning, everyone.&nbsp; It’s great to be back with all of you again.&nbsp; As always, I going to start again with the overview of the data.</p>



<p>Over the past 5 weeks, we’ve seen a steady increase in COVID-19 cases, as Dr. Jha mentioned.&nbsp; While cases remain much lower than during the Omicron surge this past winter, the current seven-day daily average of cases is now at about 94,000 cases per day, which is an increase nationally about 26 percent over the previous week and a threefold increase over the last month</p>



<p>Similarly, hospital admissions are also increasing, but remain much lower than they were during the Omicron surge.&nbsp; The seven-day average of hospital admissions now is about 3,000 per day, and that’s an increase of about 19 percent over the previous week.</p>



<p>And while deaths do remain low, we are still seeing a tragic seven-day average of daily deaths at about 275 per day.</p>



<p>And we, of course, must remember that each person lost to COVID-19 is a tragedy and that nearly 300 deaths a day is still far too many.</p>



<p>Our vaccines, prevention measures, and treatment options are working to save lives.&nbsp; However, we know those who are not consistently using these tools when recommended continue to remain vulnerable to serious disease, hospitalization, and death.</p>



<p>As Dr. Jha shared, we have many tools to help prevent severe disease from COVID-19, including vaccination and boosters.</p>



<p>Our vaccine effectiveness cohort studies have shown COVID-19 vaccines generally remain effective in preventing severe disease, including protecting against Omicron.</p>



<p>However, we know that the protection from COVID-19 vaccines wanes, or because le- &#8212; becomes less protective over time, especially in the Omicron era.&nbsp; This is one of the reasons vaccines boosters are so important.</p>



<p>One of our concerns for those at risk is outlined on this slide, which shows time since the last vaccine dose for two different age groups of adults &#8212; those 50 to 64 and those 65 and older.&nbsp; The lighter blue bars indicate the percent of people whose last vaccine dose was part of their primary series, and the darker blue bars indicates the percent of people whose last vaccine dose was a booster dose.</p>



<p>On the top graph, you can see among those 50 to 64, 62 percent have not received a COVID-19 vaccine in the last six months.&nbsp; And on the bottom graph, among those 65 and older, 57 percent have gone more than six months since their last vaccine dose.&nbsp; Many of these individuals are eligible for another COVID-19 vaccine dose now, a do- &#8212; a dose that may help strengthen their protection against infection, urgent care visits, and especially hospitalization and death.</p>



<p>So, whether it is your first booster or your second, if you haven’t had a vaccine dose since the beginning of December 2021 and you’re eligible, now is the time to get one.</p>



<p>Let me close with a brief word on COVID-19 community levels.&nbsp; Our COVID-19 community levels framework looks at a set of metrics, including cases, but also hospitalizations and health system capacity.&nbsp; This framework was designed to be predictive &#8212; anticipating where we will see further increases in cases, in hospitalizations, and in deaths &#8212; and they’re meant to inform communities, local leaders, and individuals on when and what prevention measures should be implemented in their local settings.</p>



<p>Right now, as shown on this map, over 32 percent of Americans live in an area with a medium or high COVID-19 community level –- counties shown in yellow or orange.&nbsp; Since the prior week, an additional 8 percent of the U.S. population is living in a county with a medium of high COVID-19 community level.</p>



<p>For areas currently with high COVID-19 community levels &#8212; those in orange &#8212; we urge local leaders to encourage use of prevention strategies like masking in public indoor settings and increasing access to testing and to treatment.</p>



<p>For individuals, COVID-19 community levels can also be used to inform personal decisions on how to best protect oneself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In areas where community levels are high, everyone should be using prevention measures and wearing a mask in public, indoor settings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In areas with medium COVID-19 community levels, in yellow, individuals should consider taking prevention measures based on their own risk, like avoiding crowds, wearing a mask, increasing their testing, especially before gathering with others indoors.</p>



<p>And in any COVID-19 community levels, individuals may always choose to wear a mask to protect themselves from infection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we&#8217;re currently seeing a steady rise of cases in parts of the country, we encourage everyone to use the menu of tools we have today to prevent further infection and severe disease, including wearing a mask, getting tested, accessing treatments early if infected, and getting vaccinated or boosted, especially if you&#8217;re over 50 and if your last dose was more than five months ago.</p>



<p>Thank you very much.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; What I&#8217;d like to do over the next few minutes is to dig a little bit deeper in the issue of variants and put that in the context of what you have just heard from Dr. Jha and Dr. Walensky regarding the increase in cases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at the global situation going from April 2021 to the present time.&nbsp; And as you can see, going from left to right, we&#8217;ve had the evolution over time of different variants that have progressively dominated the situation globally as determined by the sequencing of various isolates throughout the world.</p>



<p>And as you can see, we went from a group of Alpha, Beta, Gamma early on, overtaken completely by Delta.&nbsp; And most recently, over the last six months &#8212; five to six months, we&#8217;ve seen Omicron dominate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How does that spell out with regard to the different waves that we have seen in the United States?&nbsp; Next slide.</p>



<p>As you can see here, we&#8217;re looking at the United States now.&nbsp; And again, going from left to right, we had our Alpha wave, our Delta wave, and then we had a big, big spike with Omicron, which has gone down.&nbsp; And now, over the last several weeks, as you&#8217;ve heard from both Dr. Jha and Dr. Walensky, we&#8217;re seeing increases in cases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How does that really relate to the evolution of these variants?&nbsp; Next slide.</p>



<p>Right now, going with the United States as an example, again, the data are really very clear and really somewhat fascinating.&nbsp; If you go from the left to the right, you see in the Omicron era, when we had BA.1, in the orange.&nbsp; Gradually, over time, over a period of months, it got taken over by BA.1.1 and BA.2, which is the purple, that got larger and larger until around April &#8212; the beginning of April, the end of March, we started to see the very dark purple, which was the BA.2.12.1.</p>



<p>And when you see the gradual evolution of one particular variant overtaking another, there is a reason for that.</p>



<p>Next slide.</p>



<p>Here we see the exact same thing that South Africa is experiencing, but only a little bit different than what we are seeing here in the United States because they went through the same evolution of one variant taking over another variant, taking over another.&nbsp; And now, as we&#8217;ve heard from our South African colleagues, they are seeing a BA.4 and BA.5.&nbsp; BA.4, particularly in the West Cape &#8212; in Cape Town, and BA.5 in KwaZulu-Natal.&nbsp; And this is what they are currently seeing and it is expected that this particular dominance will continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why is that the case?&nbsp; Next slide.</p>



<p>This is a very simple schematic diagram of the stepwise increase in transmissibility going from left to right.&nbsp; Note: The big jump was from Delta to Omicron.&nbsp; That was a multi-fold increase in transmissibility.&nbsp; But within the Omicron sublineages, you see what I&#8217;ve actually showed you on prior slides of why one particular sublineage has taken over the next one and the next one.&nbsp; And as you go to the far right, that&#8217;s what I just showed you on the South African slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what does that tell us?&nbsp; Next slide.</p>



<p>As you&#8217;ve heard again, both from Dr. Jha and Dr. Walensky, we are experiencing an increase in cases, certainly more increase in infections since one undercounts because of the situation with regard to home tests that people may not be reporting.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing that due to the following: one, the increased transmissibility that I just showed you on the stepwise ladder. We&#8217;re seeing waning immunity to both protection and/or vaccination.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll get to, in a second, what we can do about that.&nbsp; And also, as we all know, there has been a relaxation of mitigations &#8212; of people not wearing masks indoors and having a lot more of indoor congregating without masks.</p>



<p>So, on the final slide, how do we meet the challenge that has been posed to us by the variants?&nbsp; Let&#8217;s look at some of the facts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Variants will continue to emerge if the virus circulates globally &#8212; a strong argument for what Dr. Jha said about &#8220;a global pandemic requires a global response.&#8221;&nbsp; We can keep the level of virus to the lowest possible level, which is the best way to avoid variants.&nbsp; Because the less replication, the less mutation; the less mutation, the less variants.</p>



<p>Importantly, vaccines continue to provide strong protection against severe disease.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the reason why, as cases go up and even more infections than are recorded cases, the discrepancy or ratio between hospitalization and cases clearly is much less than it was, for example, in the Delta wave.</p>



<p>However, immunity does wane, and that is why it is so important to stay up to date with vaccines and particularly boosters, apropos of the slide that Dr. Walensky just showed you.</p>



<p>Again, we can do very simple things like improving ventilation in indoor spaces where possible, and to monitor the levels in your community by the color codes that Dr. Walensky showed you, and follow the CDC guidance and recommendations for masks and other mitigations.</p>



<p>Now, again, as Dr. Jha had mentioned, treatments for COVID-19 are now widely available.&nbsp; If you test positive for COVID-19, talk to a healthcare provider as soon as possible about treatment options, including for test-to-treat.</p>



<p>And finally, we do need more resources, as all of us have said over and over.&nbsp; The development of next-generation vaccines and therapeutics is critical.&nbsp; And in order to do that, we need the resources that we’ve been asking for.</p>



<p>I’ll stop there, and back to you, Dr. Jha.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, Tony.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to &#8212; and Rochelle.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to open up now to Q&amp;A.</p>



<p>So, Kevin, open it up for us.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Dr. Jha.&nbsp; As a reminder, we&#8217;re going to take as many questions as possible, which means one question per person.</p>



<p>First, let&#8217;s go to Liz Weise at USA Today.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if Liz is asking a question.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t hear anything.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ah, sorry about that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m muted on my computer.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; Thanks for taking my question.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a paper out in Nature Today from the Gladstone in San Francisco showing that the Omicron variant doesn&#8217;t induce immunity against any of the other variants.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m curious if, looking forward, if that might have impacts on continuing to talk to Americans about vaccination or other issues.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Tony, do you want to take that?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah, I have not seen that paper, since I was doing other things this morning.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll be looking at that very carefully.</p>



<p>Yeah, I mean, obviously, we are seeing, even before that paper, that Omicron itself, when you get infected, does not have the broader coverage of the other variants such as Delta and Alpha and Beta, which is the reason why one has to be very careful.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing those studies about what the next boost should be &#8212; should it be a bivalent that includes an Omicron variant together, for example, either with a wild type or perhaps one of the other variants?</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re aware of that phenomenon.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t seen that particular paper.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s exactly the reason why we&#8217;re doing studies right now to determine what the best boost would be as we get into the fall and early winter.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Meg Tirrell at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about this phenomenon we&#8217;re seeing with Paxlovid rebounds, which seems potentially rare.&nbsp; Pfizer says they saw it about 2 percent in their clinical trial, but we hear a lot about it.&nbsp; And, you know, when people are testing positive again at day 10, I&#8217;m wondering, do you think there needs to be some federal guidance about isolation at that point, given that if people are testing positive again, they could potentially be contagious?&nbsp; How are you guys looking at this?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, so let me start maybe, and then I&#8217;ll turn it over to Rochelle to see if she has any further thoughts, or Tony.</p>



<p>But let me start by saying, Meg, you&#8217;re absolutely right that the clinical trials showed about 2 percent in the Paxlovid group and about 1.5 percent in the placebo group.&nbsp; But that was with Delta.&nbsp; And so the question is: Is this more common with Omicron?&nbsp; We&#8217;re actually doing a lot of work right now to try to sort that out.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking to health systems, getting real-world experience data.</p>



<p>But if you think about it: If you have, you know, 20,000 people getting Paxlovid every day, that would mean that about &#8212; even if it was only still 2 percent, that would mean 400 people are having rebound every day.&nbsp; So it is hard to know exactly how often it happens.</p>



<p>I think the key points &#8212; or a couple of key points that are really important: One is that the people who have that rebound are not getting particularly sick, are not ending up in the hospital.&nbsp; If the goal of this treatment, which it was, was to prevent hospitalizations and deaths, it is doing that incredibly well.</p>



<p>So the rebound issue is something we&#8217;re looking at very carefully.&nbsp; But I think that &#8212; but it is not leading to people getting particularly sick.</p>



<p>On the issue of if those people are contagious, how we should be advising them, let me see if Rochelle or Tony have any thoughts on that.</p>



<p>Rochelle, to you first.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, maybe I&#8217;ll just add that we&#8217;ve always said in our CDC recommendations that if you have symptoms, that you should put your mask on.&nbsp; So we would say if your symptoms recrudesce, that we would recommend putting your mask back on.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; And, Tony, any thoughts on that?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; No, actually no.&nbsp; Just confirming what Rochelle just mentioned.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith at NPR.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On the Paxlovid rebound question, are you also looking into whether there should be a longer course of Paxlovid?&nbsp; Instead of the 5 days, maybe 10 days?</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m just going to sneak in a point of personal privilege.&nbsp; What&#8217;s up with the under-five vaccines?&nbsp; It just doesn&#8217;t seem like there&#8217;s much urgency out there, and that&#8217;s a large population.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Tony, you want to start us off with the 5 versus 10 days and your thoughts and what we know?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah, exactly.&nbsp; In fact, we&#8217;re in active discussion about studies that we might do here at the NIH, with our own study capabilities, as well as with the people from Pfizer.&nbsp; In fact, we have been in rather direct communication with them, and we&#8217;ll continue that, about what the best study to do to determine whether or not we need a longer course or not.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s &#8212; that’s imminent.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be not only talking about that, we&#8217;re going to be planning what studies we&#8217;re going to be doing relatively soon.&nbsp; Within the next few days, we&#8217;re going to meet.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; And on the under-five, I&#8217;ll just say that I think there is actually quite a bit of urgency.&nbsp; The FDA now has all the &#8212; I think they have all the data for Moderna, and they&#8217;re going through it right now.&nbsp; And so that continues.</p>



<p>And I have &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve been in &#8212; we&#8217;ve been hearing from our colleagues at FDA that that evaluation is moving as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>I want to remind folks &#8212; because often people bring up, “Well, with some of the other pediatric vaccines, the time from submission to authorization was a little bit shorter.”</p>



<p>You know, this is the first pediatric vaccine that Moderna has submitted all of its data for.&nbsp; And so there&#8217;s a lot of data here that FDA is going through.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we all feel the sense of urgency; we want to get this done as quickly as possible.&nbsp; But I think we also all agree we want to get it done right.&nbsp; And I remain very confident, based on the conversations I&#8217;ve had, that as soon as the FDA feels like they&#8217;ve got the data analyzed, and as soon as it meets their standards, they&#8217;re going to make a determination.</p>



<p>All right, next question, Kevin.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Josh Wingrove at Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; And thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Just briefly to clarify, Dr. Jha, what you just said there: Is it your expectation then that pediatric vaccines for under-fives will be rolled out separately, regardless of manufacturer?&nbsp; Or is the thinking still that it would confuse or potentially confuse parents to have one arrive before the other?</p>



<p>And then, secondly, I&#8217;d like to circle back to the question of ordering the bivalent vaccines if, in fact, that<a></a><a> becomes available.&nbsp; What is &#8212; what are the steps?&nbsp; When would you have to enter talks with these companies?&nbsp; If you don&#8217;t get money from Congress in the coming weeks, is there anything you can do?&nbsp; Can you get in line, you know, with dollars from the seat cushions or what have you?&nbsp; Can you give us an update on, sort of, what the immediate term looks like that &#8212; looks like on that without funding from Congress if it doesn&#8217;t come through?&nbsp; Thank you.</a></p>



<p><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; On the &#8212; on the FDA under-five question, what I&#8217;ve heard &#8212; and again, this is really driven by FDA, and appropriately so driven by FDA.&nbsp; What I&#8217;ve heard from our colleagues at the FDA is that they&#8217;re looking at the data they have in front of them, and that is what they&#8217;re focused on.&nbsp; And they will make a determination as soon as they are able.<br><br>And so that &#8212; and that&#8217;s really &#8212; like, again, ultimately, that is what we want to hear from them &#8212; right? &#8212; that they&#8217;re not going to delay, that they&#8217;re not waiting for anything else, that as soon as the analysis is done, they&#8217;re going to make a determination.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s my expectation.<br><br>And our job is to make sure that as soon as FDA makes its determination, it&#8217;ll go over to the CDC, as soon as CDC makes its determination.&nbsp; If the determinations are that kids should be getting these vaccines, we will make sure that those vaccines are widely available as quickly as possible for kids under five.<br><br>All right.&nbsp; On the question of bivalent vaccines, the way to think about this is it takes about three months to manufacture these things.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And if we want to be ready for the fall, it&#8217;s not too early to start thinking about this stuff.&nbsp; And, in fact, we&#8217;ve been &#8212; we&#8217;ve had, kind of &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve had some very preliminary conversations with the manufacturers.<br><br>But &#8212; but the negotiations around it have not yet begun, partly because we&#8217;re waiting for resources.&nbsp; And &#8212; and the truth is that other countries are in conversations with the manufacturers and starting to kind of advance their negotiations.&nbsp; I obviously don&#8217;t know the details of what other countries are doing.&nbsp; And so my take is: Every day we wait, every week we wait, we just fall a little further behind in line.</p>



<p>We are very committed to finding enough resources, and that means we&#8217;re looking across all of the other programs we have, the monies we have for other things, and asking where can we pull some dollars to at least be able to get some vaccines for the fall and winter.<br><br>I think if Congress abdicates its responsibilities, it is not acceptable for us in the administration to go into the fall and winter with zero vaccines.&nbsp; I am confident we&#8217;ll find money to be able to get some Americans vaccinated, maybe just the highest risk; we don&#8217;t know.<br><br>But these are not decisions we want to be having to make.&nbsp; We want Congress to just step up and fund &#8212; fund our ability to make sure that we get enough vaccines for all Americans.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Ed O&#8217;Keefe at CBS.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, doctors, for doing this.&nbsp; Just to follow up, then, on the question about vaccines for those under five: Realistically then &#8212; because this is a question we get asked a lot too &#8212; are we weeks, are we months away from those shots?<br><br>And when you say, Dr. Jha, that you feel that Congress has been receptive to what you&#8217;ve been talking about in terms of funding, can you describe a little bit more, then, what&#8217;s holding things up?&nbsp; And how are they receiving these warnings that you continue to put out there that if there&#8217;s no money, then as many as 100 million infections could happen?&nbsp; I mean, those are big numbers to be tossing around at a time when you&#8217;re trying to get Congress to act.<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t know if anybody else wants to take the under-five question, since I feel like I&#8217;ve tried.&nbsp; Tony or &#8212; any thoughts on how you see the under-five?</p>



<p><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, yeah, Ashish, you said it very, very clearly: The important thing is that you want to leave the FDA to do what they do well, without unnecessary pressure or interference.&nbsp;<br><br>They are totally aware of the fact that this is a pressing problem, and they will do it as expeditiously as they possibly can.&nbsp; And it is a process of getting all of the data and having the time &#8212; and they don&#8217;t waste time &#8212; to analyze the data and make a decision that the United States public will feel comfortable about because they did it correctly and put all their resources into it.<br><br>So it wouldn&#8217;t be appropriate for either myself or Rochelle or Ashish to give you days versus weeks versus months.&nbsp; They are going to do it as expeditiously as they possibly can.</p>



<p><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And on the issue of funding, I&#8217;ll say, you know, I&#8217;ve spent a lot of time up in the Hill.&nbsp; I was up on the Hill again this morning.&nbsp; When I think about my one-on-one meetings and my small group meetings, I think I&#8217;ve met with more Republicans than Democrats.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve met with both members of the House and the Senate.&nbsp; And what I&#8217;ve been laying out for folks</p>



<p>is what we need the resources for and what the consequences of not getting those resources, what it means for what the fall and winter may bring.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there’s a range of models out there of what we might see in the fall and winter.&nbsp; We have got to plan for a range of scenarios, including we have to plan &#8212; it would be irresponsible for us not to &#8212; we have to plan for a scenario where we don&#8217;t get any more resources from Congress.&nbsp; I think it would be &#8212; I think it&#8217;d be terrible.&nbsp; I think we would see a lot of unnecessary loss of life if that were to happen.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re looking at all the scenarios and planning for all of them.</p>



<p>Look, I think, at the end of the day, Congress works in the ways that it works.&nbsp; I remain confident that Congress is going to pull through on this and give us the $22.5 billion supplemental requests that we have put in.&nbsp; That&#8217;s our request.&nbsp; It’s an emergency supplemental.&nbsp; And I remain confident that Congress will stand up and provide the resources that we need to protect the American people.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, we&#8217;re going to get through as many questions as possible.&nbsp; One question per person.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Zeke Miller.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you all for doing this.&nbsp; Do you expect the current uptick in Omicron-related cases to continue as we hit the summer and the busy travel months ahead?&nbsp; Should people begin reconsidering any plans that they have?&nbsp; Should they, you know, pack masks, given the uncertain situation?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then &#8212; clearly, heading into the fall and winter, Dr. Jha, you mentioned you&#8217;re planning for a range of scenarios and it could lead to unnecessary loss of life.&nbsp; Is there a number that you can put in a range of how many unnecessary deaths there could be without the resources that you say you need in order to fight the virus?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; I will see if Tony or Rochelle &#8212; Rochelle, any thoughts on kind of the summer and expectations and if people should be packing masks or not?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, maybe I&#8217;ll just sort of point back to our COVID-19 Community Levels map, which demonstrates, right now, some areas of increased infection and hospitalization in the Northeast and the Eastern Corridor, as well as in the upper Midwest.&nbsp; But what we&#8217;ve seen with prior increases in infections and in &#8212; in, you know, different waves of infection have demonstrated that this travels across the country and has the potential to travel across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think the important thing to recognize is that we actually have the tools to prevent it.&nbsp; And so, we would ask you to wisely use these tools to &#8212; we &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve always said: You know, put your mask aside when infection rates are low and pick it up again when infection rates are higher.&nbsp; We know that we have vaccines and boosters.&nbsp; We know we have treatments.&nbsp; We know that people can use tests before they gather so that they can work towards making sure that you have an environment that is a safer environment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we would ask people to engage in all of the activities that they want to engage in, but to do so wisely.&nbsp; Do so when you&#8217;re up to date with your vaccines, when you&#8217;ve tested before you gather.&nbsp; And if you have a high risk of infection in your area, to put on that mask before you gather.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; And I think, Zeke, you asked about estimates.&nbsp; Look, it&#8217;s hard to make precise assessments about what&#8217;s going to happen in the fall and winter.&nbsp; And right now, what we&#8217;ve been doing, because we&#8217;ve got to do scenario planning, is we&#8217;ve been talking to modelers.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been looking at internal models.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But most modelers don&#8217;t have models that go as far out as November, December, January.&nbsp; We expect those models to start coming out over the summer.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve been trying to get some preliminary data.&nbsp; Because from a policy point of view, we can&#8217;t go into September without having a sense of what the fall and winter will bring.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the estimates right now are large &#8212; I mean, sort of, are wide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you think about it, what&#8217;s driving those estimates is how much immunity, for instance, did BA.1 &#8212; the big wave we saw &#8212; how much did that actually generate?&nbsp;</p>



<p>If it generated a lot of population immunity, then we&#8217;re going to see fewer infections into the summer, fall, and winter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If it generated only a modest amount of immunity, we&#8217;re going to see more infections.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What will happen with mitigation?&nbsp; Are we going to put in any more mitigation or will mitigation remain relatively low?&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a bunch of factors that will drive what happens.</p>



<p>I also think: Are we going to have a new generation of vaccines that we&#8217;re going to be able to deliver for the American people?&nbsp; That will make a big difference in the fall and winter.&nbsp; If we have no new generation of vaccines or very few or only for the highest risk individuals, that will also make a difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there&#8217;s a lot of factors here; we&#8217;re trying to scenario plan across all of them.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not trying to get into the prediction business.&nbsp; We&#8217;re getting much more into the scenario planning business to make sure that we know what may be ahead of us so we can plan for it and obviously also lay those out in front of Congress so they understand that if they choose not to fund &#8212; or if they choose not to fund appropriately with the resources we need to protect the American people &#8212; that what the likely consequences of that might be.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let’s go to Jeff Mason at Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; My question is sort of a broad one about eligibility for both the treatments and for the vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Jha, you mentioned talking to doctors and the fact that the Paxlovid is available for a lot of people.&nbsp; But, at least anecdotally, a lot of doctors are telling folks that they&#8217;re not eligible for it.&nbsp; Is that a disconnect between the administration and doctors not knowing?&nbsp; Or is the supply &#8212; is the supply maybe not as great as &#8212; as you are suggesting?</p>



<p>And then, broadly, also on vaccines: Dr. Walensky, you mentioned the fact that if people are eligible, they should be getting that next boost.&nbsp; What about people who are under 50?&nbsp; There are lots of people certainly in that age group who are getting Omicron, again, who would like to take another vaccine or a booster.&nbsp; Will the eligibility open up for them as well?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; So, let me start by talking about treatments, and then maybe I&#8217;ll turn it over to Rochelle for thinking about vaccines and eligibility.</p>



<p>Jeff, the way I think about this is and as I said earlier: When we first got authorization for Paxlovid, we had very, very limited supply.&nbsp; So, the messaging was: Keep it for the highest-risk people.&nbsp; And that kind of messaging and kind of almost a scarcity mindset tends to set in, and it takes a lot of effort to get people to shift.</p>



<p>And usually, under normal circumstances, it would take years to get doctors to change their practice patterns in substantial ways.&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t have years for this.&nbsp; So, we have been going, I think, pretty clearly and pretty strong on helping doctors understand that the –- actually, the range of people who are eligible is quite broad.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not my definition, it&#8217;s the EUA of the FDA.&nbsp; If you look at the emergency use authorization, they say anybody who&#8217;s at increased risk of severe disease.&nbsp; And then they actually point to a CDC document.&nbsp; If you go to that CDC document, it&#8217;s a very broad range of people.</p>



<p>And so my general advice has been, we&#8217;ve got to follow the EUA.&nbsp; You should be relatively permissive about this.&nbsp; You should not get excessively restricted.&nbsp; We have plenty of supply right now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not trying to, you know, prevent Americans from getting them; in fact, the opposite.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to make sure that everybody who&#8217;s eligible, which is a large proportion of the population.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And whether the supply is adequate or not: What we&#8217;re doing is we&#8217;re tracking very closely ordering.&nbsp; We&#8217;re making sure that if there&#8217;s any municipality or any local district or any pharmacy that feels like they want more, we&#8217;ll make sure they get more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re making sure that the supplies are adequate.&nbsp; We have substantially increased it &#8212; more than 30,000 sites now across the country.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re not done, by the way.&nbsp; This has been four weeks of work.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to keep going, adding more test-to-treat sites, adding more opportunities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s just about messaging, it&#8217;s about clarity, it&#8217;s about making sure people understand who&#8217;s eligible, and then making sure that as people get eligibility or are eligible get the prescription &#8212; that it&#8217;s available very, very widely.</p>



<p>Rochelle, to you on the vaccine question.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Thanks, Ashish.&nbsp; So, what we do know about these vaccines is they work well to prevent severe disease – they work very well to prevent severe disease if you&#8217;re up to date.</p>



<p>We do know that, as I showed in the graph, that there are many people who are eligible for a fourth dose and even for a third dose &#8212; have not yet received them.&nbsp; So, for those over 50, those are the people who are most at risk of severe disease.&nbsp; And we really do want them to go ahead and get that third or fourth dose, if they haven&#8217;t gotten either, to prevent severe disease.</p>



<p>For those under the age of 50, there are still quite a few people out there who have not gotten their third dose.&nbsp; And we know that third dose is really important, especially against Omicron.&nbsp; So, we would encourage those people to get their third dose.</p>



<p>With regard to a fourth dose for those under the age of 50, that is going to require action from the FDA, and we&#8217;re in conversations there as well.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; So, I think, Kevin, are we &#8212; I think we&#8217;re done with Q&amp;A, so let me just wrap up here by saying thank you all for joining us.&nbsp; This is my first COVID press briefing since I took on this role from Jeff Zients.</p>



<p>And what I want to do is two things: First of all, we&#8217;ve both &#8212; Tony and I, and I know Rochelle as well &#8212; have been out there in the media talking.&nbsp; I think, Tony, I counted that between you and me, we&#8217;ve done 50 media appearances in the last five weeks.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve been out there.&nbsp; But we want to do more of these briefings, and so we will continue &#8212; I commit to continue to do these briefings on an ongoing basis.</p>



<p>Obviously, when there&#8217;s major news, we&#8217;ll do it.&nbsp; Otherwise, we&#8217;ll make sure that we do it on a regular basis so that we continue sharing information with people.</p>



<p>Thank you all for joining us, and I look forward to seeing all of you again the next time we get a chance to get together. Thank you.</p>



<p>11:37 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID-19 press briefing slides, visit: https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/COVID-Press-Briefing_18May2022.pdf </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
