<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:02:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Encouraging All Americans to Take Advantage of Critical Tax&#160;Credits</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-encouraging-all-americans-to-take-advantage-of-critical-tax-credits/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 9:50 A.M. EST THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Sharron, for that very meaningful introduction.  And Sharron and I were talking earlier.  You know, there&#8217;s so much about the Child Tax Credit that is about the &#8212; the impact &#8212; the intergenerational impact.  And Sharron was sharing with me that her grandfather actually worked&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Court Auditorium</em></p>



<p>9:50 A.M. EST<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Sharron, for that very meaningful introduction.  And Sharron and I were talking earlier.  You know, there&#8217;s so much about the Child Tax Credit that is about the &#8212; the impact &#8212; the intergenerational impact. <br> <br>And Sharron was sharing with me that her grandfather actually worked with President Kennedy.  And we were talking about the fact that, obviously, her family has a long, strong, and deep commitment to public service and this good work.  So, thank you, Sharron, for that introduction. <br> <br>It is good to be here with two of the most energetic champions of our nation&#8217;s working families: Secretary Janet Yellen and Gene Sperling. <br> <br>And as many of you know, Secretary Yellen and I are working on a number of things. <br> <br>Gene, I heard your introduction about the conspiracy.  It&#8217;s not a conspiracy; it&#8217;s just a collaboration to do very important work to lift people up with one of the &#8212; the leaders in the world on how we do that in terms of economic empowerment. <br> <br>So, Secretary Yellen, thank you.  Gene Sperling, thank you for your years of hard work.  You really are the backbone of what we, as an administration, have been doing with the Child Tax Credit. <br> <br>So, on this day of action, there are so many individuals and organizations who are dedicated to action: the United Way, AARP, and Code for America.  And I want to thank all of you for the work you do every day and for joining us today. <br> <br>So, our message today is simple: If you are eligible for the Child Tax Credit and the Earned Income Tax Credit, we want you to get those credits.  And you know why: Working families deserve a break.<br> <br>Last month, I received a letter from a mother in Pennsylvania.  She and her husband have four children.  They both work 50-hour weeks.  They coordinate their schedules to minimize the cost of childcare, and their family is still barely holding on.  They just need a little help, and that&#8217;s what she told me in her note &#8212; a hand up, not a handout.  A hand up. <br> <br>And I receive letters like this all the time.  The truth is, there are people across our nation who work hard every day and still struggle to get by.  And it should not be this way in our country &#8212; in the United States of America.<br> <br>And the President and I firmly believe that we have to do better.  And that is why we fought to expand the Child Tax Credit and the Earned Income Tax Credit as part of the American Rescue Plan: to give families and working people a little help. <br> <br>The American Rescue Plan increased the Child Tax Credit<br>and extended it to millions more families.<br> <br>And the American Rescue Plan also nearly tripled the maximum Earned Income Tax Credit and made it available to workers between 19 and 24 years of age, as well as to workers 65 years old and above.<br> <br>These tax credits are already making a difference.  In fact, thanks to the Child Tax Credit, we are on a path to cut child poverty in America by 40 percent.  That bears repeating: We are on a path to cut child poverty by 40 percent.<br> <br>This is historic and, as I said earlier, will have a generational impact.<br> <br>Millions of families have used their monthly Child Tax Credit &#8212; CTC &#8212; check to put food on the table, to save for college, to cover daily expenses, and to pay down debt.  That is why this Day of Action is so important.<br> <br>If you are eligible for either of these credits or even if you think you might be eligible, please go to the following website: ChildTaxCredit.gov.  ChildTaxCredit.gov. <br> <br>It is a quick and easy way to check whether you qualify.  And if you qualify, all you need to do to receive benefits is to file your taxes.<br> <br>Now, one more important note: If you are one of the more than 30 million families who have already received the Child Tax Credit, you still need to file your taxes.  So that is the only way to receive the second half of what you are owed.  So, remember: You are owed more, but you still need to file your taxes.<br> <br>Everyone here knows it will take a hands-on-deck approach to get people signed up for these credits.  So, we need help.  We need state and local governments to send out texts to remind folks of what they entitled to receive.  We need faith-based organizations to spread the word at houses of worship.  We need community groups to get people the help they need to file their taxes.  And we need everyone to spread the word &#8212; be it at Sunday dinner, at the barbershop, at work, at school, and at home.<br> <br>And I believe and I know our work will be worth it, because every family we lift up, when we do that, we lift up our entire nation.<br> <br>And that&#8217;s why the President and I will keep fighting to extend these measures for years to come.<br> <br>And I’ll close today where I began: with that mother from Pennsylvania.  In her letter, she wrote that, earlier this year, her family started receiving the monthly Child Tax Credit.  And with the money, she described that they bought food, they paid their daily expenses, and they supported local businesses in the process.  She wrote, “Nothing fancy.”  Just making a difference.<br> <br>So, it’s enough to make a difference.  And that’s why we are here today: to make a difference for working families across our nation, to offer just a little help.<br> <br>So, thank you all for what you have done and will continue to do.  Let’s keep getting the word out, and be well and take care. <br> <br>Thank you. <br> <br>               END                 9:57 A.M. EST<br> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Ensuring Future is Made in&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-ensuring-future-is-made-in-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tritium Announces EV Charger Manufacturing Facility in Tennessee; To Produce Up To 30,000 Buy America-Compliant Chargers Per Year, Create 500 Jobs Since his first day in office, President Biden relentlessly focused on an industrial strategy to revitalize our manufacturing base, strengthen critical supply chains, drive down prices, and position U.S. workers and businesses to compete&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Tritium Announces EV Charger Manufacturing Facility in Tennessee; To Produce Up To 30,000 Buy America-Compliant Chargers Per Year, Create 500 Jobs</em></p>



<p>Since his first day in office, President Biden relentlessly focused on an industrial strategy to revitalize our manufacturing base, strengthen critical supply chains, drive down prices, and position U.S. workers and businesses to compete and lead globally in the 21<sup>st</sup> century. This whole-of-government effort is leading to a historic recovery in domestic manufacturing. During President Biden’s first year in office, the economy added <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MANEMP">367,000 manufacturing jobs</a> – the most in nearly 30 years. The U.S. economy grew at the fastest pace in nearly 40 years in 2021, and manufacturing as a share of U.S. GDP has <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/VAPGDPMA#0">returned to pre-pandemic levels</a>. Manufacturing activity has seen a <a href="https://www.ismworld.org/supply-management-news-and-reports/reports/ism-report-on-business/pmi/december/">significant</a> <a href="https://www.markiteconomics.com/Public/Home/PressRelease/51d060f7a3314d1b8bb8d948e035d4c7">expansion</a> every month that President Biden has been in office, consistently above pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>The Build America, Buy America Act in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law expands on the Biden-Harris Administration’s work to ensure that the future is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/25/president-biden-to-sign-executive-order-strengthening-buy-american-provisions-ensuring-future-of-america-is-made-in-america-by-all-of-americas-workers/">made in America</a> by American workers by strengthening and expanding Buy America rules to all taxpayer-funded infrastructure and public works projects.</p>



<p><strong>Today, President Biden and Jane Hunter, CEO of Tritium, will announce that Tritium will break ground on its first U.S. manufacturing facility in Lebanon, Tennessee.</strong> This facility will house six production lines that will produce up to 30,000 Buy America-compliant DC Fast Chargers per year at peak production and create 500 local jobs.</p>



<p>This is the latest of announcements in recent weeks by major companies announcing investments in U.S. manufacturing and jobs, including <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-bringing-semiconductor-manufacturing-back-to-america/">Intel</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/25/statement-by-president-biden-on-general-motors-investment-in-michigan/">General Motors</a>, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/31/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-amir-sheikh-tamim-bin-hamad-al-thani-of-qatar/">Boeing</a>, and more than $200 billion in investments in domestic manufacturing of semiconductors, electric vehicles, aircraft, and batteries announced since 2021.</p>



<p>In addition to Tritium, EV charging manufacturers large and small are investing and expanding U.S. operations, driven by the Administration’s economic strategy, Made in America policies, and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Siemens</strong>, which is investing and expanding its U.S. manufacturing operations to support electric vehicle infrastructure in America, will produce 1 million EV chargers by 2025. This investment, spurred by the passage of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, is the latest in the company’s strategic plan to meet accelerating electric vehicle charging demand, and expand its U.S. manufacturing capabilities.<br><br></li><li><strong>ABB</strong>, which currently manufactures Buy America-compliant transit bus chargers in the U.S., will expand its US EV charging manufacturing operations, including Level 2 and DC Fast Chargers, over the coming five years, employing hundreds of Americans and producing thousands of EV chargers each year.<br><br></li><li><strong>FreeWire Technologies, </strong>based in Oakland, California, currently manufactures Buy America-compliant battery-integrated EV charging equipment, and recently announced groundbreaking on a research, manufacturing, and testing facility in Newark, California. FreeWire currently employs and plans to add more than 200 jobs in electrification and clean energy in and around disadvantaged communities this year.<br><br></li><li><strong>Dunamis Clean Energy Partners, </strong>a Black- and woman-owned EV charger manufacturer based in Detroit, Michigan, will manufacture Level 2 EV chargers and charging connectors in a new production facility in Detroit beginning this summer. Dunamis’ training and workforce development efforts will focus on underrepresented, economically disadvantaged communities most impacted by greenhouse gas emissions.</li></ul>



<p>The future of the auto industry is electric, and America can own that future by building more here at home, creating good-paying jobs in the process. In August, President Biden set an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">ambitious target</a> and roadmap to get to 50% of electric vehicle (EV) sale shares in the U.S. by 2030. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law included a down payment on the EV future, with more than $7 billion in funding to secure an American EV supply chain, from materials processing to battery manufacturing and recycling, along with $7.5 billion to build out the first-ever nationwide public EV charging network.</p>



<p>This charging network will provide a convenient, reliable, affordable and equitable charging experience, with a focus on serving national highway corridors, rural areas, and underserved communities. It will also accelerate the adoption of electric vehicles, fight the climate crisis, and support domestic manufacturing jobs.</p>



<p>Later this week, Department of Transportation Secretary Buttigieg and Department of Energy Secretary Granholm will announce the state allocations and guidance for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Formula Program, which will provide $5 billion over five years to help states create a network of EV charging stations along designated Alternative Fuel Corridors on the Interstate Highway System.</p>



<p><strong>The Biden-Harris Administration has already taken action to prepare for the build-out of the nationwide public EV charging network.</strong></p>



<ul><li>In December, Vice President Harris announced the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/">EV Charging Action Plan</a> to outline the steps the Administration is taking to accelerate the EV charging investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br></li><li>In December, the Department of Energy and the Department of Transportation announced the creation of the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-and-dot-launch-joint-effort-build-out-nationwide-electric-vehicle-charging-network">Joint Office of Energy and Transportation</a>, which will support and accelerate deployment of the national EV charging network, including by providing technical assistance to states as they develop their comprehensive EV charging plans. This week, the Joint Office launched <a href="https://driveelectric.gov/">DriveElectric.gov</a> to support the states in their planning.<br><br></li><li>Last week, the Department of Transportation released an <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/rural/ev/toolkit">EV Rural Charging Toolkit</a>, a one-stop resource for rural communities to plan and implement EV charging infrastructure projects.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris Leads Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Day of Action to Ensure Americans Get the Tax Credits They&#160;Deserve</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/fact-sheet-vice-president-kamala-harris-leads-biden-harris-administration-day-of-action-to-ensure-americans-get-the-tax-credits-they-deserve/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris and Secretary Yellen Headline Day of Action Event Alongside White House ARP Coordinator Gene Sperling, Mayors and Major Non-Profits to Encourage Americans to Sign Up for the Expanded Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit The American Rescue Plan Made Significant Changes to Two Critical Tax Relief Programs. Expanded the Child&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris and Secretary Yellen Headline Day of Action Event Alongside White House ARP Coordinator Gene Sperling, Mayors and Major Non-Profits to Encourage Americans to Sign Up for the Expanded Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit</em></p>



<p><strong>The American Rescue Plan Made Significant Changes to Two Critical Tax Relief Programs.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanded the Child Tax Credit</strong> from $2,000 per child to $3,600 for children under 6 and $3,000 for children between 6 and 17.</li><li><strong>Nearly Tripled the Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children</strong> – from ~$540 to up to $1,500 for 17 million workers without dependent children and made previously ineligible younger workers (19-24) who are not half-time or full-time students, and older workers (65+) newly eligible for the expanded Earned Income Tax Credit.</li></ul>



<p><strong>February 8<sup>th</sup> is a Day of Action to Ensure All Eligible Americans Sign Up for These American Rescue Plan Tax Cuts.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Families must file a tax return in 2022 to receive the second half of the Child Tax Credit. </strong>While the families of 61 million children received advance monthly payments between July and December 2021, families need to file a tax return to receive the second half.</li><li><strong>By filing a tax return, families that did not receive the advance payments in 2021 can still get the full Child Tax Credit, as well as the up to $1,400-per-person Economic Impact Payment that they might have missed.</strong> Some taxpayers with qualifying children – like those who welcomed a new baby in 2021 or those who haven’t filed taxes in recent years and did not use the non-filer portal – can get their full Child Tax Credit by filing their tax returns. Eligible families that did not receive the up to $1,400 per person Economic Impact Payment included in the American Rescue Plan can claim those payments by filing a tax return this year.</li><li><strong>Many families who are eligible for the Child Tax Credit are also eligible for the Earned Income Tax Credit and can get thousands of dollars in additional tax relief by filing their tax return this year. </strong>In addition, the American Rescue Plan nearly tripled the EITC for workers without dependent children to $1,500 and made millions more Americans eligible.</li></ul>



<p><strong>New Government Website – ChildTaxCredit.Gov – Directs Americans to Tax-Filing Assistance.</strong><br>The Day of Action coincides with the recent re-launch of the new and improved ChildTaxCredit.gov. The revamped website has several new features to help taxpayers file their taxes and access the remainder of the expanded Child Tax Credit, the full amount of the Child Tax Credit, and/or the Earned Income Tax Credit as tax filing season begins.<br><br><strong>To help Americans navigate tax filing season, the website features a new tool that directs taxpayers to free assisted filing options that suit them based on answers to a handful of simple questions.</strong> These options include both virtual and in-person support in multiple languages. Many of the organizations who have answered the Administration’s call to action are leveraging the new ChildTaxCredit.gov for assistance.<br><br><strong>Congressional Champions Join the Day of Action.<br></strong>U.S. Senators Michael Bennet (D-Colo.), Sherrod Brown (D-Ohio), Cory Booker (D-N.J.), and Reverend Raphael Warnock (D-Ga.) and U.S. Representatives Rosa DeLauro (D-Conn.) and Suzan DelBene (D-Wash.) will headline a press call on the Day of Action encouraging all Americans to file their taxes to access the Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit.<br><br><strong>Hundreds of Non-Profits and Community-Based Organizations Are Taking Action to Reach Families Across the Country.</strong><br>Hundreds of non-profits, community-based organizations, religious organizations, veterans’ organizations, youth organizations, disability organizations, seniors’ organizations, health and medical organizations, foster care organizations, and more made commitments to take a wide range of actions, today and throughout the tax filing seasons.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Events in all 50 states and Puerto Rico throughout tax filing season to encourage families to file their taxes and connect them with tax filing assistance</strong>. Major non-profits and faith-based organizations including AARP, UnidosUS, United Way Worldwide, the Partnership for America’s Children, Coalition on Human Needs, the Arc of the United States, the National Community Action Partnership, NETWORK Catholic Lobby for Social Justice, Friends Committee on National Legislation, Salvation Army, National Association of Evangelicals, National Council of Jewish Women, the Jewish Federations of North America, Catholic Charities USA, and more have committed to host community events to ensure Americans receive the tax credits they are eligible for.</li><li><strong>Texting campaigns to direct families to tax filing assistance. </strong>Organizations including but not limited to the National Urban League, the Hispanic Federation, Think of Us, the Shah Family Foundation and FindYourFunds, the Community Child Care Council (4Cs) of Alameda County, and Common Sense Media will launch direct texting campaigns.</li><li><strong>Trainings for frontline workers and service providers</strong> <strong>to ensure they encourage clients to file their taxes and direct them to assistance. </strong>Groups including Children at Risk and the Texas Family Leadership Council, Children’s Action Alliance, Partnership for America’s Children, Lutheran Services of America, UnidosUS, American Public Human Services Association, and Hunger Free America will train hundreds of frontline workers to help families navigate tax filing.</li><li><strong>Hosting Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) sites to connect people with in-person tax preparation assistance</strong>, including those run by StreetCred at Boston Medical Center, Lincoln VITA, Educational Alliance, United Way, and AARP.</li><li><strong>Developing and providing free tax preparation online services </strong>including United Way’s My Free Taxes, AARP’s Tax Counseling for the Elderly, and Code for America’s Get Your Refund.</li><li><strong>Sharing information on the Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit through social media channels, with a reach totaling 16.7 million people</strong> including campaigns led by MomsRising, Prosperity Now, National Council of Jewish Women, and dozens of other organizations.</li></ul>



<p><strong>State and Local Governments Commit to Action Throughout Tax Filing Season.</strong><br>During tax filing season, state and local leaders will take action on CTC/EITC enrollment, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>California</strong> will continue ongoing awareness activities through a variety of NGO and local government channels, including outreach and education to support prioritizing uptake of financial supports through a public-private partnership investing $30 million in community-based organizations to reach people where they live, work and play.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Illinois </strong>through its “Ladder Up” program, will continue supporting tax prep for residents with incomes below 200% of the poverty level and rely on a network of professional tax prep staff and volunteers.</li><li><strong>New York </strong>will continue encouraging New Yorkers to take advantage of Free File software, which can help millions of taxpayers claim valuable tax credits without the cost of hiring a paid tax preparer.</li><li><strong>Oregon </strong>Department of Human Services will work with several other state agencies and community organizations to spread the word to “file your taxes.” Agencies and partners can “take turns” reinforcing the main message to encourage Oregonians to find a tax filing assister near them.</li><li><strong>National Community Action Partnership </strong>the 200 Community Action Agencies that are units of local governments will do CTC/EITC outreach, with a number of them directly operating VITA sites.</li><li><strong>Chicago, IL </strong>will launch a series of webinars and trainings in partnership with elected officials as well as conduct a Tax-a-Thon event at Olive-Harvey College through VITA partners and Ladder Up Chicago.</li><li><strong>Kansas City, MO </strong>will continue leveraging its Emergency Rental Assistance hub to assist residents with applying for and obtaining the CTC/EITC, and promoting information on platforms and channels including the City’s quarterly news magazine.</li><li><strong>Newark, NJ </strong>will launch a virtual kick-off event with Mayor Baraka and New Jersey Citizen Action to promote their free tax preparation services.</li><li><strong>Detroit, MI</strong> will kick off “Ten Days of Action” including a United Way for Southeast Michigan Town Hall, and email and text message campaigns to city subscribers, public school community district subscribers, and state social services recipients.</li><li><strong>Hartford, CT </strong>will launch an SMS campaign sending direct text messages to residents, as well as radio, and media&nbsp;campaigns. Hartford has also trained local librarians to serve as navigators for individuals who need tax filing assistance.</li><li><strong>Houston, TX </strong>will amplify CTC/EITC on official channels and to their Employee News communication platform which services 22,000+ city employees.</li><li><strong>Lansing, MI: </strong>will continue partnering with Capital Area United Way to promote CTC/EITC to targeted households and conduct outreach at events such as their utility assistance events.</li><li><strong>Los Angeles County</strong><strong>, CA </strong>will continue a text-message campaign in partnership with the United Ways of California, and ensuring county residents are connected to VITA resources.</li><li><strong>Louisville, KY</strong> will continue their Tax Time Connect initiative with VITA and Bank On Louisville to promote banking access and CTC/EITC, expand VITA capacity, and partner with the Louisville Urban League in-person support.</li><li><strong>Miami Dade County</strong><strong>, CA </strong>will partner across county departments to promote local free income tax preparation services through VITA as well as conduct outreach at existing resource fairs, canvassing, radio, info cards.</li><li><strong>N</strong><strong>ew York, NY </strong>will lead press and outreach events in targeted neighborhoods with local elected officials at VITA sites, canvas at local food pantries, issue postcard mailers to 250,000 EITC eligible households, launch outdoor advertising on bus shelters and send an email to the more than 420,000 City of New York employees about CTC and EITC.</li><li><strong>Philadelphia, PA</strong> will launch “Claim Your Money PHL,” and run targeted print and digital ads, bus ads, and deploy street team outreach in addition to providing resources to our local non-profit tax preparation partners.</li><li><strong>San Antonio, TX </strong>will place VITA program information in the City’s “on-hold phone message,” host community events, and continue cross-enrollment promotion through COVID-19 emergency programs. As Chair of the Texas Big City Mayors coalition, Mayor Nirenberg will encourage statewide enrollment throughout Texas’ largest municipalities, representing over 8 million Texans.</li><li><strong>South Bend, IN </strong>will train staff at local assistance programs, canvas targeted neighborhoods, and partner with local public health workers, librarians, and other nonprofit organizations to organize sign-up events.</li><li><strong>St. Paul, MN</strong> will deploy their Office of Financial Empowerment and other departments and community partners to provide free tax prep and VITA support, and continue to amplifying their multi-language website and messaging on digital and social platforms.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Continued Biden-Harris Administration Whole-of-Government Effort On CTC/EITC Enrollment.</strong><br>Agencies across the federal government have heeded the call to reach as many families as possible.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The Treasury Department </strong>will push out information on CTC and EITC on social media during the Day of Action and in the weeks that follow and will co-lead trainings with the White House reaching external and intergovernmental CTC/EITC navigators. In addition, IRS, through its Volunteers Income Tax Assistance (VITA) and Tax Counseling for the Elderly (TCE) sites, assist taxpayers in free tax return preparation and electronically filing tax returns, including those claiming the CTC and EITC credits. Last year, in local communities, over 8,800 volunteer sites filed nearly two million tax returns at no cost. For information on a local site, visit <a href="https://www.irs.gov/individuals/free-tax-return-preparation-for-qualifying-taxpayers">https://www.irs.gov/individuals/free-tax-return-preparation-for-qualifying-taxpayers</a>.</li><li><strong>Social Security Administration </strong>will build off of their 2021 successful five-week national marketing campaign, which included web banners, digital search ads, radio ads, and billboards, to reach low-income individuals, including people who receive SSI and Social Security benefits. SSA also released guidance to 27,000 employees in over 1,200 field offices nationwide on how to educate families applying for or receiving SSI about the CTC and the advanced CTC payments and reiterated that CTC should not affect SSI benefits. SSA will build upon their successful 2021 efforts by updating instructional material to frontline technicians that explains the impact of the CTC and EITC with persons filing for SSI and SSI recipients who have a child or children. In addition, will release a blog post on the importance of the CTC and EITC.</li><li><strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development </strong>will mobilize on-the-ground staff and stakeholders to help HUD-assisted households file taxes. Through targeted communications and promotion at conferences, HUD will provide information on the CTC and EITC, and connect VITA centers to public housing authorities, multifamily housing property managers, resident services providers, housing counselors, Continuums of Care, HIV/AIDS service organizations, victim service providers and tribal organizations. These efforts will reach staff at the more than 3,000 Public Housing Authorities (PHAs), the nearly 2,000 PHA-based service providers, 2,000 tribal housing partners, nearly 400 Continuums of Care, and the roughly 16,000 housing counselors, as well as nearly 14,000 Multifamily property managers and resident service providers. HUD will also partner with VITA centers across the country and continue our ongoing collaboration with AmeriCorps to mobilize more than 200 HUD-VISTA Volunteers to assist HUD families’ tax filing. Building on the ten stakeholder CTC trainings HUD held in the fall, HUD will coordinate with Treasury to hold targeted navigator trainings for HUD stakeholders on the CTC and EITC.</li><li><strong>The Administration for Children and Families at the Department of Health and Human Services </strong>will partner with local VITA sites with tax specialists, focusing on immigrant communities, young teen parents, parents in recovery and parents with mental health. They will also share videos of parents and grandparents who are trusted messengers who share their stories on how signing up for the tax credits made a significant impact on their lives.</li><li><strong>AmeriCorps </strong>will host a roundtable during the week of 2/14 with an AmeriCorps Seniors VITA center grantee in Baltimore. AmeriCorps is also a member of the Colorado Economic Mobility Partnership, a joint effort between Colorado Governor Jared Polis’ administration, the Colorado State Service Commission, Serve Colorado, Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment and AmeriCorps. The partnership kicked off on January 14, 2022, which was declared by Governor Polis as &lt;a href=&quot;#:~:text=Governor%20Primavera%20have%20announced%20January,%E2%80%9CAmeriCorps%20Economic%20Mobility%20Day.%E2%80%9D“AmeriCorps Economic Mobility Day</a>” and marked the initial deployment of two AmeriCorps NCCC teams focused on VITA service activities. AmeriCorps NCCC is a fulltime service program that supports young adults to serve on a team and make a positive impact in communities across the country while gaining valuable leadership skills. AmeriCorps NCCC has six additional projects identified to deploy its volunteers on tax preparation efforts, including the additional CTC follow-up work. All of the projects will include VITA tax prep for low-income individuals and will include a focus on CTC and Earned Income Tax Credit, as well as other rebates available for low-income individuals.</li><li><strong>The United States Department of Agriculture Food and Nutrition Services </strong>will inform and engage FNS stakeholders through email, traditional mailed and digital lifting up and reinforcing CTC outreach opportunities and supporting materials available by Treasury.&nbsp; FNS expects to reach more than 100,000 program operators, community organizations, and interested individuals directly through our collective platforms, with an even broader reach as FNS encourages the resharing of information.</li><li><strong>The Department of Education </strong>will share information on the Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit to grantees and organizations that primarily serve disadvantaged students. The Department will ask that these grantees and organizations share information with their communities.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Philanthropic Support of Tax Benefits Access.</strong><br>Dozens of philanthropic investors have made significant investments to help families access tax relief in 2022, coordinated by the CTC and EITC funders networks. <strong>The Annie E. Casey Foundation, the AARP Foundation, Doris Duke Charitable Foundation, The Gates Foundation, The David and Lucile Packard Foundation, The Rockefeller Foundation, Charles and Lynn Schusterman Family Philanthropies, and others have contributed </strong>more than $25 million in new investments into communities to support CTC and EITC. Investments area include:<br><br><strong><em>Testing New Models for Effective Outreach.</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>EITC Funders Network</strong>, in partnership with Community Foundation Opportunity Network <strong>(</strong>CFON) and CFLeads, is managing the <strong>Community Outreach and Opportunity Fund (CO-OP Fund)</strong>. The fund partners with 24 community foundations across the country to work with their local partners testing a range of innovative outreach and engagement strategies. The purpose of the CO-OP Fund is to engage community foundations and their strongly connected local community partners to ensure that as many families as possible receive the full Child Tax Credit (CTC) and Earned Income tax Credit (EITC) benefits they have earned, as quickly and easily as possible.</li><li>Funding the <strong>American Public Human Services Association </strong>to work with state human services agencies to connect with potential eligible families and assist families in filing taxes and getting their tax refunds.</li><li>Providing resources for organizations to help gather and widely disseminate outreach materials in multiple languages, conduct non-filer focus groups, and create customized messages to new filers for the EITC and CTC.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Commitments to Focus on Newly Eligible EITC Populations (Older and younger Workers).&nbsp;</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>The <strong>AARP Foundation</strong> is redoubling its outreach effort, developing a specialized toolkit, flyers, and postcards to let newly eligible older workers know about the EITC. They are investing deeply in three communities to build capacity and test effective models of outreach and engagement.</li><li>The <strong>Annie E. Casey and Rockefeller Foundations</strong> are initiating an aggressive social media campaign to reach young adults also newly eligible for the EITC.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Specific Funding for Puerto Rico’s CTC and EITC Eligible Populations.</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Funders are investing resources in leading organizations, such as <strong>Espacios Abiertos </strong>and <strong>Instituto del Desarrollo de la Joventud, </strong>in Puerto Rico to ensure that newly eligible populations are filing for the CTC and EITC.</li><li>This effort includes investments from the Rockefeller Foundation, the EITC Funder Network Pooled Fund and Hispanic Federation, who are providing support to Puerto Rican organizations to undertake and expand outreach and enrollment for the tax credits over the next two years.</li></ul>



<p><strong>About the Child Tax Credit: Tax Cuts for Families with Children.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Largest-ever Child Tax Credit: </strong>The American Rescue Plan dramatically expanded the Child Tax Credit – providing by far the largest credit ever. For families with children under 17, the American Rescue Plan increased the Child Tax Credit from $2,000 per child to $3,000 per child for children over the age of six and from $2,000 to $3,600 for children under the age of six. It also raised the age limit from 16 to 17, providing families of older children up to an additional $3,000 in Child Tax Credit.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>First-ever monthly tax payments to the families of 61 million children: </strong>In July, just four months after President Biden signed the American Rescue Plan, Treasury began distributing advance monthly Child Tax Credit payments to the overwhelming majority of families with children. Advance payments went out each month from July to December 2021 – providing most families with the first half of their Child Tax Credit.</li><li><strong>Payments were delivered on the same day – the 15<sup>th</sup> – of each month from July to December</strong>: Close to 90% of families enrolled in advance payments received their Child Tax Credit payments with direct deposit – on the 15th of every month (or earlier if the 15<sup>th</sup> fell on a weekend or a holiday), listed under “CHILDCTC”.</li><li><strong>Helping middle class families cover the costs of raising their children and dramatically reducing child poverty:</strong> The Child Tax Credit is helping middle income families cover the costs of raising their children, from paying for <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2021/10/nearly-a-third-of-parents-spent-child-tax-credit-on-school-expenses.html">childcare</a> to making their mortgage and car payments, to <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/up-front/2021/09/24/the-new-child-tax-credit-does-more-than-just-cut-poverty/">helping</a> build a college fund. The Child Tax Credit is also a critical tool to cut child poverty. Treasury estimates that the families of over 26 million lower-income children will receive the full credit for 2021 who would have previously gotten a partial credit or no credit because they had too little in income. Monthly Child Tax Credit payments had an immediate impact – <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w29285/w29285.pdf">reducing</a> food insufficiency among lower-income families by 25 percent. Experts estimate that expanded Child Tax Credit and other critical policies in the American Rescue Plan will have brought child poverty to its lowest levels on record.</li><li><strong>729,000 children in non-filing families received advance payments automatically: </strong>The Biden-Harris administration automatically enrolled the families of 729,000 children – whose parents or guardians had signed up for a previous Economic Impact Payment.</li><li><strong>First-ever simplified filing tools Child Tax Credit</strong>: The Biden-Harris Administration launched the first-ever non-filer tools for the Child Tax Credit in 2021, including a portal that was mobile friendly and available in Spanish.</li></ul>



<p><strong>About the Earned Income Tax Credit: Over 17 Million Americans to Benefit from Expansion of EITC for Workers Without Dependent Children.</strong><br>The American Rescue Plan expanded the Earned Income Tax Credit to include more people, more families, and more money by nearly tripling the credit for workers without dependent children and including younger (19-24) and older workers (65+) who were previously excluded.<br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Nearly tripled EITC to $1500 for workers without dependent children – benefitting 17 million Americans: </strong>The American Rescue Plan nearly tripled the Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children from about $540 to $1,500. The Center on Budget and Policy Priorities <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/american-rescue-plan-act-includes-critical-expansions-of-child-tax-credit-and">estimates</a> that this expansion has the potential to benefit <em><u>over 17 million Americans</u>.</em></li><li><strong>First increase to EITC for workers without dependent children since 1993: </strong>While the Earned Income Tax Credit provides thousands of dollars of critical relief to families with children, workers without dependent children, including younger workers, and workers with adult children, have not seen a meaningful increase in their Earned Income Tax Credit since 1993.</li><li><strong>Younger and older workers <em><u>Are</u> </em>eligible: </strong>Before the American Rescue Plan, people under 25 or 65 and over were ineligible for the Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children. The American Rescue Plan changed that. Younger workers (19-24) who are not half-time or full-time students, and older workers (65+) are newly eligible for the Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children. In addition – the American Rescue Plan increased the cap at which someone’s income made them ineligible for a benefit – from about $16,000 to over $21,000 for a single filer and from about $21,000 to more than $27,000 for a married couple.</li></ul>



<p><strong>APPENDIX: FULL LIST OF COMMITMENTS FROM NON-PROFITS AND COMMUNITY-BASED ORGANIZATIONS</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>AARP </strong>will host VITA sites, offer free tax assistance through their Tax Counseling for the Elderly program, and will host events to raise awareness about CTC and EITC in all 50 states.</li><li><strong>Afterschool Alliance</strong> will host a webinar that will be recorded and can be re-watched at any time.</li><li><strong>Agudath Israel of America </strong>will enlist accountants and other experts to educate and assist individuals and families in the community to obtain the CTC/EITC and will assist populations within their community that require language assistance (e.g. in Yiddish, Hebrew or Russian) to learn about the CTC/EITC.</li><li><strong>Alliance to End Hunger </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>American Children’s Campaign</strong> will distribute social media materials to their large network of organizational partners to share with their followers and lists.</li><li><strong>Americans for Tax Fairness </strong>will distribute flyers on the CTC and EITC and will promote the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>American Muslim Health Professionals </strong>will share information about CTC, its impact on child health, and ChildTaxCredit.gov on social media, email lists and newsletters.</li><li><strong>American Public Health Services Association </strong>will provide technical assistance and resources to state and local governments to support outreach efforts and increase awareness of benefits for family economic mobility through the Earned Income Tax Credit and the Child Tax Credit. APSHA will support development of targeted resources for state and local human service agencies to use in customer communications by text and web, as well as in-person resources. These efforts will include effective parent-led campaigns to raise awareness to these important benefit for all families.</li><li><strong>Association of American Medical Colleges </strong>will ask affiliates to share information with the communities they serve.</li><li><strong>Blue Future </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Boston Medical Center </strong>will share information about the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America </strong>will share information about free tax prep resources on Childtaxcredit.gov with their Boys &amp; Girls Clubs affiliates that serve 4.3 million youth at over 4,700 Club sites in a typical year.</li><li><strong>Building Back Together </strong>will share information about the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Care Income Now </strong>will host a press conference with community partners. They will distribute flyers on the CTC and EITC and will promote the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Catholic Charities USA </strong>and their local affiliates will continue to host trainings and share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Center on Budget and Policy Priorities </strong>will host a learning series on EITC/CTC outreach called Tax Time Thursdays every other week throughout the tax season. Presentation topics will include peer-to-peer outreach, reaching foster and homeless youth, reaching older adults, and reaching immigrants.</li><li><strong>Center for the Study of Social Policy </strong>will create and circulate flyers specific to their networks.</li><li><strong>Change Machine</strong> will reach out to 5,000 people, primarily nonprofit practitioners offering direct services to build financial security.</li><li><strong>CHILDREN AT RISK, the Texas Family Leadership Council, the Coalition on Human Needs, and the Partnership for America’s Children </strong>will co-host a training for Texas service providers on February 16.</li><li><strong>Children Now </strong>will distribute flyers on the CTC and EITC and will promote the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Children’s Action Alliance, Partnership for America’s Children, and the Coalition on Human Needs </strong>will co-host a training for Arizona service providers and other organizations in early March.</li><li><strong>Children’s Advocacy Alliance </strong>will distribute flyers on the CTC and EITC and will promote the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Children’s Defense Fund </strong>published FAQs about tax filing on their website and will discuss the CTC and EITC on media. They will send information and flyers on CTC/EITC to their email networks.</li><li><strong>Children’s HealthWatch </strong>will host a virtual event on how to assist families with accessing the CTC/EITC.</li><li><strong>Children’s Home &amp; Aid Society of Illinois </strong>will provide information and training to frontline staff to help families access the CTC/EITC. They will also post information on social media.</li><li><strong>Citizens’ Committee for New York, Inc. </strong>will host a training for frontline staff and will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>CityGate Network </strong>will distribute a 12-page publication to their 300 affiliates with information on the tax credits and how to access them.</li><li><strong>Coalition on Human Needs </strong>will host webinars for community health networks across the country. They will also partner with <strong>Lutheran Services in America</strong> and the <strong>Partnership for America’s</strong> <strong>Children</strong> on a training on February 17<sup>th</sup>. Coalition on Human Needs will also partner with <strong>UnidosUS</strong> and the <strong>Partnership for America’s Children</strong> on trainings for families in Spanish.</li><li><strong>Code for America’s </strong>GetYourRefund tool will continue to help tens of thousands of Americans with free, simple tax filing assistance.</li><li><strong>Common Sense Media</strong> will launch a direct texting campaign to eligible families and will host a press conference with community partners.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Community Catalyst </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Community Child Care Council (4Cs) of Alameda County </strong>will launch a direct texting campaign to eligible families.</li><li><strong>Community Economic Development of Michigan </strong>and its member organizations will host more than a dozen “Show Me The Money Days” &#8212; local financial empowerment and community resource fairs for lower-income families that will highlight free tax prep and state and federal tax credits including the CTC and EITC.</li><li><strong>Community Legal Aid Society, Inc. (Delaware) </strong>will post a training for community members on social media.</li><li><strong>Community Legal Services of Philadelphia </strong>will be hosting a Claim Your Cash Party in Philadelphia to help young people ages 18-25 learn about the tax credits and refunds they can get, including the Earned Income Tax Credit and the Child Tax Credit, if they are parents. Many low-income youth must support themselves and their families, but aren’t required to file taxes, and might not be getting all of the income support they are entitled to. CLS’s party will help youth engage in the process so they can claim their refunds and credits, which will help them support themselves and their families.</li><li><strong>Connecticut Association for Human Services </strong>will host pop up events, including a “Super Refund Saturday” on February 26 to help people with tax filing. They will also distribute information through social media, text campaigns, and other communications.</li><li><strong>Economic Security Project</strong>&nbsp;is spreading the word about the Day of Action to their network of 100+ advocacy and nonprofit groups with reach on the ground who can amplify the message and distribute it directly to impacted people and is working with Members of Congress to lift up.</li><li><strong>Educare Learning Network</strong> will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Education Alliance </strong>will host a VITA site and distribute their own translated materials.</li><li><strong>Espacios Abiertos Puerto Rico </strong>will launch an EITC/CTC data visualization map that shows the economic impact in dollars, number of families and children that will benefit from the credits and how it all relates to poverty levels island-wide and for each one of the 78 municipalities in Puerto Rico. This platform will serve as the compass for a strategic multi-sector collaborative effort across the island for a tax filing campaign and free tax preparation services.</li><li><strong>Evangelical Lutheran Church in America </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Family Equality </strong>will share information about childtaxcredit.gov on their LGBTQ+ family Facebook page and other on-line groups and will circulate a one-pager.</li><li><strong>Family Healthcare of St. George, Utah </strong>will share information on social media, and on their website news page.</li><li><strong>Feeding America </strong>will share materials on CTC/EITC and tax prep assistance with their 199 local affiliates and will host nation-wide webinars. They will also encourage further sharing of resources with over 60,000 faith-based and charitable food distribution partners. Feeding America will also invite network members engaging in SNAP application assistance to help with outreach. Additional actions include: adding new content on tax prep service to their website, sending text messages to their listserv, posting content on social media, post links to free tax prep services on the “thank you” pages displayed to neighbors upon electronic submission of an online referral form for SNAP application assistance.</li><li><strong>First Choice Primary Care </strong>will share CTC/EITC information with their staff and their community on their social media platform as well as at outreach events.</li><li><strong>First Focus on Children </strong>will host a virtual event in April.</li><li><strong>Food Research &amp; Action Center</strong> will host a training for frontline staff.</li><li><strong>Georgia Budget and Policy Institute </strong>will issue a press release and share a toolkit on CTC and EITC with partners.</li><li><strong>Get My Payment Illinois </strong>is working with a number of organizations on outreach and press, including a press release.</li><li><strong>Goodwill Industries International, Inc. </strong>will Goodwill share resources with our network of local Goodwill organizations and share information via social media channels.</li><li><strong>Hispanic Federation </strong>is committing $600,000 to support affiliate community-based organizations in Puerto Rico for tax prep assistance by way of Mobile Assistance Centers [“Tax Prep Mobile Labs”] deployed to low-income communities, mainly rural. In coordination with the Youth Development Institute (IDJ), they will also be supporting an outreach and strategic communications campaign to reach these families with resources to help them file federal tax returns in order to claim their Child Tax Credit.</li><li><strong>Hunger Free America </strong>will print and distribute a bilingual one pager on CTC/EITC in combination with our ongoing food benefits and vaccine outreach work in low-income neighborhoods in NYC, share information about CTC/EITC on social media and their website, and prepare their frontline staff – including those who answer calls for the USDA Hunger Hotline – with basic facts to share on CTC/EITC.</li><li><strong>Institute on Taxation and Economic Policy </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Jewish Federations of North America </strong>will share toolkits and information via weekly emails to 146 Jewish Federations during filing season and participate in a joint webinar with many other faith organizations for early March with human service providers, faith leaders, educators, and other groups that work with or encounter families.</li><li><strong>Lincoln VITA </strong>will host VITA free tax clinics at 11 sites in Lincoln, NE and will facilitate a virtual free tax preparation site.</li><li><strong>MAZON </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Minority Veterans of America </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Missouri Budget Project </strong>will share information on social media and will share the information with direct service organizations and tax assistance partners in Missouri.</li><li><strong>MomsRising </strong>will launch a bilingual social media campaign.</li><li><strong>Montessori Public Policy Initiative </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Mother’s Outreach Network/DC Guaranteed Income Coalition </strong>will print and distribute information on CTC/EITC and how to get help with free filing, share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their websites, and incorporate CTC/EITC information into existing communications streams, including text outreach to low-income populations.</li><li><strong>National Association of Hispanic Nurses </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media and with their email lists.</li><li><strong>National Association of Social Workers </strong>will co-host a webinar with the Coalition on Human Needs and will share information about CTC/EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>National Black Justice Coalition </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>National Center for Lesbian Rights </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC with LGBTQ parents via social media.</li><li><strong>National Community Action Partnership </strong>will host 5-10 virtual events that walk people through how to get their CTC/EITC by utilizing ChildTaxCredit.gov. They will also distirbute CTC/EITC flyers to frontline staff who can distribute them to families enrolled in Head Start and other programs such as LIHEAP, weatherization, case management, and emergency food assistance. National Community Action Partnership will also produce bilingual graphics and social media content for easy use and dissemination and will host office hour sessions with tax specialists to respond to specific tax credit inquiries from frontline staff helping families across their network. The 200 Community Action Agencies that are units of local go</li><li><strong>National Military Family Association </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>National Urban League </strong>will print and distribute information on CTC/EITC and how to get help with free filing, share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their websites, and incorporate CTC/EITC information into existing communications streams, including text outreach to low-income populations.</li><li><strong>National Women’s Law Center </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Network Lobby for Catholic Social Justice </strong>will host a webinar with faith communities in early March and will integrate CTC/EITC into planned communications throughout tax season.</li><li><strong>NN4Y </strong>will share info on social media and will provide very practical resources to their youth homelessness service providers about EITC for homeless and foster youth.</li><li><strong>ParentsTogether Action</strong> will host online events for members to walk them through the tax filing process and share information.</li><li><strong>PFLAG </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Philabundance </strong>will hold a training to reach partner agencies and members of their network.</li><li>Propel, a mission-driven financial technology company, will provide information via the Providers app to connect more than 5 million low-income families to information and partners to help them file taxes to receive the EITC and CTC.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Prosperity Now </strong>will include PSAs about CTC/EITC at all external and learning events and will send emails to their list of over 20,000 people.</li><li><strong>Religious Action Center of Reform Judaism </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Religious Organizations including Friends Committee on National Legislation, Salvation Army, National Association of Evangelicals, Bread for the World, National Council of Jewish Women </strong>will host a joint webinar.</li><li><strong>RESULTS </strong>will embed messages about CTC/EITC and ChildTaxCredit.gov in letters to the editor generated by RESULTS volunteers in local newspapers.</li><li><strong>Robinson Elementary Community Hub </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Save the Children </strong>and their local affiliates will share materials in English and Spanish with individuals and families they serve and also amplify CTC/EITC information through their social media channels.</li><li><strong>SaverLife </strong>will share their one-stop guide which highlights CTC/EITC with their networks.</li><li><strong>Shah Family Foundation/FindYourFunds </strong>will work with the Massachusetts Department of Transitional Assistance to send texts messages to 1 in 7 Massachusetts families and will host a statewide webinar with over 200 providers on February 16. They will also host Facebook Live Events with key groups representing immigrant leaders in Portuguese and Spanish.</li><li><strong>Skagit Legal Aid </strong>will leverage recently received funding from the Washington Department of Commerce and the Skagit County Commissioners to conduct outreach to historically disadvantaged communities in Skagit County while also resolving unmet civil legal needs that have prevented them from not regularly filing tax returns. The project will aim to serve the following communities: Single Parents with Young Children; Individuals Living with a Disability; Low-Income Seniors; Rural Black, Indigenous, and People of Color (BIPOC), emphasizing those who identify as Hispanic, Latinx, or Indigenous; Immigrants, emphasizing Mixteco and Triqui speaking farmworkers; and Tribal Members, emphasizing the Swinomish Indian Tribal Community, Upper Skagit Tribe, Samish Indian Nation, and the Sauk-Suiattle Indian Tribe.</li><li><strong>Southern Economic Advancement Project </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Start Early </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>StreetCred at Boston Medical Center</strong> will run a VITA site at Boston Medical Center and distribute their own VITA tax site information in English, Spanish, Haitian Creole, and Portuguese.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Student PIRGs </strong>will distribute a flyer to staff and administrators on campuses that work with graduate students &amp; non-traditional students and will send it out to their student e-mail lists.</li><li><strong>Student Veterans of America </strong>share information about the CTC/EITC on social media and through their newsletter.</li><li><strong>The Arc of the United States </strong>will host events on CTC/EITC which will reach hundreds of people with disabilities, their families, and the direct care workforce.</li><li><strong>Think Babies NC Alliance </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Think of Us </strong>will directly contacting 22,000 young people to make sure they are aware that they may be eligible for the ETIC. In addition, they will provide marketing support to 44 states foster care systems.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>TransLatin@ </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>UnidosUS </strong>will deploy a tax credits campaign to promote the CTC/EITC which will include: distributing resources to nearly 300 affiliates, hosting townhalls and navigator trainings, supporting efforts to promote CTC/EITC in Puerto Rico, sharing content on social media accounts.</li><li><strong>United State of Women </strong>will work with local partner organizations on the ground in communities to refer and send information on the free tax prep services to their memberships.</li><li><strong>United Way of Puerto Rico </strong>has implemented five Facilitated Self-Service Centers (FSA-Facilitated Self Assistance), in the municipalities of San Juan, Ponce, Mayagüez, Arecibo, Canóvanas and remote centers and is operating a 2-1-1 call center offering information and referral on CTC, VITA Centers, Facilitated Self-Service Centers. They will help schedule appointments to fill out the digital 1040-PR form at the UWPR FSA Centers, register volunteers, and collaborate with organizations in Puerto Rico to expand these services.</li><li><strong>United Way Worldwide </strong>will host more than 300 VITA sites through their local affiliates. United Way Worldwide will also offer tax preparation support through MyFreeTaxes. In addition, they will host a webinar for local partners around the country to update them on what’s new this year with CTC/EITC and tools/resources available to them to help individuals file their taxes (e.g., VITA, MyFreeTaxes, ChildTaxCredit.gov, tool kits etc.). The webinar will be presented in partnership with <strong>Prosperity Now</strong> and <strong>The Jewish Federation</strong> during the first two weeks of March.</li><li><strong>Virginia Campaign for a Family Friendly Economy </strong>will share information on social media and on their website.</li><li><strong>Vote Common Good </strong>will dedicate a podcast to CTC/EITC awareness and outreach.</li><li><strong>We Got Us </strong>will provide information about CTC/EITC during community outreach events in the coming months.</li><li><strong>Women of Color in the Global Women’s Strike</strong> will continue to organize and participate in community-based events in low income communities with information on how people can get their CTC/EITC.</li><li><strong>Youth Development Institute/Instituto del Desarrollo de la Juventud (IDJ) </strong>will encourage national and local partners to become VITA volunteers and/or allocate funds for CTC tax assistance efforts, post on their social media accounts stories addressing frequently asked questions about CTC in Puerto Rico and informing about free tax prep services, and activate local CTC champions (journalist and influencer for mothers with children, “Milly Méndez”) to re-share social media posts.</li><li><strong>YMCA </strong>will encourage local YMCAs to post information about free tax prep services in highly visible, highly trafficked physical spaces and will post to social media.</li><li><strong>YWCA USA </strong>will distribute materials to their associations throughout the country.</li><li><strong>ZERO TO THREE </strong>will share information on social media.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Chancellor Scholz of the Federal Republic of Germany at Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/remarks-by-president-biden-and-chancellor-scholz-of-the-federal-republic-of-germany-at-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 3:40 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Please, sit down.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; I’d like to start by thanking Chancellor Scholz for making this visit to Washington.&#160; We had an opportunity to have a very productive meeting.&#160; I think our staffs wondered whether we were going to let them in at all.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>3:40 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Please, sit down.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’d like to start by thanking Chancellor Scholz for making this visit to Washington.&nbsp; We had an opportunity to have a very productive meeting.&nbsp; I think our staffs wondered whether we were going to let them in at all.&nbsp; We spent the first half hour or more talking together, and &#8212; and it’s been a very, very useful meeting.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of the things that struck me was the shared values, and &#8212; that shape how each of us approaches leadership, among them the foundational commitment to the dignity of workers and the need to treat all people with respect.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I enjoyed speaking with you, Olaf.&nbsp; And I know, working together, we’ll continue to strengthen and deepen our alliance and the extensive partnership between Germany and the United States.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of course, at the top of our agenda today was our united approach to deterring Russia&#8217;s threats against Ukraine and the longstanding principles of rule-based international order.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we spent most of our time talking about.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Germany and the United States, together with our Allies and partners, are working closely together to pursue diplomatic resolutions of this situation.&nbsp; And diplomacy is the very best way forward for all sides, we both agree, including best for Russia, in our view.&nbsp; And we have made it very clear we&#8217;re ready to continue talks in good faith with Russia.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Germany has also been a leader in pushing de-escalation of tensions and encouraging dialogue through the Normandy Format.&nbsp; But if Russia makes the choice to further invade Ukraine, we are jointly ready and all of NATO is ready.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, the Chancellor and I discussed our close cooperation and developed a strong package of sanctions that are going to clearly demonstrate international resolve and impose swift and severe consequences if Russia violates Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty and its territorial integrity.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to thank Germany and our &#8212; and all of our other partners in Eastern Europe &#8212; in the European Union for their work in this united effort.&nbsp; We are in agreement that it cannot be business as usual if Russia further invades.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also discussed our shared commitment to NATO&#8217;s Article 5 responsibilities and reassurance of our eastern flank allies.&nbsp; We’re united in that as well.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Already, the United States is sending troops to reinforce the Alliance, and I want to thank the Chancellor of Germany for hosting additional U.S. forces and for the longstanding hospitality to our women and men in uniform.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also discussed the challenges we&#8217;re facing to the international order from China, along with Russia and other competitors that are pursuing more illiberal futures.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve agreed that Germany and the United States will continue to work together to ensure that the rules and principles governing emerging technologies are geared to advance freedom of opportunity, not repression or authoritarianism.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also reaffirmed our commitment to completing the work of integrating the Western Balkans into the European institutions and to finally realize a Europe that is whole, free, and at peace.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With Germany holding the presidency of the G7, we also talked about how that form can harness the world&#8217;s leading democracies to advance a robust agenda of global &#8212; on global challenges, from ending the pandemic to addressing climate change.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the bottom line is this: Whether as Allies in NATO, partners through the European Union, as leaders of the G7 and G20, or through our strong bilateral relationship, Germany and the United States are close friends and reliable partners, and we can count on one another.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There is no issue of global importance where Germany and the United States are not working together strength-to-strength and applying and amplifying our efforts together.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I want to thank you, Olaf, for making the journey today.&nbsp; And I look forward to being the first of many opportunities we can spend together, beginning this meeting and throughout the rest of the year and the rest of our terms.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, thank you and welcome.&nbsp; The floor is yours, sir.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Good afternoon from my side as well.&nbsp; I&#8217;m very grateful that we had the opportunity to talk in much detail today, and that I was able to make my first official visit here and that we also could talk about the important questions that we&#8217;re dealing with today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are in a very difficult situation, and it is a good thing that Joe and I were able to discuss what we need to do in this difficult context.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of course, there is a military threat in Ukraine &#8212; against Ukraine, and we cannot remain silent on that.&nbsp; We see the number of Russian troops along the Ukrainian border, and that is a serious threat to European security.&nbsp; And this is why it is important that we act together, that we stand together, and that we do what is necessary together.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is important that all allies &#8212; the U.S. and Germany, the transatlantic partnership between the U.S. and Europe, NATO &#8212; say the same thing, speak with one voice, and do things together.&nbsp; And we made it very clear: If there was a military aggression against Ukraine, this will entail severe consequences that we agreed upon together, severe sanctions that we have worked on together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there will be a high price for Russia.&nbsp; This is a very clear message; everybody has understood it.&nbsp; And I think this message has been made clear again and again so that even Russia has understood the message now.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is important is that we also intensively worked on preparing possible sanctions together.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want to start once there is a military aggression against Ukraine; we have prepared a reaction that will help us to react swiftly if needed, and we will do that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the same time, it is important to use all diplomatic means we have.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m very glad about your great willingness to move forward together, especially the bilateral talks between the U.S. and Russia, and, of course, the talks that we have agreed upon within the NATO-Russia format.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is also important, also because Russia needs to understand that NATO stands together and that NATO is prepared.&nbsp; After so many years, there have not been any talks in this format.&nbsp; So, it is a good sign that they are happening now.&nbsp; Of course, we have controversial debates there, but it is important that we talk.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the same is true for the OSCE where we need to discuss about security in Europe.&nbsp; This is also a progress, as tiresome as it may be.&nbsp; And we have not yet reached any very substantial conclusions yet, but it is good to see that this format plays a role now.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the same is true for the talks between Ukraine, Russia, France, and Germany &#8212; the Normandy Format.&nbsp; We have this format, but we haven&#8217;t been able to really use it in a productive way over the last few years, so now we have come back to that format.&nbsp; We&#8217;re having tough discussions in that format, and that shows that there are ways that will lead us out of this difficult situation.</p>



<p>And this dual-track approach of clear announcements with regard to sanctions that will be taken if there is a military aggression and, at the same time, keeping all dialogue formats open &#8212; I think this is the most promising strategy one can have.&nbsp; And that is what we&#8217;re doing together, and we stand side by side in this approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also talked about many other topics that are important for us today, especially when it comes to the G7 presidency of the Federal Republic of Germany.&nbsp; We will work closely as strong economies, strong democracies.&nbsp; And we also therefore have a special mandate to contribute to cohesion worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And part of this is that we continue to do everything we can to make sure that the citizens of the world can be vaccinated not only in our rich countries, but also in countries where people would love to have the vaccine but don&#8217;t have access yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these are initiatives that we have carried out together and that are of utmost importance worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The same is true for fighting manmade climate change &#8212; a big topic that keeps us all busy.&nbsp; Even though it is obvious that only a global solution can be successful, because climate is a global thing.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t stop at national borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As an industrialized nation, we have an important contribution to make.&nbsp; We have technological opportunities, economic opportunities, and have to use them in order to prepare a situation where we and others can enjoy prosperity without harming the climate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is the big challenge that we see and that is of great importance to us.&nbsp; So, this is why we want to work together on this strategy and use a climate club of likeminded people and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These are some of the topics we discussed.&nbsp; And once again, the personal discussion we had illustrates the excellent cooperation between our countries, the strong bond we have within our transatlantic partnership, and the fact that both countries can rely on each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll now take a couple questions to each &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reuters.&nbsp; Andra- &#8212; Andrea.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got the first question.</p>



<p>Q    Thank you, Mr.  President.  And thank you, Chancellor Scholz.  Mr.  President, I have wanted to ask you about this Nord Stream project that you&#8217;ve long opposed.  You didn&#8217;t mention it just now by name, nor did Chancellor Scholz.  Did you receive assurances from Chancellor Scholz today that Germany will, in fact, pull the plug on this project if Russia invades Ukraine?  And did you discuss what the definition of &#8220;invasion&#8221; could be?</p>



<p>And then, Chancellor Scholz:</p>



<p>(Speaks German.) (As interpreted.)&nbsp; If I may ask you, Chancellor Scholz &#8212; you said there was some strategic ambiguity that was needed in terms of sanctions.&nbsp; I just wanted to know whether the sanctions you are envisaging and the EU is working on &#8212; and the U.S. as well &#8212; are already finished, finalized, or is there still work ongoing?</p>



<p>And you&#8217;re not really saying what the details are.&nbsp; Is that just an excuse for Germany, maybe, to not support the SWIFT measures?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; The first question first.&nbsp; If Germany &#8212; if Russia invades &#8212; that means tanks or troops crossing the &#8212; the border of Ukraine again &#8212; then there will be &#8212; we &#8212; there will be no longer a Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; We will bring an end to it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But how will you &#8212; how will you do that exactly, since the project and control of the project is within Germany&#8217;s control?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We will &#8212; I promise you, we&#8217;ll be able to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much for your question.&nbsp; I want to be absolutely clear: We have intensively prepared everything to be ready with the necessary sanctions if there is a military aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is necessary.&nbsp; It is necessary that we do this in advance so that Russia can clearly understand that these are far-reaching, severe measures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is part of this process that we do not spell out everything in public because Russia could understand that there might be even more to come.&nbsp; And, at the same time, it is very clear we are well prepared with far-reaching measures.&nbsp; We will take these measures together with our Allies, with our partners, with the U.S., and we will take all necessary steps.&nbsp; You can be sure that there won&#8217;t be any measures in which we have a differing approach.&nbsp; We will act together jointly.</p>



<p>(Speaks in English.) And possibly this is a good idea to say to our American friends: We will be united, we will act together, and we will take all the necessary steps.&nbsp; And all the necessary steps will be done by all of us together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And will you commit today &#8212; will you commit today to turning off and pulling the plug on Nord Stream 2?&nbsp; You didn&#8217;t mention it, and you haven&#8217;t mentioned it.</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve already said, we are acting together, we are absolutely united, and we will not be taking different steps.&nbsp; We will do the same steps, and they will be very, very hard to Russia, and they should understand.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You can recognize someone now, Chancellor.</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Herr Fischer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Michael Fischer, DPA.&nbsp; Mr.&nbsp; President, one question to you: The U.S., over the last few years, have exported heavy weapons to Ukraine, and Germany excludes that &#8212; has only delivered 5,000 helmets to Ukraine.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t you think that NATO should act unanimously in this respect and Germany, as the strongest European NATO partner, should also deliver heavy weapons to Ukraine?&nbsp; And Ukraine has asked Germany to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on Nord Stream 2, I would also like to ask: Don&#8217;t you think, with regards to the threat posed by Russia, Germany should already rethink its position on Nord Stream 2?</p>



<p>And the third question, if I may: Over the last few days and weeks, there has been severe criticism from the U.S. media and from Congress as well vis-à-vis Germany about the reliability of Germany as an ally.&nbsp; This has been called into question.&nbsp; Do you understand this criticism?&nbsp; Is Germany a reliable partner, from your point of view?</p>



<p>And, Mr. Chancellor, also a question to you: Nord Stream 2 &#8212; you said all options around the table.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not mentioning Nord Stream 2 by name.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t you think if you were to spell this out, you could win back trust as a strong ally here for the U.S.?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no need to win back trust.&nbsp; He has the complete trust of the United States.&nbsp; Germany is our &#8212; one of our most important allies in the world.&nbsp; There is no doubt about Germany&#8217;s partnership with the United States.&nbsp; None.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to helping Ukraine, one of the largest contributors financially to Ukraine has been Germany.&nbsp; Germany has been in the forefront of making sure &#8212; providing economic assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You also asked the question &#8212; you asked so many I can&#8217;t remember them all.&nbsp; But in terms of the U.S. media saying Germany is not reliable, Germany is completely reliable &#8212; completely, totally, thoroughly reliable.&nbsp; I have no doubt about Germany at all.</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; We are united.&nbsp; And the transatlantic partnership between Germany and the U.S. is one of the permanent pillars of German policy, and it will be relevant in the future as well &#8212; just as relevant.&nbsp; And this will be one of our top priorities always.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On behalf of NATO, we are the country in continental Europe that is doing &#8212; making the largest contribution: financial means and also military power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we are the country that contributes a great share &#8212; we&#8217;re not fully &#8212; we don&#8217;t fully agree with you as who pays the biggest part of financial support to Ukraine.&nbsp; So, since 2014, about 2 billion U.S. dollars direct bilateral support and, within the EU, an additional 3.8 billion that is made available.&nbsp; So a substantial financial means to stabilize the Ukraine economy, and we are willing to continue with that sort of contribution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is the very strong and unbreakable friendship between our two countries.&nbsp; Part of this is that with regard to the difficult situation at the Ukrainian border due to the Russian troops, we have made it very clear we will unanimously act in terms of sanctions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Mr. President, once again, a question with regard to arms exports.&nbsp; Do you think it is okay that NATO partners have different approaches here?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on Nord Stream 2, once again, do you think the current positioning of Germany with regard to the Russian threat is okay?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Look, there is no doubt in America&#8217;s mind that Germany is an incredibly reliable Ally and one of the leading physical powers in NATO, number one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, the notion that Nord Stream T [sic] would go &#8212; Nord Stream 2 would go forward with an invasion by the Russians &#8212; it’s just not going to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, Wall Street Journal, Sabrina.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Based on everything you know now, do you think that President Putin will authorize an invasion of Ukraine before the end of the winter?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what is your message to the roughly 30,000 Americans who are currently in Ukraine?&nbsp; Do you think that they should leave the country?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ve had discussions &#8212; numerous discussions with the &#8212; with the Russians and particularly with Putin.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that he&#8217;s even made a &#8212; I don&#8217;t know that he knows what he&#8217;s going to do.&nbsp; And I think he has to realize that it would be a gigantic mistake for him to move on Ukraine.&nbsp; The impact on Europe and the rest of the world would be devastating, and he would pay a heavy price.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have been very, very straightforward and blunt with President Putin, both on the phone and in person.&nbsp; We will impose the most severe sanctions that have ever been imposed &#8212; economic sanctions &#8212; and there&#8217;ll be a lot to pay for that down the road.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It will affect others as well.&nbsp; It will affect us somewhat.&nbsp; It will affect Europeans.&nbsp; But it will have profound impact on his economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; I &#8212; but I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; I know that he&#8217;s in a position now to be able to invade almost &#8212; assuming that the ground is frozen above Kyiv.&nbsp; He has the capacity to do that.&nbsp; What he&#8217;s going to do, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think anybody knows but him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is your message to the Americans who are currently in Ukraine &#8212; should they leave the country?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;d be wise to leave the country.&nbsp; Not &#8212; I don&#8217;t mean our &#8212; I don&#8217;t mean &#8212; I&#8217;m not talking about our diplomatic corps; I&#8217;m talking about Americans who are there.&nbsp; I’d hate to see them get caught in a crossfire if in fact they did invade.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no need for that.&nbsp; And I &#8212; if I were they &#8212; if I had anyone there, I&#8217;d say leave.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to Chancellor Scholz: Can you outline specific steps that Germany is taking to reduce its energy dependence on Russia?&nbsp; And what do you say to those who suggest that German reliance on Russian gas is limiting Europe&#8217;s options for how to respond to the crisis in Ukraine?</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much for raising that question because it gives me the opportunity to address a topic that&#8217;s important to me.&nbsp; One good news, maybe, within its strategy on fighting manmade climate change, Germany has decided at very short &#8212; in a very short period of time to phase out of the use of oil and gas by &#8212; very soon.&nbsp; And by 2045, Germany will have a carbon neutral economy as one of the strongest economies of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with regard to these energies &#8212; we often think about heating at home and driving a car, but we&#8217;re talking about industrial production: producing steel, chemical substances, cement.&nbsp; And changing these industrial processes and reorganizing such systems is what we have planned.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this year, we will continue to take far-reaching decisions that will help us to use more wind energy &#8212; offshore wind energy, onshore wind energy &#8212; and solar energy; and expand the capacities, expand the grids; and have a strategy for Germany but also worldwide on the use of hydrogen, which is a central element for us to change our industrial processes that are using oil and gas right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The industry is willing to be on board.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing this together with them, but it will probably be the biggest industrial modernization project in Germany in 100 years, with very good prospects that we will develop new technologies that other partners in the world can use as well, and this will help us fight climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, the energy mix today, we are talking about one quarter of our energy that is linked to gas.&nbsp; And only part of that gas comes from Russia; a big part comes from Norway or the Netherlands.&nbsp; And, of course, it is very important to us that we develop an infrastructure that will give us the opportunity to have all options available and react if needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you don&#8217;t have to be concerned.&nbsp; There are some who should be concerned who see themselves maybe too much as a deliverer of such resources.&nbsp; Because we are focusing on renewable energies, we will go down that path and make sure that this is the profitable future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Rinke.<br><br>     Q    (As interpreted.)  Mr. President, I would like to ask you a question about LNG.  Germany and Europe are much more dependent on Russian gas than other regions of the world, and you promised European allies to help with LNG.  But this resource is more expensive; it&#8217;s not available in the volumes that might be needed to replace Russian gas.  And I would like to know from you how you would help Europeans in case of a conflict with Russia.  Is this an empty promise, or what can you really do?  What can you offer?<br><br>     And, in addition, the U.S. are buying oil from Russia worth billions of dollars.  And I would like to know whether these transfers are also part of the sanctions package against Russia. </p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Mr. Chancellor &#8212; liquefied natural gas.&nbsp; There is a big controversy in Germany about fracking gas and how far is LNG even a real replacement, or is it also with a view to the climate collab you intend to found.&nbsp; Is it really an alternative to Russian pipeline gas?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Let me respond.&nbsp; First of all, we are looking at opportunities to make up for lost gas &#8212; LNG &#8212; from Russia.&nbsp; We&#8217;re underway of trying to see what we can do to do that and dealing with our friends around the world, as well.&nbsp; We think we could make up a significant portion of it that would be lost.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, you know, what everybody forgets here is Russia needs to be able to sell that gas and sell that oil.&nbsp; Russia relies &#8212; a significant part of Russia&#8217;s budget &#8212; it&#8217;s the only thing they really have to export.&nbsp; And if, in fact, it&#8217;s cut off, then they&#8217;re going to be hurt very badly, as well.&nbsp; And it’s of consequence to them as well.&nbsp; This is not just a one-way street.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, we are looking at what we could do to help compensate for loss of &#8212; immediate loss of gas in Europe if it occurs.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been working on for some time now.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; I can confirm that we work closely with the United States of America, and Joe Biden and I are working closely together as well.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are prepared for all kinds of situation.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of what we do when we say we prepare sanctions.&nbsp; That means we need to be able to react at any time, and this is happening.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With regard to the use of LNG, I can say that the biggest volume of LNG used across the world is gas, and that is part of the debate.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Concerning a long-term perspective, I already outlined what this is about.&nbsp; We will modernize our economy.&nbsp; And where gas is being used, we will switch to hydrogen.&nbsp; This will be a process that will happen faster than many might imagine today, and that will create a bright future for all of us.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on de-escalation, sir.&nbsp; Do you still believe there’s an off-ramp for Vladimir Putin here?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, do you believe there’s still an off-ramp for him &#8212; that de-escalation is an actual possibility, given that there are 100,000 troops at the border?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; The answer is “yes.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">4:08 P.M. EST<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Stakeholder Call on the Partnerships for Climate-Smart Commodities&#160;Program</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/readout-of-stakeholder-call-on-the-partnerships-for-climate-smart-commodities-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 23:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, White House National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy and Department of Agriculture Under Secretary for Farm Production and Conservation Robert Bonnie led a call with farmers, ranchers, foresters, and climate advocates to discuss the Department of Agriculture’s new Partnerships for Climate-Smart Commodities program, which will invest $1 billion. On the call, Advisor McCarthy tied the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, White House National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy and Department of Agriculture Under Secretary for Farm Production and Conservation Robert Bonnie led a call with farmers, ranchers, foresters, and climate advocates to discuss the Department of Agriculture’s new Partnerships for Climate-Smart Commodities program, which will invest $1 billion.</p>



<p>On the call, Advisor McCarthy tied the program back to President Biden’s January 2021 Executive Order on “Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad,” in which the President emphasized that our farmers, ranchers, and foresters can help lead the fight against climate change by advancing practices that reduce greenhouse gases and collect and store carbon in soils, trees, and vegetation. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Under Secretary Bonnie emphasized how the new Partnerships for Climate-Smart Commodities program builds on a year of USDA efforts to realize that vision. Through this $1 billion investment, USDA will fund pilots and demonstration projects that encourage farmers and foresters to deploy climate-smart production; implement innovative approaches to measure and verify greenhouse gas benefits; and then connect those climate-smart commodities to markets that value them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Advisor McCarthy noted that this initiative will amass more information than has ever before been available regarding the climate benefits that the U.S.’s agricultural and forestry sectors can generate. She predicted that the program could be a “game changer” for the U.S., and for the many nations around the world with significant agricultural and forestry sectors. Both Under Secretary Bonnie and Advisor McCarthy also emphasized that the program will focus on equity and the Administration’s Justice40 commitment that substantial program benefits flow to smaller and underserved producers. &nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-chancellor-olaf-scholz-of-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 23:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. welcomed Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany to the White House.&#160;President Biden reaffirmed his commitment to further strengthening U.S.-German relations and working with the new Chancellor to deepen the transatlantic partnership.&#160;The leaders discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders, reaffirmed their support&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. welcomed Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany to the White House.&nbsp;President Biden reaffirmed his commitment to further strengthening U.S.-German relations and working with the new Chancellor to deepen the transatlantic partnership.&nbsp;The leaders discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders, reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and reiterated their commitment to preventing Russia from using energy as a weapon.&nbsp;The leaders also discussed Germany’s G7 Presidency, including taking stronger joint action to end the COVID-19 pandemic, building back better health security, tackling the climate crisis, and supporting an inclusive global economic recovery.&nbsp;The leaders committed to cooperate closely on challenges posed by China and to continue promoting stability and prosperity in the Western Balkans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 7,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/07/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-7-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:55 P.M. EST&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; I know we have a time limit because of the press avail with the Germans, so we will get to as many people as possible.&#160; I just have a couple of items for you at the top. Today, the White&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:55 P.M. EST<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; I know we have a time limit because of the press avail with the Germans, so we will get to as many people as possible.&nbsp; I just have a couple of items for you at the top.</p>



<p>Today, the White House Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment, led by Vice President Harris as Chair and Labor Secr- &#8212; and as well as Chair &#8212; as Chair and Labor Secretary &#8212; as well as Chair, and Labor Secretary Walsh as Vice-Chair –&nbsp;released publicly the report it delivered to President Biden&nbsp;that&nbsp;includes nearly 70 recommendations to promote worker organizing and collective bargaining.</p>



<p>The recommendations include ways to increase private-sector workers’ access to information about their existing right to join or organize a union &#8212; a hugely important issue for the President.</p>



<p>The President accepted the recommendations, and as a follow-up, the task force will submit a second report to the President in six months, which will describe progress in implementation and contain additional proposals for further action.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note that, today, the Secretary &#8212; Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack will be announcing that the Partnerships for Climate-Smart connection &#8212; Commodities program, in which the Department of Agriculture will invest $1 billion in partnerships to support America’s climate-smart farmers, ranchers, and forest landowners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So these funds will go to projects that promote farming, ranching, and forestry practices that either remove carbon from the atmosphere or cut greenhouse gas emissions.&nbsp; And the investment is the latest Biden administration initiative aimed at combatting climate change with a goal to cut the farm sector’s greenhouse gas emissions in half by 2030 and put the United States on a path to net-zero emissions by 2050.</p>



<p>Finally, I wanted to note: I have a Team USA water bottle out here today and a Team USA pin out here today.&nbsp; As you all know, we made a decision &#8212; the United States &#8212; not to send a diplomatic or official delegation to Beijing given the PRC’s ongoing genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang and other human rights abuses.&nbsp; And that was a clear statement and a clear policy made by our government.</p>



<p>But at the same time, we wanted to note Team USA has our full support.&nbsp; We’re behind them; we’re watching from home.&nbsp; And we want to thank them and their families for everything they have sacrificed over the course of time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lots of athletes to watch. &nbsp;I’ll just give a plug, because I’m an Olympics-obsessed person: Nathan Chen, we’re going to watch him; Chloe Kim; Mikaela Shiffrin, you’ve got lots of more chances.</p>



<p>Anyway, we’ll be rooting for our U.S. athletes even as we made a very important statement about our concerns about Beijing’s and the Chinese human rights abuses.</p>



<p>With that, let’s go ahead.&nbsp; Colleen, kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, regarding Dr. Lander, I wondered if he should have been reprimanded more strongly, given the President&#8217;s pledge on his first day in office to, you know, fire anybody who mistreated their employees.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just give you an overview of what we have done to date.&nbsp; And I know there may be more questions on this, of course, which we welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has been crystal clear with all of us about his high expectations of how he and his staff should be creating a respectful work environment.</p>



<p>And one of the steps we took early on in the administration was to institute a Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy across the Executive Office of the President &#8212; something that was done early on.</p>



<p>It was because of this policy and this process that when these &#8212; when the complaint was filed, a full and thorough investigation was conducted pursuant to that policy.</p>



<p>In addition, following the conclusion of the thorough investigation into these actions, senior White House officials conveyed directly to Dr. Lander that his behavior was inappropriate and the corrective actions that were needed, which were &#8212; which the White House will monitor for compliance moving forward.</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that Dr. Lander also sent a message to his staff outlining some of the steps he&#8217;s intending to take to build a respectful work environment.&nbsp; And certainly, we would encourage those.&nbsp; And again, the team &#8212; the senior team will be watching for compliance to these steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It looks like he’s had a history of, you know, possible mistreatment of his employees over a long period of time.&nbsp; How can you be sure that this reprimand will stick?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just reiterate, again, that &#8212; well, let me start with the first part of your question.</p>



<p>Each nominee undergoes a thorough vetting process as a part of their nomination and confirmation process.&nbsp; And, of course, we look carefully to ensure each candidate&#8217;s suitability for the role they&#8217;re chosen for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Lander’s record was thoroughly examined as a part of his confirmation, and he received bipartisan support, including final confirmation with a voice vote.</p>



<p>But again, once we were made aware of the complaint, we launched a thorough investigation, and compliance with the recommendations is &#8212; will be &#8212; will be required in this regard.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On Ukraine, Zelenskyy’s office said yesterday that a diplomatic solution seems much more likely than war, and then we saw Jake Sullivan say yesterday that an invasion could come at any day.&nbsp; Can you help us square the difference here and why there still seems to be such a dark assessment &#8212; a stark difference in assessing the threat?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what our National Security Advisor also conveyed during some interviews with a range of your networks yesterday was that we&#8217;re pursuing a two-track approach, which includes deterrence and diplomacy, but that we are ready either way for whatever decision President Putin might make.&nbsp; And we don&#8217;t have a new assessment of his decision and where he stands on it.</p>



<p>We also need to be prepared.&nbsp; Being prepared is exactly what we can do from the U.S. government, in coordination and in partnership with our NATO Allies, our partners in Eastern Europe, and of course, the Ukrainians.&nbsp; And that is what we&#8217;re focused on.&nbsp; So, we don&#8217;t actually see it as a conflict.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Kyiv wrong, then, on this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In terms of the preparations?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A diplomatic solution being more likely than war.&nbsp; It seems hard to square that with Sullivan saying that an invasion could come at any day.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we would certainly prefer a diplomatic solution.&nbsp; I think that’s everybody’s preference and everybody’s hope.</p>



<p>But again, this is up to &#8212; remains up to President Putin to make a decision about which path he is going to take.&nbsp; We don’t have an assessment of that, so what our focus is on is preparing for a range of contingencies, including in coordination with the Ukrainians, making sure they have the supplies they need, the humanitarian assistance they need, the security assistance they need.&nbsp; And we’re doing that &#8212; we’re doing that consistently, even while we are closely watching the buildup of troops on the border.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To switch topics if I may, Delta’s CEO is asking for the administration’s help in creating this no-fly list for unruly passengers.&nbsp; Is that something the administration supports?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not had a chance to talk to our team about that.&nbsp; I can see if there’s any opinion on that from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And, quickly, a housekeeping thing: Do you have a sense of when the President will start meeting with SCOTUS candidates?&nbsp; And if any of these meetings happen in Delaware, where the President &#8212; where there are not visitor logs, does the White House pledge to disclose that those meetings took place?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, at this point, I don’t have any more details about the process to outline for you.&nbsp; As you know, what the President has been focused on over the course of the last several days is reviewing and consulting with internal team members on a group of qualified nominees.&nbsp; He also has been engaging, as you all know, with Democrats and Republicans and consulting closely to &#8212; as a part of the “advice and consent,” &#8220;consent&#8221; part of his &#8212; the role of picking a nominee to move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>After last week’s meeting with Chairman Durbin and Ranking Member Grassley, the President and Vice President and their senior teams, including White House Counsel Dana Remus, have also spoken to the range of additional members of Congress and outside legal experts, and that engagement will continue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There, is of course, a vetting process that takes place.&nbsp; We have not outlined that in detail from here.&nbsp; And, of course, we will venture to be as transparent as possible, even as we are working to protect the process as the President is making his decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; With the meeting today between the President and the German Chancellor, does the President view Germany as a reliable partner on this issue?&nbsp; When it comes to troop movements or sending weapons to Ukraine or talking publicly about sanctions, they&#8217;ve been much less aggressive than other NATO Allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;d also note that Germany is the second-largest donor to Ukraine and Europe.&nbsp; The President has also noted, as we have noted, that different countries make different contributions.&nbsp; I think that the Chancellor also did an interview with the Washington Post this morning where he spoke to that in more detail.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have a close, abiding, important relationship with the Germans.&nbsp; That includes having forces stationed in Germany, which has a huge strategic value to the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So today is an opportunity for the President to build on the relationship with the Chancellor, to continue to build on the long and abiding relationship with the Germans.&nbsp; And we are united in our view of the actions &#8212; the potential actions of Russian leaders and united in our efforts to hold them accountable.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s your understanding about where the Chancellor stands right now when it comes to including Nord Stream 2 in potential sanctions if Russia invades.&nbsp; They’ve really danced around that issue and haven&#8217;t given a clear answer about whether they would, in fact, be willing to put that pipeline on hold.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know you all will have the opportunity to, I&#8217;m sure, ask him this question himself.&nbsp; And I, of course, don&#8217;t speak for him.&nbsp; But what I can reiterate here is that we said we’d work with Germany to ensure that Nord Stream 2 does not move forward should Russia invade, and that remains the position &#8212; agreed position.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Emmanuel Macron is meeting with President Putin today, and Chancellor Scholz will be meeting with him in the coming weeks.&nbsp; So, has President Biden asked either of them to deliver a message to Putin when they meet with him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to remember that there are a range of different diplomatic talks happening at the same time through different formats.&nbsp; Some are leader to leader; some are through NATO; some are through the OSCE.&nbsp; And this is reflective of that &#8212; these conversations that are happening.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, the President spoke with President Macron yesterday.&nbsp; And, of course, that close discussion and coordination with a range of leaders is part of how we&#8217;re approaching this.<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is multilayered diplomacy at work here.&nbsp; So &#8212; and we are also directly in touch with the Russians ourselves.&nbsp; So, I wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t look at it through that prism.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You guys are &#8212; said in a background call that part of the discussion with Germany today was about continuing to prepare this robust sanctions package, but we&#8217;ve been talking about sanctions for months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So if Germany is as aligned with its Allies as they &#8212; you all are conveying, why isn&#8217;t this sanctions package already complete?&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t that done already, in terms of figuring out what it looks like?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our internal sanctions package?&nbsp; Or what sanctions package?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because you&#8217;ve said consistently that the sanctions that you&#8217;re preparing are in close consultation with Allies, including Germany.&nbsp; And that conversation is, you know, obviously happening again today, as we&#8217;re getting warnings that Russia could at any moment take significant action.<br>&nbsp;<br>So the discussion about sanctions has been over the course of several months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t it done yet if Germany is as on board with the rest of the NATO Alliance as they&#8217;re projecting to be?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, Jacqui, I mean, as we&#8217;ve said before: One, I think there is alignment that we will work with Germany to ensure that Nord Stream 2 does not move forward, which is obviously a key &#8212; a key point of discussion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note, just &#8212; and reiterate that it&#8217;s not operational at this time, and there&#8217;s no oil flowing through the pipeline.&nbsp; That has been a key point of discussion, and that is agreed to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also reiterate what we&#8217;ve said in here in the past is that: While we have our own sanctions package prepared, which we&#8217;ve been consulting with and briefing members of Congress on, and others do &#8212; and we&#8217;re united in the effort to put forward an economic sanctions package that has significant consequences, as are our European partners &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s identical.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One point to clarify: You said that that is agreed to on Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; I just want to clarify: The Germans have &#8212; are you saying that the Germans have committed not to bring Nord Stream 2 online if Russia invades?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I&#8217;m not going to get into the private diplomatic conversations, but it &#8212; we have said a number of times that if they invade, it will not move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, I wanted to ask about Dr. Lander again.&nbsp; I know you got a question on this earlier, but does the fact that Dr. Lander has a job, still, cheapen the President&#8217;s promise to fire anyone who treats colleagues with disrespect on the spot?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I would just reiterate that the President takes his commitment to having a respectful work environment incredibly seriously.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something that he conveys clearly to all of us on a regular basis.&nbsp; That is why we put in place &#8212; in part put in place a safe and respectful workplace policy, which is how &#8212; which is the process through which this thorough investigation proceeded through and the process through which, again, that there was an internal investigation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Dr. Lander &#8212; obviously, his behavior was inappropriate, and corrective actions needed to be taken, and that was clearly conveyed through this process.&nbsp; And he will be held to account for delivering on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, real quick &#8212; one third topic.&nbsp; We got announcements that in Delaware and New Jersey, the governors are going to be ending mask mandates coming up pretty soon.&nbsp; What is the White House view on these kinds of announcements, given that in Virginia, Governor Youngkin faced a lot of pushback from Democrats for making similar changes to the mask policy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, but they weren&#8217;t actually that similar because what happened here in New Jersey and a couple of other states you mentioned is that they pulled back the requirement.&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t make it more difficult for schools, school administrators, and local officials to keep requirements that they made a determination would keep their schools safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect that President Macron and President Biden will have a follow-up conversation so that he can relay any, sort of, impressions that he got from his face-to-face meeting?&nbsp; And would you commit to letting us know if that conversation happens?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly would.&nbsp; On the latter, I would say that, as you know, the President spoke with President Macron just yesterday.&nbsp; Again, there’s multilayers of diplomacy happening at many times.&nbsp; Sometimes those readouts happen at the Secretary of State level or National Security Advisor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I can assure you we are in close contact with the French; of course, the Germans; and all of our NATO partners and Allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the Pentagon, John Kirby has talked about the possibility of additional U.S. forces being moved to Europe.&nbsp; Has the President requested any additional recommendations from Secretary Austin?&nbsp; And is he reviewing any other plans along those lines?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just say that we are in constant contact, of course, with the Defense Department but also with our NATO partners about what their needs are.&nbsp; So, I don’t have anything to predict for you other than to reiterate what was said last week, which is that we leave the door open to that possibility.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that’s an active possibility at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It always has been.&nbsp; And I would remind everyone that there are thousands of troops that are on the &#8212; in Eastern European countries as a part of our NATO Alliance, so this is to bolster up the troops that are already there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back on the mask mandate question in New Jersey and other states: The CDC is still recommending universal masking in schools, so &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s correct.&nbsp; And that still remains our recommendation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So are you pleased with and fine with the New Jersey governor&#8217;s decision?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, our advice to every school district is to abide by public health guidelines.&nbsp; It continues to be, at this point, that the CDC is advising that masks can delay, reduce transmission.&nbsp; There are also a number of other mitigation measures that we&#8217;ve put in place, but that continues to be CDC guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s always been up to local school districts to determine how they implement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does it say, then, that a governor like Phil Murphy, who’s been so closely aligned with the policies of this administration, would get ahead of the medical experts and say, “Never mind what they say; school districts, you decide”?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s always been up to school districts.&nbsp; That&#8217;s always been our point of view and always been our policy from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our policy from the federal government is to continue to advise everybody to abide by public health guidelines.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think it signals that perhaps the public believes it&#8217;s time for a change in the federal guidelines &#8212; the CDC’s guidance?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we certainly understand and have seen in polling that the public is tired of COVID.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp; So are we.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there has been some good signs recently where there has been a decrease in hospitalizations around the country.&nbsp; And again, we&#8217;re in constant touch about &#8212; about what it looks like moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>But our responsibility, as the federal government, is to rely on the data and the science that is being analyzed by our public health experts.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to rely on that for what recommendations we&#8217;re making.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; A couple things.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve reported that U.S. officials are losing patience with the Chinese in these negotiations about them fulfilling their purchase commitments under the phase one trade deal signed by Donald Trump.&nbsp; What is the perspective from the White House in terms of what can you do? &nbsp;And does the President intend to weigh in on this issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s a good question, Andrea.&nbsp; I mean, we &#8212; as you know, they did not abide by their purchase agreements.&nbsp; We know that factually; we&#8217;ve seen that.&nbsp; This is really under the purview of the USTR and our Trade Representative, Katherine Tai.&nbsp; We remain in close touch with her about that, but I&#8217;d really point you to them for any updates on the process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, this situation on the Canadian bor- &#8212; or in Ottawa, the truckers protest: There does seem to be evidence that these truckers are getting support from conservative forces or right-wing forces in the U.S.&nbsp; Are you investigating that at all?&nbsp; Is there any, kind of, you know, involvement of U.S. authorities in looking at those money flows going to these truckers?&nbsp; And are you concerned about it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say a couple of things. &nbsp;This doesn&#8217;t answer your question, but I just want to get this out there too on this particular topic, and then I&#8217;ll come around &#8212; I promise.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have been engaged since the outset &#8212; well, some of it hopefully answers your question, I should say &#8212; of the protests.&nbsp; There have been zero impacts to CBP operations, which is a question people have understandably been asking us.&nbsp; Some &#8212; some shipments were rerouted by our law enforcement partners to other points of entry due to road closures.&nbsp; Some shippers have had to reroute.&nbsp; But CBP has been in communication throughout to ensure shipments can be cleared and onto the normal routes.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of an assessment of any other engagement from here, we have &#8212; we don&#8217;t really have any update on that or any investigation to read out at this point in time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, you know, the Federal &#8212; the Federal Reserve nominees have run into a little bit of criticism from Republicans, in particular Sarah Raskin.&nbsp; Are you concerned that you&#8217;re &#8212; I mean, especially given the absence of Senator Luján, are you concerned that you might not get all those nominees through and that you may have to withdraw Sarah Raskin?&nbsp; There’s just been another dust &#8212; dustup overnight?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She is one of the most, if not the most, qualified person to ever be nominated to this position.&nbsp; She just gave extensive answers at a hearing last week, and she would be someone the President would be proud to have in that role, as independent as it may be.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, no, that is not an assessment or a prediction we&#8217;re making.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, two questions for you.&nbsp; One, the Secretary-General of NATO has recently talked about the possibility of a more permanent military presence in Europe in response to Russia.&nbsp; Where does the Biden administration stand on that issue?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had a permanent military presence in Europe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You mean in addition?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, a longer &#8212; a longer-term, more permanent presence in Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve always had one.&nbsp; But you mean a plussed-up one?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the language that was used was “longer term.”<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, but we&#8217;ve always had one, so it&#8217;s been very long term to date.&nbsp; But I would say: If &#8212; if he is asking &#8212; and I have not seen his comments about increased, plussed-up presence in some of the places from U.S. troops that we&#8217;ve had &#8212; I would really point to the Department of Defense.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we would &#8212; we would be in touch with our NATO Allies and partners about that.&nbsp; But that is really related to the aggression at the border that we&#8217;re seeing in Ukraine, but there&#8217;s been tens of thousands of troops in Europe for some time now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the topic of masking in schools, if you could just clarify &#8212; I know you’ve talked about this a little bit already: Do you think that at some point in the future, even if that point isn&#8217;t now, it would be appropriate for there to be updated federal guidelines just to avoid confusion?&nbsp; I think the administration has been clear that on other issues, there are sort of messaging issues that could have been a little bit more clear coming from the administration.&nbsp; So on this issue, do you think that that might be appropriate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the guidance is very clear, which is that we recommend masking in schools.&nbsp; That is the recommendation from the CDC.&nbsp; It is also true that at some point, when the science and the data warrants, of course our hope is that that&#8217;s no longer the recommendation.&nbsp; And they are continually assessing that.&nbsp; But the guidance is very clear.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is also true that it has always been up to local school districts to make determinations about how to implement these policies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just to follow on that, you had said that you guys are in “constant contact” with the CDC about what it looks like to move forward.&nbsp; Can we expect the President to provide some sort of roadmap for how states can transition out of a state of emergency &#8212; kind of akin to what he did with the winter strategy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re in constant discussion internally about the moment we&#8217;re in, as it relates to COVID.&nbsp; And, of course, as the President said, I think during his press conference just two weeks ago &#8212; a week and a half ago &#8212; you know, we certainly don&#8217;t see this moment now as the new normal, right?&nbsp; And we &#8212; but we want to get to a point where we are not &#8212; where COVID is not disrupting our daily lives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m sure you will hear more from the President about that, but that&#8217;s &#8212; we&#8217;re constantly discussing that internally.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask one more just for our colleague?&nbsp; The Education Department announced Friday it was going to withdraw its appeal for a $100,000 student loan forgiveness court decision.&nbsp; I’m wondering if you could shed any light on why the Biden administration reversed its decision to appeal the case and if there&#8217;s any plans to fight other bankruptcy cases.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point you to the Department of Education and the Department of Justice, potentially. &nbsp;But I will check and see if there&#8217;s anything more we can offer on that from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I got one more on masks.&nbsp; I just &#8212; I was wondering if I could just ask it this way &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the President’s wife is an educator.&nbsp; He just heard from governors across the country last week, many of whom were saying, “This is enough.&nbsp; It’s time for a new normal.”&nbsp; Where is he on this after taking all of these inputs?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President is not a private citizen; he is President of the United States, right?&nbsp; So his &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you’re his spokesperson, so I’m asking you &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, but I guess I&#8217;m saying it&#8217;s different than asking kind of a person on the street.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; I mean, I&#8217;m just &#8212; you know, it is different because he is the President; he needs to project the &#8212; what the data and the science is telling us.&nbsp; And the data and science &#8212; where we get that guidance from is the CDC and our health and medical experts.&nbsp; Their guidance remains &#8212; continues to be that, in schools, people should mask up.&nbsp; So that is what we are continuing to convey and recommend.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, can you tell us any more about where he will be going on Thursday?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not quite yet, but hopefully &#8212; maybe by the end of the day.&nbsp; We hope to have some more details very soon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Going back to Dr. Lander, &#8220;the investigation found credible evidence of multiple women having complained to other staff about negative interactions with him,&#8221; with a pattern of abusive and disrespectful behavior.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, the President, at the outset of this administration said, “I will fire you on the spot.&nbsp; On the spot.&nbsp; No ifs, ands, or buts.”&nbsp; So why is he not being fired?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Matt, let me first say that no one is suggesting that this behavior is acceptable &#8212; quite the opposite.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that since he&#8217;s &#8212; he made the comment he did &#8212; which I think was one of the first few days in office, if I remember correctly &#8212; we put in place this &#8220;Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy&#8221; to ensure there was a mechanism &#8212; right?&nbsp; &#8212; to conduct investigations, as was conducted in this case, that can be thorough, that result in some actions and some steps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s exactly what happened here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, this is not acceptable behavior.&nbsp; Dr. Lander is expected to comply.&nbsp; And he will be monitored for compliance, because having a safe workplace environment is imperative to the President, the Vice President, the First Lady, the Second Gentleman &#8212; all of us who work here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But are there ways in which he&#8217;s being held to account if he&#8217;s not being fired?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, as I outlined a little bit earlier, but let me reiterate a little bit: In addition to a full and thorough investigation, he was &#8212; it was conveyed through meetings with senior White House officials directly that his behavior was inappropriate, corrective action was needed, and we will monitor for compliance to that &#8212; to those actions that were required.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, I think you may have also seen, or it was reported, that he also sent a note to his staff conveying his commitment to abiding by that.&nbsp; And we certainly hope that that is the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it doesn&#8217;t sound like a zero-tolerance policy if that&#8217;s the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our objective and the President&#8217;s objective is to prevent this behavior from ever happening again.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the Supreme Court.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just &#8212; I wanted to ask about the President&#8217;s efforts to engage with Republicans &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and whether that&#8217;s the best use of his time, considering what he has said about the public not wanting him to be the “President Senator.”<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is true.&nbsp; And I think he has &#8212; he has not been the “President Senator” over the course of the last period of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s also true that he takes his role as President and going through the process of selecting and nominating an eminently qualified nominee very seriously.&nbsp; And in his experience as the former Chairman of the Judiciary Community [sic] &#8212; Committee, that includes consultation with key members of the Senate, and that is an important part of the process in this case.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think what he was referring to in those comments was hours and hours and hours of endless closed-door meetings as it related to negotiating through the course of the fall.&nbsp; But this is a opening to a lifetime appointment &#8212; an opening on the Supreme Court, which is a lifetime appointment &#8212; something the President takes very seriously.&nbsp; And consulting with Republicans and Democrats is an important part of that process, in his view.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Nord Stream 2, you have &#8212; you’ve made clear the administration&#8217;s position.&nbsp; I did want to understand, though: Is the administration ready to take some type of action without Germany to stop Nord Stream 2?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand your question.&nbsp; I just am not in a position to detail further, other than to convey that it will not move forward if Russia invades.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Dr. Lander, if I may.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about what some of the specific corrective changes that were ordered &#8212; what some of those were?&nbsp; And also, has the President spoken with Dr. Lander since the investigation was completed?&nbsp; And does he worry about this overshadowing Moonshot?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the President&#8217;s hope &#8212; all of our hope &#8212; is certainly that Dr. Lander will abide by &#8212; making changes, that he will be held to account to &#8212; to comply fully with the steps that needed to be taken.<br>&nbsp;<br>I can see if there&#8217;s more specific details.&nbsp; I certainly understand why you&#8217;re asking.&nbsp; But overall, it&#8217;s ensuring that he is creating a work environment that people feel safe, they feel supported, and that is respectful.&nbsp; And that is the overarching policy that needs to be implemented moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>You saw him send a note to staff last week, and now it is whether he is implementing those policies moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have they spoken?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any conversations between them to read out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just following up on a question asked earlier about the &#8212; what you said isn&#8217;t a split between Ukraine&#8217;s messaging and your guys&#8217; messaging &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the risk of an invasion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Can you walk us through the communication strategy &#8212; like what you&#8217;re trying to highlight, given the risk of invasion, and why you&#8217;re trying to highlight it more strongly than Ukraine?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Do you see it as &#8212; you know, sounding the alarm more vocally, is there an advantage that you see in sort of preventing Putin from taking any further steps here?&nbsp; Have we &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; And I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t speak for the communication strategy of the Ukrainians; only they can speak to that.&nbsp; But I can tell you that what we have been trying to do &#8212; we obviously have a range of information &#8212; a broad range of information that we have been able to gather here and also through partnership with our allies across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our objective, as we talked about a little bit on Friday, is to deny Russia the opportunity to use some of the tactics, sometimes some of the lies that they have done in the past to justify an invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s straight out of their playbook.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have seen tactics they have used in the past, where a few years ago, Russia&#8217;s Defense Ministry falsely accused the United States of running a clandestine biological weapons lab in the country of Georgia, enabling them &#8212; their efforts to destabilize the Georgian government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They used to fabricate stories in Syria about how attacks on international aid convoys were undertaken by rebels or terrorists.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve &#8212; so we have undertaken an effort to, in some cases, declassify information; in other cases, describe in as great of detail as we can without putting at risk sources and methods what we&#8217;re seeing, what information we&#8217;re evaluating so that they are &#8212; it is &#8212; it makes it more difficult for them to lay a predicate for invading Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that is why we&#8217;re doing it.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also note that a number of your news organizations of course have reporters near there who are seeing the troop buildup.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So there is justification and validation from even that, but also from our partners around the world as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Senator Manchin expressed confidence over the weekend that reforms of the Electoral Count Act will pass.&nbsp; Would the President be supportive of signing reforms to the Electoral Count Act if it were to pass?&nbsp; Or would he require that there be elements of the bill &#8212; voting rights bill included in order to do so?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would really point you to Senator Klobuchar, who is really one of the point people leading this effort.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we have said many times that the Electoral Count Act, while we support the effort, is not a replacement for voting rights legislation for a range of reasons.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know there&#8217;s a lot of discussions on the Hill about what that may look like or want a final package.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t outline that from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And China used a young Uyghur athlete to carry the Olympic Torch during the Opening Ceremony of the Games in Beijing.&nbsp; What did the administration make of that, given the ongoing genocide against Uyghurs in Xinjiang?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know that our U.N. Ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, spoke to this yesterday.&nbsp; So let me reiterate what I thought were some very powerful comments &#8212; if I&#8217;m remembering &#8212; I know someone spoke to it, but I believe it was her &#8212; that we can&#8217;t allow this to be a distraction from, exactly as you said, the human rights abuses, the genocide that we’re seeing in parts of China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That is why we did not send a diplomatic delegation, even as we’re cheering for our U.S. athletes.&nbsp; Diplomacy is complicated, as we know, but we can&#8217;t allow it to be a distraction from what we know is happening to many people in China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to reiterate, on Inauguration Day, President Biden said he would fire anyone that treated another colleague with disrespect, talked down to someone &#8212; and they would &#8212; he would fire them &#8220;on the spot&#8221; &#8212; “No, ifs, ands, or buts.”&nbsp; So what is the White House’s message to people that work in this building and throughout the federal government that took the President at his word and don’t understand why Dr. Lander has not been fired?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our message &#8212; and thank you for your question &#8212; is that the President has crystal-clear expectations with all of us about how we are to treat our colleagues, treat people who work for us, and that is what he expects for people across the building.<br>&nbsp;<br>It is because of those comments that he made early on, in part, that we put in place a Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy that was the mechanism for which this thorough investigation went forward.&nbsp; And it also &#8212; it is based on that that their investigation &#8212; from that came the meeting that Dr. Lander had with senior White House officials where it was made clear what steps he was required to take and that we will be complying and watching for compliance with those steps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our objective is, of course, to prevent any of this behavior from happening again in the future.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the overarching objective.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But those weren’t comments; those were a promise.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he &#8212; we put in place a policy to ensure there is a mechanism for investigating and a mechanism for preventing this type of behavior from repeating itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he promised to fire people that did this, and he hasn’t fired the individual the White House found violated what he said.&nbsp; (Inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand.&nbsp; And, again, let me just reiterate: Nothing about his behavior is acceptable to anyone here &#8212; at all.&nbsp; Quite the opposite.&nbsp; Let me be clear about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there is now a process in place, that was not in place at the time, to evaluate and determine what the next step &#8212; the steps should be taken in the event that any behavior like this occurs to prevent it from happening in the future.&nbsp; That is exactly what happened in this case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, fellow federal employees shouldn&#8217;t expect that people will be fired if they treat colleagues with disrespect?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I think I&#8217;ve outlined very clearly what the process was.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re just saying it’s legal &#8212; that it’s legal what you’re doing.&nbsp; Correct?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions for you.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp; Two questions &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s more than &#8212; it&#8217;s more than that.&nbsp; I think it’s clear that we are putting in place &#8212; we had put in place a process &#8212; an internal process &#8212; to ensure that there was a thorough investigation, that the &#8212; that it was evaluated, that steps were taken for this individual, Dr. Lander, to meet with senior officials to make clear that there were requirements that would be put in place and he was expected to comply with them to prevent this behavior from ever happening again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, on Senator Manchin, on Build Back Better: He reiterated again his view that that structure is done.&nbsp; And he said he wants regular order for any pieces of that (inaudible); that means potentially weeks &#8212; hearings, all of that.&nbsp; Is the President on board with that idea of hearings, markups?&nbsp; And if not, what&#8217;s his plan for elements of Build Back Better to move forward?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak for Senator Manchin; I know you’re not asking me to, but what there is broad agreement on and support for is taking steps to lower costs for the American people, whether it&#8217;s Medicare or whether it’s the ability to negotiate the price of prescription drugs &#8212; something broadly supported; whether it&#8217;s lowering the cost of childcare, eldercare; making sure that the tax system is more fair.</p>



<p>In terms of the mechanisms and the legislative process, I just don&#8217;t have any more predictions for you in terms of how it will proceed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on jobs, a positive report on Friday, by and large.&nbsp; However, Black unemployment is still twice the rate of white unemployment.&nbsp; What is the White House doing?&nbsp; What does the White House think needs to be done to deal with that, especially for Black men?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, just as a reminder, that there is still &#8212; as much as the President oversaw the largest creation of jobs &#8212; job creation ever in one year in American history, it means there&#8217;s more work to be done, because there are still a lot of work that needs to be done to level the playing field, to ensure that small businesses have the assistance they need, including Black-owned small businesses; that we are doing everything we can to ensure there is opportunity for a range of parts of the economic world.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A few on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Congressman Clyburn says that the President will need bipartisan support for his Supreme Court pick, citing Senator Luján’s stroke and hospitalization.&nbsp; Is it the White House&#8217;s position that Republican votes would be helpful in the Senate, or do you view them as necessary?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve, I think, conveyed from here that we haven&#8217;t set a deadline for when a vote should be.&nbsp; We have said we want it to happen as expeditiously as possible.&nbsp; We have also said, and I&#8217;ll reiterate, that because the President has every intention of nominating an eminently qualified Black woman to serve on the Supreme Court, that this is a person who should warrant bipartisan support.&nbsp; And that is certainly what we hope for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of the timeline, the President has said that he intends to make that announcement by the end of the month.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has that timeline shifted in any way?&nbsp; Might he make this announcement before President’s Day weekend?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; February is February, so I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you in terms of when in February, quite, at this point, it will be.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And one more question, if you don’t mind.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As far as where and when he could meet with the potential nominees &#8212; he&#8217;s going to Camp David this weekend.&nbsp; Is the President going to meet with potential Supreme Court justices at Camp David this weekend?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything for you on the process of how the President will interview nominee &#8212; potential candidates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Does the White House have a reaction to the death of the Navy SEAL candidate who died after completing what&#8217;s known as “Hell Week”?&nbsp; And has the President spoken to his family, or does he have plans to?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; not &#8212; not yet, Karen.&nbsp; I will &#8212; we will check and see where that is at this point.&nbsp; Obviously, there&#8217;ll be an investigation here.&nbsp; I&#8217;d point you to the Department of Defense for any specifics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a starting point here, obviously, our heart goes out to the family members, the community, the friends, and we look &#8212; we will look for more details to come out of an investigation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And would there be any thought given to reexamining that training as part of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I would really point you to the Department of Defense, and the President would certainly look to his Defense Department and leadership to make any recommendations in that regard.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, on the Olympics: Does the White House agree with Speaker Nancy Pelosi that American athletes shouldn&#8217;t speak out against Beijing for their own safety?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know we saw those comments, obviously.&nbsp; I think they were last week, if I remember correctly.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s view is that, first, we support our athletes 100 percent.&nbsp; (Holds up Team USA water bottle).&nbsp; Yay.&nbsp; All athletes have the right to freely express themselves, and that is the case in Beijing at the Olympics; it is the case anywhere.&nbsp; They will make those choices as individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s the responsibility of China to live up to its own obligations to maintain a safe environment for all athletes at these games.&nbsp; The world will be watching.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we leave it up to individuals.&nbsp; We certainly support the right to peaceful protest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the First Lady&#8217;s comments this morning about &#8212; she said &#8212; she conceded that free tuition for community college is dead; it’s out of Build Back Better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m wondering, kind of, what was the thought about having her give that message.&nbsp; Is the White House trying to restart negotiations on Build Back Better?&nbsp; Was there some sort of underlying intent to have the First Lady come out and say that this morning?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it was speaking from her heart about her view that free community college would benefit kids, young people, level the playing field across the country.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something the President agrees with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think you all have seen many, many iterations of the Build Back Better legislation &#8212; or options &#8212; in recent months.&nbsp; It hasn&#8217;t been in there in a while, so I think it was speaking &#8212; she was speaking from her heart about how beneficial she thinks that funding and that support would be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, April.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, two topics.&nbsp; One, recently, a Black man was killed in Minnesota over a no-knock warrant.&nbsp; Has the White House taken note of this?&nbsp; And does this bring a fresh &#8212; a renewed call for this executive order &#8212; this police reform executive order, as well as the standalone pieces that are potentials on police reform on Capitol Hill?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely. &nbsp;And it should.&nbsp; Let me reiterate, because I asked a little bit about this, this morning, as well. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, one, let me first say that we mourn the tragic death of Amir Locke, and our thoughts and prayers are with his family.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is committed to ensuring fair, impartial, and effective policing in keeping our communities safe.&nbsp; These goals go hand-in-hand, in our &#8212; in his view, with what we can achieve by building trust between the police and communities they serve.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, back in September, Attorney General Garland issued a new policy impoving [sic] &#8212; imposing restrictions on the use of no-knock warrants, chokeholds, and carotid restraints by federal agents.&nbsp; Obviously, that&#8217;s for federal agents, so that&#8217;s limited &#8212; not to local. &nbsp;But &#8212; you know, I know you follow this closely but for others.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden &#8212; the reason he has been such a strong supporter &#8212; one of the reasons &#8212; of the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act is that it would further restrict the use of no-knock warrants across the country, incentivizing funding &#8212; by using funding as an incentive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have been engaging with, as you know, civil rights groups, a number of law enforcement groups.&nbsp; All agree on the need to reform the use of no-knock warrants.&nbsp; That is &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of agreement on that to keep both citizens and law enforcement officers safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President is examining the possibility of extending those restrictions to other federal agencies through actions &#8212; executive actions that he would have the power to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think you all saw Susan Rice convey last week that we&#8217;re not there yet.&nbsp; We want to make sure we do any action through the administration the right way and it&#8217;s thorough, but certainly, that&#8217;s part of what&#8217;s being looked at.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And on the second topic: There is a serious shroud of secrecy around the nominees of the Supreme Court, understandably.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve got two questions on this.&nbsp; One, what&#8217;s traditional about the process?&nbsp; And then, what is very unique to the process because of the historical nature?&nbsp; If you can tell us. &nbsp;And I&#8217;m sure you can give us something.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, no, no, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very thoughtful question.&nbsp; I was just trying to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, it is.&nbsp; Yes, it is.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I walked right into that one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, you did.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I walked right into that one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I think is unique in this moment is that the President is someone who has served as the Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, as the Vice President when there were a number of nominees &#8212; historic &#8212; many historic &#8212; a number of historic nominees who were nominated and confirmed by the Senate. &nbsp;And he takes the process and the seriousness &#8212; the need for it to be thorough &#8212; he&#8217;s very focused on it.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I don&#8217;t know that that&#8217;s unique.&nbsp; Obviously, every President, I would hope, takes the process seriously.&nbsp; But he also takes, as is &#8212; there was a question earlier about this &#8212; the component about advice part of it very seriously, in terms of consulting with Republicans and Democrats in the process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, what is unique about this moment?&nbsp; You know, that’s a good &#8212; I want to read your article about this to hear what you have to say.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, you &#8212; we’ve got a lot of articles already.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay. &nbsp;Well, your next article about it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, I think it&#8217;s safe to say that there are some criticisms that have been out there, without any names being confirmed, that are unique to &#8212; to having the possibility, the likelihood, the plan for a woman of color being nominated for this position.&nbsp; And the types of language that are used by some to describe who the President might pick as a nominee are unique to that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you just spoke, a moment ago, about advice on &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; his nominees.&nbsp; We know the internal advice, particularly from the Counsel&#8217;s Office, as well as the Vice President. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But externally &#8212; when is the last time the President talked to Anita Hill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; To Anita Hill?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to check on that for you, April.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is she part of this process?&nbsp; Because we know there are &#8212; we know that he talked, and they had a very real conversation before he, you know, became President-elect.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is she &#8212; I want to know, one: Has he consul- &#8212; when is the last time he consulted with her?&nbsp; And if she is part &#8212; because the names of those who are on the outside are dribbling out &#8212; and is she one of those, and he respects her opinion.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will check with our team who are overseeing the process.&nbsp; And you &#8212; you&#8217;re familiar with who that internal team is.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know we probably have to wrap up soon here.&nbsp; Go ahead, Ed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Two things.&nbsp; On gas prices: So, if President Biden has said, with oil prices, that he released the Strategic Petroleum Reserves and that brought down prices &#8212; actually, on that day, the price of oil actually rose and went down for the Omicron variant as the fears of lockdown.&nbsp; Today, oil prices are $91 &#8212; more than $91 a barrel.&nbsp; Is there any consideration by the administration to reversing any of the policies or regulations or removing some to encourage more drilling in the U.S. for future demand?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me tell you what we are doing.&nbsp; Of course &#8212; we, of course, tapped the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; sometimes they take some time to be digested into the system.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also worked with a number of countries around the world to do something similar.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been engaged with OPEC nation countries about the need for the supply available to meet the demand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve also called out the record profits made by oil companies, which should not be lost as an issue as consumers are looking at the price that they are paying at &#8212; the prices they are paying.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then I would also note that you should check with oil companies on whether they are tapping into all of the land leases they have available at their disposal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what about the &#8212; what about &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about encouraging the investment in drilling in other places in the U.S.?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I think the President&#8217;s view is that we are &#8212; it is a huge advantage to us to be a leader in the clean energy transition.&nbsp; And over the course of years and decades, we&#8217;ve become a clean energy superpower because, ultimately, that&#8217;s such &#8212; not just where the jobs are, it&#8217;s where the strategic advantage will lie in 10, 20, 30 years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note again &#8212; and you can ask the oil companies this &#8212; there is land they&#8217;re not all drilling on.&nbsp; Every lease is not used.&nbsp; I&#8217;d encourage them &#8212; you to ask them that question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the President provided to continue (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, in the middle.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this time for him to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Can we &#8212; just finish.&nbsp; I think we just &#8212; go ahead, in the middle right there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m asking if it is the time for the President to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Simon, let me just &#8212; let me just &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible)?&nbsp; His approval rating continues to sink.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; let me just &#8212; let me just have him ask his question.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the American people (inaudible) sending a different message?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Quickly back to Nord Stream 2.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We know the American position to that; you made that crystal clear.&nbsp; Did the pro- &#8212; did the President know the German position before the talks in the Oval Office began?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I’m sure this will be a part of the discussion.&nbsp; I would bet someone will ask about this when we&#8217;re having a press conference in just a little bit here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I can just reiterate is that it will not move forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, one on Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And quick question on President Macron’s visit in &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Moscow today and the Minsk agreement.&nbsp; What is the White House’s position on the question of autonomy or more autonomy for the different regions in Ukraine?&nbsp; For instance, the Donbass with a majority Russian population, should they have an increased say in the Ukrainian national politics, including the question of which alliance Ukraine wants to be a member of?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, our position on this has not changed.&nbsp; Obviously, the Minsk agreements is part of the discussion, as has been reported, between President Putin and President Macron.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll wait for those discussions to conclude.&nbsp; And we certainly support any means of diplomatic engagement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, thanks, everyone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to give us water bottles?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have enough water in here for everybody.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>2:43 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Chancellor Scholz of the Federal Republic of Germany Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/remarks-by-president-biden-and-chancellor-scholz-of-the-federal-republic-of-germany-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 22:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 1:37 P.M. EST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Welcome, everyone.&#160; I&#8217;m delighted to have the Chancellor here today &#8212; Chancellor Scholz.&#160; We&#8217;ve met before, but this is the first time I&#8217;m able to host you in the White House.&#160; And it’s good to have a chance to get to know you more personally.&#160; And we’re going&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>1:37 P.M. EST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Welcome, everyone.&nbsp; I&#8217;m delighted to have the Chancellor here today &#8212; Chancellor Scholz.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve met before, but this is the first time I&#8217;m able to host you in the White House.&nbsp; And it’s good to have a chance to get to know you more personally.&nbsp; And we’re going to spend some time alone together, I hope.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, to state the obvious, Germany is one of America&#8217;s closest allies.&nbsp; We’re working in lockstep to further deter Russian aggression in Europe and to address the challenges posed by China and to promote stability in the We- &#8212; in the Western Balkans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We then &#8212; we have to take on the pandemic, climate change, and &#8212; among many others issues.&nbsp; So, we have a lot to talk about, Mr. Chancellor &#8212; Chancellor, and &#8212; Olaf.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m looking forward to us working closely together with you and this year during Germany&#8217;s presence at the G7.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking forward to that as well.&nbsp; So, welcome, welcome, welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The floor is yours, sir, if you wish to say anything.</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you for having me here.&nbsp; And, really, I appreciate very much that we have the chance to discuss all the topics you raised.&nbsp; They are very important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are closest allies and working intensely together.&nbsp; And this is necessary for doing the steps that we have to do &#8212; for instance, fighting against Russian aggression against Ukraine.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s an important meeting at a very, very important time. &nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you all.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We’ll get a ch- &#8212; we’ll get a &#8212;</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p> 1:40 P.M. EST </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Situation in and in Relation to&#160;Burma</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-situation-in-and-in-relation-to-burma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 22:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C.&#160;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal&#160;Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C.&nbsp;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date. &nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the situation in and in relation to Burma declared in Executive Order 14014 of February 10, 2021, is to continue in effect beyond February 10, 2022.</p>



<p>The situation in and in relation to Burma, and in particular the February 1, 2021 coup, in which the military overthrew the democratically elected civilian government of Burma and unjustly arrested and detained government leaders, politicians, human rights defenders, journalists, and religious leaders, thereby rejecting the will of the people of Burma as expressed in elections held in November 2020 and undermining the country&#8217;s democratic transition and rule of law, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States. &nbsp;Therefore, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14014 with respect to Burma.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>February 7, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency With Respect to the Situation in and in Relation to&#160;Burma</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/07/continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-situation-in-and-in-relation-to-burma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 21:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 10, 2021, by Executive Order 14014, I declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in and in relation to Burma. The situation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 10, 2021, by Executive Order 14014, I declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in and in relation to Burma.</p>



<p>The situation in and in relation to Burma, and in particular the February 1, 2021 coup, in which the military overthrew the democratically elected civilian government of Burma and unjustly arrested and detained government leaders, politicians, human rights defenders, journalists, and religious leaders, thereby rejecting the will of the people of Burma as expressed in elections held in November 2020 and undermining the country&#8217;s democratic transition and rule of law, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States. &nbsp;For this reason, the national emergency declared on February 10, 2021, must continue in effect beyond February 10, 2022. &nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14014 with respect to the situation in and in relation to Burma.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>February 7, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
