<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 11:48:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on U.S. Government Delegation to Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/12/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-u-s-government-delegation-to-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 11:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 11, a United States interagency delegation with representatives from the Department of Justice, Department of Homeland Security, Department of State, and National Security Council traveled to Haiti in response to the Haitian government’s request for security and investigative assistance following the July 7 assassination of Haitian President Jovenel Moïse. The delegation reviewed the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 11, a United States interagency delegation with representatives from the Department of Justice, Department of Homeland Security, Department of State, and National Security Council traveled to Haiti in response to the Haitian government’s request for security and investigative assistance following the July 7 assassination of Haitian President Jovenel Moïse. The delegation reviewed the security of critical infrastructure with Haitian government officials and met with the Haitian National Police, who are leading the investigation into the assassination. The delegation also met with Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph and Prime Minister-Designate Ariel Henry in a joint meeting, as well as Senate President Joseph Lambert, to encourage open and constructive dialogue to reach a political accord that can enable the country to hold free and fair elections. In all their meetings the delegation committed to supporting the Haitian government as it seeks justice in this case and affirmed the United States’ support for the people of Haiti in this challenging time. The United States stands with Haiti in becoming a safer, more democratic country. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Air Force One Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/09/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base Andrews Prince George’s County, Maryland 3:15 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, does it make sense to attack the servers that are used in Russia to carry out &#8212; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Inaudible.) Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Does it make sense to attack the servers that are used to carry out these ransom attacks in Russia?&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Prince George’s County, Maryland</p>



<p>3:15 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, does it make sense to attack the servers that are used in Russia to carry out &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does it make sense to attack the servers that are used to carry out these ransom attacks in Russia?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; To attack them?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, what happened was there was one company that got &#8212; I mean, they weren&#8217;t specifically attacking servers; they were attacking businesses.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean the U.S. response.&nbsp; Up until now, the U.S. response has been to exercise sanctions &#8212; impose sanctions on Russia for this malign activity.&nbsp; Does it make sense for the U.S. to take it up a notch and attack the actual servers that are used?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, what are the consequences for Putin if he does not step up against cyberattacks?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, we set up a committee &#8212; joint committee.&nbsp; They’re meeting on, I think, the 16th.&nbsp; And I believe we’re going to get some cooperation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what do you expect President Putin (inaudible) &#8212; what do you expect him to do?&nbsp; What are those actions?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s not appropriate for me to say what I expect him to do now.&nbsp; But we’ll see.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>  3:17 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call By Senior Administration Officials On President Biden&#8217;s Call With President Putin of Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/09/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-president-bidens-call-with-president-putin-of-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 3:25 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Today&#8217;s call is going to be on background, attributed to a “senior administration official,” and the contents are going to be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; With that, we&#8217;ll turn it over to our speaker, [senior administration official].&#160; [Senior administration official], over&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>3:25 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s call is going to be on background, attributed to a “senior administration official,” and the contents are going to be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With that, we&#8217;ll turn it over to our speaker, [senior administration official].&nbsp; [Senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for being here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There were two main topics, obviously, in the President&#8217;s call today with President Putin.&nbsp; First, Syria &#8212; which I really want to underscore because I think it deserves some attention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I really &#8212; the leaders commended the work of their respective teams following the U.S.-Russia summit that led to today&#8217;s unanimous renewal of cross-border humanitarian assistance to Syria in the U.N. Security Council.&nbsp; And I genuinely encourage you to reach out to NGOs and other humanitarian organizations about the impact of this.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For months, we&#8217;ve been concerned about the likelihood, if not a near certainty, of a Russian veto of the U.N. Security Council resolution that allows for humanitarian assistance to be provided across the Syrian border from Turkey.&nbsp; And it is our strong sense that only leader-level engagement along the lines that took place at the summit in Geneva would have gotten this extension done and this access secured at a time of severe humanitarian distress and need in Syria.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, we think that&#8217;s quite a consequential action and a genuine impact of the President&#8217;s personal engagement and of the summit.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden also spoke with President Putin, obviously, about the ongoing ransomware attacks by criminals based in Russia that have impacted the United States and other countries around the world.&nbsp; President Biden underscored the need for Russia to take action to disrupt ransomware groups operating on Russian territory, and emphasized that he&#8217;s committed to continued engagements on the broader threat posed by ransomware.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President believes strongly in this leader-level engagement on this issue as well.&nbsp; And we engage in this type of diplomacy not because we agree often or all the time, but precisely because we have these disagreements in so many areas, including this one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden reiterated that the United States will take necessary action to defend its people and its critical infrastructure in the face of this continuing challenge.&nbsp; And the President has also called on governments and agencies to modernize their defenses to meet this threat, building on the President&#8217;s executive order on cybersecurity that was released in May.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to say a few other things about this: The President really meant what he said just after concluding the summit meeting in Geneva, when he said that our assessment of this process and our evaluation of Russia&#8217;s actions would take time and play out over time.&nbsp; The President said six months or more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is more than just a conversation that’s taking place between the two leaders, President Biden and President Putin.&nbsp; This is really about our own resilience, as a nation, in the face of these attacks, and strengthening that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the cybersecurity executive order was largely about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s about addressing the challenges posed by cryptocurrency, which provides fuel for these sorts of transactions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s about ensuring that our allies and our partners are working with us, collaboratively, and upping their own game when it comes to resilience and these broader issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is a broad campaign and won&#8217;t have an immediate on-off effect like a light switch, but we’re going to have to stay on top of this over a period of time and remain focused on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, [senior administration official], I’m happy to take whatever questions there are.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Syria, you mentioned we should call NGO groups, and we have.&nbsp; And they say that this isn&#8217;t good enough, that six-month extension; even if there&#8217;s no requirement for another vote &#8212; in six months, it’s just not long enough to plan for humanitarian groups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Human Rights Watch said that Russia successfully blackmailed the international community.&nbsp; Amnesty said Russia continues to play games with the lives and welfare of millions of people.&nbsp; So how do you paint this as a success if these groups are saying it&#8217;s not?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on cyber, the U.S. has given Russia information on the people it wants arrested.&nbsp; Assuming Russia has not made those arrests, how is it that you can expect Russian action when you&#8217;ve asked for those actions and they haven&#8217;t been taken?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank, Nick.&nbsp; So, first of all, this was a 15 to 0 vote in the Security Council, broadly, strongly believed by the United States and our closest allies that this was a big step forward on the humanitarian front.&nbsp; And the groups that we&#8217;ve been in touch with have a different impression from the ones that you&#8217;ve just quoted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We see the six-month extension with a virtually automatic additional six months.&nbsp; In other words, adding up to a full-year extension of humanitarian access is being far better than what was expected in recent months and consider this to be a significant progress on the humanitarian issues.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to have to stay on top of them, obviously.</p>



<p>On Russia’s follow-up actions: Look, you know, time will tell.&nbsp; The President was quite clear that part of why he wanted to gauge what President Putin was willing to do with regard to these actions that have taken place from Russian territory was so the United States could gauge what we&#8217;re going to be willing to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the President was asked today if he expected us, the United States, to take action, to follow up.&nbsp; He said, “Yes.”&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to telegraph what those actions will be precisely.&nbsp; Some of them will be manifest and visible, some of them may not be.&nbsp; But we expect those to take place, you know, in the days and weeks ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; What did Russia get in exchange for not voting to close the crossing into Syria?</p>



<p>And as far as the timing, did the administration wait until Russia did vote that way before making this, kind of, more punitive call on ransomware?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on your second question: No &#8212; I mean, I think the timing of these two topics was more coincidental than linked.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we linked these issues in any way.</p>



<p>On your first question, I guess I would refer you to the Russian government to explain its rationale and its calculus for this vote.&nbsp; I mean, for our purposes, you know, what we were concerned about was the continued, sustained, and ideally enhanced flow of humanitarian assistance into all parts of Syria, and we think that&#8217;s what this has accomplished.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, this is actually Rachel Scott with ABC.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just in the booth together.&nbsp; Thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President was just asked (inaudible) servers that are used to carry out ransomware hacks.&nbsp; So, my first question is: Has the President already directed officials to do that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just another follow-up question.&nbsp; We just got a readout from the Kremlin.&nbsp; They say that they&#8217;ve received no formal request to assist in dealing with the attacks from U.S. agencies.&nbsp; What is the administration&#8217;s response to that?&nbsp; Is there any indication that they&#8217;re taking (inaudible) this morning?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; Can &#8212; the very first part of your question got garbled.&nbsp; Has the President directed agencies and departments to do what specifically, did you ask?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; (Inaudible) now, given &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; You&#8217;re still &#8212; you&#8217;re still really breaking up, so &#8212; I’m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; maybe, Operator, you can hear this, but I can&#8217;t.</p>



<p>OPERATOR:&nbsp; It&#8217;s breaking up on my end as well.&nbsp; Molly, can you hear us?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me?</p>



<p>OPERTATOR:&nbsp; Your line was breaking up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I can &#8212; I&#8217;ll ask it again.&nbsp; I’m walking out of the booth.&nbsp; Sorry, stick with me (inaudible).</p>



<p>So, the President was just asked on the tarmac if it makes sense to attack the servers that are used to carry out the ransomware hacks.&nbsp; The President said, “Yes.”&nbsp; So, my question is: Has he &#8212; has he planned to direct &#8212; have you already directed any officials to carry out that action?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So &#8212; okay, I guess I&#8217;ll take the two parts of your question.&nbsp; On the first question, that&#8217;s obviously not something that we would speak to publicly, in terms of any specific actions the President has or hasn&#8217;t ordered.&nbsp; So I just won&#8217;t speak to those operational questions in detail.</p>



<p>On your second question about the Kremlin&#8217;s readout, I guess what I can say is that we have relayed multiple specific requests for action on cybercriminals to Russia through official channels and been clear about what Russia&#8217;s responsibility is with regard to taking action, including, again, today, at the level of the two presidents.&nbsp; And I’ll just leave it at that.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hey, everyone.&nbsp; This is [senior administration officials].&nbsp; Just on that &#8212; on that first part of that last question, I would encourage folks to go back and look at the full official transcript of what the President said earlier.&nbsp; I think that there might be a bit of a garble there, but folks should be checking the transcript, please.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;m afraid that we&#8217;re out of time, and we have to get our speaker to his next meeting.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining, and have a good rest of your afternoon.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;3:36 P.M. EDT</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden At Signing of An Executive Order Promoting Competition in the American Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-an-executive-order-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 21:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining&#160;Room&#160; 1:48&#160;P.M. EDT&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; They have a Cabinet meeting.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Please &#8212; please be seated.&#160; Thank you. Well, it is not “good morning,” which my remarks say here, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; good afternoon.&#160; We&#8217;re in the midst of a historic economic recovery.&#160; And because our successful vaccination program strategy has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining&nbsp;Room&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:48&nbsp;P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; They have a Cabinet meeting.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Please &#8212; please be seated.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Well, it is not “good morning,” which my remarks say here, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; good afternoon.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in the midst of a historic economic recovery.&nbsp; And because our successful vaccination program strategy has been working and the immediate relief through the American Rescue Plan has brought back our economy from the worst economic crisis in nearly a century, America is now on track.&nbsp; We&#8217;re now on track for the highest economic growth in 40 years and among the highest growth records on record.</p>



<p>We designed our ecomi- &#8212; our economic strategy to be durable through the ups and downs that come with recovery.&nbsp; And there are ups and downs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why the American Rescue Plan was designed to help people not just all at once, but over the course of a full year so we could continue supporting families, small businesses, state and local budgets to help them weather those ups and downs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now that the economy is back on track, we&#8217;re making progress on the second phase of our strategy: ensuring long-term growth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what my Build Back Better agenda, including my Americans Family Plan and the bipartisan infrastructure agreement we reached last month &#8212; that&#8217;s what they&#8217;re all about: long term.</p>



<p>But to keep our country moving, we have to take another step as well &#8212; and I know you&#8217;re all tired of hearing me during the campaign and since I&#8217;m elected President talk about it &#8212; and that&#8217;s bringing fair competition back to the economy.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why today I&#8217;m going to be signing shortly an executive order promoting competition to lower price &#8212; to lower prices, to increase wages, and to take another critical step toward an economy that works for everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The heart of American capitalism is a simple idea: open and fair competition &#8212; that means that if your companies want to win your business, they have to go out and they have to up their game; better prices and services; new ideas and products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That competition keeps the economy moving and keeps it growing.&nbsp; Fair competition is why capitalism has been the world&#8217;s greatest force for prosperity and growth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the same token, “competitive economy” means companies must do all they do to do &#8212; everything they do to compete for workers: offering higher wages, more flexible hours, better benefits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;ve seen over the past few decades is less competition and more concentration that holds our economy back.&nbsp; We see it in big agriculture, in big tech, in big pharma.&nbsp; The list goes on.</p>



<p>Rather than competing for consumers, they are consuming their competitors.&nbsp; Rather than competing for workers, they&#8217;re finding ways to gain the upper hand on labor.&nbsp; And too often, the government has actually made it harder for new companies to break in and compete.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look at what that means for family budgets.&nbsp; Take prescription drugs: Just a handful of companies control the market for many vital medicines, giving them leverage over everyone else to charge whatever they want.&nbsp; As a result, Americans pay two and a half times more for prescription drugs than in any other leading country.&nbsp; And nearly one in four Americans struggles to afford their medication.</p>



<p>Another example: hearing aids.&nbsp; Right now, if you need a hearing aid, you can&#8217;t just walk into a pharmacy and pick one up over the counter.&nbsp; You have to get it from a doctor or a specialist.&nbsp; Not only does that make getting hearing aids inconvenient, it makes them considerably more expensive, and it makes it harder for new companies to compete, innovate, and sell hearing aids at lower prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a result, a pair &#8212; a pair of hea- &#8212; a pair of hearing aids can cost thousands of dollars.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a big reason why just one in seven Americans with hearing loss actually use a hearing aid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another example: Internet services.&nbsp; There are more than 65 million Americans who live in a place with only one high-speed Internet provider.&nbsp; Research shows, when you have unlimited Internet operation, you pay up to five times more on average than families in places with more choices.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what a lack of competition does: it raises the prices you pay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not just consumers getting hurt.&nbsp; Big ag is putting a squeeze on farmers.&nbsp; Small and family farms, first-time farmers &#8212; like veterans coming home and Black and Latino and Indigenous farmers &#8212; they&#8217;re seeing price hikes for seed, lopsided contracts, shrinking profits, and growing debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lack of competition hurts workers as well.&nbsp; In many communities, there are only a handful of employers left competing for workers.&nbsp; Think of company towns across Appalachia and other parts of the country where one big corporation runs the show.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When corporations have that kind of leverage over workers, it pushes down aver- &#8212; it pushes down advertised wages by up to 17 percent.&nbsp; And as competition decreases, businesses don&#8217;t feel the pressure to innovate or invest in their workforce.&nbsp; That hurts working families and it hurts our economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All told, between rising prices and lowering wages, lack of competition costs the median American household $5,000 a year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, look, I&#8217;m a proud capitalist.&nbsp; I spent most of my career representing the corporate state of Delaware.&nbsp; I know America can’t succeed unless American business succeeds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But let me be very clear: Capitalism without competition isn&#8217;t capitalism; it’s exploitation.&nbsp; Without healthy competition, big players can change and charge whatever they want and treat you however they want.&nbsp; And for too many Americans, that means accepting a bad deal for things that can&#8217;t go &#8212; you can&#8217;t go without.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, we know we&#8217;ve got a problem &#8212; a major problem.&nbsp; But we also have an incredible opportunity.&nbsp; We can bring back more competition to more of the country, helping entrepreneurs and small businesses get in the game, helping workers get a better deal, helping families save money every month.&nbsp; The good news is: We&#8217;ve done it before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the early 1900s, President Teddy Roosevelt saw an economy dominated by giants like Standard Oil and JP Morgan&#8217;s railroads.&nbsp; He took them on, and he won.&nbsp; And he gave the little guy a fighting chance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Decades later, during the Great Depression, his cousin Franklin Roosevelt saw a wave of corporate mergers that wiped out sec- &#8212; scores of small businesses, crushing competition and innovation.&nbsp; So he ramped up antitrust enforcement eightfold in just two years, saving families billions in today&#8217;s dollars and helping to set the course for sustained economic growth after World War Two.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He also called for an economic bill of rights, including, quote, “the right of every businessman, large and small, to trade in an atmosphere of freedom from unfair competition and domination by monopolies.”&nbsp; End of quote.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Between them, the two Roosevelts established an American tradition &#8212; an antitrust tradition.&nbsp; It is how we ensure that our economy isn&#8217;t about people working for capitalism; it&#8217;s about capitalism working for people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, over time, we&#8217;ve lost the fundamental American idea that true capitalism depends on fair and open competition.&nbsp; Forty years ago, we chose the wrong path, in my view, following the misguided philosophy of people like Robert Bork, and pulled back on enforcing laws to promote competition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re now 40 years into the experiment of letting giant corporations accumulate more and more power.&nbsp; And where- &#8212; what have we gotten from it?&nbsp; Less growth, weakened investment, fewer small businesses.&nbsp; Too many Americans who feel left behind.&nbsp; Too many people who are poorer than their parents.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I believe the experiment failed.&nbsp; We have to get back to an economy that grows from the bottom up and the middle out.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The executive order I&#8217;m soon going to be signing commits the federal government to full and aggressive enforcement of our antitrust laws.&nbsp; No more tolerance for abusive actions by monopolies.&nbsp; No more bad mergers that lead to mass layoffs, higher prices, fewer options for workers and consumers alike.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My executive order includes 72 specific actions.&nbsp; I expect the federal agencies &#8212; and they know this &#8212; to help restore competition so that we have lower prices, higher wages, more money, more options, and more convenience for the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, I want to focus on three specific actions:&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, the FDA &#8212; the Food and Drug Administration &#8212; are going to work with states and Tribes to safely import prescription drugs from Canada.&nbsp; That&#8217;s just one of many actions in the executive order that will lower prescription drug prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, the FDA is going to issue rules so that hearing aids can be sold over the counter.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the last administration was supposed to have done but didn&#8217;t do.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to get it done.&nbsp; After these rules go into effect, a pair of hearing aids can cost hundreds of dollars, not thousands.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ll be able to pick them up at your local drugstore.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, we&#8217;re going to improve competition for workers.&nbsp; I’ve talked a lot about non-compete agreements &#8212; contracts that say you can&#8217;t take another job in your field, even if you get a better deal.&nbsp; I made a speech &#8212; I was just reminiscing with my staff &#8212; back in 2018, at the Brookings Institution, where I talked about the non-compete clauses that were just &#8212; I found &#8212; to be absolutely ridiculous, but how prevalent they were throughout industries.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At least one in three businesses require their workers to sign a non-compete agreement.&nbsp; These aren’t just high-paid executives or scientists who hold secret formulas for Coca-Cola so Pepsi can’t get their hands on it.&nbsp; A recent study found one in five workers without a college education is subject to non-compete agreements.&nbsp; They’re construction workers, hotel workers, disproportionately women and women of color.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Think of the 26-year-old employee at a company.&nbsp; She’s a star worker, but she isn&#8217;t being treated right.&nbsp; She&#8217;s underpaid, passed over for promotions.&nbsp; A competitor across the street knows and wants to bring her in at a higher wage, but she can’t do it.&nbsp; Her company threatens legal action over a non-compete clause she had to sign in order to get hired in the first place.&nbsp; She can&#8217;t afford a lawyer for help, so she’s locked in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Imagine if you’re in her shoes.&nbsp; You’d feel powerless, disrespected, bullied, trapped.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not right.&nbsp; Workers should be free to take a better job if someone offers it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If your employer wants to keep you, he or she should have to make it worth your while to stay.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the kind of competition that leads to better wages and greater dignity of work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to go into it now, but I used to talk about, you know, there&#8217;s non-compete clauses of people running the machines that lay down asphalt.&nbsp; If, in fact, you get offered a job and you have a &#8212; you know, you&#8217;re in Arkansas doing it, a lot of &#8212; a specific example is you can’t take a job in west Texas to do it.&nbsp; What in the hell does that have to do with anything?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I’m serious.&nbsp; Or there were clauses in McDonald&#8217;s contracts: You can&#8217;t leave Burger King to go to McDonald&#8217;s.&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; Is there a trade secret about what&#8217;s inside that patty?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, but I’m serious.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You all &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if you do know; I didn&#8217;t know it until five years ago &#8212; the incredible number of non-compete clauses for ordinary people who &#8212; it was done for one reason: to keep wages low.&nbsp; Period.</p>



<p>Look, my executive order calls on the FTC to ban or limit non-compete agreements.&nbsp; Let workers chose who they want to work for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m also calling on the FTC to do away with certain occupational licensing requirements.&nbsp; You realize, if you want to braid hair and you move from one state to another, sometimes you have to do a six-month apprenticeship, even though you’ve been in the business for a long, long time?&nbsp; What the hell &#8212; what’s that all about?</p>



<p>Military families, for example, they’re often on the move between states with each new assignment.&nbsp; So you have a woman in the military, her husband is following her, or vice versa.&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; If you have &#8212; if you’re a plumber, you have to get a different license when you move from Delaware to Missouri.</p>



<p>Look, it can&#8217;t be a significant burden to get a new license in a new home state.&nbsp; That burden can&#8217;t be around anymore.&nbsp; It takes time and it takes money.&nbsp; It takes a toll on a family’s income while you&#8217;re waiting.&nbsp; We should remove that barrier, providing more mobility, more opportunity, higher wages for families on the move.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is something that my wife, Jill, has worked on together with Michelle Obama through the Joining Forces initiative for the military.</p>



<p>We’re going to keep that moving.&nbsp; We’re going to get it done in an executive order.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: Competition works.&nbsp; We know it works.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen it works when it exists.&nbsp; Fair competition is was what made America the wealthiest, most innovative nation in history.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why people come here to invent things and start new businesses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the competition against China and other nations of the 21st century, let&#8217;s show that American democracy and the American people can truly outcompete anyone.&nbsp; Because I know that just given half a chance, the American people will never, ever, ever let their country down.&nbsp; Imagine if we give everyone a full and fair chance.&nbsp; That’s what this is all about.&nbsp; That’s what I’m about to do.</p>



<p>So I’d like to invite the Cabinet members up here.&nbsp; I’d like to &#8212; and the Attorney General is here &#8212; Attorney General Garland.&nbsp; Xavier &#8212; Mr. Secretary, you can come up too.&nbsp; I’ve been watching on television; you’ve been really good.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Gina Raimondo.&nbsp; Also, Pete Buttigieg.&nbsp; And the chair of the <s>FCC</s> [FTC], Lian [sic] &#8212; excuse me, Lina Khan, Acting Chair of the FTC.&nbsp; And Director of the National Economic Council.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Am I leaving anybody out?&nbsp; Anyway, come on up.&nbsp; This may be the first Cabinet meeting we’ve had.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; “Promoting Competition in the American Economy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>First pen.&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;Second pen.&nbsp; Third.&nbsp; Fourth.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Fifth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m wondering how Barack did this with a shorter name.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>(The executive order is signed.)</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how did President Putin respond to your call today, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I made it very clear to him that &#8212; that the United States expects, when a ransomware operation is coming from his soil, even though it’s not &#8212; not sponsored by the state, we expect them to act if we give them enough information to act on who that is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, secondly, that we have set up a means of communications now, on a regular basis, to be able to communicate to one another when each of us thinks something is happening in another country that affects the home country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, it went well.&nbsp; I’m optimistic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said, three weeks ago, there would be consequences.&nbsp; Will there be, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">2:06 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 9, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/09/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-9-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 21:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:50 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Friday.&#160; I have a couple of items for all of you at the top. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; First, we welcome the unanimous adoption today in the U.N. Security Council to extend the mandate for a critical humanitarian aid lifeline to Syria.&#160; This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:50 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Friday.&nbsp; I have a couple of items for all of you at the top.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, we welcome the unanimous adoption today in the U.N. Security Council to extend the mandate for a critical humanitarian aid lifeline to Syria.&nbsp; This agreement, which will directly impact the lives of millions of Syrians, was the result of hard work among the members of the Council and intensive diplomacy following a detailed discussion at the Geneva summit between President Biden and President Putin.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today’s resolution, which renews the cross-border agreement that would have expired on July 10th, will provide further lifesaving humanitarian assistance to the people of northwest Syria and is part of a broader humanitarian initiative led by the United Nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The two leaders, today, on their call &#8212; there was a readout that just went out that should be in your inboxes, you may have seen &#8212; commended the work of their respective teams following the summit and welcomed the unanimous vote in the Council.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was a readout, I should note, that just went out, of a call that President Biden did with President Putin this morning.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll talk more about that.&nbsp; But just to note for all of your inboxes.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also, today, the President will sign an executive order that will direct a historic whole-of-government effort to promote competition in the American economy.&nbsp; This effort has three goals: lower prices for consumers, higher wages for workers, and more innovation and economic growth.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lack of competition drives up prices for consumers.&nbsp; Barriers to competition also drive down wages for workers.&nbsp; When there are only a few employers in town, workers have less opportunity to bargain for a higher wage and to demand dignity and respect.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In total, higher prices and lower wages caused by lack of competition are now estimated to cost the median American household $5,000 per year, so we want to work to address that.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Competition is the engine of our economy.&nbsp; And this is just the beginning.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be back, in the weeks ahead, to update you on the progress we&#8217;re making on this executive order and the concrete benefits we are delivering to the American people.</p>



<p>     I also wanted to provide a quick update for you on our work in Haiti.  The United States remains engaged and in close consultations with our Haitian and international partners to support the Haitian people in the aftermath of the assassination of the president.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In response to the Haitian government’s request for security and investigative assistance, we will be sending senior FBI and DHS officials to Port-au-Prince as soon as possible to assess the situation and how we may be able to assist.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also wanted to note that in January of 2021, we announced a $75.5 million for a wide range of issues, including democratic governance, health, education, agricultural development, and strengthening of pre-election activities.&nbsp; Strengthening Haiti&#8217;s law enforcement capacity is a key U.S. priority &#8212; was before the assassination a few days ago, continues to be.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the U.S. Department of State&#8217;s Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs provides assistance directly to the Haitian National Police.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are also providing $5 million to strengthen the Haitian National Police capacity to work with communities to resist gangs.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also wanted to remind you all that, earlier this year, the Department of Homeland Security re-designated Temporary Protected Status for Haiti for 18 months &#8212; something the Secretary announced in May and something we are working to implement.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, Haiti is one of the countries that is &#8212; will be receiving vaccines from the United States.&nbsp; We will be prepared to deliver those, hopefully as early as next week.&nbsp; Part of that is assessing what the airport &#8212; what can happen with the airport and how we will be able to deliver these.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, one other &#8212; two other updates.&nbsp; One other update and the week ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On global vaccines, today we are sending 3 million doses to Indonesia, 1.5 million doses to Nepal, 500,000 doses to Moldova, and 500,000 doses to Bhutan.&nbsp; With these shipments, in this week alone, we have sent nearly 15 million doses to countries including Guatemala, Uruguay, Paraguay, Bolivia, Afghanistan, and Vietnam.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Indonesia, I also wanted to add that, in addition to the vaccines, we are also sending &#8212; we are also moving forward on plans to increase assistance for Indonesia’s broader COVID-19 response efforts.&nbsp; We recognize the difficult situation Indonesia currently finds itself in with a surge of COVID cases, and our thoughts are with all those in Indonesia who are affected.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Finally, let me get to the week ahead<a>.</a></p>



<p>On Monday, the President will meet with local leaders &#8212; including law enforcement, elected officials, and a community violence intervention advocate &#8212; to discuss his administration’s comprehensive strategy to reduce gun crimes and other violent crimes.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s here at the White House.</p>



<p>     On Tuesday, the President will deliver remarks in Philadelphia &#8212; the birthplace of democracy &#8212; on his administration’s actions to protect the sacred, constitutional right to vote and the need to overcome anti-voter laws.  He will make the moral case to the American people on why the right to vote is fundamental to who we are as a nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Thursday, the President will deliver remarks to mark the day that tens of millions of families will get their first monthly tax relief payments thanks to the American Rescue Plan. The expanded Child Tax Credit provides working families $250 each month for every child 6 to 17 years old, and $300 each month for every child under 6 years old.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also Thursday, the President will welcome German Chancellor Angela Merkel to the White House for an official working visit.&nbsp; Her visit will affirm the deep and enduring bilateral ties between the United States and Germany.&nbsp; This forward-looking visit will address our robust partnership on shared global challenges and identify areas to further strengthen cooperation in the months and years ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Friday, the President will participate in the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Leaders Retreat &#8212; remotely, obviously &#8212; on the response to the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; On Friday afternoon, the President will travel to Camp David, where he will remain over the weekend.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Alex.&nbsp; That was a lot of information, hopefully.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was.&nbsp; And we have new information about a call with President Putin.&nbsp; Can you tell us more about what prompted this?&nbsp; Was it decided in response to these recent randomware &#8212; ransomware attacks?&nbsp; What exactly did President Biden say?&nbsp; He reiterated that the United States will take any necessary action to defend its people.&nbsp; What threats, if any, did he make?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, I wanted to know &#8212; the top of readout suggests that it was partly, sort of, a pleasant call.&nbsp; The leaders commended their joint work.&nbsp; So can you explain why President Biden was at all pleasant in this call when it seems that there are all of these ransomware attacks coming from Russia that may have been government-approved?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, let me say that the President is a believer in face-to-face diplomacy when possible and leader-to-leader diplomacy when that&#8217;s not possible, and this is an example of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And this is the first time &#8212; even though ransomware attacks have been increasing over the past 18 months, if not longer &#8212; that there has been this level of engagement at this level.&nbsp; And certainly, the President knew, even when they met in Geneva, that there would be a need for ongoing discussions and engagements.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would say the reason that they commended the work of their teams is: This is consistent with the President&#8217;s view that diplomacy includes working together where there is opportunity and agreement, and being clear and candid and forthright when there&#8217;s disagreement.&nbsp; And this call is an example of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, because of their agreement and the discussion they had in Geneva, the U.N. Security Council is going to extend access for humanitarian corridors &#8212; providing assistance, humanitarian assistance to people in Syria.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that is pivotal and that is going to save lives.&nbsp; That is something to be commended.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the same time, the President made clear, as I think you could see in the readout, that &#8212; he underscored the need for President Putin to take action to disrupt these ransomware groups.&nbsp; While REvil, we know, operates in Russia and other countries around the world, and we don&#8217;t have additional or new information suggesting the Russian government directed these attacks, we also know and we also believe that they have a responsibility.&nbsp; They have a responsibility to take action.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as you can see in the readout, the President also made clear that the United States will take any necessary action to defend its people and its critical infrastructure.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, this was an example of leader-to-leader diplomacy &#8212; something the President feels is vital as he operates in the world.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick note of clarification on the new CDC guidelines on schools &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; because there seems to be a lot of confusion when these come out.&nbsp; Schools are now supposed to allow teachers and students that are vaccinated not to wear masks, but they&#8217;re not recommended to keep track of that.&nbsp; Is that recommendation enforceable?&nbsp; And if not, why even make the recommendation to begin with?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, going forward, as we&#8217;re seeing an increase in vaccinations &#8212; or increase in Delta &#8212; the Delta variant in some of these under-vaccinated clusters, is there a situation in which the administration would suggest returning to virtual learning at all?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, the CDC laid out ways, several months ago, that all schools can safely return to in-person learning.&nbsp; That applies to schools in areas where there are high levels of vaccination and areas where there are lower levels of vaccination.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And thanks to the American Rescue Plan &#8212; $122 billion in funding &#8212; schools can implement these mitigation measures that they may not have been able to prior.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So this &#8212; this guidance today reiterated that masks should be worn indoors by all unvaccinated individuals; schools should continue to maintain at least three feet of physical distance.&nbsp; Screening, testing, ventilation, hand washing, and respiratory etiquette, staying home when sick, and getting tested, contact tracing with quarantine and isolation, and cleaning and disinfection continue to be important layers of prevention to keep schools safe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, the guidelines that they provided &#8212; the guidance &#8212; is in line with their public health guidance that theyhave provided broadly.&nbsp; So if somebody is vaccinated, they are safe. &nbsp;If they are not vaccinated &#8212; which obviously applies to children who are under a certain age who are not yet eligible &#8212; then there are additional &#8212; there are guidelines that remain in place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How these guidelines will be implemented has always been the purview of local school districts.&nbsp; That has always been the case with vaccines in general, even prior to the coronavirus.&nbsp; So, this is public health guidelines that they are providing.&nbsp; It is up to the school districts to apply and implement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some three weeks or so ago, President Biden, in Geneva, said that Vladimir Putin &#8220;knows there are consequences&#8221; &#8212; &#8220;he knows I will take action.&#8221;&nbsp; Did he raise the volume of a similar message in their call today, or did he amplify it in any way, or did he just repeat it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as the readout makes clear, he reiterated that the United States will take any necessary action to defend its people and its critical infrastructure.&nbsp; And he also reiterated his expectation that President Putin take action, even if it is not directed by the Russian government and if it is because of criminal actors in his own country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m not going to give you a tone-and-tenor readout here.&nbsp; But the President believes that this is &#8212; that &#8212; and he&#8217;s always believed this was going to need to be an ongoing diplomatic engagement with the Russians.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had expert-level talks.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had those talks focused on cyber, focused on ransomware, but he also understands that there&#8217;s going to need to be talks at times at the leader level (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said you don&#8217;t have new information that Russia was involved, specifically, in these attacks.&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are the cyber groups still meeting next week &#8212; the U.S. group and the Russia side meeting next week on cyber?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Yes, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, in this call with President Putin, did Putin provide any assurances to President Biden that he will in fact crack down on cyber criminals that are in his country?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to read out on behalf of the Kremlin.&nbsp; I will let them read out their own &#8212; what the President conveyed &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But did &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; to President Biden.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, sorry.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t mean to cut you off.&nbsp; But did President Putin provide any assurances to President Biden on that call at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, that&#8217;s not an appropriate role for the United States to convey.&nbsp; I can convey and read out to you what role President Biden played and what message he delivered to the Russians.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;ve talked about the visit of Chancellor Merkel coming on Thursday.&nbsp; What &#8212; to what extent will President Biden ask Germany and other countries that are involved to stand with him in a response to Russia on these ransomware attacks?&nbsp; Is that a big part of your agenda?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that it is &#8212; it has long been and it was &#8212; back to the G7 and the meetings on the President&#8217;s first foreign trip, part of his message to other European leaders and partners was: We need to stand together and work together to address the threat of ransomware cyberattacks.&nbsp; It is not just an issue for the United States.&nbsp; It is an issue for a range of countries around the globe.</p>



<p>In terms of what percentage of the meeting, I think we&#8217;ll have more as we get closer to the meeting with &#8212; with Chancellor Merkel.&nbsp; But, certainly, I would expect that the rising threat of cyber and ransomware would be part of the agenda.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on Germany and then another quick one.&nbsp; So, on Germany, you know, this one residual issue that is still to be addressed has to do with Nord Stream.&nbsp; To what extent are you hopeful that you might be able to reach some kind of an agreement or extract some kind of promises from Germany that would stave off the need to have this tariff &#8212; sanctions takes place &#8212; take effect?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it certainly will be a part of the discussion.&nbsp; And the President &#8212; our view continues to be that it&#8217;s a bad deal and one that has global issues involved in it.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to predict for you what the outcome of the meeting will look like.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just real &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; real quick on Haiti.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we have some reporting that there&#8217;s an investigation going on about the role that Haitian Americans may have played in that attack.&nbsp; Can you say a few words about your understanding of that?&nbsp; I understand you&#8217;re sending to the FBI and DHS &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and it may be a bit premature, but any readout now would be helpful.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to update in that regard.&nbsp; Obviously, the investigation is being led by Haitian police forces on the ground.&nbsp; There have been some reports, I think you&#8217;re referencing, but I don&#8217;t have any update beyond that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would that be a serious concern for the White House if you found that there were in fact American citizens involved in this assassination?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of where the investigation is going.&nbsp; It&#8217;s ongoing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s led by the Haitians on the ground.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Kelly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did the President, in his conversation with President Putin, expand on the list that he presented to him in Geneva about the types of critical infrastructure and parts of the U.S. economy that were off limits?&nbsp; Has the increase in ransomware informed his view on that to expand that?&nbsp; And should we interpret this call and the implicit warning in there again as a sign that the U.S. will act and act soon?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that, as you noted, the President did provide a list of critical infrastructure when he met with President Putin just a few weeks ago.&nbsp; He did that because, of course, an attack on critical infrastructure that would take out a swath of the American economy would have a significant national security impact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He did not provide that list to say: If the attack is not on critical infrastructure, we&#8217;re not going to take action.&nbsp; That was not the restriction he gave himself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think, in this call today, he was making clear that, again &#8212; and reiterating again &#8212; that attacks by criminal groups, by actors that may not be directed by the Russian government, you still have a responsibility.</p>



<p>And in terms of actions, he made clear that he&#8217;s going to take steps to defend the American people and our own infrastructure and our interests here in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So while we&#8217;re not going to preview, operationally, what that looks like or what he may decide to do, he did make clear that he reserves that option to take action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you think the President&#8217;s intent in having this call and on this topic within the call was to send that signal that action could be imminent?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think his intent was to make clear and reiterate, again, that attacks by criminal groups, ransomware attacks by criminal groups on entities in the United States is not acceptable and that we reserve the right to take action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Weijia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Did President Biden specifically ask about Kaseya and the RNC hack in this phone call?&nbsp; And did Putin say he was investigating?&nbsp; Did he deny it?&nbsp; What was that conversation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m still not going to read out what President Putin said, and I&#8217;m sure that the Kremlin will do their own readout of what he conveyed.&nbsp; I can tell you broadly that, of course, the ransomware attack that happened over the course of last weekend was a big focus, of course, of the call, which was &#8212; was clear in the readout that we provided.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, I would reiterate, on the RNC attack, that that &#8212; that the information we have to date is that that was on a third-party entity and it&#8217;s something the FBI is working with them on.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have additional information beyond that at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did the President express when he would take this action (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to have more to read out for you on operational details or specifics.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And I have a question on Hunter Biden&#8217;s artwork.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did the White House play any role in crafting the sales agreement with the New York gallery to protect the &#8212; the purchasers &#8212; or the ultimate purchasers&#8217; identity?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can tell you that after careful consideration, a system has been established that allows for Hunter Biden to work in his profession within reasonable safeguards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, he has the right to pursue an artistic career, just like any child of a President has the right to pursue a career.&nbsp; But all interactions regarding the selling of art and the setting of prices will be handled by a professional gallerist, adhering to the highest industry standards.&nbsp; And any offer out of the normal course would be rejected out of hand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the gallerist will not share information about buyers or prospective buyers, including their identities, with Hunter Biden or the administration, which provides quite a level of protection and transparency (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the gallery owner is a private citizen who might not be privy to who might have some interests in purchasing this artwork.&nbsp; Is the White House doing anything to work with the owner to make sure there&#8217;s not impropriety there, when it is ultimately sold?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it would be challenging for an anonymous person who we don&#8217;t know and Hunter Biden doesn&#8217;t know to have influence.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a protection.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On this call this morning with the Russian President, did President Biden discuss at all the Taliban delegation that was in Moscow yesterday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The focus of the call and the conversation, which I can tell you was about an hour long, was really primarily on these two topics.&nbsp; I can see if there was anything in addition that was raised, and I can follow up with you after the briefing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then, on the Afghan translators: Does the President believe he has any executive authority to determine where these Afghan nationals await their visas?&nbsp; I know that the President said, yesterday, you guys are working closely with Congress.&nbsp; I want to know what that looks like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in addition, does he have any influence on where they wait out this time period for their visas &#8212; as he&#8217;s similarly exercised with immigrants at the southern border by ending the &#8220;Remain in Mexico&#8221; policy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s a different program, obviously &#8212; which I know you&#8217;re conveying.&nbsp; And what we are trying to determine is U.S. facilities and bases that are located in different parts of the world where we can house these brave and courageous individuals while their processing continues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re determining.&nbsp; We have not made a final determination of that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to also protect, for security and operational reasons, what that may look like, even when a final determination is made.&nbsp; So I would see it as a different type of a program.&nbsp; And &#8212; but those are the considerations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s already law, so we are &#8212; we are in a position where we can make a decision to &#8212; to relocate individuals from Afghanistan to these third-party countries.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the vaccine: Pfizer requesting approval for a third shot from regulators.&nbsp; CDC, FDA said, at this time, you don&#8217;t need a booster to be considered vaccinated.&nbsp; But what&#8217;s the timeline that you guys are looking at on when that would be recommended, especially as it pertains to meeting vaccination requirements to forego things like masks?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first &#8212; and you referenced this, but just for others &#8212; the CDC and the FDA put out a pretty clear statement last night after the announcement by Pfizer, making clear that Americans who have been fully vaccinated do not need a booster shot at this time.</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that they are constantly engaged in a rigorous process to consider when &#8212; when a booster might be necessary.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s &#8212; I can&#8217;t make a prediction of that; that&#8217;s going to be led by the data and by the science.&nbsp; But at this time, that is not a determination that they have made, and we wanted to make clear that that is not something that the American people need to plan for at this moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to jump around because I haven&#8217;t gotten to a bunch of people in this room in a couple days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, go ahead, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a couple on Afghanistan, just to follow.&nbsp; Yesterday, the President said that he den- &#8212; he actually denied that the intelligence community had assessed that Af- &#8212; that the Afghan governments could collapse.&nbsp; That conflicts with the reporting at the Journal and other news outlets that said that it could collapse within six months.&nbsp; Was he not briefed on that intelligence?&nbsp; Or are you denying that intelligence exists at all?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that we, of course, abide by the intelligence presented by our own intelligence community.&nbsp; But the way the question was answered &#8212; and, in part, presented &#8212; was whether it was inevitable.&nbsp; And the President does not believe that it is inevitable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The intelligence community has never said it was inevitable for the &#8212; for the Taliban to take over the country.&nbsp; And so his objective or his &#8212; what he was trying to convey was that there&#8217;s a responsibility and the responsibility now lies in the hands of the Afghans.</p>



<p>We have provided &#8212; we have trained over 300,000.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve provided $3.9 billion in humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; These are brave fighters who have fought off &#8212; taken on casualties and fought off over the course of the last several years.&nbsp; We want to equip and empower them, and it is now in their hands.&nbsp; But it is not inevitable, nor has any intelligence assessment predicted it was inevitable.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more.&nbsp; Yesterday, he also said that the U.S. doesn&#8217;t bear responsibility for any deaths that might occur after the U.S. withdraws.&nbsp; Can you explain, you know, how the U.S. doesn&#8217;t bear any responsibility for that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what the President was conveying is that we are doing everything we can to equip, train, empower the Afghan National Security Forces, and we&#8217;re going to continue to remain engaged not just through the end of August, but then forward.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s going to be up to them to &#8212; it is ultimately their job and responsibility now to demonstrate their capabilities and their will to defend their country.&nbsp; And that was what he was working &#8212; attempting to convey yesterday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just really briefly on the competition executive order: Was there any discussion about trying to accomplish those goals through legislation?&nbsp; And would that be the President&#8217;s preferred approach over an executive order that could be overturned by his successor?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s certainly value in legislation; it makes it more permanent.&nbsp; So there’s no question about that.&nbsp; But the President is going to continue to use authorities that every President before him has had &#8212; executive actions, executive &#8212; which allow him to take actions to make industries more competitive, to bring relief to consumers and the American people.</p>



<p>So I&#8217;m not going to rule out future legislative discussions with Congress should they want to pursue them.&nbsp; But these are actions he could take that could have a huge, immediate impact on the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, in the middle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just two quick questions, Jen.&nbsp; The first is: I spoke with a number of justice organizations and families that want to know if the President is going to address the over 4,000 inmates &#8212; low-offending inmates &#8212; that are at home, sent home due to the pandemic, then they have to go back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They&#8217;re saying that they want to know: Is he going to make a statement, how is he going to address it, and is he willing to find a way to keep them home, whether that&#8217;s granting clemency or ordering the DOJ to go back and revisit that memo that was done under the Trump administration?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; It is something that President is following closely.&nbsp; A lot of it is under the purview of the Department of Justice.&nbsp; I can see if there&#8217;s any new update for you that I can provide to you after the briefing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secondly, on the campaign trail, the President said, “Especially for those moments when this campaign was at its lowest, the African American community stood up again for me.”&nbsp; Then, “They always have my back and I&#8217;ll have theirs.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that said, I know you said on Tuesday he&#8217;s going to Philly, but there are many activists on the ground who feel like the President has not done all that he can.&nbsp; Are we going to see him going state to state, like he did with infrastructure, and having a very in-your-face approach with many Republicans, like in Arizona, confronting some of these rules or even pressing Democrats when it comes to nuking the filibuster?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that the speech the President is delivering is about our fundamental right to vote in the country and the moral obligation we all have to defend that, stand up for that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about legislative process, and this issue is bigger than that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would say that: To those who are critics, we stand with you in wanting to make voting more accessible around the country.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the President signed a historic executive order into law in his first month in office.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he &#8212; his Department of Justice has already taken action to double the funding and support around the country to fighting voter laws and fighting voter suppression.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he fought &#8212; nominated and fought for the confirmation of Kristen Clarke and Vanita Gupta, two civil rights activists who are now playing prominent roles in the Department of Justice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He has said this will be the cause of his presidency.&nbsp; He&#8217;s delivering a speech in Philadelphia &#8212; the foundation of democracy &#8212; next Tuesday.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a continuation of his efforts.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thank you.&nbsp; Nobody really would expect you to preview what the United States might do as a retaliatory cyberattack on Russia, but does the President understand that &#8212; assuming Russia would not acknowledge such an attack, does he understand that for political consumption &#8212; domestic political consumption, perhaps worldwide political consumption &#8212; that we have to make some kind of show of it; we have to point out that we have to respond and the United States has responded and then the President has fulfilled what he said he would do?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say the President doesn&#8217;t make his global decisions or his decisions as Commander-in-Chief or a leader in the global community based on politics; he makes them on what is in the interests of our national security, in the interests of the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly &#8212; I know you alluded to this &#8212; but I don&#8217;t think anyone expects him or us to preview our punches.&nbsp; He reserves that option, has been clear about that, and we&#8217;re probably not going to preview that in advance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But doesn&#8217;t he want to make a show of it, though?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;ve answered your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Two questions on vaccines, and back to Pfizer saying that the third shot is better.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve mentioned that the FDA and the CDC came out very quickly with a statement saying it&#8217;s not needed at this time, but is anybody in the administration asking Pfizer to coordinate on announcements like this so Americans are not confused to see such a whiplash of headlines?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, they are a private-sector company.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to their &#8212; the origin or the motivation of their announcement; you&#8217;d have to ask them that.&nbsp; But the role we can play from the U.S. government is to provide accurate information and public health information, which is what we ventured to do last night pretty rapidly in response to the announcement.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you were asked about this on Wednesday on Air Force One, but I just want to go back to it because there&#8217;s still pushback about the President&#8217;s comments about going door to door to encourage vaccinations.</p>



<p>The South Carolina governor said today that “Enticing, coercing, intimidating, mandating, or pressuring anyone to take a vaccine is a bad policy that will deteriorate the public trust and confidence in the state&#8217;s efforts.”&nbsp; And Governor McMaster said he&#8217;s going to prohibit the state health agency from using the administration&#8217;s targeted tactics.&nbsp; Can you respond to the governor and explain what it is that is being done and what is not being done in this outreach?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me first say that the failure to provide accurate public health information, including the efficacy of vaccines and the accessibility of them to people across the country, including South Carolina, is literally killing people, so maybe they should consider that.&nbsp; But I would say that what this is and what is &#8212; it is not &#8212; this is not federal employees going door to door.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is grassroots volunteers, this is members of the clergy, these are volunteers who believe that people across the country, especially in low-vaccinated areas, should have accurate information, should have information about where they can get vaccinated, where they can save their own lives and their neighbors’ lives and their family members&#8217; lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s exactly what this is.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something that&#8217;s been going on since April.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something where we&#8217;ve seen an impact in states where there are lower vaccination rates.&nbsp; So, it is something we will continue to &#8212; to work with local groups to do.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a disservice to the country and to the people who may lose their lives, who may lose family members to provide inaccurate disinformation at a moment when we&#8217;re still fighting a pandemic.</p>



<p>Go ahead, George.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Two questions on the President&#8217;s trade agenda.&nbsp; He&#8217;s spoken a lot about “Buy America” and he settled the Airbus thing, but when can we expect activity on the major things like lifting the Trump tariffs or the UK talks?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; This is, of course, under the purview of Ambassador Tai, and somebody who is working every day to work with countries around the world to communicate what our agenda is.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you in terms of additional components of his trade agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will note that as he looks at our global approach, our economic approach, he believes that we need to build the middle class, make sure we are making decisions through the prism of what&#8217;s going to help the middle class here in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any reaction to the IMF calling on him to lift the tariffs?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to review.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update for you on a timeline.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, I have a question on vaccine sharing, and then on Afghanistan.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On vaccine sharing, many humanitarian organizations say that despite $1 billion doses pledged by G7, the lion&#8217;s share of which is coming from the U.S., it&#8217;s still not nearly enough to get the world vaccinated, to stop the spread of variants.&nbsp; My question is: Does the administration have any plans to expand from the 580 million doses already pledged?</p>



<p>And jumping off on your Indonesia announcement, the Jakarta government has just announced that they&#8217;re going to use the 3 million Moderna doses to vaccinate one and a half million healthcare workers who have already been vaccinated &#8212; fully vaccinated with Sinovac.&nbsp; So, would you care to comment about that in regards to U.S. vaccine diplomacy versus Chinese vaccine goals?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that there are no strings attached to our vaccines that we&#8217;re providing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re providing them around the world to save lives and to be a contributor to the global effort to fight the pandemic.</p>



<p>You&#8217;re absolutely right that there are more doses needed beyond the billion.&nbsp; I would note that the United States is far and away the largest contributor in the world to the fight against the pandemic, including specific doses of vaccines.&nbsp; And we have &#8212; the President has made clear that we will continue to build from here, and we&#8217;re working on manufacturing capacity around the world and in the United States, and we will continue to contribute even beyond the billion doses.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Afghanistan, the Taliban has captured a key border crossing with Iran today &#8212; a move that&#8217;s designed to choke the Kabul government economically.&nbsp; So if the Taliban continues to make military gains to push the Kabul government towards collapse, at what point would the President reconsider his strike policy to include airstrikes on the Taliban rather than just ISIS and al Qaeda?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’m not going to predict an outcome that we are certainly working to &#8212; with the Afghan National Security Forces to push against.</p>



<p>I can reiterate, of course, why the President made the decision he made based on a clear-eyed assessment of what the impact could be.</p>



<p>But at this point in time, what our focus is on is ensuring we are bringing our servicemen and women home from Afghanistan on the timeline he outlined yesterday; that we are spreading our counterterrorism capacity out to parts of the world where we see the biggest threats beyond Afghanistan; that we are continuing to work to empower, equip, train, support financially the Afghan National Security Forces.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; We&#8217;re almost halfway through the 90-day period that the White House has set for the U.S. intelligence community to redouble its efforts and analyze information about the origin of COVID-19.&nbsp; Is the President receiving or has the President received any update on that front?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates to provide to all of you, but go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then, second question: Delegates to the National Education Association, they approved a measure last week calling for support of, quote, “implementation of culturally responsive education, critical race theory, and ethnic studies curriculum” in preK-through-12 and higher education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President is obviously a big fan of education.&nbsp; The First Lady is a teacher; she&#8217;s a union teacher.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: What are the President&#8217;s thoughts on anti-racism curriculum in the classroom?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President believes that, in our history, there’s many dark moments.&nbsp; And there is not just slavery and racism in our history; there are systemic racism that is still impacting society today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he believes &#8212; as I believe, as a parent of children &#8212; that kids should learn about our history.&nbsp; So as the spouse of an educator and as somebody who is &#8212; continues to believe that children should learn not just the good, but also the challenging in our history.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of what we&#8217;re talking about here, even as it&#8217;s become politically charged.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just want to follow up on something you said about Pfizer.&nbsp; Before, you said this is a private-sector company.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is a company that&#8217;s gotten billions of dollars from the federal government, and it&#8217;s a key part of probably the most important effort you&#8217;re working on right now.&nbsp; Given that, is it still not appropriate to coordinate on messaging that might confuse people?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, the role we can play is to determine how we communicate from the federal government and how we communicate accurate public health information to the American people.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we ventured to do as quickly as possible last night after the statement came out.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on the EO that the President is about to sign: We’ve seen some of the business groups that, you know, while not often the allies of Democrats, have been, especially around the infrastructure deal &#8212; groups like the Chamber of Commerce &#8212; expressing concern that government is just, kind of, inserting itself too much into business dealings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The National Association of Manufacturers saying they are “solutions in search of a problem” and threaten to “undo progress by undermining free markets [that] are premised on the false notion our workers are not positioned for success.”</p>



<p>And, you know &#8212; and more broadly, are you just concerned about the reaction coming from industry that they will try to push back on this, that there will likely be lawsuits and all &#8212; and all kinds of other things that can bog down this?&nbsp; And how are you planning to respond to all of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there may be, but I think the role and the President&#8217;s role is to &#8212; to focus on what&#8217;s in the interests of American consumers.&nbsp; And his view is that when you have a lack of competition that&#8217;s driving up prices for consumers, driving down wages for workers, a lack of competition that is costing the median American household $5,000 per year, that, as the President of the United States &#8212; somebody who represents middle-class Americans across the country &#8212; he has a responsibility to act.&nbsp; We understand some may be opposed to that, and that&#8217;s okay; it&#8217;s a free country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow up &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, very quickly, Brian.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The follow-up to that is: You said in the statement today that he&#8217;s going to take decisive action against consolidation in a lot of industries.&nbsp; Does that include the media industry?&nbsp; I mean, we suffer consolidation more than any other.&nbsp; So is your administration going to break up the large media conglomerates?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to predict or preview for you on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m from a large media conglomerate.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a question &#8212; a question on Haiti.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Some members of the press exit the briefing room.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nothing crazy is happening.&nbsp; The pool has to gather.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question on Haiti: How will the arrest of two Americans affect the assistance that the FBI and DHS provides to Haitian authorities?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our assistance is to help the people of Haiti and to help them get through what is a very challenging time and has long been even before the assassination of the President.&nbsp; So, the investigation is not going to impact the assistance we&#8217;re providing to the people of Haiti.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as you &#8212; as I announced at the beginning, we are sending &#8212; because supporting law enforcement efforts on the ground and making sure we are providing resources &#8212; in terms of women- and manpower, but also financial resources &#8212; is part of what our objective is as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how many law enforcement agents are we sending?&nbsp; And have there been any requests for any additional aid from the U.S., either from the State Department or another agency?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this &#8212; this action was in response to a specific request.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s what it exactly was.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a specific number.&nbsp; I can check and see if there&#8217;s something more specific we can provide to you.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Eugene.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the Biden administration considering easing travel restrictions to allow vaccinated people into the U.S.?&nbsp; The CDC has already said that you can &#8212; it’s safe to travel &#8212; I’ve done it; a lot of us have done it &#8212; if you’re fully vaccinated.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s an ongoing process, which I know is to the frustration of many, which includes working groups with countries so that we can communicate about and share information about what the criteria will be for easing these travel restrictions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We certainly want to ensure families are reunited, people are reunited, people can travel &#8212; as you have, as you’ve said &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have anything to predict in terms of the timeline there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The question is: If the conditions are the same &#8212; they’re otherwise the same &#8212; why does the destination matter?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They look at a range of criteria, but it&#8217;s based on public health discussions.&nbsp; Public health experts are a part of these discussions on all sides from our country and from the others who are participating.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question: In May, the administration came out in support of the TRIPS Waiver, which would make vaccines more available around the world by waiving the IP protections.&nbsp; Angela Merkel will be here next Thursday.&nbsp; Germany is against the TRIPS Waiver.&nbsp; They &#8212; and I think it has to be unanimous.&nbsp; Is President Biden &#8212; is that on the agenda for President Biden to talk to her about that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He is a strong proponent of it.&nbsp; It’s one tool in our toolbox.&nbsp; There are a number of others, including increasing manufacturing.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;ve already made an announcement about the number of doses &#8212; the 500 million we&#8217;re sharing around the world &#8212; and we&#8217;ve already started implementing them.</p>



<p>I know &#8212; it sounds like there&#8217;s a lot of interest in what will be on the agenda.&nbsp; Let me see if there&#8217;s more about the agenda for the meeting with the German Chancellor to predict.</p>



<p>Let me go all the way to the &#8212; go ahead, in the middle.&nbsp; Go, in the middle.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just two quick questions.&nbsp; First, on voting rights: Is the speech next week in Pennsylvania &#8212; is it like a one-off speech or is the President going to, sort of, consistently start to deliver speeches and have events publicly on this issue?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he just had a meeting with civil rights leaders yesterday.&nbsp; And we provided a readout of that.&nbsp; So, I can’t predict for you what the schedule will look like beyond next Tuesday, but this is an opportunity to go to the birthplace of democracy to make the case for the moral imperative of making voting more accessible to people across the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just quickly on &#8212; it&#8217;s been several months since Neera Tanden was withdrawn as the nominee to lead OMB.&nbsp; Is there an update on the timeline for when the President might nominate a full-time nominee to lead that department?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There &#8212; I do not have a timeline update for you.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thanks, Jen.&nbsp; As you probably have noticed, gas prices are up considerably right now all across the U.S.&nbsp; The average price of gasoline is $3.14.&nbsp; In fact, gas prices are up 40 percent since the very beginning of the year.&nbsp; What is your message to motorists out there in the country that are concerned about how much it costs to get to work every day, how it&#8217;s really impacting their family budgets?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that gas prices do historically rise in the summer, and that&#8217;s particularly true even in moments like this where there&#8217;s a spike in people traveling.&nbsp; And even more people are hitting the road now because of our success in defeating the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in the last 10 years pre-pandemic, for example, the average price of gas in July is nearly 30 cents higher than it is in January.&nbsp; And any prices are higher now than they were last year because Americans are finally able to travel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just thought that context was important as it relates, but the President is quite focused on ensuring that we are doing everything we can to keep prices low for the &#8212; to keep the cost of living low for the American people, including the cost of gas.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he was against &#8212; vehemently against a gas tax; why he was against a vehicle mileage tax.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are not a member &#8212; a party of OPEC, as you know.&nbsp; We are engaged with a number of countries, in part because we want to ensure that we are remaining abreast of what is happening in those discussions as well, because that will have an impact.</p>



<p>But his direct message to the American people is that he is going to work &#8212; just as he worked to get the virus under control, he’s going to &#8212; and to create jobs &#8212; he&#8217;s going to work to ensure we are doing everything we can to keep the gas price low.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will releasing oil from the SPR have any impact?&nbsp; Is that a consideration of the administration?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; As a candidate, President Biden said &#8212; and I&#8217;m quoting &#8212; quote, “I have never spoken to my son about his overseas business dealings.”&nbsp; But recently, photographs and documents have called that into question. &nbsp;</p>



<p>In 2015, President Biden, as Vice President, met at Cafe Milano with his son&#8217;s Ukrainian, Russian, and Kazakhstani business associates one day before a Burisma executive thanked the First Son for the opportunity to meet his father.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, in 2015, as Vice President, the President hosted at the Naval Observatory Mexican business associates of Hunter Biden before Hunter Biden emailed these associates from Air Force Two the next year, going to Mexico.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I have kind of a two-part question.&nbsp; Was President Biden indeed unaware that his son was pursuing business opportunities with these people he met?&nbsp; And also, according to recent reporting, the First Son still has a stake in a Chinese investment company.&nbsp; When is he going to unload that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the last part: He&#8217;s working to unload that.&nbsp; I&#8217;d point you to his representatives.&nbsp; The President does not discuss business dealings with family members.&nbsp; And otherwise, I&#8217;m not going to respond to Rudy Giuliani&#8217;s lawyer.</p>



<p>Go ahead, in the back.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about the executive order that the President is going to sign on competition.&nbsp; Most of that executive order, to me, looks like it would be done through regulation at the agencies &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and in directing a whole bunch of different rulemaking.&nbsp; Can you talk about &#8212; so, the office inside OMB that handles regulations still has no director &#8212; or administrator, I believe, is the title.&nbsp; Can you talk about how the coordination is going to go to get this all out the door and make sure that it&#8217;s &#8212; I mean, cross the T&#8217;s and dot the i&#8217;s without someone in that job that would traditionally do that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that OMB has &#8212; is one of the agencies in the federal government that is also staffed by talented men and women from the Career Service, and they can help make sure we are continuing to function and implement government actions, and that continues to be the case in this regard.</p>



<p>As you noted, the order includes several actions that agencies would take, which &#8212; those actions would be implemented within agencies; even independent agencies, of course, will make their own decisions.&nbsp; So this order is encouraging independent agencies to take certain actions, even as they make those decisions.</p>



<p>But the federal government is designed in a way so that we can function from administration to administration, even as individuals need to be nominated and confirmed.&nbsp; And that is certainly the case in this regard as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, let&#8217;s see.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Nikki.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thanks.&nbsp; So, since Tampa won the Stanley Cup, what is President Biden &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right, that wasn’t on my bingo card today, but that’s fine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A fun little segue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is President Biden receiving from Prime Minister Trudeau?&nbsp; Because I know that there’s a bet out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, when are we going to see the Lightning or other, sort of, bigger events start happening again at the White House?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Soon.&nbsp; We’ve already started to have events.&nbsp; As you all know, we’ve had some over the course of the last few weeks.&nbsp; We’ve already welcomed one sports team here to the White House, and there will be more to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have a prediction of the timeline, but we are starting to schedule and plan those events for the coming months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you know the winnings?&nbsp; Like what is the President getting from the Prime Minister?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I don’t have an update on that specifically, but we can see if there&#8217;s more detail to share.</p>



<p>Why don&#8217;t we go all the way in the back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on the nuclear talks in Vienna?&nbsp; Will we have a seventh round of talks?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sorry, I didn&#8217;t hear the last part.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nuclear talks in Vienna.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nuclear talks.&nbsp; Will we have a seventh round of talks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is certainly the intention, but I don&#8217;t have any update on the timeline of those.</p>



<p>Go ahead, next to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much, Jen.&nbsp; On China: Is the White House planning to hold another phone call with Chinese leader Xi?&nbsp; At the G20 Summit in October, is President Biden willing to hold a summit with Xi, on the sidelines?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know the G20 summit is coming up right around Halloween, but that is quite some time from now in terms of the planning and what other events may or may not be around it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Certainly, we are in touch, at a very high level, with Chinese leaders.&nbsp; In terms of an upcoming call with President Xi, I don&#8217;t have anything to predict on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why don&#8217;t we go all the way &#8212; I&#8217;m just trying to get all the way to the back because I&#8217;m not great at doing that.&nbsp; Go all the way in the &#8212; yeah, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On the competition policy executive order, are there any additional steps that have already been taken, like at the interagency level, so that we&#8217;re going to see a proposed rule from the Department of Transportation on airline fees or something &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; next Tuesday?&nbsp; How much of this is sort of pre-staged versus starting at the beginning of the process?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, where appropriate, with agencies that &#8212; of course, not independent agencies that we&#8217;ve been working closely with &#8212; we have been working with them to develop policies and do that in alignment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The timing of proposed rules, I would point you to each agency.&nbsp; Obviously, as you know, that takes some time depending on the complication of the role.&nbsp; But we developed this through an interagency process, where appropriate, and there is, of course, broad support for the competition agenda in the administration.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I also just also ask: Because there was another &#8212; the Bipartisan Policy Center had a report the other day on the debt limit.&nbsp; Treasury has been unclear on when exactly the &#8220;X date&#8221; will arrive.&nbsp; Is the President going to be pushing Congress to raise the debt limit or suspend it again before they leave for the August recess in the early August?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President certainly expects that Congress will take steps, as they have three times during the prior administration, to raise the debt limit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, I think we have to wrap up because I think you have to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to move to the President&#8217;s remarks.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Have a wonderful weekend.</p>



<p>1:37 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces His Intent to Nominate Four Individuals to Serve as Ambassadors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/president-biden-announces-his-intent-to-nominate-four-individuals-to-serve-as-ambassadors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 19:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following four individuals to serve as U.S. ambassadors: Denise Campbell Bauer, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the French Republic and to the Principality of Monaco Peter D. Haas, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to People’s Republic of Bangladesh Eric M.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following four individuals to serve as U.S. ambassadors:</p>



<ul><li>Denise Campbell Bauer, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the French Republic and to the Principality of Monaco</li><li>Peter D. Haas, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to People’s Republic of Bangladesh</li><li>Eric M. Garcetti, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of India</li><li>Bernadette M. Meehan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Chile</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Denise Campbell Bauer, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the French Republic and to the Principality of Monaco</u></strong></p>



<p>Denise Campbell Bauer is an experienced diplomat, non-profit leader, and advocate for women’s voices in politics and policy.&nbsp;She served as the United States Ambassador to the Kingdom of Belgium from August 2013 until January 2017, where she led one of the largest embassies in Europe and earned a reputation for her collaborative leadership style, high ethics standards, and crisis management skills.&nbsp; In that role, she focused on building transatlantic security partnerships and expanding international trade.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bauer began her career in Los Angeles, where she worked as a journalist for two internationally respected television networks.&nbsp;She went on to serve in leadership roles for a number of non-profits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In 2019, Bauer became the Executive Director of Women for Biden, a nationwide network of women that organized and mobilized to elect President Biden.&nbsp;In 2012, she served in a similar role for the Obama-Biden presidential campaign, while also chairing the Women’s Leadership Forum for the Democratic National Committee.&nbsp;Upon returning from Brussels in 2017, she re-engaged in politics, focusing on supporting women running for office for the first time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bauer received a B.A. in Political Science from Occidental College.&nbsp;She speaks French.</p>



<p><strong><u>Peter D. Haas, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to People’s Republic of Bangladesh</u></strong></p>



<p>Peter D. Haas, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as Acting Assistant Secretary of State and concurrently as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary, for Economic and Business Affairs for the Department of State. Previously, Haas was Senior Advisor/Deputy Assistant Secretary for Trade Policy and Negotiations for the State Department and prior to that was the Deputy Permanent Representative to the U.S. Mission to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development in Paris, France. Over his career he has served in positions across five geographic bureaus of the State Department including as Consul General of the U.S. Consulate General Mumbai, India.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Haas holds a BA in International Studies and German from Illinois Wesleyan University. He attended the London School of Economics as a Marshall Scholar, where he earned MSc (Econ) degrees in both the Politics of the World Economy and Comparative Government. He is the recipient of the James Clement Dunn Award for Excellence and the Cordell Hull Award for Economic Achievement by Senior Officers.&nbsp; His foreign languages are French and German.</p>



<p><strong><u>Eric M. Garcetti, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of India</u></strong></p>



<p>Eric M. Garcetti has been the Mayor of the City of Los Angeles since 2013, following 12 years as a member of the City Council, including six as Council President.&nbsp; As Mayor, Garcetti oversees the busiest container port in the Western Hemisphere, the largest municipal utility in the country, and one of the busiest airports in the world.&nbsp; He led LA’s successful bid to return the summer Olympic Games to American soil for the first time in three decades.&nbsp; He currently chairs LA Metro, the country’s second-busiest transit agency, which is building or extending 15 new transit lines, and shifting to an all-electric fleet.</p>



<p>Garcetti co-founded Climate Mayors and led more than 400 U.S. mayors to adopt the Paris Climate agreement.&nbsp; He is the current Chair of C40 Cities – a network of 97 of the world&#8217;s biggest cities taking bold climate action and has led the organization’s engagement and expansion in India as well as C40’s global response to the COVID pandemic through the sharing of best practices and resources.</p>



<p>During 12 years as an Intelligence Officer in the U.S. Navy Reserve Component, Garcetti served under the Commander, U.S. Pacific Fleet and the Defense Intelligence Agency, retiring in 2017 as a Lieutenant.&nbsp; A Rhodes Scholar, he studied at Queen’s College, Oxford and the London School of Economics and Political Science. Garcetti was selected as an inaugural Asia 21 Fellow of the Asia Society, and taught at Occidental College’s Department of Diplomacy and World Affairs, as well as at the University of Southern California’s School of International Relations.&nbsp; He has lived and conducted field work on nationalism, ethnicity, and human rights in Southeast Asia and Northeast Africa.&nbsp; He is the founding Chair of the Latino Alliance of Mayors at the U.S. Conference of Mayors, serves on the Board of National Association of Latino Elected and Appointed Officials, and speaks fluent Spanish. Garcetti earned a B.A. and M.A. at Columbia University, where he was a John Jay Scholar.</p>



<p><strong><u>Bernadette M. Meehan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Chile</u></strong></p>



<p>Bernadette Meehan currently serves as the Executive Vice President of Global Programs for the Obama Foundation, where she served previously as Chief International Officer and Executive Director of International Programs.&nbsp; Prior to joining the Obama Foundation, Ms. Meehan was a career Foreign Service Officer for over a decade.&nbsp; During her time with the State Department, she was detailed to work in multiple positions at the National Security Council, including as a Senior Advisor, as Special Assistant to the President and National Security Council Spokesperson, and earlier, as Director for Strategic Communications.&nbsp; Among her other assignments, Ms. Meehan served as Special Assistant to Secretary of State Hillary Clinton; Dean and Virginia Rusk Fellow at Georgetown University’s Institute for the Study of Diplomacy; Special Assistant in the State Department’s Executive Secretariat; Public Affairs Officer at the U.S. Consulate General Dubai, United Arab Emirates; both Consular Officer and Special Assistant to the Ambassador at the U.S. Embassy in Baghdad, Iraq; and Consular Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Bogota, Colombia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ms. Meehan earned her B.A. from Boston College.&nbsp; Her civic leadership includes service on the Board of Advisors at Georgetown University’s Institute for the Study of Diplomacy and the Advisory Council of Hostage US.&nbsp; She speaks Spanish and Arabic.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Promoting Competition in the American Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/09/executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 19:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to promote the interests of American workers, businesses, and consumers, it is hereby ordered as follows: Section 1.  Policy.      A fair, open, and competitive marketplace has long been a cornerstone of the American&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to promote the interests of American workers, businesses, and consumers, it is hereby ordered as follows:<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1.  Policy</span>.  <br>    A fair, open, and competitive marketplace has long been a cornerstone of the American economy, while excessive market concentration threatens basic economic liberties, democratic accountability, and the welfare of workers, farmers, small businesses, startups, and consumers.<br>     The American promise of a broad and sustained prosperity depends on an open and competitive economy.  For workers, a competitive marketplace creates more high-quality jobs and the economic freedom to switch jobs or negotiate a higher wage.  For small businesses and farmers, it creates more choices among suppliers and major buyers, leading to more take-home income, which they can reinvest in their enterprises.  For entrepreneurs, it provides space to experiment, innovate, and pursue the new ideas that have for centuries powered the American economy and improved our quality of life.  And for consumers, it means more choices, better service, and lower prices. <br>     Robust competition is critical to preserving America&#8217;s role as the world&#8217;s leading economy.<br>     Yet over the last several decades, as industries have consolidated, competition has weakened in too many markets, denying Americans the benefits of an open economy and widening racial, income, and wealth inequality.  Federal Government inaction has contributed to these problems, with workers, farmers, small businesses, and consumers paying the price.<br>     Consolidation has increased the power of corporate employers, making it harder for workers to bargain for higher wages and better work conditions.  Powerful companies require workers to sign non-compete agreements that restrict their ability to change jobs.  And, while many occupational licenses are critical to increasing wages for workers and especially workers of color, some overly restrictive occupational licensing requirements can impede workers&#8217; ability to find jobs and to move between States.<br>     Consolidation in the agricultural industry is making it too hard for small family farms to survive.  Farmers are squeezed between concentrated market power in the agricultural input industries &#8212; seed, fertilizer, feed, and equipment suppliers &#8212; and concentrated market power in the channels for selling agricultural products.  As a result, farmers&#8217; share of the value of their agricultural products has decreased, and poultry farmers, hog farmers, cattle ranchers, and other agricultural workers struggle to retain autonomy and to make sustainable returns.<br>     The American information technology sector has long been an engine of innovation and growth, but today a small number of dominant Internet platforms use their power to exclude market entrants, to extract monopoly profits, and to gather intimate personal information that they can exploit for their own advantage.  Too many small businesses across the economy depend on those platforms and a few online marketplaces for their survival.  And too many local newspapers have shuttered or downsized, in part due to the Internet platforms&#8217; dominance in advertising markets.<br>     Americans are paying too much for prescription drugs and healthcare services &#8212; far more than the prices paid in other countries.  Hospital consolidation has left many areas, particularly rural communities, with inadequate or more expensive healthcare options.  And too often, patent and other laws have been misused to inhibit or delay &#8212; for years and even decades &#8212; competition from generic drugs and biosimilars, denying Americans access to lower-cost drugs.<br>     In the telecommunications sector, Americans likewise pay too much for broadband, cable television, and other communications services, in part because of a lack of adequate competition.  In the financial-services sector, consumers pay steep and often hidden fees because of industry consolidation.  Similarly, the global container shipping industry has consolidated into a small number of dominant foreign-owned lines and alliances, which can disadvantage American exporters.<br>     The problem of economic consolidation now spans these sectors and many others, endangering our ability to rebuild and emerge from the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic with a vibrant, innovative, and growing economy.  Meanwhile, the United States faces new challenges to its economic standing in the world, including unfair competitive pressures from foreign monopolies and firms that are state-owned or state-sponsored, or whose market power is directly supported by foreign governments.<br>     We must act now to reverse these dangerous trends, which constrain the growth and dynamism of our economy, impair the creation of high-quality jobs, and threaten America&#8217;s economic standing in the world. <br>     This order affirms that it is the policy of my Administration to enforce the antitrust laws to combat the excessive concentration of industry, the abuses of market power, and the harmful effects of monopoly and monopsony &#8212; especially as these issues arise in labor markets, agricultural markets, Internet platform industries, healthcare markets (including insurance, hospital, and prescription drug markets), repair markets, and United States markets directly affected by foreign cartel activity.<br>     It is also the policy of my Administration to enforce the antitrust laws to meet the challenges posed by new industries and technologies, including the rise of the dominant Internet platforms, especially as they stem from serial mergers, the acquisition of nascent competitors, the aggregation of data, unfair competition in attention markets, the surveillance of users, and the presence of network effects.<br>     Whereas decades of industry consolidation have often led to excessive market concentration, this order reaffirms that the United States retains the authority to challenge transactions whose previous consummation was in violation of the Sherman Antitrust Act (26 Stat. 209, 15 U.S.C. 1 <em>et seq.</em>) (Sherman Act), the Clayton Antitrust Act (Public Law 63-212, 38 Stat. 730, 15 U.S.C. 12 <em>et seq.</em>) (Clayton Act), or other laws.  <em>See</em> 15 U.S.C. 18; <em>Standard Oil Co. v. United States</em>, 221 U.S. 1 (1911). <br>     This order reasserts as United States policy that the answer to the rising power of foreign monopolies and cartels is not the tolerance of domestic monopolization, but rather the promotion of competition and innovation by firms small and large, at home and worldwide.<br>     It is also the policy of my Administration to support aggressive legislative reforms that would lower prescription drug prices, including by allowing Medicare to negotiate drug prices, by imposing inflation caps, and through other related reforms.  It is further the policy of my Administration to support the enactment of a public health insurance option.<br>     My Administration further reaffirms the policy stated in Executive Order 13725 of April 15, 2016 (Steps to Increase Competition and Better Inform Consumers and Workers to Support Continued Growth of the American Economy), and the Federal Government&#8217;s commitment to the principles that led to the passage of the Sherman Act, the Clayton Act, the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (Public Law 67-51, 42 Stat. 159, 7 U.S.C. 181 <em>et seq.</em>) (Packers and Stockyards Act), the Celler-Kefauver Antimerger Act (Public Law 81-899, 64 Stat. 1125), the Bank Merger Act (Public Law 86-463, 74 Stat. 129, 12 U.S.C. 1828), and the Telecommunications Act of 1996 (Public Law 104-104, 110 Stat. 56), among others.   <br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 2.  The Statutory Basis of a Whole-of-Government Competition Policy</span>. <br>     (a)  The antitrust laws, including the Sherman Act, the Clayton Act, and the Federal Trade Commission Act (Public Law 63-203, 38 Stat. 717, 15 U.S.C. 41 <em>et seq.</em>), are a first line of defense against the monopolization of the American economy.<br>     (b)  The antitrust laws reflect an underlying policy favoring competition that transcends those particular enactments.  As the Supreme Court has stated, for instance, the Sherman Act &#8220;rests on the premise that the unrestrained interaction of competitive forces will yield the best allocation of our economic resources, the lowest prices, the highest quality and the greatest material progress, while at the same time providing an environment conducive to the preservation of our democratic political and social institutions.&#8221;  <em>Northern Pac. Ry. Co. v. United States</em>, 356 U.S. 1, 4 (1958).<br>     (c)  Consistent with these broader policies, and in addition to the traditional antitrust laws, the Congress has also enacted industry-specific fair competition and anti-monopolization laws that often provide additional protections.  Such enactments include the Packers and Stockyards Act, the Federal Alcohol Administration Act (Public Law 74-401, 49 Stat. 977, 27 U.S.C. 201 <em>et seq.</em>), the Bank Merger Act, the Drug Price Competition and Patent Term Restoration Act of 1984 (Public Law 98-417, 98 Stat. 1585), the Shipping Act of 1984 (Public Law 98-237, 98 Stat. 67, 46 U.S.C. 40101 <em>et seq.</em>) (Shipping Act), the ICC Termination Act of 1995 (Public Law 104-88, 109 Stat. 803), the Telecommunications Act of 1996, the Fairness to Contact Lens Consumers Act (Public Law 108-164, 117 Stat. 2024, 15 U.S.C. 7601 <em>et seq.</em>), and the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (Public Law 111-203, 124 Stat. 1376) (Dodd-Frank Act).<br>     (d)  These statutes independently charge a number of executive departments and agencies (agencies) to protect conditions of fair competition in one or more ways, including by:<br>          (i)    policing unfair, deceptive, and abusive business practices;<br>          (ii)   resisting consolidation and promoting competition within industries through the independent oversight of mergers, acquisitions, and joint ventures;<br>          (iii)  promulgating rules that promote competition, including the market entry of new competitors; and<br>          (iv)   promoting market transparency through compelled disclosure of information.<br>     (e)  The agencies that administer such or similar authorities include the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Transportation, the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Maritime Commission, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and the Surface Transportation Board.<br>     (f)  Agencies can influence the conditions of competition through their exercise of regulatory authority or through the procurement process.  <em>See </em>41 U.S.C. 1705.<br>     (g)  This order recognizes that a whole-of-government approach is necessary to address overconcentration, monopolization, and unfair competition in the American economy.  Such an approach is supported by existing statutory mandates.  Agencies can and should further the polices set forth in section 1 of this order by, among other things, adopting pro‑competitive regulations and approaches to procurement and spending, and by rescinding regulations that create unnecessary barriers to entry that stifle competition.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 3.  Agency Cooperation in Oversight, Investigation, and Remedies</span>. <br>     (a)  The Congress frequently has created overlapping agency jurisdiction in the policing of anticompetitive conduct and the oversight of mergers.  It is the policy of my Administration that, when agencies have overlapping jurisdiction, they should endeavor to cooperate fully in the exercise of their oversight authority, to benefit from the respective expertise of the agencies and to improve Government efficiency.<br>     (b)  Where there is overlapping jurisdiction over particular cases, conduct, transactions, or industries, agencies are encouraged to coordinate their efforts, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, with respect to:<br>          (i)    the investigation of conduct potentially harmful to competition;<br>          (ii)   the oversight of proposed mergers, acquisitions, and joint ventures; and<br>          (iii)  the design, execution, and oversight of remedies.<br>     (c)  The means of cooperation in cases of overlapping jurisdiction should include, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:<br>          (i)    sharing relevant information and industry data;<br>          (ii)   in the case of major transactions, soliciting and giving significant consideration to the views of the Attorney General or the Chair of the FTC, as applicable; and<br>          (iii)  cooperating with any concurrent Department of Justice or FTC oversight activities under the Sherman Act or Clayton Act.<br>     (d)  Nothing in subsections (a) through (c) of this section shall be construed to suggest that the statutory standard applied by an agency, or its independent assessment under that standard, should be displaced or substituted by the judgment of the Attorney General or the Chair of the FTC.  When their views are solicited, the Attorney General and the Chair of the FTC are encouraged to provide a response to the agency in time for the agency to consider it in advance of any statutory deadline for agency action.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 4.  The White House Competition Council</span>.  <br>    (a)  There is established a White House Competition Council (Council) within the Executive Office of the President.<br>     (b)  The Council shall coordinate, promote, and advance Federal Government efforts to address overconcentration, monopolization, and unfair competition in or directly affecting the American economy, including efforts to:<br>          (i)    implement the administrative actions identified in this order;<br>          (ii)   develop procedures and best practices for agency cooperation and coordination on matters of overlapping jurisdiction, as described in section 3 of this order;<br>          (iii)  identify and advance any additional administrative actions necessary to further the policies set forth in section 1 of this order; and<br>          (iv)   identify any potential legislative changes necessary to further the policies set forth in section 1 of this order.<br>     (c)  The Council shall work across agencies to provide a coordinated response to overconcentration, monopolization, and unfair competition in or directly affecting the American economy.  The Council shall also work with each agency to ensure that agency operations are conducted in a manner that promotes fair competition, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law.<br>     (d)  The Council shall not discuss any current or anticipated enforcement actions.<br>     (e)  The Council shall be led by the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy and Director of the National Economic Council, who shall serve as Chair of the Council.<br>     (f)  In addition to the Chair, the Council shall consist of the following members:<br>          (i)     the Secretary of the Treasury;<br>          (ii)    the Secretary of Defense;<br>          (iii)   the Attorney General;<br>          (iv)    the Secretary of Agriculture;<br>          (v)     the Secretary of Commerce;<br>          (vi)    the Secretary of Labor;<br>          (vii)   the Secretary of Health and Human Services;<br>          (viii)  the Secretary of Transportation;<br>          (ix)    the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs; and<br>          (x)     the heads of such other agencies and offices as the Chair may from time to time invite to participate.<br>     (g)  The Chair shall invite the participation of the Chair of the FTC, the Chair of the Federal Communications Commission, the Chair of the Federal Maritime Commission, the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and the Chair of the Surface Transportation Board, to the extent consistent with their respective statutory authorities and obligations.<br>     (h)  Members of the Council shall designate, not later than 30 days after the date of this order, a senior official within their respective agency or office who shall coordinate with the Council and who shall be responsible for overseeing the agency&#8217;s or office&#8217;s efforts to address overconcentration, monopolization, and unfair competition.  The Chair may coordinate subgroups consisting exclusively of Council members or their designees, as appropriate.<br>     (i)  The Council shall meet on a semi-annual basis unless the Chair determines that a meeting is unnecessary.<br>     (j)  Each agency shall bear its own expenses for participating in the Council.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 5.  Further Agency Responsibilities</span>.  <br>     (a)  The heads of all agencies shall consider using their authorities to further the policies set forth in section 1 of this order, with particular attention to:<br>          (i)   the influence of any of their respective regulations, particularly any licensing regulations, on concentration and competition in the industries under their jurisdiction; and<br>          (ii)  the potential for their procurement or other spending to improve the competitiveness of small businesses and businesses with fair labor practices.<br>     (b)  The Attorney General, the Chair of the FTC, and the heads of other agencies with authority to enforce the Clayton Act are encouraged to enforce the antitrust laws fairly and vigorously.<br>     (c)  To address the consolidation of industry in many markets across the economy, as described in section 1 of this order, the Attorney General and the Chair of the FTC are encouraged to review the horizontal and vertical merger guidelines and consider whether to revise those guidelines.<br>     (d)  To avoid the potential for anticompetitive extension of market power beyond the scope of granted patents, and to protect standard-setting processes from abuse, the Attorney General and the Secretary of Commerce are encouraged to consider whether to revise their position on the intersection of the intellectual property and antitrust laws, including by considering whether to revise the Policy Statement on Remedies for Standards-Essential Patents Subject to Voluntary F/RAND Commitments issued jointly by the Department of Justice, the United States Patent and Trademark Office, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology on December 19, 2019.<br>     (e)  To ensure Americans have choices among financial institutions and to guard against excessive market power, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Comptroller of the Currency, is encouraged to review current practices and adopt a plan, not later than 180 days after the date of this order, for the revitalization of merger oversight under the Bank Merger Act and the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (Public Law 84-511, 70 Stat. 133, 12 U.S.C. 1841 <em>et seq.</em>) that is in accordance with the factors enumerated in 12 U.S.C. 1828(c) and 1842(c).<br>     (f)  To better protect workers from wage collusion, the Attorney General and the Chair of the FTC are encouraged to consider whether to revise the Antitrust Guidance for Human Resource Professionals of October 2016.<br>     (g)  To address agreements that may unduly limit workers&#8217; ability to change jobs, the Chair of the FTC is encouraged to consider working with the rest of the Commission to exercise the FTC&#8217;s statutory rulemaking authority under the Federal Trade Commission Act to curtail the unfair use of non-compete clauses and other clauses or agreements that may unfairly limit worker mobility.<br>      (h)  To address persistent and recurrent practices that inhibit competition, the Chair of the FTC, in the Chair&#8217;s discretion, is also encouraged to consider working with the rest of the Commission to exercise the FTC&#8217;s statutory rulemaking authority, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, in areas such as:<br>          (i)    unfair data collection and surveillance practices that may damage competition, consumer autonomy, and consumer privacy;<br>          (ii)   unfair anticompetitive restrictions on third-party repair or self-repair of items, such as the restrictions imposed by powerful manufacturers that prevent farmers from repairing their own equipment;<br>          (iii)  unfair anticompetitive conduct or agreements in the prescription drug industries, such as agreements to delay the market entry of generic drugs or biosimilars;<br>          (iv)   unfair competition in major Internet marketplaces;<br>          (v)   unfair occupational licensing restrictions;<br>          (vi)   unfair tying practices or exclusionary practices in the brokerage or listing of real estate; and<br>          (vii)  any other unfair industry-specific practices that substantially inhibit competition.<br>     (i)  The Secretary of Agriculture shall:<br>           (i)    to address the unfair treatment of farmers and improve conditions of competition in the markets for their products, consider initiating a rulemaking or rulemakings under the Packers and Stockyards Act to strengthen the Department of Agriculture&#8217;s regulations concerning unfair, unjustly discriminatory, or deceptive practices and undue or unreasonable preferences, advantages, prejudices, or disadvantages, with the purpose of furthering the vigorous implementation of the law established by the Congress in 1921 and fortified by amendments.  In such rulemaking or rulemakings, the Secretary of Agriculture shall consider, among other things:<br>               (A)  providing clear rules that identify recurrent practices in the livestock, meat, and poultry industries that are unfair, unjustly discriminatory, or deceptive and therefore violate the Packers and Stockyards Act;<br>               (B)  reinforcing the long-standing Department of Agriculture interpretation that it is unnecessary under the Packers and Stockyards Act to demonstrate industry-wide harm to establish a violation of the Act and that the &#8220;unfair, unjustly discriminatory, or deceptive&#8221; treatment of one farmer, the giving to one farmer of an &#8220;undue or unreasonable preference or advantage,&#8221; or the subjection of one farmer to an &#8220;undue or unreasonable prejudice or disadvantage in any respect&#8221; violates the Act;<br>               (C)  prohibiting unfair practices related to grower ranking systems &#8212; systems in which the poultry companies, contractors, or dealers exercise extraordinary control over numerous inputs that determine the amount farmers are paid and require farmers to assume the risk of factors outside their control, leaving them more economically vulnerable;<br>               (D)  updating the appropriate definitions or set of criteria, or application thereof, for undue or unreasonable preferences, advantages, prejudices, or disadvantages under the Packers and Stockyards Act; and<br>               (E)  adopting, to the greatest extent possible and as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, appropriate anti-retaliation protections, so that farmers may assert their rights without fear of retribution;<br>          (ii)   to ensure consumers have accurate, transparent labels that enable them to choose products made in the United States, consider initiating a rulemaking to define the conditions under which the labeling of meat products can bear voluntary statements indicating that the product is of United States origin, such as &#8220;Product of USA&#8221;;<br>          (iii)  to ensure that farmers have greater opportunities to access markets and receive a fair return for their products, not later than 180 days after the date of this order, submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, with a plan to promote competition in the agricultural industries and to support value-added agriculture and alternative food distribution systems through such means as:<br>               (A)  the creation or expansion of useful information for farmers, such as model contracts, to lower transaction costs and help farmers negotiate fair deals;<br>               (B)  measures to encourage improvements in transparency and standards so that consumers may choose to purchase products that support fair treatment of farmers and agricultural workers and sustainable agricultural practices;<br>               (C)  measures to enhance price discovery, increase transparency, and improve the functioning of the cattle and other livestock markets;<br>               (D)  enhanced tools, including any new legislative authorities needed, to protect whistleblowers, monitor agricultural markets, and enforce relevant laws;<br>                 (E)  any investments or other support that could bolster competition within highly concentrated agricultural markets; and<br>                 (F)  any other means that the Secretary of Agriculture deems appropriate;<br>          (iv)   to improve farmers&#8217; and smaller food processors&#8217; access to retail markets, not later than 300 days after the date of this order, in consultation with the Chair of the FTC, submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, on the effect of retail concentration and retailers&#8217; practices on the conditions of competition in the food industries, including any practices that may violate the Federal Trade Commission Act, the Robinson-Patman Act (Public Law 74-692, 49 Stat. 1526, 15 U.S.C. 13 <em>et seq.</em>), or other relevant laws, and on grants, loans, and other support that may enhance access to retail markets by local and regional food enterprises; and<br>          (v)    to help ensure that the intellectual property system, while incentivizing innovation, does not also unnecessarily reduce competition in seed and other input markets beyond that reasonably contemplated by the Patent Act (<em>see </em>35 U.S.C. 100 <em>et seq.</em> and 7 U.S.C. 2321<em> et seq.</em>), in consultation with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office, submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, enumerating and describing any relevant concerns of the Department of Agriculture and strategies for addressing those concerns across intellectual property, antitrust, and other relevant laws.<br>     (j)  To protect the vibrancy of the American markets for beer, wine, and spirits, and to improve market access for smaller, independent, and new operations, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Chair of the FTC, not later than 120 days after the date of this order, shall submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, assessing the current market structure and conditions of competition, including an assessment of any threats to competition and barriers to new entrants, including:<br>          (i)    any unlawful trade practices in the beer, wine, and spirits markets, such as certain exclusionary, discriminatory, or anticompetitive distribution practices, that hinder smaller and independent businesses or new entrants from distributing their products;<br>          (ii)   patterns of consolidation in production, distribution, or retail beer, wine, and spirits markets; and<br>          (iii)  any unnecessary trade practice regulations of matters such as bottle sizes, permitting, or labeling that may unnecessarily inhibit competition by increasing costs without serving any public health, informational, or tax purpose.<br>     (k)  To follow up on the foregoing assessment, the Secretary of the Treasury, through the Administrator of the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau, shall, not later than 240 days after the date of this order, consider:<br>          (i)    initiating a rulemaking to update the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau&#8217;s trade practice regulations;  <br>          (ii)   rescinding or revising any regulations of the beer, wine, and spirits industries that may unnecessarily inhibit competition; and<br>          (iii)  reducing any barriers that impede market access for smaller and independent brewers, winemakers, and distilleries.<br>     (l)  To promote competition, lower prices, and a vibrant and innovative telecommunications ecosystem, the Chair of the Federal Communications Commission is encouraged to work with the rest of the Commission, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to consider:<br>          (i)    adopting through appropriate rulemaking &#8220;Net Neutrality&#8221; rules similar to those previously adopted under title II of the Communications Act of 1934 (Public Law 73-416, 48 Stat. 1064, 47 U.S.C. 151 <em>et seq.</em>), as amended by the Telecommunications Act of 1996, in &#8220;Protecting and Promoting the Open Internet,&#8221; 80 Fed. Reg. 19738 (Apr. 13, 2015);<br>          (ii)   conducting future spectrum auctions under rules that are designed to help avoid excessive concentration of spectrum license holdings in the United States, so as to prevent spectrum stockpiling, warehousing of spectrum by licensees, or the creation of barriers to entry, and to improve the conditions of competition in industries that depend upon radio spectrum, including mobile communications and radio-based broadband services;<br>          (iii)  providing support for the continued development and adoption of 5G Open Radio Access Network (O-RAN) protocols and software, continuing to attend meetings of voluntary and consensus-based standards development organizations, so as to promote or encourage a fair and representative standard-setting process, and undertaking any other measures that might promote increased openness, innovation, and competition in the markets for 5G equipment;<br>          (iv)   prohibiting unjust or unreasonable early termination fees for end-user communications contracts, enabling consumers to more easily switch providers;<br>          (v)    initiating a rulemaking that requires broadband service providers to display a broadband consumer label, such as that as described in the Public Notice of the Commission issued on April 4, 2016 (DA 16–357), so as to give consumers clear, concise, and accurate information regarding provider prices and fees, performance, and network practices;<br>          (vi)   initiating a rulemaking to require broadband service providers to regularly report broadband price and subscription rates to the Federal Communications Commission for the purpose of disseminating that information to the public in a useful manner, to improve price transparency and market functioning; and<br>          (vii)  initiating a rulemaking to prevent landlords and cable and Internet service providers from inhibiting tenants&#8217; choices among providers.<br>     (m)  The Secretary of Transportation shall:<br>          (i)    to better protect consumers and improve competition, and as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:<br>               (A)  not later than 30 days after the date of this order, appoint or reappoint members of the Advisory Committee for Aviation Consumer Protection to ensure fair representation of consumers, State and local interests, airlines, and airports with respect to the evaluation of aviation consumer protection programs and convene a meeting of the Committee as soon as practicable;<br>               (B)  promote enhanced transparency and consumer safeguards, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, including through potential rulemaking, enforcement actions, or guidance documents, with the aims of:<br>                     (1)  enhancing consumer access to airline flight information so that consumers can more easily find a broader set of available flights, including by new or lesser known airlines; and<br>                     (2)  ensuring that consumers are not exposed or subject to advertising, marketing, pricing, and charging of ancillary fees that may constitute an unfair or deceptive practice or an unfair method of competition;<br>               (C)  not later than 45 days after the date of this order, submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, on the progress of the Department of Transportation&#8217;s investigatory and enforcement activities to address the failure of airlines to provide timely refunds for flights cancelled as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic;<br>               (D)  not later than 45 days after the date of this order, publish for notice and comment a proposed rule requiring airlines to refund baggage fees when a passenger&#8217;s luggage is substantially delayed and other ancillary fees when passengers pay for a service that is not provided;<br>               (E)  not later than 60 days after the date of this order, start development of proposed amendments to the Department of Transportation&#8217;s definitions of &#8220;unfair&#8221; and &#8220;deceptive&#8221; in 49 U.S.C. 41712; and<br>               (F)  not later than 90 days after the date of this order, consider initiating a rulemaking to ensure that consumers have ancillary fee information, including &#8220;baggage fees,&#8221; &#8220;change fees,&#8221; and &#8220;cancellation fees,&#8221; at the time of ticket purchase;<br>          (ii)   to provide consumers with more flight options at better prices and with improved service, and to extend opportunities for competition and market entry as the industry evolves:<br>               (A)  not later than 30 days after the date of this order, convene a working group within the Department of Transportation to evaluate the effectiveness of existing commercial aviation programs, consumer protections, and rules of the Federal Aviation Administration;<br>               (B)  consult with the Attorney General regarding means of enhancing effective coordination between the Department of Justice and the Department of Transportation to ensure competition in air transportation and the ability of new entrants to gain access; and<br>               (C)  consider measures to support airport development and increased capacity and improve airport congestion management, gate access, implementation of airport competition plans pursuant to 49 U.S.C. 47106(f), and &#8220;slot&#8221; administration;<br>          (iii)  given the emergence of new aerospace-based transportation technologies, such as low-altitude unmanned aircraft system deliveries, advanced air mobility, and high-altitude long endurance operations, that have great potential for American travelers and consumers, yet also the danger of early monopolization or new air traffic control problems, ensure that the Department of Transportation takes action with respect to these technologies to:<br>               (A)  facilitate innovation that fosters United States market leadership and market entry to promote competition and economic opportunity and to resist monopolization, while also ensuring safety, providing security and privacy, protecting the environment, and promoting equity; and<br>               (B)  provide vigilant oversight over market participants.<br>     (n)  To further competition in the rail industry and to provide accessible remedies for shippers, the Chair of the Surface Transportation Board (Chair) is encouraged to work with the rest of the Board to:<br>          (i)    consider commencing or continuing a rulemaking to strengthen regulations pertaining to reciprocal switching agreements pursuant to 49 U.S.C. 11102(c), if the Chair determines such rulemaking to be in the public interest or necessary to provide competitive rail service;<br>          (ii)   consider rulemakings pertaining to any other relevant matter of competitive access, including bottleneck rates, interchange commitments, or other matters, consistent with the policies set forth in section 1 of this order;<br>          (iii)  to ensure that passenger rail service is not subject to unwarranted delays and interruptions in service due to host railroads&#8217; failure to comply with the required preference for passenger rail, vigorously enforce new on-time performance requirements adopted pursuant to the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 (Public Law 110-423, 122 Stat. 4907) that will take effect on July 1, 2021, and further the work of the passenger rail working group formed to ensure that the Surface Transportation Board will fully meet its obligations; and<br>          (iv)   in the process of determining whether a merger, acquisition, or other transaction involving rail carriers is consistent with the public interest under 49 U.S.C. 11323-25, consider a carrier&#8217;s fulfillment of its responsibilities under 49 U.S.C. 24308 (relating to Amtrak&#8217;s statutory rights).<br>     (o)  The Chair of the Federal Maritime Commission is encouraged to work with the rest of the Commission to:<br>          (i)    vigorously enforce the prohibition of unjust and unreasonable practices in the context of detention and demurrage pursuant to the Shipping Act, as clarified in &#8220;Interpretive Rule on Demurrage and Detention Under the Shipping Act,&#8221; 85 Fed. Reg. 29638 (May 18, 2020);<br>          (ii)   request from the National Shipper Advisory Committee recommendations for improving detention and demurrage practices and enforcement of related Shipping Act prohibitions; and<br>          (iii)  consider further rulemaking to improve detention and demurrage practices and enforcement of related Shipping Act prohibitions.<br>     (p)  The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall:<br>          (i)     to promote the wide availability of low-cost hearing aids, not later than 120 days after the date of this order, publish for notice and comment a proposed rule on over-the-counter hearing-aids, as called for by section 709 of the FDA Reauthorization Act of 2017 (Public Law 115-52, 131 Stat. 1005);<br>          (ii)    support existing price transparency initiatives for hospitals, other providers, and insurers along with any new price transparency initiatives or changes made necessary by the No Surprises Act (Public Law 116-260, 134 Stat. 2758) or any other statutes;<br>          (iii)   to ensure that Americans can choose health insurance plans that meet their needs and compare plan offerings, implement standardized options in the national Health Insurance Marketplace and any other appropriate mechanisms to improve competition and consumer choice;<br>          (iv)    not later than 45 days after the date of this order, submit a report to the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy and Director of the Domestic Policy Council and to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, with a plan to continue the effort to combat excessive pricing of prescription drugs and enhance domestic pharmaceutical supply chains, to reduce the prices paid by the Federal Government for such drugs, and to address the recurrent problem of price gouging;<br>          (v)     to lower the prices of and improve access to prescription drugs and biologics, continue to promote generic drug and biosimilar competition, as contemplated by the Drug Competition Action Plan of 2017 and Biosimilar Action Plan of 2018 of the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), including by:<br>               (A)  continuing to clarify and improve the approval framework for generic drugs and biosimilars to make generic drug and biosimilar approval more transparent, efficient, and predictable, including improving and clarifying the standards for interchangeability of biological products;<br>               (B)  as authorized by the Advancing Education on Biosimilars Act of 2021 (Public Law 117-8, 135 Stat. 254, 42 U.S.C. 263-1), supporting biosimilar product adoption by providing effective educational materials and communications to improve understanding of biosimilar and interchangeable products among healthcare providers, patients, and caregivers;<br>               (C)  to facilitate the development and approval of biosimilar and interchangeable products, continuing to update the FDA&#8217;s biologics regulations to clarify existing requirements and procedures related to the review and submission of Biologics License Applications by advancing the &#8220;Biologics Regulation Modernization&#8221; rulemaking (RIN 0910-AI14); and<br>               (D)  with the Chair of the FTC, identifying and addressing any efforts to impede generic drug and biosimilar competition, including but not limited to false, misleading, or otherwise deceptive statements about generic drug and biosimilar products and their safety or effectiveness;<br>          (vi)    to help ensure that the patent system, while incentivizing innovation, does not also unjustifiably delay generic drug and biosimilar competition beyond that reasonably contemplated by applicable law, not later than 45 days after the date of this order, through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, write a letter to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office enumerating and describing any relevant concerns of the FDA; <br>          (vii)   to support the market entry of lower-cost generic drugs and biosimilars, continue the implementation of the law widely known as the CREATES Act of 2019 (Public Law 116-94, 133 Stat. 3130), by:<br>               (A)  promptly issuing Covered Product Authorizations (CPAs) to assist product developers with obtaining brand-drug samples; and<br>               (B)  issuing guidance to provide additional information for industry about CPAs; and<br>          (viii)  through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, prepare for Medicare and Medicaid coverage of interchangeable biological products, and for payment models to support increased utilization of generic drugs and biosimilars.<br>     (q)  To reduce the cost of covered products to the American consumer without imposing additional risk to public health and safety, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs shall work with States and Indian Tribes that propose to develop section 804 Importation Programs in accordance with the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 (Public Law 108-173, 117 Stat. 2066), and the FDA&#8217;s implementing regulations.<br>     (r)  The Secretary of Commerce shall:<br>          (i)    acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), consider initiating a rulemaking to require agencies to report to NIST, on an annual basis, their contractors&#8217; utilization activities, as reported to the agencies under 35 U.S.C. 202(c)(5);<br>          (ii)   acting through the Director of NIST, consistent with the policies set forth in section 1 of this order, consider not finalizing any provisions on march-in rights and product pricing in the proposed rule &#8220;Rights to Federally Funded Inventions and Licensing of Government Owned Inventions,&#8221; 86 Fed. Reg. 35 (Jan. 4, 2021); and<br>          (iii)  not later than 1 year after the date of this order, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission, conduct a study, including by conducting an open and transparent stakeholder consultation process, of the mobile application ecosystem, and submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, regarding findings and recommendations for improving competition, reducing barriers to entry, and maximizing user benefit with respect to the ecosystem.<br>     (s)  The Secretary of Defense shall:<br>          (i)    ensure that the Department of Defense&#8217;s assessment of the economic forces and structures shaping the capacity of the national security innovation base pursuant to section 889(a) and (b) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (Public Law 116-283, 134 Stat. 3388) is consistent with the policy set forth in section 1 of this order;<br>          (ii)   not later than 180 days after the date of this order, submit to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, a review of the state of competition within the defense industrial base, including areas where a lack of competition may be of concern and any recommendations for improving the solicitation process, consistent with the goal of the Competition in Contracting Act of 1984 (Public Law 98-369, 98 Stat. 1175); and<br>          (iii)  not later than 180 days after the date of this order, submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, on a plan for avoiding contract terms in procurement agreements that make it challenging or impossible for the Department of Defense or service members to repair their own equipment, particularly in the field.<br>     (t)  The Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, consistent with the pro-competition objectives stated in section 1021 of the Dodd-Frank Act, is encouraged to consider:<br>          (i)   commencing or continuing a rulemaking under section 1033 of the Dodd-Frank Act to facilitate the portability of consumer financial transaction data so consumers can more easily switch financial institutions and use new, innovative financial products; and<br>          (ii)  enforcing the prohibition on unfair, deceptive, or abusive acts or practices in consumer financial products or services pursuant to section 1031 of the Dodd-Frank Act so as to ensure that actors engaged in unlawful activities do not distort the proper functioning of the competitive process or obtain an unfair advantage over competitors who follow the law.<br>     (u)  The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, through the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, shall incorporate into its recommendations for modernizing and improving regulatory review required by my Memorandum of January 20, 2021 (Modernizing Regulatory Review), the policies set forth in section 1 of this order, including consideration of whether the effects on competition and the potential for creation of barriers to entry should be included in regulatory impact analyses.<br>     (v)  The Secretary of the Treasury shall:<br>          (i)   direct the Office of Economic Policy, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Labor, and the Chair of the FTC, to submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, not later than 180 days after the date of this order, on the effects of lack of competition on labor markets; and<br>          (ii)  submit a report to the Chair of the White House Competition Council, not later than 270 days after the date of this order, assessing the effects on competition of large technology firms&#8217; and other non‑bank companies&#8217; entry into consumer finance markets.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 6.  General Provisions</span>. <br>     (a)  This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>     (b)  Where not already specified, independent agencies are encouraged to comply with the requirements of this order.<br>     (c)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>     (d)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>    July 9, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with President Vladimir Putin of Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-president-vladimir-putin-of-russia-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke today with President Putin. The leaders commended the joint work of their respective teams following the U.S.-Russia Summit&#160;that&#160;led to the unanimous renewal of cross-border humanitarian assistance to Syria today in the UN Security Council. President Biden also spoke with President Putin about the ongoing ransomware attacks by criminals based in Russia that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke today with President Putin. The leaders commended the joint work of their respective teams following the U.S.-Russia Summit&nbsp;that&nbsp;led to the unanimous renewal of cross-border humanitarian assistance to Syria today in the UN Security Council.</p>



<p>President Biden also spoke with President Putin about the ongoing ransomware attacks by criminals based in Russia that have impacted the United States and other countries around the world. President Biden underscored the need for Russia to take action to disrupt ransomware groups operating in Russia and emphasized that he is committed to continued engagement on the broader threat posed by ransomware. President Biden reiterated that the United States will take any necessary action to defend its people and its critical infrastructure in the face of this continuing challenge.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order on Promoting Competition in the American Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The economy is booming under President Biden’s leadership. The economy has gained more than three million jobs since the President took office—the most jobs created in the first five months of any presidency in modern history. Today, the President is building on this economic momentum by signing an Executive Order to promote competition in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The economy is booming under President Biden’s leadership. The economy has gained more than three million jobs since the President took office—the most jobs created in the first five months of any presidency in modern history. Today, the President is building on this economic momentum by signing an Executive Order to promote competition in the American economy, which will lower prices for families, increase wages for workers, and promote innovation and even faster economic growth.</p>



<p>For decades, corporate consolidation has been accelerating. In&nbsp;<a href="https://poseidon01.ssrn.com/delivery.php?ID=409065022090123092012067078086115107100012095020070029025083079086096073094098075085122016002103042099002113082005024090123021051037093012023080067090015110022015049069087098078117019024125021127031003020126124121120123113125029089025105027005103097&amp;EXT=pdf&amp;INDEX=TRUE">over 75%</a>&nbsp;of U.S. industries, a smaller number of large companies now control more of the business than they did twenty years ago. This is true across healthcare, financial services, agriculture and more.</p>



<p>That lack of competition drives up prices for consumers. As fewer large players have controlled more of the market, mark-ups (charges over cost)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.janeeckhout.com/wp-content/uploads/RMP.pdf">have tripled</a>. &nbsp;Families are paying higher prices for necessities—things like prescription drugs, hearing aids, and internet service.</p>



<p>Barriers to competition are also driving down wages for workers. When there are only a few employers in town, workers have less opportunity to bargain for a higher wage and to demand dignity and respect in the workplace. In fact, research shows that industry consolidation is decreasing advertised wages by&nbsp;<a href="http://jhr.uwpress.org/content/early/2020/05/04/jhr.monopsony.1218-9914R1.full.pdf+html">as much as 17%</a>.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/noncompete-agreements/">Tens of millions</a>&nbsp;of Americans—including those working in construction and retail—are required to sign non-compete agreements as a condition of getting a job, which makes it harder for them to switch to better-paying options.<br><br>In total, higher prices and lower wages caused by lack of competition are now estimated to cost the median American household&nbsp;<a href="https://www.economicliberties.us/our-work/confronting-americas-concentration-crisis-a-ledger-of-harms-and-framework-for-advancing-economic-liberty-for-all/">$5,000 per year</a>.</p>



<p>Inadequate competition holds back economic growth and innovation. The rate of&nbsp;<a href="https://eig.org/dynamism">new business formation</a>&nbsp;has fallen by almost 50% since the 1970s as large businesses make it harder for Americans with good ideas to break into markets. There are&nbsp;<a href="https://ilsr.org/wp-content/uploads/downloads/2016/08/MonopolyPower-SmallBusiness.pdf">fewer opportunities</a>&nbsp;for existing small and independent businesses to access markets and earn a fair return. &nbsp;Economists find that as competition declines,&nbsp;<a href="https://one.oecd.org/document/DAF/COMP/WD(2018)67/en/pdf">productivity growth</a>&nbsp;slows,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w23583/w23583.pdf">business investment and innovation decline</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://research.chicagobooth.edu/~/media/5872FBEB104245909B8F0AE8A84486C9.pdf">income</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.oecd.org/daf/competition/Inequality-hidden-cost-market-power-2017.pdf">wealth</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://rooseveltinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/RI_Racial-Rules-of-Corporate-Power_Issue-brief_201911-1.pdf">racial inequality</a>&nbsp;widen.</p>



<p>When past presidents faced similar threats from growing corporate power, they took bold action. In the early 1900s, Teddy Roosevelt’s Administration broke up the trusts controlling the economy—Standard Oil, J.P. Morgan’s railroads, and others—giving the little guy a fighting chance. In the late 1930s, FDR’s Administration supercharged antitrust enforcement, increasing more than eightfold the number of cases brought in just two years—enforcement actions that saved consumers&nbsp;<a href="https://lawecommons.luc.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?referer=&amp;httpsredir=1&amp;article=1494&amp;context=facpubs">billions</a>&nbsp;in today’s dollars and helped unleash decades of sustained, inclusive economic growth.</p>



<p>Today President Biden is taking decisive action to reduce the trend of corporate consolidation, increase competition, and deliver concrete benefits to America’s consumers, workers, farmers, and small businesses.&nbsp;<strong>Today’s historic Executive Order established a whole-of-government effort to promote competition in the American economy.&nbsp;</strong>The Order<strong>&nbsp;includes 72 initiatives by more than a dozen federal agencies to promptly tackle some of the most pressing competition problems across our economy.&nbsp;</strong>Once implemented, these initiatives will result in concrete improvements to people’s lives.</p>



<p>Among other things, they will:</p>



<ul><li>Make it easier to change jobs and help raise wages by banning or limiting non-compete agreements and unnecessary, cumbersome occupational licensing requirements that impede economic mobility.</li><li>Lower prescription drug prices by supporting state and tribal programs that will import safe and cheaper drugs from Canada.</li><li>Save Americans with hearing loss thousands of dollars by allowing hearing aids to be sold over the counter at drug stores.</li><li>Save Americans money on their internet bills by banning excessive early termination fees, requiring clear disclosure of plan costs to facilitate comparison shopping, and ending landlord exclusivity arrangements that stick tenants with only a single internet option.</li><li>Make it easier for people to get refunds from airlines and to comparison shop for flights by requiring clear upfront disclosure of add-on fees.</li><li>Make it easier and cheaper to repair items you own by limiting manufacturers from barring self-repairs or third-party repairs of their products.</li><li>Make it easier and cheaper to switch banks by requiring banks to allow customers to take their financial transaction data with them to a competitor.</li><li>Empower family farmers and increase their incomes by strengthening the Department of Agriculture’s tools to stop the abusive practices of some meat processors.</li><li>Increase opportunities for small businesses by directing all federal agencies to promote greater competition through their procurement and spending decisions.</li></ul>



<p><strong>The Order also encourages the leading antitrust agencies to focus enforcement efforts on problems in key markets and coordinates other agencies’ ongoing response to corporate consolidation.&nbsp;</strong>The Order:</p>



<ul><li>Calls on the leading antitrust agencies, the Department of Justice (DOJ) and Federal Trade Commission (FTC), to&nbsp;<strong>enforce the antitrust laws vigorously</strong>&nbsp;and recognizes that the law allows them to&nbsp;<strong>challenge prior bad mergers</strong>&nbsp;that past Administrations did not previously challenge.</li><li>Announces a policy that enforcement should focus in particular on&nbsp;<strong>labor markets, agricultural markets, healthcare markets (which includes prescription drugs, hospital consolidation, and insurance)</strong>,&nbsp;<strong>and the tech sector.</strong></li><li>Establishes a&nbsp;<strong>White House Competition Council, led by the Director of the National Economic Council,&nbsp;</strong>to monitor progress on finalizing the initiatives in the Order and to coordinate the federal government’s response to the rising power of large corporations in the economy.</li></ul>



<p>A more detailed summary of the key actions in the Order is provided below:</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Labor Market</u><span style="text-decoration: underline">s</span></strong></p>



<p>Competition in labor markets empowers workers to demand higher wages and greater dignity and respect in the workplace. One way companies stifle competition is with non-compete clauses. Roughly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/half-of-u-s-businesses-ask-employees-to-sign-noncompete-agreements-and-half-of-them-are-low-wage-workers/">half</a>&nbsp;of private-sector businesses require at least some employees to enter non-compete agreements, affecting some&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/noncompete-agreements/">36 to 60 million</a>&nbsp;workers.</p>



<p>Overly burdensome occupational licensing requirements that impede worker mobility and suppress wages also restrict competition. Today, almost&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/documents/reports/options-enhance-occupational-license-portability/license_portability_policy_paper_0.pdf">30%</a> of jobs in the United States require a license, up from less than 5% in the 1950s.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ncsl.org/Portals/1/Documents/employ/Occu-Licensing-2nd-Edition_v02_web.pdf">Fewer than 5%</a>&nbsp;of occupations that require licensing in at least one state are treated consistently across all 50 states. That locks some people out of jobs, and it makes it harder for people to move between states—particularly burdening military spouses,&nbsp;<a href="https://download.militaryonesource.mil/12038/MOS/Reports/military-spouse-licensure-report-2019.pdf">34%</a>&nbsp;of whom work in a field requiring a license and are subject to military-directed moves every few years.</p>



<p>Workers may also be harmed by existing&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/atr/file/903511/download">guidance</a>&nbsp;provided by the Department of Justice and Federal Trade Commission to Human Resource personnel that&nbsp;<a href="https://www.booker.senate.gov/news/press/booker-warren-question-doj-ftc-on-policy-allowing-employers-to-share-compensation-data">allows</a>&nbsp;third parties to make wage data available to employers—and not to workers—in certain circumstances without triggering antitrust scrutiny. This may be used to collaborate to suppress wages and benefits.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the FTC to&nbsp;<strong>ban or limit non-compete agreements</strong>.</li><li>Encourages the FTC to&nbsp;<strong>ban unnecessary occupational licensing restrictions that impede economic mobility</strong>.</li><li>Encourages the FTC and DOJ to strengthen antitrust guidance to&nbsp;<strong>prevent employers from collaborating to suppress wages</strong>&nbsp;<strong>or reduce benefits&nbsp;</strong>by sharing wage and benefit information with one another.</li></ul>



<p>These actions complement the President’s call for Congress to pass the Protecting the Right to Organize (PRO) Act to ensure workers have a free and fair choice to join a union and to collectively bargain. Unions are critical to empowering workers to bargain with their employers for better jobs and to creating an economy that works for everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Healthcare</u></strong></p>



<p>The proposed Order tackles&nbsp;four&nbsp;areas where lack of competition in healthcare increases prices and reduces access to quality care.</p>



<p><strong><em><u>Prescription Drugs</u></em>:</strong>&nbsp;Americans pay&nbsp;more than&nbsp;<a href="https://www.rand.org/news/press/2021/01/28.html">2.5 times&nbsp;</a>as much for the same prescription drugs as peer countries, and&nbsp;<a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/pdf-report/Comparing-Insulin-Prices">sometimes much more</a>.&nbsp;Price increases continue to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/democracy/reports/2019/08/30/473911/big-pharma-reaps-profits-hurting-everyday-americans/">far surpass inflation</a>. As a result, nearly one in four Americans&nbsp;report difficulties&nbsp;paying for medication, and nearly one in three Americans&nbsp;<a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/press-release/poll-nearly-1-in-4-americans-taking-prescription-drugs-say-its-difficult-to-afford-medicines-including-larger-shares-with-low-incomes/">report</a>&nbsp;not taking their medications as prescribed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These high prices are in part the result of lack of competition among drug manufacturers. The largest pharmaceutical companies are able to wield their market power to reap average annual profits of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-18-40.pdf">15-20%,</a>&nbsp;as compared to average annual profits of 4-9% for the largest non-drug companies.</p>



<p>One strategy that drug manufacturers have used to avoid competing is “pay for delay” agreements, in which brand-name drug manufacturers pay generic manufacturers to stay out of the market. That has raised drug prices&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/media-resources/mergers-competition/pay-delay">by $3.5 billion per year</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28964/w28964.pdf?utm_campaign=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_medium=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_source=PANTHEON_STRIPPED">research also shows</a>&nbsp;that “pay for delay” and similar deals between generic and brand name manufacturers reduce innovation—reducing new drug trials and R&amp;D expenditures.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs the Food and Drug Administration to&nbsp;<strong>work with states and tribes to safely import&nbsp;prescription drugs from Canada</strong>, pursuant to the Medicare Modernization Act of 2003.</li><li>Directs the Health and Human Services Administration (HHS) to increase&nbsp;<strong>support for generic and biosimilar drugs</strong>, which provide low-cost options for patients.</li><li>Directs HHS to issue&nbsp;<strong>a comprehensive plan within 45 days to combat high prescription drug prices and price gouging</strong>.&nbsp;</li><li>Encourages the FTC to&nbsp;<strong>ban “</strong><a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28964/w28964.pdf?utm_campaign=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_medium=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_source=PANTHEON_STRIPPED"><strong>pay for delay</strong></a><strong>” and similar agreements by rule.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Hearing Aids</u></em>:</strong>&nbsp;Hearing aids are so expensive that only&nbsp;<a href="https://hearinghealthfoundation.org/blogs/why-so-many-cant-afford-to-hear-better">14%</a>&nbsp;of&nbsp;the approximately&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nceh/hearing_loss/public_health_scientific_info.html">48 million Americans&nbsp;</a>with hearing loss use them. On&nbsp;average, they cost more than&nbsp;<a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/hearing-aids/best-and-worst-hearing-aid-brands-and-retailers/">$5,000&nbsp;</a>per pair, and those costs are often not covered by health insurance.&nbsp;A major driver of the expense is that consumers must get&nbsp;them from a doctor or a specialist, even though&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nap.edu/download/23446">experts agree</a>&nbsp;that medical evaluation is not necessary.&nbsp;Rather, this requirement serves only as red tape&nbsp;and a barrier to more companies selling hearing aids.&nbsp;The four largest hearing aid manufacturers now control&nbsp;<a href="http://concentrationcrisis.openmarketsinstitute.org/industry/hearing-aid-manufacturing/">84%</a>&nbsp;of the market.&nbsp;<br>In 2017, Congress passed a bipartisan proposal to allow hearing aids to be sold over the counter. However, the Trump Administration Food and Drug Administration failed to issue the necessary rules that would actually allow hearing aids to be sold over the counter, leaving millions of Americans without low-cost options.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs&nbsp;HHS&nbsp;to consider issuing&nbsp;<strong>proposed rules within 120 days for&nbsp;allowing hearing aids to be sold over the counter.</strong>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Hospitals</u></em>:</strong>&nbsp;Hospital consolidation has left&nbsp;many areas,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-21-93">especially rural communities</a>,&nbsp;without good options for convenient and affordable healthcare service. Thanks to unchecked mergers,&nbsp;the ten largest healthcare systems&nbsp;now&nbsp;control a&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/industry/health-care/hospital-mergers-acquisition-trends.html">quarter</a>&nbsp;of the market.&nbsp;Since 2010,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.shepscenter.unc.edu/programs-projects/rural-health/rural-hospital-closures/">139</a>&nbsp;rural hospitals&nbsp;have shuttered, including a high of 19 last year, in the middle of a healthcare crisis.&nbsp;Research shows that hospitals in consolidated markets charge&nbsp;<a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/issue-brief/what-we-know-about-provider-consolidation/">far higher prices</a>&nbsp;than hospitals in markets with several competitors.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Underscores that hospital mergers can be harmful</strong>&nbsp;to patients and encourages the Justice Department and FTC to review and revise their merger guidelines to ensure patients are not harmed by such mergers.</li><li>Directs HHS to&nbsp;<strong>support existing hospital price transparency rules and to finish implementing bipartisan federal legislation to address surprise hospital billing</strong>.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Health Insurance</u></em>:</strong>&nbsp;Consolidation in the health insurance industry has meant that many consumers have&nbsp;<a href="https://www.kff.org/private-insurance/issue-brief/insurer-participation-on-the-aca-marketplaces-2014-2021/">little choice</a>&nbsp;when it comes to selecting insurers. And even when there is some choice, comparison shopping is hard because plans offered on the exchanges are complicated—with different services covered or different deductibles.<br><br><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs HHS to&nbsp;<strong>standardize plan options in the National Health Insurance Marketplace so people can comparison shop</strong>&nbsp;more easily.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Transportation</u></strong></p>



<p>In the transportation sector, multiple industries are now dominated by large corporations—air travel, rail, and shipping.</p>



<p><strong>Airlines:&nbsp;</strong>The top four commercial airlines control nearly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/250577/domestic-market-share-of-leading-us-airlines/">two-thirds</a>&nbsp;of the domestic market. Reduced competition contributes to increasing fees like baggage and cancellation fees. These fees are often&nbsp;<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/american-delta-united-all-raise-checked-baggage-fees-2018-9">raised in lockstep</a>, demonstrating a lack of meaningful competitive pressure, and are&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/travel/which-airlines-have-the-best-and-worst-fees">often hidden</a>&nbsp;from consumers at the point of purchase. The top ten airlines collected&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aviationpros.com/airlines/press-release/21115541/with-travel-season-ahead-senator-markey-and-reps-cohen-and-garcia-reintroduce-legislation-to-stop-rising-airline-fees">$35.2 billion</a>&nbsp;in ancillary fees in 2018, up from just $1.2 billion in 2007. Inadequate competition also reduces incentives to provide good service. For example, the Department of Transportation (DOT) estimates that airlines were late delivering&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/sites/dot.gov/files/2020-02/February%202020%20ATCR.pdf">at least</a>&nbsp;2.3 million checked bags in 2019.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs the DOT to consider issuing<strong>&nbsp;clear rules requiring the refund of fees when baggage is delayed or when service isn’t actually provided</strong>—like when the plane’s WiFi or in-flight entertainment system is broken.</li><li>Directs the DOT to consider issuing&nbsp;<strong>rules that require baggage, change, and cancellation fees to be clearly disclosed</strong>&nbsp;to the customer.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Rail</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;In 1980, there were&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ams.usda.gov/sites/default/files/media/Railroad%20Concentration%2C%20Market%20Shares%2C%20and%20Rates.pdf">33 “Class I” freight railroads</a>, compared to just seven today, and four major rail companies now dominate their respective geographic regions. Freight railroads that own the tracks can privilege their own freight traffic—making it harder for passenger trains to have on-time service—and can overcharge other companies’ freight cars.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the Surface Transportation Board to&nbsp;<strong>require railroad track owners to provide rights of way to passenger rail&nbsp;</strong>and to strengthen their obligations to&nbsp;<strong>treat other freight companies fairly</strong>.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Shipping</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;In maritime shipping, the global marketplace has rapidly consolidated. In 2000, the largest 10 shipping companies controlled&nbsp;<a href="https://www.joc.com/maritime-news/container-lines/new-oligopoly-container-shipping_20190704.html">12%</a>&nbsp;of the market. Today, it is more than 80%, leaving domestic manufacturers who need to export goods at these large foreign companies’ mercy. This has let powerful container shippers charge exporters exorbitant fees for time their freight was sitting waiting to be loaded or unloaded. These fees, called “detention and demurrage charges,” can add up to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.joc.com/regulation-policy/us-detention-demurrage-probes-initial-focus-carriers-terminals_20180402.html">hundreds of thousands</a>&nbsp;of dollars.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the Federal Maritime Commission to&nbsp;<strong>ensure vigorous enforcement against shippers charging American exporters exorbitant charges</strong>.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Agriculture</span></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Over the past few decades, key agricultural markets have become more concentrated and less competitive. The markets for seeds, equipment, feed, and fertilizer are now dominated by just a few large companies, meaning family farmers and ranchers now have to pay more for these&nbsp;<a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/reports/2019/05/07/469385/fair-deal-farmers/">inputs</a>.&nbsp;For example, just&nbsp;<a href="https://civileats.com/2019/01/11/the-sobering-details-behind-the-latest-seed-monopoly-chart/">four companies</a>&nbsp;control most of the world’s seeds, and corn seed prices have gone up as much as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.agri-pulse.com/ext/resources/pdfs/m/e/r/p/t/Merger_Paper_Full_manuscript.pdf">30</a>% annually.</p>



<p>Consolidation also limits farmers’ and ranchers’ options for selling their products. That means they get&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/23/business/beef-prices.html">less</a>&nbsp;when they sell their produce and meat—even as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/meat-price-spreads/">prices rise</a>&nbsp;at the grocery store. For example,&nbsp;four large meat-packing companies dominate over&nbsp;<a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/reports/2019/05/07/469385/fair-deal-farmers/">80</a>% of the beef market and, over the last five years, farmers’ share of the price of beef has dropped by more than a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/meat-price-spreads/">quarter</a>—from 51.5% to 37.3%—while the price of beef has risen.</p>



<p>Overall, farmers’ and ranchers’ share of each dollar spent on food has been&nbsp;<a href="https://data.ers.usda.gov/reports.aspx?ID=17885&amp;reportPath=/FoodDollar/Real">declining </a>for decades. In short, family farmers and ranchers are getting less, consumers are paying more, and the big conglomerates in the middle are taking the difference.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the law designed to combat these abuses—the Packers and Stockyards Act—was systematically weakened by the Trump Administration Department of Agriculture (USDA).</p>



<p>American farmers and ranchers are also getting squeezed by foreign corporations importing meat from overseas with labels that mislead customers about its origin. Under current labeling rules, meat can be labeled “Product of USA” if it is only processed here—including when meat is raised overseas and then merely processed into cuts of meat here. For example,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-23/most-grass-fed-beef-labeled-product-of-u-s-a-is-imported">most grass-fed beef labeled “Product of USA”</a>&nbsp;is actually imported. That makes it hard or impossible for consumers to know where their food comes from and to choose to support American farmers and ranchers.</p>



<p>Corporate consolidation even affects farmers’ ability to repair their own equipment or to use independent repair shops. Powerful equipment manufacturers—such as tractor manufacturers—use proprietary repair tools, software, and diagnostics to prevent third-parties from performing repairs. For example, when certain tractors detect a failure, they cease to operate until a dealer unlocks them. That forcers farmers to pay dealer rates for repairs that they could have made themselves, or that an independent repair shop could have done more cheaply.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs USDA to consider issuing&nbsp;<strong>new rules under the Packers and Stockyards Act making it easier for farmers to bring and win claims, stopping chicken processors from exploiting and underpaying chicken farmers, and adopting anti-retaliation protections</strong>&nbsp;for farmers who speak out about bad practices.</li><li>Directs USDA to consider issuing&nbsp;<strong>new rules defining when meat can bear “Product of USA” labels, so that consumers have accurate, transparent labels that enable them to choose products made here.</strong></li><li>Directs USDA to develop a plan to&nbsp;<strong>increase opportunities for farmers to access markets and receive a fair return, including supporting alternative food distribution systems like farmers markets and developing standards and labels</strong>&nbsp;so that consumers can choose to buy products that treat farmers fairly.</li><li>Encourages the FTC to&nbsp;<strong>limit powerful equipment manufacturers from restricting people’s ability to use independent repair shops or do DIY repairs—such as when tractor companies block farmers from repairing their own tractors</strong>.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Internet Service</u></strong></p>



<p>The Order tackles four issues that limit competition, raise prices, and reduce choices for internet service.</p>



<p><strong><em><u>Lack of competition among broadband providers</u></em>:&nbsp;</strong>More than<a href="https://broadbandmap.fcc.gov/#/area-summary?version=jun2020&amp;type=nation&amp;geoid=0&amp;tech=acfw&amp;speed=25_3&amp;vlat=38.09830512359795&amp;vlon=-97.57983008590088&amp;vzoom=2.779496173169071">200 million</a>&nbsp;U.S. residents live in an area with only one or two reliable high-speed internet providers, leading to prices as much as&nbsp;<a href="https://poseidon01.ssrn.com/delivery.php?ID=153105123123122096085069108028083069015084039027010010113122030072017096030080000111022041026045103029042116102105092074116105009011053002088124092068090068124020088055017094105076107024069120007103094103025106024007073088080121124071098084103125111021&amp;EXT=pdf&amp;INDEX=TRUE"><em>five times higher</em></a>&nbsp;in these markets than in markets with more options. A related problem is landlords and internet service providers entering&nbsp;<a href="https://www.newamerica.org/oti/reports/cost-connectivity-2020/us-policy-recommendations/">exclusivity deals or collusive arrangements</a>&nbsp;that leave tenants with only one option. This impacts low-income and marginalized neighborhoods, because landlord-ISP arrangements can effectively block out broadband infrastructure expansion by new providers.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President encourages the FCC to:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Prevent ISPs from making deals with landlords that limit tenants’ choices.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong>Lack of price transparency</strong>:&nbsp;Even where consumers have options, comparison shopping is hard. According to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), actual prices paid for broadband services can be&nbsp;<a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-338708A1.pdf">40%</a> higher than advertised. During the Obama-Biden Administration, the FCC began&nbsp;<a href="https://www.newamerica.org/oti/press-releases/oti-applauds-bill-to-create-a-broadband-nutrition-label/">developing</a>&nbsp;a “Broadband Nutrition Label”—a simple label that provides basic information about the internet service offered so people can compare options. The Trump Administration FCC abandoned those plans.<br><br><strong>In the Order, the President encourages the FCC to:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Revive the “</strong><a href="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6286175/BroadbandLabel.0.jpg"><strong>Broadband Nutrition Label</strong></a><strong>”</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>require providers to report prices and subscription rates</strong>&nbsp;to the FCC.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>High termination fees</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;If a consumer does find a better internet service deal, they may be unable to actually switch because of high early termination fees—on average nearly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.newamerica.org/oti/reports/cost-connectivity-2020/focus-on-the-fees/">$200</a>—charged by internet providers.<br><strong>In the Order, the President encourages the FCC to:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Limit excessive early termination fees.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Companies discriminatorily slowing down internet access</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;Big providers can use their power to discriminatorily block or slow down online services. The Obama-Biden Administration’s FCC adopted “Net Neutrality” rules that required these companies to treat all internet services equally, but this was&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/11/technology/net-neutrality-repeal.html">undone</a>&nbsp;in 2017.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President encourages the FCC to:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Restore Net Neutrality rules</strong>&nbsp;undone by the prior administration.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Technology</u></strong></p>



<p>The Order tackles three areas in which dominant tech firms are undermining competition and reducing innovation:</p>



<p><strong><em><u>Big Tech platforms purchasing would-be competitors</u></em>:</strong>&nbsp;Over the past ten years, the largest tech platforms have acquired hundreds of companies—including alleged “<a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3241707">killer acquisitions</a>” meant to shut down a potential competitive threat. Too often, federal agencies have not blocked, conditioned, or, in some cases, meaningfully examined these acquisitions.<br><br><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Announces an Administration policy of&nbsp;<strong>greater scrutiny of mergers</strong>, especially by dominant internet platforms, with particular attention to the acquisition of nascent competitors, serial mergers, the accumulation of data, competition by “free” products, and the effect on user privacy.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Big Tech platforms gathering too much personal information</u></em></strong><strong>:&nbsp;</strong>Many of the large platforms’ business models have depended on the accumulation of extraordinarily amounts of sensitive personal information and related data.<br><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the FTC to establish&nbsp;<strong>rules on surveillance and the accumulation of data.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Big Tech platforms unfairly competing with small businesses</u></em></strong><strong>:&nbsp;</strong>The large platforms’ power gives them unfair opportunities to get a leg up on the small businesses that rely on them to reach customers. For example, companies that run&nbsp;<a href="https://judiciary.house.gov/uploadedfiles/competition_in_digital_markets.pdf?utm_campaign=4493-519">dominant online retail marketplaces</a>&nbsp;can see how small businesses’ products sell and then use the data to launch their own competing products. Because they run the platform, they can also display their own copycat products more prominently than the small businesses’ products.<br><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the FTC to establish&nbsp;<strong>rules barring unfair methods of competition on internet marketplaces.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Cell phone manufacturers and others blocking out independent repair shops</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;Tech and other companies impose restrictions on self and third-party repairs, making repairs&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/7/3/18761691/right-to-repair-computers-phones-car-mechanics-apple">more costly and time-consuming</a>, such as by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/ypkqxw/do-you-know-anything-about-apples-authorized-service-provider-program">restricting</a>&nbsp;the distribution of parts, diagnostics, and repair tools.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the FTC to issue&nbsp;<strong>rules against anticompetitive restrictions on using independent repair shops or doing DIY repairs</strong>&nbsp;of your own devices and equipment.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Banking and Consumer Finance</u></strong></p>



<p>Over the past four decades, the United States has lost 70% of the banks it once had, with around <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/USNUM">10,000</a> bank closures. Communities of color are disproportionately affected, with <a href="https://ncrc.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/NCRC_Branch_Deserts_Research_Memo_050517_2.pdf">25%</a> of all rural closures in majority-minority census tracts. Many of these closures are the <a href="https://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/app.20170543">product</a> of mergers and acquisitions. Though subject to federal review, federal agencies have not formally denied a bank merger application in more than <a href="https://digitalcommons.law.yale.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1557&amp;context=yjreg">15 years</a>.<br><br>Excessive consolidation raises costs for consumers, restricts credit for small businesses, and harms low-income communities. Branch closures can reduce the amount of small business lending by about <a href="http://faculty.haas.berkeley.edu/hqn/nguyen_aej_201901.pdf">10%</a> and leads to <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/j.1540-6261.2006.00847.x">higher interest rates</a>. Even where a customer has multiple options, it is hard to switch banks partly because customers cannot easily take their financial transaction history data to a new bank. That increases the <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/reports/2021/02/26/496444/switching-responsible-banking/">cost</a> of the new bank extending you credit.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages DOJ and the agencies responsible for banking (the Federal Reserve, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency) to&nbsp;<strong>update guidelines on banking mergers to provide more robust scrutiny</strong>&nbsp;<strong>of mergers</strong>.</li><li>Encourages the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to issue&nbsp;<strong>rules allowing customers to download their banking data</strong>&nbsp;and take it with them.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting With Leaders from Legacy Black Civil Rights Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/08/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-leaders-from-legacy-black-civil-rights-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 01:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden and Vice President Harris met today with leaders from legacy Black civil rights organizations. The group discussed the wave of anti-voter legislation that has recently passed or is pending in state legislatures across the country and the path forward to protect the right to vote. The group also discussed steps the Administration recently&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris met today with leaders from legacy Black civil rights organizations. The group discussed the wave of anti-voter legislation that has recently passed or is pending in state legislatures across the country and the path forward to protect the right to vote. The group also discussed steps the Administration recently announced to address the rise in gun violence and the status of the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act that is currently being negotiated in the Senate. The President and Vice President reiterated that they will continue to push for Congress to pass critical legislation that protects the right to vote and combats subversion of the election process, while continuing to utilize all existing authorities in an all-of-government effort to ensure full voter participation and elections that reflect the will of the people.<br><br>The civil rights leaders provided an update on the work their organizations are doing, both nationally and in the states, to protect the right to vote. They also provided the President and Vice President with their ideas on ways to engage the public on civil rights issues.<br><br>The meeting participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Melanie Campbell, President and CEO of the National Coalition on Black Civic Participation</li><li>Dr. Johnnetta Cole, National Chair and President of the National Council of Negro Women</li><li>Wade Henderson, Interim President of the Leadership Conference on Civil and Human</li><li>Damon Hewitt, President and Executive Director of the Lawyers’ Committee for Civil Rights Under Law</li><li>Sherrilyn Ifill, President and Director-Counsel of the NAACP Legal Defense Fund</li><li>Derrick Johnson, President and CEO of the NAACP (virtual)</li><li>Marc Morial, President and CEO of the National Urban League</li><li>Reverend Al Sharpton, President of the National Action Network</li></ul>



<p>From the White House:</p>



<ul><li>Danielle Conley, Deputy Counsel to the President</li><li>Tina Flournoy, Assistant to the President and Chief of Staff to the Vice President</li><li>Catherine Lhamon, Deputy Assistant to the President for Racial Justice and Equity</li><li>Dana Remus, Assistant to the President and White House Counsel</li><li>Susan Rice, Assistant to the President and Domestic Policy Advisor</li><li>Cedric Richmond, Assistant to the President and Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
