<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 22:44:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 3613 and S.&#160;4160</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/16/bill-signed-h-r-3613-and-s-4160/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 22:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3613, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 202 Trumbull Street in Saint Clair, Michigan, as the Corporal Jeffrey Robert Standfest Post Office Building; Thank you to Representatives McClain, Bergman, Huizenga, Meijer, Moolenaar, Upton, Walberg, Andy Levin, Stevens, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3613, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 202 Trumbull Street in Saint Clair, Michigan, as the Corporal Jeffrey Robert Standfest Post Office Building;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives McClain, Bergman, Huizenga, Meijer, Moolenaar, Upton, Walberg, Andy Levin, Stevens, and Dingell for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 4160, the &#8220;Supreme Court Police Parity Act of 2022,&#8221; which authorizes the Marshal of the Supreme Court and Supreme Court Police to protect immediate family members of the Chief Justice, any Associate Justice, or any officer of the Supreme Court.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Cornyn and Coons for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Announcing the Launch of the White&#160;House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and&#160;Abuse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/16/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-announcing-the-launch-of-the-white-house-task-force-to-address-online-harassment-and-abuse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 21:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eisenhower Executive Office Building 1:52 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Please have a seat.  Hi, everyone.  Well, let me start by saying it is so good to be with our Attorney General, Merrick Garland; our Surgeon General, Vivek Murthy; and on Gender Policy Council &#8212; where she? &#8212; Dr. Jennifer Klein; and all the members of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></p>



<p>1:52 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Please have a seat.  Hi, everyone.  Well, let me start by saying it is so good to be with our Attorney General, Merrick Garland; our Surgeon General, Vivek Murthy; and on Gender Policy Council &#8212; where she? &#8212; Dr. Jennifer Klein; and all the members of the task force.  Thank you all for the work you do, for the extraordinary work that you do.<br> <br>Sloane, thank you for your courage.  It takes a lot to put yourself out there as a public figure, period, but then to speak out about something so many people, regardless of gender, are experiencing.  So thank you for your leadership.  Thank you.<br> <br>And to all the other survivors who are here today: You motivate us.  You inspire us.  And you are the voice of so many people who are in this room because of the voice that you express around these issues.  And so I thank you for that and your strength and your sense of purpose.<br> <br>And in particular, I also want to acknowledge Matthew and Francesca. <br> <br>So I know it is not easy to talk about what you&#8217;ve experienced.  And as all of you know, most of my career, I spent it as a prosecutor.  And the majority of that time, I was focused on crimes affecting women and children, crimes that involved sexual abuse.  And &#8212; and in many of the cases, in particular when they were going to trial, and we were prepared to go to trial, I’d sit down for extensive periods of time to talk with the survivors about their case and talk with them about what it would be like when they were going to walk out of my office and walk down the hall and walk into a courtroom.<br> <br>And for some, as you all know, it was impossible to imagine what it would mean to speak publicly about what they&#8217;d been through, when, you know, most don&#8217;t want to even speak about it in private.<br> <br>But every time, I have to tell you, I was inspired by their bravery for so many reasons, both because of the courage it takes to tell a story that is a story that is informed by some of the most horrible experiences but also informed by such pain.  But I was also inspired because, again, the courage that it takes to be that voice.<br> <br>You know, when I would prosecute a case, and the prosecutors here know that, it was &#8212; the &#8212; I would stand in front of the jury, and I would say, “Kamala Harris for the people.”  And the charging document would not be the name of the victim or survivor versus the defendant, it was the “The People versus.”<br> <br>Because, you see, in our form of justice, we have rightly said that individual should not be made to fight alone.  A harm against her, against him, against them is a harm against all of us as a society. <br> <br>And so, it is with that spirit that we are doing the work we are doing today to convene and to inaugurate this task force, understanding this affects all of us if it affects any one of us. <br> <br>And we therefore, all of us, have a responsibility to stand together to support those who have gone through this, but to also recognize they shouldn’t have to be alone fighting on this issue. <br> <br>So that&#8217;s the spirit with which we convene today and the spirit with which we are doing this work. <br> <br>And I will tell you, as Attorney General, many of you know, when I was in California, I prosecuted the first case in the country of an operator of a cyber exploitation website. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ll never forget &#8212; you know, my office was mostly in Sacramento, and we were dealing with a case &#8212; if you know California &#8212; in another part of the state.  And I flew down to meet with the person who was actually handling the case, to go o- &#8212; went through the files to see: Where were we?  What was going on?  What were we going to do about this case?<br> <br>Because it was, in many ways, a case of first impression &#8212; although it wasn&#8217;t when we thought about the pathology of what was at play.  When we thought about the &#8212; you know, we call it the “MO” &#8212; modus operandi.  Right?  When we talked about and thought about how it was being done, what was motivating it, and how it was making that victim and that survivor feel. <br> <br>So, yes, it was the first in the nation, but we&#8217;d seen that kind of stuff before.  The point was that we needed to update and upgrade ourselves as law enforcement and as the criminal justice system, as a justice system, to recognize where it is now occurring and update our approach to deal with it in all places where it exists in a way that causes harm and pain and injury. <br> <br>And so, that website in particular, it &#8212; what it did is it let people upload sexually explicit photographs of their former partners &#8212; the photographs that were taken and shared with consent in a consensual relationship.  But, of course, what ended up happening is that one of those partners usually in that relationship had &#8212; had a grudge or an issue or a motivation to embarrass or to harm, and would allow the photograph to be posted with the explicit intent &#8212; certainly with the implicit effect &#8212; of trying to embarrass and degrade and hurt and cause pain and attract judgment to that individual. <br><br>Well, in that case, I’m happy to report that the person who ran that website went to prison, because I do believe that there should be consequence for behaviors that harm other human beings.<br><br>But this kind of justice is still so rare, because many of our laws have not caught up with the advances in technology.  So, as a United States senator, I introduced legislation to make these acts a federal crime.<br> <br>And thanks to the recent &#8212; and our President, Joe Biden &#8212; and the recent reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act, for the first time, cyber exploitation victims can sue their abusers in federal civil court.<br> <br>And this is progress, yet we still have so much more work to do to protect people from online harassment and abuse, which is why the work of this task force is so important.<br> <br>Context.  Well, the Internet is an essential part of life in the 21st century.  Can’t get around it.  Can’t get around without it.  And for far too many people &#8212; and Sloane told her story &#8212; the Internet is a place of fear.<br> <br>One in three women under the age of 35 report being sexually harassed online.  Over half of the LGBTQ+ people in our country are survivors of severe harassment.<br> <br>Nearly one in four Asian Americans report being called an offensive name, usually motivated by racism &#8212; being called an offensive name online.  And Black people who have been harassed online in our country are three times more likely to be targeted, again, because of their race.<br> <br>No one should have to endure abuse just because they are attempting to participate in society.<br> <br>Of course, the impact of this abuse extends beyond the ability to use Internet &#8212; the Internet system and the power of the Internet &#8212; without fear.  It’s beyond that.  In many cases, cyberstalking have serious mental health consequences for its victims, sometimes leading to self-harm, sometimes leading to suicide.<br><br>And we continue to see how some acts of mass violence &#8212; the most recent included &#8212; have followed expressions of online hate and abuse.<br> <br>The white supremacist who murdered 10 Black people in Buffalo, New York, was first radicalized, by all accounts, online.<br> <br>And after the massacre of 19 children &#8212; 19 babies &#8212; and 2 teachers in Uvalde, it was revealed that the shooter had threatened to kidnap, rape, and kill teenage girls on Instagram.  One of the girls he harassed described the abuse, I quote, as “just how online is.”  Think about that.  Hate has become so common on the Internet that, as a society, it&#8217;s kind of becoming normalized, and for users, some might say unavoidable. <br> <br>Recent events have also made it clear that we face new threats.  Earlier this week, I met with a group of legal experts about how overturning Roe v. Wade will impact the right to privacy. <br> <br>Now, just think about this: In states where abortion is criminalized, an abuser could purchase a woman&#8217;s location history through a data broker.  This is a realistic scenario.  If that history shows that she sought an abortion out of state, he could then turn it over to law enforcement in a jurisdiction that has deemed that a crime.  This is a horrifying possibility for that woman. <br> <br>So let us be clear: No one should be afraid that an abuser will use their private personal data &#8212; or that a person&#8217;s private personal data will be used against them.  And all people deserve to use the Internet free from fear.<br> <br>This task force, then, will tackle a threat that has been far too real for far too many people for far too long.  And the recommendations of this group and the extens- &#8212; extended group of experts and those who have been advocates in this space for so long &#8212; the collective work &#8212; will help modernize the federal government&#8217;s response to violence against women and people of all genders.  It will lead to more evidence-informed policies and interventions.  And it will support more federal funding to address online harassment and abuse, including grants to train law enforcement and prosecutors. <br> <br>It is incumbent on all of us &#8212; government, local law enforcement, and the tech sector &#8212; to respond to the task at hand with a sense of urgency. <br> <br>So I thank you all for your tireless fight and for your advocacy, for your strength to prevent these harms from happening in the first place and to hold perpetrators accountable.  And the President and I look forward to hearing all of your recommendations. <br> <br>Thank you all so very much.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END                 2:04 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: S.&#160;3580</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/16/bill-signed-s-3580/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 20:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 3580, the &#8220;Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 2022,&#8221; which authorizes appropriations for the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) for fiscal years 2022 through 2025; establishes additional requirements and prohibited conduct for ocean carriers; requires the FMC to issue rules related to certain fee assessments, prohibited&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 3580, the &#8220;Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 2022,&#8221; which authorizes appropriations for the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) for fiscal years 2022 through 2025; establishes additional requirements and prohibited conduct for ocean carriers; requires the FMC to issue rules related to certain fee assessments, prohibited practices, and establishment of a shipping registry; and authorizes the FMC under certain circumstances to issue an emergency order requiring common carriers to share information directly with shippers and rail and motor carriers.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Amy Klobuchar, John Thune, Maria Cantwell, and Roger Wicker and Representatives Peter DeFazio, Sam Graves, John Garamendi, and Dusty Johnson for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Healthcare Cybersecurity Executive Forum Hosted by National Cyber Director Chris&#160;Inglis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/readout-of-healthcare-cybersecurity-executive-forum-hosted-by-national-cyber-director-chris-inglis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 20:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis hosted Deputy Secretary of Health and Human Services Andrea Palm, senior U.S. government cybersecurity officials, and CEOs and other senior executives representing entities on the Health Sector Coordinating Council Cybersecurity Working Group Executive Committee for a cyber threat briefing and roundtable discussion about cybersecurity in the healthcare and public&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis hosted Deputy Secretary of Health and Human Services Andrea Palm, senior U.S. government cybersecurity officials, and CEOs and other senior executives representing entities on the Health Sector Coordinating Council Cybersecurity Working Group Executive Committee for a cyber threat briefing and roundtable discussion about cybersecurity in the healthcare and public health sector. Participants discussed the five-year anniversary of the Health Care Industry Cybersecurity Task Force’s “Report on Improving Cybersecurity in the Health Care Industry,” including the progress that has been made since the report came out and areas where additional focus is needed. Deputy Secretary Palm provided an update on HHS’s work to finalize a sector incident response plan, and Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency Deputy Director Nitin Natarajan shared resources CISA has available to help manage cybersecurity risk in critical infrastructure sectors, including healthcare. Healthcare CEOs and senior executives relayed their experiences protecting their systems, products, and patients; the investments they’ve made to combat growing cyber threats; and the challenges they’ve faced in dealing with vulnerabilities in the cyber ecosystem. All of the participants agreed on the importance of additional collaboration, including through exercises, to help improve cybersecurity in the sector.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joe&#160;Biden will Host Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate Leaders&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/president-joe-biden-will-host-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate-leaders-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 19:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden will host a virtual leader-level meeting of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate (MEF) on June 17, 2022, at 8:30 a.m. Eastern Time. This will be President Biden’s third leader-level convening of the MEF since taking office. This meeting of the MEF is a continuation of the President’s efforts to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joe Biden will host a virtual leader-level meeting of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate (MEF) on June 17, 2022, at 8:30 a.m. Eastern Time. This will be President Biden’s third leader-level convening of the MEF since taking office.</p>



<p>This meeting of the MEF is a continuation of the President’s efforts to use all levers to tackle the global climate crisis, urgently address rising costs around the world exacerbated by Russia’s war on Ukraine, and put the U.S. and allies on a path to long-term energy and food security.&nbsp;&nbsp;In urging countries to enhance climate ambition, he invited fellow leaders to join the United States in a set of concrete, collective initiatives that will accelerate global action on climate as well as our energy security and food security efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The MEF includes countries representing 80 percent of global GDP, population, and greenhouse gas emissions.  Other leaders critical to the global effort to tackle the climate crisis have also been invited to participate.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Montana Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-montana-disaster-declaration-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 18:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Montana and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe storm and flooding beginning on June 10, 2022, and continuing. Federal funding is available to State, tribal, eligible local governments&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Montana and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe storm and flooding beginning on June 10, 2022, and continuing.<br> <br>Federal funding is available to State, tribal, eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storm and flooding in the counties of Carbon, Park, and Stillwater.<br> <br>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.<br> <br>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Maona N. Ngwira as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.  <br> <br>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the State and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.<br> <br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a>FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Bipartisan Senate Passage of the PACT&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-bipartisan-senate-passage-of-the-pact-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 18:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of the Unity Agenda that I laid out in my State of the Union address, I called on Congress to make sure that veterans and their families and caregivers impacted by toxic exposures finally get the benefits and comprehensive health care they earned and deserve. Today, the United States Senate answered that call&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As part of the Unity Agenda that I laid out in my State of the Union address, I called on Congress to make sure that veterans and their families and caregivers impacted by toxic exposures finally get the benefits and comprehensive health care they earned and deserve. Today, the United States Senate answered that call by overwhelmingly passing the bipartisan<em>&nbsp;Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson Honoring Our PACT Act of&nbsp;</em>2022­—the largest single bill in American history to address our service members’ exposure to burn pits and other toxic substances.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This bill will provide expanded access to health care and disability benefits for veterans harmed by certain toxic exposures, whether in the jungles of Vietnam or the mountains of Afghanistan. It will also let the Department of Veterans Affairs move more quickly and comprehensively in the future to determine if illnesses are related to military service, and it will offer critical support to survivors who were harmed by exposures, including from water contamination at Camp LeJeune. Importantly, the bill includes the tools and resources to ensure that the VA can effectively implement it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Above all, this legislation makes good on our sacred obligation to care for veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors. I want to thank Chair Tester and Ranking Member Moran for their remarkable work to pass the PACT Act, and I urge the House to swiftly pass this bill so I can sign it into law right away.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in a Press Call on Improving Maternal Health&#160;Outcomes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/16/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-press-call-on-improving-maternal-health-outcomes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 16:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:11 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Gene Sperling.&#160; Thank you, and for your extraordinary longstanding service to our country, including the work that you have been doing to ensure the &#8212; the speedy and effective and meaningful implementation of the ARP.&#160; So, thank you for that. I do believe our nation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Via Teleconference</em></p>



<p>10:11 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Gene Sperling.&nbsp; Thank you, and for your extraordinary longstanding service to our country, including the work that you have been doing to ensure the &#8212; the speedy and effective and meaningful implementation of the ARP.&nbsp; So, thank you for that.</p>



<p>I do believe our nation is facing a maternal mortality crisis, given the extent of the work that we as an administration have been doing with our partners.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it is evidenced by the fact that women in our nation are dying from pregnancy-related causes at a higher rate than any other developed nation &#8212; dying before, during, and after childbirth.</p>



<p>Black women are three times more likely to be affected by this and to die from childbirth-related causes.&nbsp; Native women, twice as likely.&nbsp; Rural women, one and a half times likely.</p>



<p>So, our administration has taken historic action to elevate this issue and protect the women of our nation.&nbsp;It&#8217;s that simple.</p>



<p>Last year, we hosted the first-ever White House Maternal Health Day of Action.&nbsp; And this year, I was pleased to bring together members of our Cabinet to focus on the issue of maternal health, which followed, as Gene mentioned, a Call to Action to states to extend Medicaid coverage for postpartum women from 2 months &#8212; from a mere 2 months &#8212; to 12 months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And notably, the ARP gives &#8212; and gives the states the authority to do this.&nbsp; So, again, the connection between this initiative and the details of the ARP and its implementation have made all the difference.&nbsp; And it matters because, of course, Medicaid covers approximately 40 percent of all births nationwide, and one third of pregnancy-related deaths occur between one and a half months and one year postpartum.</p>



<p>Throughout my career, as Gene has said, I do believe that one of the greatest priorities for us in public policy must be the health, safety, and wellbeing of women, including maternal health.&nbsp; And so, today, we are proud to announce that the Centers for Medicaid and Medicaid Service &#8212; and Medicare Services will expand coverage and approve the expansion of coverage in the states of Maine, Minnesota, in&nbsp;<s>New York</s>&nbsp;[New Mexico], and in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>What this means is that 235,000 women will now have access to 12 months of critical postpartum coverage across 14 states and D.C.&nbsp; This means that 12 months of pelvic exams, vaccinations, postpartum depression screening, and regular checkups will be available to those women.</p>



<p>And I think I said New Mexico and I cer- &#8212; I &#8212; New York &#8212; and I certainly meant New Mexico &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; so I&#8217;ll go back to that.&nbsp;<br><br>But what it also means is that the states now, under the leadership of extraordinary leaders &#8212; like Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham, under the leadership of Lieutenant Governor Peggy Flanagan &#8212; can take the step forward and do what we know the women of America need and deserve, which is to have assistance and to have some recognition about what the realities of this are and what their needs are.<br>This is only the beginning.&nbsp; Our administration will continue to fight until every state has expanded Medicaid coverage.&nbsp; And to be clear, this is about prioritizing the right all women in our nation should have to full reproductive healthcare.</p>



<p>That is what this is about.&nbsp; It is about understanding how all women in our nation, regardless of their income, regardless of where they live, should have access to full reproductive healthcare.</p>



<p>So, together, of course, we are going to continue to work with our partners at the state level, at the local level, our community-based and nonprofit folks to ensure that every woman, every mother has the healthcare she needs to thrive.</p>



<p>And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it back over to the team.&nbsp; And &#8212; and thank you all.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 10:15 A.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 1298, S. 66, and S.&#160;2201</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/16/bills-signed-h-r-1298-s-66-and-s-2201/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 15:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 1298, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1233 North Cedar Street in Owasso, Oklahoma, as the Technical Sergeant Marshal Roberts Post Office Building; Thank you to Representatives Hern and Mullin and Senators Lankford and Inhofe for their leadership.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 1298, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1233 North Cedar Street in Owasso, Oklahoma, as the Technical Sergeant Marshal Roberts Post Office Building;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Hern and Mullin and Senators Lankford and Inhofe for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 66, the &#8220;South Florida Clean Coastal Waters Act of 2021,&#8221; which requires the Inter-Agency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia to develop a plan for reducing, mitigating, and controlling harmful algal blooms and hypoxia in South Florida;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Rubio and Rick Scott and Representatives Mast, Soto, and Posey for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 2201, the &#8220;Supply Chain Security Training Act,&#8221; which requires the Administrator of General Services to develop a training program for officials with supply chain risk management responsibilities at Federal agencies.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Peters and Johnson, and Representative Neguse for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Establishment of the White&#160;House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and&#160;Abuse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/16/memorandum-on-the-establishment-of-the-white-house-task-force-to-address-online-harassment-and-abuse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 13:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES SUBJECT:       Establishment of the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to improve efforts to prevent and address online harassment and abuse,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Establishment of the White House Task Force to <br>                           Address Online Harassment and Abuse</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to improve efforts to prevent and address online harassment and abuse, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1.  Policy.  Technology platforms and social media can be vital tools for expression, civic participation, and building a sense of community.  But the scale, reach, and amplification effects of technology platforms have also exacerbated gender-based violence, particularly through online harassment and abuse.  Online harassment and abuse include a broad array of harmful and sometimes illegal behaviors that are perpetrated through the use of technology.  Women, adolescent girls, and LGBTQI+ individuals, who may be additionally targeted because of their race, ethnicity, religion, and other factors, can experience more severe harms from online harassment and abuse.  Online harassment and abuse take many forms, including the non-consensual distribution of intimate digital images; cyberstalking; sextortion; doxing; malicious deep fakes; gendered disinformation; rape and death threats; the online recruitment and exploitation of victims of sex trafficking; and various forms of technology-facilitated intimate partner abuse.  In the United States, 1 in 3 women under the age of 35 reports having been sexually harassed online, and over half of LGBTQI+ individuals report having been the target of severe online abuse, including sustained harassment, physical threats, and stalking in addition to sexual harassment.  Globally, half of girls report that they are more likely to be harassed through social media than on the street.</p>



<p>In the United States and around the world, women and LGBTQI+ political leaders, public figures, activists, and journalists are especially targeted by sexualized forms of online harassment and abuse, undermining their ability to exercise their human rights and participate in democracy, governance, and civic life.&nbsp;&nbsp;Online abuse and harassment, which aim to preclude women from political decision-making about their own lives and communities, undermine the functioning of democracy.&nbsp;&nbsp;Growing evidence also demonstrates that online radicalization can be linked to gender-based violence, which, along with other forms of abuse and harassment, spans the digital and physical realms.&nbsp;&nbsp;Online harassment and abuse can result in a range of dire consequences for victims, from psychological distress and self-censorship to economic losses, disruptions to education, increased self-harm, suicide, homicide, and other forms of physical and sexual violence.&nbsp;&nbsp;Further, digital technologies are often used in concert with other forms of abuse and harassment, underscoring the urgency of addressing the interplay of in-person and online harms.&nbsp;&nbsp;More research is needed to fully understand the nature, magnitude, and costs of these harms and ways to address them in the United&nbsp;States and globally.</p>



<p>Therefore, I am directing the Director of the White House Gender Policy Council and the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to lead an interagency effort to address online harassment and abuse, specifically focused on technology-facilitated gender-based violence, and to&nbsp;develop concrete recommendations to improve prevention, response, and protection efforts through programs and policies in the United States and globally.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;2.&nbsp;&nbsp;Establishment.&nbsp;&nbsp;There&nbsp;is established within the Executive Office of the President the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse (Task Force).</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;3.&nbsp;&nbsp;Membership.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;The&nbsp;Director of the White House Gender Policy Council and the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs,&nbsp;or their designees, shall serve as Co-Chairs of the Task Force.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;In addition to the Co-Chairs, the Task Force shall consist of the following members:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of State;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Defense;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Attorney General;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Commerce;</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</p>



<p>(vi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Education;</p>



<p>(vii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</p>



<p>(viii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Homeland Security;</p>



<p>(ix)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy;</p>



<p>(x)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Assistant to the President and Director of the Domestic Policy Council;</p>



<p>(xi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy and Director of the National Economic Council;</p>



<p>(xii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development;</p>



<p>(xiii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the Counsel to the President;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(xiv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Counsel to the Vice President; and</p>



<p>(xv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the heads of such other executive departments, agencies, and offices as the Co-Chairs may, from time to time, designate.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;A member of the Task Force may designate, to perform the Task Force functions of the member, senior officials within the member&#8217;s executive department, agency, or office who are full-time officers or employees of the Federal Government.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;4.&nbsp;&nbsp;Mission and Function.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;The Task Force shall work across executive departments, agencies, and offices to assess and address online harassment and abuse that constitute technology-facilitated gender-based violence, including by:&nbsp;</p>



<p>(i)    improving coordination among executive departments, agencies, and offices to maximize the Federal Government&#8217;s effectiveness in preventing and addressing technology-facilitated gender-based violence in the United States and globally, including by developing policy solutions to enhance accountability for those who perpetrate online harms;</p>



<p>(ii)   enhancing and expanding data collection and research across the Federal Government to measure the costs, prevalence, exposure to, and impact of technology-facilitated gender-based violence, including by studying the mental health effects of abuse on social media, particularly affecting adolescents; </p>



<p>(iii)  increasing access to survivor-centered services, information, and support for victims, and increasing training and technical assistance for Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments as well as for global organizations and entities in the fields of criminal justice, health and mental health services, education, and victim services;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;developing programs and policies to address&nbsp;online&nbsp;harassment, abuse, and disinformation campaigns targeting women and LGBTQI+ individuals who are public and political figures, government and civic leaders, activists, and journalists in the United States and globally;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp;&nbsp;examining existing Federal laws, regulations, and policies to evaluate the adequacy of the current legal framework to address technology-facilitated gender-based violence; and</p>



<p>(vi)    identifying additional opportunities to improve efforts to prevent and address technology-facilitated gender-based violence in United States foreign policy and foreign assistance, including through the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;Consistent with the objectives of this memorandum and applicable law, the Task Force may consult with and gather relevant information from external stakeholders, including&nbsp;Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial government officials, as well as victim advocates, survivors, law enforcement personnel, researchers and academics, civil and human rights groups, philanthropic leaders, technology experts, legal and international policy experts, industry stakeholders, and other entities and persons the Task Force identifies that will assist the Task Force in accomplishing the objectives of this memorandum.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;5.&nbsp;&nbsp;Reporting on the Work and Recommendations of the Task Force.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this memorandum, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall submit to the President a blueprint (Initial Blueprint) outlining a whole-of-government approach to preventing and addressing technology-facilitated gender-based violence, including concrete actions that executive departments, agencies, and offices have committed to take to implement the Task Force&#8217;s recommendations.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Initial Blueprint shall include a synopsis of key lessons from stakeholder consultations and preliminary recommendations for advancing strategies to improve efforts to prevent and address technology-facilitated gender-based violence.&nbsp;&nbsp;Following submission of the Initial Blueprint to the President, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall make an executive summary of the Initial Blueprint publicly available.</p>



<p>(b)  Within 1 year of the date that the Initial Blueprint is submitted to the President, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall submit to the President and make publicly available an update and report (1-Year Report) with additional recommendations and actions that executive departments, agencies, and offices can take to advance how Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments; service providers; international organizations; technology platforms; schools; and other public and private entities can improve efforts to prevent and address technology-facilitated gender-based violence.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;Prior to issuing its Initial Blueprint and 1-Year Report, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall consolidate&nbsp;any input received and&nbsp;submit periodic recommendations to the President on policies, regulatory actions, and legislation&nbsp;on technology sector accountability to address systemic harms to people affected by online harassment and abuse.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp;&nbsp;Following the submission of the 1-Year Report to the President, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall, on an annual basis, submit a follow-up report to the President on implementation of this memorandum.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;6.&nbsp;&nbsp;Definition.&nbsp;&nbsp;For the purposes of this memorandum, the term &#8220;technology-facilitated gender-based violence&#8221; shall refer to any form of gender-based violence, including harassment and abuse, which takes place through, or is aided by, the use of digital technologies and devices.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;7.&nbsp;&nbsp;General Provisions.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;This memorandum shall not apply to independent regulatory agencies as described in section 3502(5) of title 44, United States Code.&nbsp;&nbsp;Independent regulatory agencies are nevertheless strongly encouraged to participate in the work of the Task Force.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp;&nbsp;This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp;&nbsp;The Attorney General is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
