<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:26:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the situation in Hong Kong declared in Executive Order 13936 of July 14, 2020, is to continue in effect beyond July 14, 2021. <br><br>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat, which has its source in substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the situation in Hong Kong. <br>                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,<br><br>JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/07/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 14, 2020, by Executive Order 13936, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 etseq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&#160;States constituted by the situation with respect to Hong Kong. &#160;&#160; The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 14, 2020, by Executive Order 13936, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et</em><em>seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the situation with respect to Hong Kong. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States. &nbsp;For this reason, the national emergency declared on July 14, 2020, must continue in effect beyond July 14, 2021. &nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section&nbsp;202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the situation in Hong Kong.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.<br>                             </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>July 7, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden During a Tour of McHenry County College</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/07/remarks-by-president-biden-during-a-tour-of-mchenry-county-college/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 20:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[McHenry County CollegeCrystal Lake, Illinois 1:22 P.M. CDT Q Mr. President, Mitch McConnell says you&#8217;re in for a heck of a fight on this one. THE PRESIDENT: Mitch McConnell loves our programs. Did you see what Mitch McConnel said? He told me he wasn’t going to get a single vote in order to allow me&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">McHenry County College<br>Crystal Lake, Illinois</p>



<p>1:22 P.M. CDT</p>



<p>Q Mr. President, Mitch McConnell says you&#8217;re in for a heck of a fight on this one.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Mitch McConnell loves our programs. Did you see what Mitch McConnel said? He told me he wasn’t going to get a single vote in order to allow me to get, with the help of everybody here, that $1.9 trillion tax cut &#8212; I mean, excuse me, program to &#8212; for economic growth.</p>



<p>Look it up, man. He&#8217;s bragging about in Kentucky: “It&#8217;s a great thing for Kentucky. It&#8217;s getting $4 billion to help poor.” It&#8217;s amazing. Check out Mitch McConnell. You can even see it on TV.</p>



<p>Anyway, thanks. Thank you.</p>



<p>1:22 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki Aboard Air Force One En Route Crystal Lake, IL</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/07/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-crystal-lake-il/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 18:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Crystal Lake, Illinois 11:13 A.M. CDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Welcome to our trip to Crystal Lake, Illinois.&#160; In Crystal Lake, the President will make the case for generational investments in human infrastructure and other critical priorities like clean energy that form his Build Back Better agenda, a combination of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Crystal Lake, Illinois</p>



<p>11:13 A.M. CDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Welcome to our trip to Crystal Lake, Illinois.&nbsp; In Crystal Lake, the President will make the case for generational investments in human infrastructure and other critical priorities like clean energy that form his Build Back Better agenda, a combination of the American Families Plan, and policies from the American Jobs Plan that aren’t included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.</p>



<p>At McHenry County College, which has workforce development programs and a childcare center, the President will underline the specific game-changing impacts of the Buil- &#8212; his Build Back Better agenda.</p>



<p>He will argue that to build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out, we need to invest in our people by providing four additional years of public education to every student, increasing Pell Grants and investing in job training.</p>



<p>You’ll also hear him talk about the fact that, as a former single father, he will &#8212; he will stress that his plan is to help boost childcare affordability by building new childcare centers and ensuring that no middle-class family pays more than 7 percent of their income on high-quality care for children up to age five.</p>



<p>He will also note that the Build Back Better plan will invest in the childcaring workforce, provide parents with an up to $8,000 tax credit to cover their childcare expenses, institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, and extand [sic] &#8212; and extend the expanded Child Tax Credit from the Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>Finally, with over 10 million Americans currently paying over half of what they earn in rent, the President will cover how the Build Back Better agenda includes a historic investment in affordable housing &#8212; something I think you all haven’t heard him talk about that much yet &#8212; to address supply and building or rehabilitating more than 2 million homes.</p>



<p>One other item for all of you: Today we also announced three initiatives as part of the President’s forthcoming executive order, fulfilling his campaign promise to promote competition in labor markets in order to raise wages and make it easier for workers to change jobs and to move between states.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, roughly half of private sector businesses require at least some employees to enter non-compete agreements, affecting over 30 million people.&nbsp; This affects construction workers, hotel workers, many blue-collar jobs, not just high-level executives.&nbsp; He believes that if someone offers you a better job, you should be able to take it.&nbsp; It makes sense.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in keeping with his campaign promise, the executive order will call on the FTC to adopt rules that curtail non- compete agreements.&nbsp; His executive order will also call on the Federal Trade Commission to adopt rules that ban unnecessary occupational licensing requirements.&nbsp; Today, almost 30 percent of jobs in the U.S. require a license from attorneys and accountants to interior designers and hairdressers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While occupational licensing can serve important health and safety concerns, unnecessary or overly burdensome licensing can lock people out of jobs.&nbsp; This hugely affects military families in particular, over one third of whom work in a field requiring a license and who are subject to military-directed moves every year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, a little update for you on vaccine doses.&nbsp; Today we&#8217;re announcing we are sharing more doses with Latin America.&nbsp; One million Johnson &amp; Johnson doses will be headed to Bolivia on Thursday.&nbsp; One million doses of Pfizer will be sent to Paraguay.</p>



<p>Sorry, actual last thing: The Department of Education also released today nearly $6 billion in American Rescue Plan funds to six states and Washington, D.C., to support the safe reopening of K-through-12 schools.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lots going on.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of questions.&nbsp; Off the top, I know the midterms are a while away, but they come quicker than you expect, so can we talk politics a little bit, partly because the President has visited three top targeted congressional districts in the past week.&nbsp; Obviously, today is one of them.&nbsp; So, considering the party in power typically loses seats in a midterm, is part of the strategy right now to mitigate those potential losses?&nbsp; And does the White House see the President&#8217;s policies as swaying voters in the upcoming midterms?</p>



<p>Well, first, I would say that the President is visiting this district in Illinois today because Congresswoman &#8212; in part because Congresswoman Lauren Underwood has &#8212; is a registered nurse.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a champion for healthcare and expanding access to affordable healthcare.&nbsp; And that certainly is part of what&#8217;s under discussion and what is part of his Build Back Better agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will say that when the President put together his economic plans &#8212; his Build Back Better agenda, the American Rescue Plan, the American Jobs Plan, the American Families Plan &#8212; what he had in mind was governing for all Americans &#8212; Democrats, Republicans &#8212; and making clear that he was going to be the President for everyone, not just the people who voted for him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly the most effective role he can play as President, as Commander-in-Chief, and certainly as leader of the party, is to go out there and do what he does best, which is to be the “explainer-in-chief” and make &#8212; and lay out the specific plans and specific ways his plans, his proposals, and the agenda of the Democratic Party, but also his administration, are going to help people across the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on these cyberattacks, the RNC was just attacked by a likely Russian actor.&nbsp; And so, considering that reining in these cyberattacks was a central focus of the Putin summit, does the President still believe that that summit was a success considering we&#8217;ve seen two new Russia-linked cyberattacks in the last week?</p>



<p>And then, coming out of this interagency meeting that just happened, can you tell us a little bit more about what went on there and if there were any sort of clear retaliatory actions that the U.S. is considering in response to these attacks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; First, on the RNC report &#8212; because I think some of the reporting got a little ahead of where the administration is and where actual attribution is.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also note that the RNC put out a statement conveying this was a third-party vendor and that none of their data was accessed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we, of course, are investigating.&nbsp; The FBI, CISA are in touch with the RNC, and when &#8212; we will determine attribution and make a decision accordingly.</p>



<p>As it relates to the meeting that the President had earlier today, he met &#8212; the President and the Vice President, I should say, met this morning with our national security team as a part of an internal update briefing on our across-whole-of-government effort to address ransomware attacks.</p>



<p>Now, I would remind all of you that ransomware attacks are not new; they long predated this administration.&nbsp; What is new is this level of engagement at the &#8212; at a high level &#8212; at the highest level, ongoing high-level engagement from our national security officials with the Russian government, and expert-level talks about the cyber and ransomware attacks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in this meeting, they provided an update on their ongoing work: surge capacity, resilience and reporting, addressing payment systems, and our ongoing efforts to combat ransomware.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We don&#8217;t have anything new to report in terms of attribution, nor do we have anything to preview in terms of operational actions or considerations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we do continue &#8212; what we did &#8212; they did discuss is the fact that the President reserves the right to respond against any ransomware networks and those that harbor them.&nbsp; That continues to be his policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what did the President mean today when he said, at departure, that he would “deliver” this message to Putin?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the question was &#8212; I can&#8217;t remember what the context &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The question was, “What’s your message to Putin?”&nbsp; And he said, “I’ll deliver it to him.”</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think he wasn&#8217;t going to share with all of you what he just discussed in a private briefing.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the RNC asked the administration for assistance at all?&nbsp; Have you been in &#8212; has the administration &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The FBI and CISA have been in touch with the RNC, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I ask for an update on OPEC?&nbsp; Do you have any new details about outreach from the administration &#8212; who&#8217;s been doing that?&nbsp; Do you still feel encouraged, like you did yesterday, as the talks continue to drag out?&nbsp; And just a general kind of status check on how things are going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand your question.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any update from yesterday.&nbsp; Just to reiterate: While we&#8217;re not a party of OPEC, we are in touch with key participants in these discussions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re encouraged that they&#8217;re continuing, but we don&#8217;t have any update on the status.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Still don&#8217;t expect the President to get involved directly at any point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any expectation of that at this point, or prediction (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I go back to cyber just for one second?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned payment systems, and I know that you’re looking into whether &#8212; you know, how to approach this &#8212; how ransoms are paid, and whether they should be paid in that entire question.&nbsp; But given the role that cryptocurrencies are playing in that, is that an area that you&#8217;re looking into for further investigations?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, that’s a part of ransom payments.&nbsp; And I should just say that part of this is there&#8217;s been ongoing work led by Deputy National Security Advisor Anne Neuberger and others across the government to consider what has long been a range of issues as it relates to ransomware attacks.&nbsp; And certainly cryptocurrency, the role of cryptocurrency, the role of payment systems is a part of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Surge capacity &#8212; the importance of partnering but also encouraging the private sector to harden their own protections &#8212; that&#8217;s all part of it.&nbsp; And this was a internal, you know, somewhat standard update, but one with an across-the-government representation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on that.&nbsp; So, sanctions are one of the tools that you&#8217;ve used against Russia.&nbsp; You used them in response to election interference issues.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering, if this is something that we see happening with the RNC &#8212; another leg of Russia attempting to interfere in the political process here &#8212; do you still see sanctions as a viable tool for dealing with that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, on the RNC piece, I think it&#8217;s really important to asse- &#8212; to speak to where we are in this moment, which is the RNC has put out a statement conveying this was a third-party vendor.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve said none of their data was accessed.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not that at this point.&nbsp; We&#8217;re investigating.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll conclude the investigation and make an assessment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of operational considerations, obviously it&#8217;s not in our interest to preview those or preview our punches, as I like to say.&nbsp; The President has a range of options should he determine to take action.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Afghanistan: How is the U.S. going to continue its civilian &#8212; its civil and humanitarian support for the country if the Taliban continues its march?&nbsp; Is there a plan to work with the Taliban?&nbsp; Is there &#8212; how do you do it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, there are ongoing political negotia- &#8212;</p>



<p>(Turbulence on the plane.)</p>



<p>Ooh, okay.&nbsp; Oh, okay, let&#8217;s see how this happens here.&nbsp; Everyone is okay on the plane &#8212; happy to report &#8212; currently.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Alex has been teaching me.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve flown a little, but everyone seems fine.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Okay, sorry.&nbsp; To get back to your question: So, there are a number of efforts that will be underway; one are political negotiations.&nbsp; Certainly, the State Department would provide an update of when those will reconvene, but we certainly expect and hope and are supportive of the continuation of those political discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the reasons that the President made the decision he did is because he does not feel there&#8217;s a military solution for a 20-year war.&nbsp; Has &#8212; has long felt there was not a military solution.&nbsp; Diplomatic negotiations.</p>



<p>Two, as he reiterated when Afghan leaders were here just a couple of weeks ago, we will continue to provide, as you said, humanitarian assistance, security assistance.&nbsp; We intend to continue to have a diplomatic presence on the ground in Kabul, even after we bring the servicemen and women home at the end of August.&nbsp; So, that is a mechanism for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say, three, obviously, as you know, we&#8217;re going to continue to work with partners in the region to plan for our own CT preparations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On vaccination: Yesterday, you talked about door knocking, which is a pretty standard thing, and it was picked up in the far-right sphere as, you know, “the government is going to come to your door and make you get a vaccine.”&nbsp; I am wondering your reaction to that and what that type of messaging does for the efforts to, you know, convince people who might be hesitant to get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I appreciate the question.&nbsp; Well, let me tell you what this is and what it is not.&nbsp; What this effort is is a continuation of what we have seen as an impactful effort that we&#8217;ve had by local public health officials and volunteers in a range of communities over the last month of action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve actually seen an impact &#8212; a positive impact of a range of steps we’ve taken in states like Florida, Mississippi, others where there have been lower vaccination rates.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been actually an increase by over 4 percent in Florida, over the last month, of adults.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;re doing is local officials are going to areas where there are lower vaccination rates and providing information on where people can get access to a vaccine, where they can go, that it&#8217;s free, that they can take time off of work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s up to individuals to decide whether they want to get vaccinated or not.</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;ve seen as a barrier all along, for months, has been access and information, and so we’re going to continue to deploy the tactic &#8212; tactics that we&#8217;ve seen effective over the last few months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a lot of folks in the public health world have said that while they appreciate the voluntary nature, that you guys are &#8212; you know, what you just said, that it&#8217;s up to the individual to get vaccinated &#8212; they also think that the only way to get to, sort of, much larger numbers of vaccinated people is if there are mandates &#8212; whether those be mandates by private companies for their employees or universities or public schools or states that mandate for different kinds of, you know, healthcare workers or others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, when I asked you the question, you said you had no interest in the government &#8212; that the administration has no interest in encouraging that.&nbsp; I mean, is that really the position of the federal government, is that you do not want to encourage the kind of mandates that public health officials say would work?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, for clarity, that&#8217;s not currently the role of the federal government.&nbsp; And our role is to provide supply, provide information, provide public health experts.&nbsp; As &#8212; to your point, there are a number of private sector entities, universities, institutions that are starting to mandate, and that&#8217;s an innovative step that they will take and they should take.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not &#8212; and we&#8217;re not taking issue with that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But public health officials say that you guys are in a &#8212; and the President of the United States, with his bully pulpit and, you know, obviously taking not the kind of hands-off approach that Donald Trump took to federal (inaudible) &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say first &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; they want you to &#8212; they want you to be part of pushing these institutions to do that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But, Mike, I think the important thing to remind everyone of is that, one, we have reduced the rate of COVID by 90 percent.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve reduced the death rate by 90 percent.&nbsp; Almost 70 percent of the adult population is vaccinated, and we&#8217;re continuing to press further.</p>



<p><a>There are institutions, there are private sector entities that will take this step.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not standing in their way.&nbsp; Those are innovative steps.&nbsp; Go forward and take steps that you feel are appropriate.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just talking about what the steps are, what the role is of the federal government.</a></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You had said to me that you&#8217;re sort of trapped between &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) on the violence in Chicago?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration is sort of trapped between the people who are saying, “You need to do more; you need to mandate or you&#8217;re just not going to reach people,” and the people who are saying, “Oh, my God.&nbsp; The government is going to mandate this.”&nbsp; It seems like you&#8217;re kind of stuck in the middle.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; But I think what we continue to remember is what constructive role we can play as the federal government, and that includes continuing to use resources to get out into communities; to empower public health officials; to get accurate information out; to ensure people understand, as the CDC put out information earlier today or overnight, that 50 percent of the indivi- &#8212; of the cases are now, as a result of the Delta variant, higher in areas where there are lower vaccination rates.</p>



<p>That is the role where we&#8217;re going to spend our energy and our resources.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we get the White House reaction to the violence in Chicago &#8212; those three officers shot overnight, one of whom was an ATF agent?&nbsp; There&#8217;s an alderman in Chicago who is asking that the President come in the wake of what happened.&nbsp; He says, quote, “Our communities and police officers are under siege.”&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s message as we’re about to land there and he&#8217;s about to meet with the mayor of that city?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me first say that we are closely monitoring the situation in coordination with the Department of Justice and ATF.&nbsp; We stand ready to provide any assistance needed.&nbsp; Our thoughts go out to the two ATF agents and the Chicago Police Department officer who were wounded, as well as their families and fellow agents and officers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President has said many times, every time a law enforcement officer pins on their shield and walks out the door, they&#8217;re carrying a sacred responsibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will note that, in terms of the efforts the President has underway to address the rise in violence we&#8217;ve seen over the last 18 months, including in Chicago, there are a number of steps that impact Chicago directly and specifically, including &#8212; his Rescue Plan is giving cities like Chicago &#8212; alone is getting almost $1.9 billion through the Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Cook County is getting over $1 billion.&nbsp; And the state government of Illinois is receiving an additional $8.13 billion.</p>



<p>As a part of our gun crime reduction strategy, Chicago is also taking part in a community violence intervention collaborative with 15 jurisdictions nationwide to help them invest in proven evidence-based, community-based strategies.</p>



<p>And Chicago is also one of the five cities we announced recently that&#8217;s going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be working with &#8212; the Department of Justice is going to be working with in launching a gun trafficking strike force &#8212; there&#8217;s four other cities, I should say, nationwide &#8212; to help interrupt gun trafficking corridors that send crime into Chicago from across the city and state lines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he visit?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Will he visit &#8212; our plans today have not changed in terms of our travel plans.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President spoken to Governor Pritzker or Mayor Lightfoot this week, following the extremely violent weekends?&nbsp; Has he &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to see both of them today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the bipartisan infrastructure plan &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; we still haven&#8217;t seen congressional scoring or legislative language, especially on the payfors.&nbsp; Is that a signal that, you know, they’re still in that, kind of, “coffee, late-night” area that you discussed before?&nbsp; Or might we a- &#8212; the alternate solution is that there&#8217;s been a problem with the scoring and it doesn&#8217;t quite add up?&nbsp; Is there a possibility that the payfors change in any way at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the order of events here, as I think you&#8217;re alluding to, is they need to write the legislation first, which they&#8217;re working on over the coming days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One on Haiti.&nbsp; I believe that you sent out a tweet &#8212; and I don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s happened in the past hour and a half, but I believe the U.S. Embassy in Haiti has not tweeted any form of tweet about what happened, and a lot of the Western embassies have.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m just checking to see if there&#8217;s any sort of, like, friction or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we put out a statement from the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the U.S. Embassy in Haiti should be putting out &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would ask the State Department that question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s an issue.&nbsp; We put out a statement from the President on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re about to land.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the U.S. been asked to help in Haiti?&nbsp; I mean, I know that you guys are providing whatever &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We stand prepared to assist.&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly in touch, but obviously this is &#8212; this is still developing, and so we&#8217;ll assess what their needs are.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re ready to provide needs &#8212;&nbsp;you know, respond to the needs they ask for.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:31 A.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the Visit of His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-visit-of-his-majesty-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 18:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23395</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President and the First Lady look forward to welcoming His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan, Her Majesty Queen Rania, and His Royal Highness Crown Prince Hussein to the White House on July 19, 2021. His Majesty’s visit will highlight the enduring and strategic partnership between the United States and Jordan, a key security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President and the First Lady look forward to welcoming His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan, Her Majesty Queen Rania, and His Royal Highness Crown Prince Hussein to the White House on July 19, 2021. His Majesty’s visit will highlight the enduring and strategic partnership between the United States and Jordan, a key security partner and ally of the United States. It will be an opportunity to discuss the many challenges facing the Middle East and showcase Jordan’s leadership role in promoting peace and stability in the region. President Biden looks forward to working with His Majesty to strengthen bilateral cooperation on multiple political, security, and economic issues, including the promotion of economic opportunities that will be vital for a bright future in Jordan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Marine One Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/07/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The South Lawn 10:46 A.M. EDT Q What&#8217;s your reaction, Mr. President, to the Haitian President being assassinated? THE PRESIDENT: We need a lot more information, but it’s just &#8212; it’s very worrisome about the state of Haiti. Q Does the U.S. have a role in seeking justice here? Q Mr. President, these cyberattacks keep&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The South Lawn</p>



<p>10:46 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q What&#8217;s your reaction, Mr. President, to the Haitian President being assassinated?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: We need a lot more information, but it’s just &#8212; it’s very worrisome about the state of Haiti.</p>



<p>Q Does the U.S. have a role in seeking justice here?</p>



<p>Q Mr. President, these cyberattacks keep happening. At what point does the United States respond and take action?</p>



<p>Q What&#8217;s your message to Putin on cyber? Any message after your briefing on cyber from your officials?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I will deliver it to him.</p>



<p>10:47 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the Assassination of President Jovenel Moïse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-assassination-of-president-jovenel-moise/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are shocked and saddened to hear of the horrific assassination of President Jovenel Moïse and the attack on First Lady Martine Moïse of Haiti.&#160; We condemn this heinous act, and I am sending my sincere wishes for First Lady Moïse’s recovery. The United States offers condolences to the people of Haiti, and we stand&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We are shocked and saddened to hear of the horrific assassination of President Jovenel Moïse and the attack on First Lady Martine Moïse of Haiti.&nbsp; We condemn this heinous act, and I am sending my sincere wishes for First Lady Moïse’s recovery. The United States offers condolences to the people of Haiti, and we stand ready to assist as we continue to work for a safe and secure Haiti.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Meeting with Youth Voting Groups</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-youth-voting-groups/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 11:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23369</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Public Engagement Director and Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond marked the 50th Anniversary of the ratification of the 26th Amendment, which effectively lowered the national voting age to 18, by meeting with the leadership of non-partisan groups who are focused on youth voting access and civic participation.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Public Engagement Director and Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond marked the 50<sup>th</sup> Anniversary of the ratification of the 26<sup>th</sup> Amendment, which effectively lowered the national voting age to 18, by meeting with the leadership of non-partisan groups who are focused on youth voting access and civic participation. During the meeting, senior White House officials expressed their gratitude for the work the groups are doing and reiterated the President’s strong commitment to protecting the sacred right to vote.</p>



<p>The advocates shared updates on their work in states across the country to increase civic participation, including both fighting back against laws that suppress voter turnout as well as advocating for federal and state laws that expand access to the ballot box by making voter registration and casting a ballot more streamlined. They also shared recommendations for how the Administration can do more to advance youth voting rights, including through the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/07/executive-order-on-promoting-access-to-voting/">Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting</a>.</p>



<p>Meeting participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Mike Burns, Campus Vote Project</li><li>Mia Charity, Close Up Foundation</li><li>Wisdom Cole, NAACP Youth &amp; College Division</li><li>Bella D’Alacio, March for Our Lives</li><li>Mike Dean, LeadMN</li><li>Morgan Stahr, Blue Future</li><li>Alex Harris, Andrew Goodman Foundation</li><li>Mary-Pat Hector, Rise</li><li>Nicole Hensel, New Era Colorado</li><li>Jazmin Kay, 18by.vote</li><li>Abby Kiesa, CIRCLE</li><li>Eve Leveson, YouthinGov</li><li>Edwith Theogene, Generation Progress</li><li>Clarissa Unger, Students Learn Students Vote Coalition</li><li>Griffin Sinclair-Wingate, New Hampshire Youth Movement</li><li>Joey Wozniak, Vote Early Day</li><li>Dan Xie, StudentPIRG</li><li>Claudia Yoli Ferla, MOVE Texas</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology Anne Neuberger’s Meeting with Bipartisan U.S. Conference of Mayors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/06/readout-of-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-cyber-and-emerging-technology-anne-neubergers-meeting-with-bipartisan-u-s-conference-of-mayors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 01:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, as part of ongoing engagement with stakeholders across the country, Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology Anne Neuberger met virtually with the bipartisan U.S. Conference of Mayors to speak to the cybersecurity challenges facing cities and towns across the nation, including the threat from ransomware. Neuberger described the Administration’s ransomware strategy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, as part of ongoing engagement with stakeholders across the country, Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology Anne Neuberger met virtually with the bipartisan U.S. Conference of Mayors to speak to the cybersecurity challenges facing cities and towns across the nation, including the threat from ransomware. Neuberger described the Administration’s ransomware strategy which includes several lines of effort: disruption of ransomware infrastructure and actors by working closely with the private sector; international cooperation to hold countries who harbor ransom actors accountable; expanding cryptocurrency analysis to find and pursue criminal transactions; and the federal government’s review to build a cohesive and consistent approach towards ransom payments.<br><br>Participants also discussed how mayors and the Administration can work together to prevent and respond to cyber threats against cities and towns, and how to best posture communities across the country to reduce the likelihood of cyber incidents. Neuberger reinforced the Administration’s commitment to ensure state and local governments have the full resources of the federal government when responding to a cyber incident, including the assistance of cybersecurity professionals from the FBI and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA). Neuberger listened to the mayors on the cyber challenges they are facing, and briefed them on measures they can immediately take to help bolster cyber defenses.<br><br>Neuberger outlined the measures the Biden Administration has already taken to modernize cyber defenses, including the recent “Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity” Executive Order (E.O.) and the Administration’s ongoing efforts to partner with the public and private sectors to strengthen cyber defenses including for critical infrastructure. She spoke about the recent public-private Cybersecurity Industrial Control Systems Initiative and its pilot program to strengthen cyber resilience in the electric sector, noting the electric sector pilot will soon be followed by similar initiatives to strengthen the cyber resilience of other critical sectors like pipelines, water, and chemicals. In a reference to her open letter to the private sector, Neuberger reiterated the need for private and public sector partnership to effectively guard against ransomware, and urged mayors to immediately convene heads of state agencies to review their cybersecurity posture and continuity plans. <br><br>The threat of ransomware is a national security and economic security priority for the Administration. Tomorrow the President will convene key leaders across the interagency to discuss ransomware and strategic efforts to counter it.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/06/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-saudi-vice-minister-of-defense-khalid-bin-salman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud to discuss the longstanding partnership between the United States and Saudi Arabia, regional security, and the U.S. commitment to help Saudi Arabia defend its territory as it faces attacks from Iranian-aligned groups. They also&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud to discuss the longstanding partnership between the United States and Saudi Arabia, regional security, and the U.S. commitment to help Saudi Arabia defend its territory as it faces attacks from Iranian-aligned groups. They also discussed the importance of coordinating efforts to ensure a strong global economic recovery, to advance the climate agenda, and to de-escalate tensions in the Middle East. Mr. Sullivan emphasized the importance of progress in advancing human rights in the Kingdom. They agreed to stay in touch regularly over the coming months on these and other issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
