<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:41:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Donate Life Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-national-donate-life-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, more than 100,000 men, women, and children in the United States need a life-saving organ transplant.  In many cases, an organ donation provides another chance to live a full life.  For those waiting for that gift of life &#8212; the uncertainty can be excruciating, exacting a physical and emotional toll on the potential recipient and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, more than 100,000 men, women, and children in the United States need a life-saving organ transplant.  In many cases, an organ donation provides another chance to live a full life.  For those waiting for that gift of life &#8212; the uncertainty can be excruciating, exacting a physical and emotional toll on the potential recipient and their loved ones.  During National Donate Life Month, we give thanks to the families and friends of donors who have supported their loved one&#8217;s decision to save lives by donating; we show our appreciation for the professionals who serve the transplantation community; and we encourage Americans who can to become organ, eye, tissue, marrow, and blood donors.  In so doing, we honor those who have given this most extraordinary of gifts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, because of the charity and generosity of the American people, our Nation&#8217;s transplant experts performed more than 41,000 organ transplants &#8212; a record number. &nbsp;We saw organ donations from deceased donors set an annual record for the 11th consecutive year. &nbsp;Living donor transplants, which decreased significantly in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic, increased with over 6,500 living donor transplants performed.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Despite our progress, our Nation continues to face a critical shortage of organ donors, and the number of people in need of a transplant is high, with 17 people dying every day while waiting for a transplant.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s transplant waitlist also includes more than 1,900 children under the age of 18 awaiting the gift of life.&nbsp; That is why during National Donate Life Month, we also recognize National Pediatric Transplant Week&nbsp;from April 24-30, a period dedicated to ending the pediatric transplant waiting list.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Waitlist data shows that people of color make up nearly 60&nbsp;percent of individuals awaiting an organ transplant. &nbsp;To increase access to transplantation for everyone, we recommit to promoting greater diversity in organ donation, as we continue to advance health equity for all communities, including those that have gone underserved, across our Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every year, nearly 18,000 people in America are diagnosed with life-threatening blood cancers or other diseases for which a blood stem cell transplant may be their best or only hope for a cure.&nbsp; Approximately 70 percent of these individuals need donors from outside their families. &nbsp;Although nearly 23 million adults in the United States are currently registered as blood stem cell donors, we need more registrants to help the many individuals who still have difficulty finding a suitably matched donor.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During National Donate Life Month, we thank the millions of&nbsp;individuals across America who are living or registered organ donors.&nbsp; We recognize and commend the researchers, advocates, volunteers, and medical professionals working to reduce the number of people awaiting vital organ transplants.&nbsp; Our Nation applauds the therapeutic innovations that have decreased rates of organ rejection and have extended the lifespan of transplanted organs.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; While transplantation continues to increase substantially and meet the needs of many people with organ failure, we must continue our efforts to shorten the waiting list and encourage organ donation. &nbsp;If you have not signed up as an organ donor, we&nbsp;can use your help.&nbsp; I encourage every American to help people in&nbsp;need by visiting <a href="https://www.organdonor.gov/sign-up">organdonor.gov</a> for organ, eye, and tissue donation, and <a href="https://bloodstemcell.hrsa.gov/">bloodstemcell.hrsa.gov</a> for marrow and blood donation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the&nbsp;United States of America, by the authority vested in me by the&nbsp;Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Donate Life Month.&nbsp; I call upon every person who can to share the gift of life and hope by becoming organ, eye, tissue, marrow, and blood donors.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this</p>



<p>thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the Month Of The Military Child,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-the-month-of-the-military-child-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each April, the Month of the Military Child provides a chance for us to recognize and thank the children of our service members and veterans. &#160;I have always believed that America has a sacred obligation to prepare our troops when we send them into harm&#8217;s way and to support them and their families both while&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Each April, the Month of the Military Child provides a chance for us to recognize and thank the children of our service members and veterans. &nbsp;I have always believed that America has a sacred obligation to prepare our troops when we send them into harm&#8217;s way and to support them and their families both while they are deployed and after they return home.&nbsp; The First Lady and I recognize that it is not only those who wear the uniform that serve our country &#8212; it is also their loved ones, and especially their children.&nbsp; In the timeless words of the poet John Milton, &#8220;They also serve who only stand and wait.&#8221;<br><br>Military-connected children shoulder the burdens of service, facing unique challenges from a young age. &nbsp;They move frequently with their families &#8212; leaving friends, schools, and communities behind. &nbsp;They say goodbye to deploying family members, not knowing when they will see them again.&nbsp; Some of these young people endure deployments and separations, spending months or even years away from their beloved parent. &nbsp;Birthdays, holidays, graduations, and other important milestones are celebrated with just a phone call or virtual hug. &nbsp;The First Lady and I witnessed these sacrifices firsthand, when our grandchildren experienced their father&#8217;s deployment to Iraq.<br><br>Even after their parent has left the military, children can continue to face challenges as their parent transitions to civilian life and they may be called on to care for wounds or injuries their parent suffered during their service. &nbsp;Too many live with the pain and loss of a parent or family member who made the ultimate sacrifice in service to our country.<br><br>This month &#8212; and every month &#8212; we share our gratitude for these children. &nbsp;We recognize the hardships they face and commit to supporting the physical, social, and emotional health and safety of their families. &nbsp;That is why the White House&#8217;s Joining Forces initiative, guided by the First Lady, is focused on supporting the military and veteran families, caregivers, and survivors. &nbsp;<br><br>As a symbol of our support and gratitude to our military children, during the Month of the Military Child, the Department of Defense uses the color purple &#8212; representing all services in the military community. &nbsp;I encourage Americans everywhere to find ways to support our military-connected children, including by wearing purple to honor their service.&nbsp; Let us recommit ourselves to our sacred obligation to provide our military children and their families with the full support of our communities and our Government.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as the Month of the Military Child. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to honor military children with appropriate ceremonies and activities.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Finding of a Severe Energy Supply&#160;Interruption</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/memorandum-on-finding-of-a-severe-energy-supply-interruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT:        Finding of a Severe Energy Supply Interruption The Russian Federation&#8217;s unjustified, unprovoked, and unconscionable war against Ukraine, including its further invasion in violation of international law and its ongoing destructive military campaign across Ukraine, has had a profound impact on global oil markets.  On March 1, 2022, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY<br> <br>SUBJECT:        Finding of a Severe Energy Supply Interruption</p>



<p>The Russian Federation&#8217;s unjustified, unprovoked, and unconscionable war against Ukraine, including its further invasion in violation of international law and its ongoing destructive military campaign across Ukraine, has had a profound impact on global oil markets.  On March 1, 2022, the International Energy Agency Governing Board agreed to a collective release of petroleum reserves and the United States committed to a drawdown and sale of 30 million barrels from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.  Since that time, the Russian Federation has escalated its attacks across broad swaths of Ukrainian territory and has devastated the civilian population.  The United States and its allies have imposed sanctions on the Russian Federation&#8217;s economy and financial system.  Public recognition of the gravity of the Russian Federation&#8217;s actions has precipitated a significant reduction in international economic engagement with Russian businesses, including with respect to transactions not currently subject to sanctions.<br><br>Based on information from and advice of the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) and on other information, I find and determine, in accordance with section 161(d) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA), 42 U.S.C. 6241(d), that a drawdown and sale of petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) is required by a severe energy supply interruption, as defined in 42 U.S.C. 6202(8), on the basis that there is a national energy supply shortage that:<br><br>     (A)  is, or is likely to be, of significant scope and duration, and of an emergency nature;<br><br>     (B)  may cause major adverse impact on national safety or the national economy; and<br><br>     (C)  results, or is likely to result, from an interruption in the supply of imported petroleum products.<br><br>For these reasons, the Secretary is authorized and directed to draw down and sell petroleum from the SPR at public sale to the highest qualified bidder at a rate the Secretary may determine, in accordance with section 161 of EPCA and the SPR competitive sales procedures in 10 CFR Part 625.  If the Secretary determines the circumstances leading to this finding no longer support initiation or continuation of a drawdown and sale of petroleum from the SPR, the Secretary is authorized to cancel in whole or in part any offer to sell petroleum as a part of any drawdown and sale pursuant to this finding. <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as&#160;amended.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/memorandum-on-presidential-determination-pursuant-to-section-303-of-the-defense-production-act-of-1950-as-amended/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential DeterminationNo.        2022-11 MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SUBJECT:       Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right">Presidential Determination<br>No.        2022-11</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE<br><br>SUBJECT:       Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended<br><br>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the &#8220;Act&#8221;) (50 U.S.C. 4533), it is hereby ordered:<br><br>Section 1.  Policy.  It is the policy of my Administration that ensuring a robust, resilient, sustainable, and environmentally responsible domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy, such as the production of large-capacity batteries, is essential to our national security and the development and preservation of domestic critical infrastructure.<br><br>The United States depends on unreliable foreign sources for many of the strategic and critical materials necessary for the clean energy transition &#8212; such as lithium, nickel, cobalt, graphite, and manganese for large-capacity batteries.  Demand for such materials is projected to increase exponentially as the world transitions to a clean energy economy.<br><br>To promote the national defense, the United States must secure a reliable and sustainable supply of such strategic and critical materials.  The United States shall, to the extent consistent with the promotion of the national defense, secure the supply of such materials through environmentally responsible domestic mining and processing; recycling and reuse; and recovery from unconventional and secondary sources, such as mine waste.</p>



<p>These actions shall be conducted, to the extent consistent with the promotion of the national defense and applicable law, with strong environmental, sustainability, safety, labor, Tribal consultation, and impacted community engagement standards, to rebuild and maintain American expertise and productive capacity in these critical sectors.<br><br>Sec. 2.  Determination.  (a)  I hereby determine, pursuant to section 303(a)(5) of the Act, that:<br><br>          (1)  sustainable and responsible domestic mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing of strategic and critical materials for the production of large-capacity batteries for the automotive, e-mobility, and stationary storage sectors are essential to the national defense;<br><br>          (2)  without Presidential action under section 303 of the Act, United States industry cannot reasonably be expected to provide the capability for these needed industrial resources, materials, or critical technology items in a timely manner; and<br><br>          (3)  purchases, purchase commitments, or other action pursuant to section 303 of the Act are the most cost-effective, expedient, and practical alternative method for meeting the need.<br><br>     (b)  Consistent with section 303(a)(1) of the Act, the Secretary of Defense shall create, maintain, protect, expand, or restore sustainable and responsible domestic production capabilities of such strategic and critical materials by supporting feasibility studies for mature mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing projects; by-product and co-product production at existing mining, mine waste reclamation, and other industrial facilities; mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing modernization to increase productivity, environmental sustainability, and workforce safety; and any other such activities authorized under section 303(a)(1) of the Act.<br><br>     (c)  In the execution of projects to create, maintain, protect, expand, or restore sustainable and responsible domestic production capabilities of such strategic and critical materials consistent with section 303(a)(1) of the Act, the Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, and the heads of other executive departments and agencies (agencies) as appropriate.<br><br>     (d)  Further, pursuant to section 303(a)(7)(B) of the Act, I find that action to expand the domestic production capabilities for such strategic and critical materials is necessary to avert an industrial resource or critical technology item shortfall that would severely impair the national defense capability.  Therefore, I waive the requirements of section 303(a)(1)–(a)(6) of the Act for the purpose of expanding the sustainable and responsible domestic mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing of strategic and critical materials necessary for the production of large-capacity batteries for the automotive, e-mobility, and stationary storage sectors.<br><br>Sec. 3.  Annual Report to the President and the Congress by the Secretary of Defense.  (a)  The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the heads of other agencies as appropriate, shall conduct a survey of the domestic industrial base for the mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing of strategic and critical materials for the production of large-capacity batteries for the automotive, e-mobility, and stationary storage sectors.  Such survey shall assess whether conditions continue to warrant the use of the authority under section 303 of the Act.<br><br>     (b)  Consistent with the designation under section 309 of Executive Order 13603 of March 16, 2012 (National Defense Resources Preparedness), the Secretary of Defense shall include the survey stated in section 3(a) of this determination in the annual report to the Congress required by section 304(f) of the Act, and also shall submit such report to the President.<br><br>Sec. 4.  Limitations.  Nothing in this determination shall be construed to waive or supersede the requirement for mines or other industrial facilities to comply with all Federal and State permitting requirements and environmental health and safety laws.<br><br>Sec. 5.  General Provisions.  (a)  Nothing in this determination shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br><br>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br><br>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br><br>     (b)  This determination shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br><br>     (c)  This determination is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.<br><br>     (d)  You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Plan to Respond to Putin&#8217;s Price Hike at the&#160;Pump</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/31/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-president-bidens-plan-to-respond-to-putins-price-hike-at-the-pump/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:51 A.M. EDT MS. SIMONS:&#160; Thank you so much for joining this call.&#160; As a reminder, this call is on background as “senior administration officials” and is not under embargo. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; On this call, our senior administration officials will provide an overview on President Biden’s plan to respond to Putin’s price hike at&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:51 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Thank you so much for joining this call.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call is on background as “senior administration officials” and is not under embargo.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this call, our senior administration officials will provide an overview on President Biden’s plan to respond to Putin’s price hike at the pump.&nbsp; We will take some questions at the end.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not for reporting but for your awareness, the speakers on the call today are [senior administration official], [senior administration official], and [senior administration official].<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With that, I will now turn it over to [senior administration official].<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks so much for everyone joining.&nbsp; The President will be speaking this afternoon on the effect of Putin’s price hike on gas prices for American families.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Prices at the pump right now are up almost $1 since Vladimir Putin accelerated his military buildup in January.&nbsp; That’s because Russian oil now is coming off the market.&nbsp; The United States banned the import of Russian oil, which Republicans and Democrats in Congress called for and supported.&nbsp; It was the right thing to do.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as the United States and others aren’t buying Russian oil, supply is dropping and the price has increased.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has said from the start that standing up to Putin’s aggression would never be painless, but he is committed to doing everything he can to help American families.&nbsp; That’s why today he is announcing a two-part plan to bring American families relief.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Part one involves immediately increasing the supply of oil as a wartime bridge to greater domestic production.&nbsp; Part two is charting a path towards real American energy independence by accelerating the clean energy transition so that we are no longer reliant on foreign oil.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Starting with part one, which is about immediately increasing supply: The fact is that there is nothing standing in the way of domestic oil production, which is expected to increase by a million barrels a day this year alone.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; U.S. oil companies are recording their largest profits in years and can put those profits toward productive use.&nbsp; While some companies have already announced they are increasing immediate production, too many are choosing right now to make extraordinary profits without investing in more supply.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why, today, the President is proposing a “use it or lose it” policy to incentivize companies to produce more in the short term with the resources they already have.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right now, the oil and gas industry is sitting on more than 9,000 unused but approved permits for production on federal lands and more than 12 million unused acres.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Congress should make companies pay fees on unused wells on federal lands and on acres of public land that they are sitting on without producing.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, the industry has indicated that they can get online an additional million barrels per day this year, as I said.&nbsp; That is something that we need, that they should be doing.&nbsp; But we know it will take months, not days, for that production to come online, including through the kinds of measures the President is laying out today to encourage additional production.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We need a bridge to that additional supply.&nbsp; That’s why the President is announcing a historic release of a million barrels a day for the next six months from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That release will immediately shore up global supplies.&nbsp; These barrels will be a wartime bridge to additional U.S. production and other production that we expect later this year.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Importantly, from rev- &#8212; with revenues from that sale, we’ll restock the reserve when prices are lower.&nbsp; And the Department of Energy already has that authority.&nbsp; That can also incentivize the additional production we need this year, knowing that those purchases will occur in the future at a lower price when we’re through this emergency.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This release is being coordinated with allies and partners around the world.&nbsp; Together, our combined efforts will supply well over 1 million barrels per day to the market.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This will be the largest release from reserves over time that has been done, so it is a historic release.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; These actions will increase our immediate supply and help us meet the immediate emergency and address the lack of supply as a result of Putin’s actions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The second part of President Biden’s plan is to declare real American energy independence for the long term so that Americans aren’t subject to the kind of volatility in the oil market and at the pump that we now see due to Putin’s actions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ll now turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk more about that.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everybody.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, President Biden knows that the path to real American energy independence depends on reducing our reliance on foreign oil and on fossil fuels, and that the path to that energy security runs through clean energy.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why President Biden is calling on Congress to pass his landmark plan to speed the transition to a cleaner energy future made here in the United States of America.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Implementing the President’s climate plans would save Americans more than $900 a year in gasoline from the adoption of electric and hydrogen vehicles.&nbsp; It would save Americans $500 a year by increasing the use of clean electricity to power homes, not only on the grid but in the household as well &#8212; technologies like heat pumps and solar and storage.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And altogether, this would create millions of good-paying union jobs &#8212; jobs that cannot be outsourced.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Together, these actions would move us towards freeing ourselves from dependence on fossil fuels and, certainly, on sourcing outside of North America.</p>



<p>And President Biden, of course, is not waiting on Congress to take action, and this week alone is illustrative of that push to achieve real American energy independence.</p>



<p>One example of that, that he will announce today, is taking the next step in using the Defense Production Act by issuing an authorization for use of the DPA to secure American supplies of the critical materials needed to boost our clean energy economy.&nbsp; That is specifically focused on the procurement of the tools needed to build batteries here in the United States &#8212; batteries that will go into electric vehicles, batteries that will help us support a cleaner electricity grid.&nbsp; And all of this to be done in a way that respects and really sets the best &#8212; the highest standards on labor, on environment, on engagement with communities, and with Tribal Nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, he will make $3.2 billion available to states, Tribes, and territories for the weatherization of homes through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; That&#8217;s 10x the amount of historic funding levels that will help electrify and make efficient homes all around the country.</p>



<p>The third is advancing a set of strong energy efficiency standards designed to lower consumer and small-business costs.&nbsp; These are the appliance efficiency and equipment efficiency standards set by the Department of Energy.&nbsp; The President will talk about the 100 actions that his administration will take by the end of this year that will save families $100 annually through more efficiency in these appliances and equipment.</p>



<p>And finally, he will talk about the upcoming finalization of new fuel economy standards for cars and trucks that will save drivers money at the pump through more efficient vehicles &#8212; combining more production here at home in the short run to meet the emergency situation that [senior administration official] described, with a strategy that drives a reduced dependence on fossil fuels and an increased production of homemade clean energy means more energy security.&nbsp; That is what real American energy independence is all about, and that&#8217;s the plan the President will speak to today.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you so much, [senior administration officials].&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ll now take some questions.&nbsp; If you can use the “raise hand” feature, we&#8217;ll try and get to as many of you as we can in our allotted time.</p>



<p>The first question will go to Justin Sink at Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, can you hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; So, I have two quick questions.&nbsp; The first was how you guys were planning to deal with the Jones Act to move this amount of product.&nbsp; And the second was if you had any more details on the partner release of strategic oil that would be part of this.&nbsp; Is it coordinated through the IEA?&nbsp; Do you have a sense of how much and how soon we would see those sort of additional releases from partners?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll take that &#8212; the first question and then turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>When it comes to the Jones Act, the administration is obviously releasing a historic amount of oil through this action by the President &#8212; over the next six months, a million barrels a day.&nbsp; We are also committed to fully complying with the Jones Act and the President&#8217;s Made in America commitment.</p>



<p>A sizable portion of the release of a million barrels a day will be carried by pipeline.&nbsp; In fact, in the most recent reserve drawdown, the vast majority of the sales, 85 percent, were delivered via pipeline, while 15 percent have been slated for shipment by sea.</p>



<p>However, shipping is likely to also be needed to transport oil to parts of the country not serviced by pipelines.&nbsp; Based upon the support offered by American carriers and labor unions, we expect the Jones Act-qualified vessels will be available to meet those needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, given the historic volumes we plan to release, it is also possible that Jones Act-qualified vessels may not always be available to carry additional shipments in a timely manner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When that is the case, the administration stands ready to promptly process Jones Act waiver requests to ensure orderly and timely delivery of oil.&nbsp; Several agencies have already coordinated to make this process work smoothly.&nbsp; We will be receiving requests seven days a week, and we will work to process any waiver requests quickly with the goal of providing a response within two days.</p>



<p>On your second question, I&#8217;ll now turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; I really appreciate the question.&nbsp; Regarding working with partners and allies, this is an effort and a cadence we&#8217;ve been doing for the last several weeks and months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just most recently, the President was in Europe, where he talked about the importance of energy supply with his G7 counterparts.&nbsp; And earlier this week, we gave a readout of the call he had with the Quint, where he again &#8212; once again, they discussed the importance of ensuring energy supply in the markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, regarding the collective action and actions taken with other countries, as you all know, the United States has a much larger reserve than other countries.&nbsp; And the President has said he would not hesitate to act to protect Americans from Putin&#8217;s price hike.</p>



<p>I will not speak to what other countries will do, but I will note that tomorrow there is a meeting of the International Energy Agency to further discuss collaborative efforts to address energy markets and supply, and we will not prejudge those outcomes.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Next question will go to Weijia Jiang from CBS News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, and thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; To better understand how this latest release is going to bring down gas prices, can you share what the deficit is in the global market supply of oil since the U.S. and other nations sanctioned Russian oil?&nbsp; In other words, every day, how many millions of oil &#8212; barrels of oil have been removed from the market supply?</p>



<p>And then, just more basically, you know, once this release is triggered, how quickly could that actually have an impact on U.S. gas prices?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, to take your question &#8212; so, thanks for the questions.</p>



<p>First, when it comes to the effect on global supply, what we know is that there is reduced global supply right now.&nbsp; Obviously, outside analysts have given us sort of a range of estimates of the reduction in supply.&nbsp; We know, for instance, that, you know, across points of last year, the United States was importing 700,000 barrels per day of crude and petroleum product from Russia; we obviously have now banned those imports.</p>



<p>What we know is that there is a lack of supply and that the kind of action that the President is taking today, this historic action &#8212; the million barrels per day that will be released from the reserve over the next six months as we see a ramp-up in U.S. production and production elsewhere &#8212; will be very important in helping to address that lack of supply.</p>



<p>When it comes to, you know, how quickly will this translate into relief: You know, obviously, we&#8217;ve seen, even overnight, markets responding to the initial news of a reserve release &#8212; where we&#8217;ve seen, you know, with a reduction in the oil price.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re not focused right now on sort of the immediate, short-term price movements.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re focused on is a real challenge we have.&nbsp; You know, looking ahead with Russian supply coming off the market, we want to address that lack of supply.&nbsp; We know and believe that that will then translate into helping to provide relief to American consumers.&nbsp; We think that this historic release from the reserve will be an important step in that direction, will have meaningful effects.&nbsp; And then, in combination with actions by other countries taken around the world, it will mean we will have well in excess of a million barrels per day being released from reserves around the world in response.</p>



<p>MR. SIMONS:&nbsp; Next, we&#8217;ll go to Jeremy Diamond.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks very much for doing this.&nbsp; Just to follow up on Weijia’s question, you just said that you think this release will be an important step in the direction of helping to reduce gas prices.&nbsp; But do you not have an estimate of how quickly that will happen or by how much Americans can expect to see their gas prices reduced, say in three months from now or six months from now?</p>



<p>And then secondly, what are your plans in terms of replenishing the Strategic Petroleum Reserve?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, what we &#8212; where we’re focused is a structural challenge right now in the oil market as a result of Putin’s actions.&nbsp; We know that there is too little supply to meet demand, as Russian oil was coming off the market.&nbsp; Obviously, United States banned Russian imports; others also are not purchasing.&nbsp; We know that there&#8217;s a reduction in supply.&nbsp; And we are focused on the difference, that deficit between supply and demand, and that this historic action &#8212; a million barrels per day &#8212; will help to address that in coordination with other countries around the world.</p>



<p>You know, when it comes to the particular price effects, there is good evidence from studies of prior reserve releases that it can have significant effects in that sort of interim period, that short-term period, in order to provide relief.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where we&#8217;re focused.&nbsp; This is a bridge towards greater supply coming on the market from production both in the United States and elsewhere.</p>



<p>When it comes to the refilling, restocking the reserves, all of the funds that will be attained by the Department of Energy as a result of the sale of this oil will then go to restocking the reserve.&nbsp; That is an authority that the Department of Energy already has; that&#8217;s how they can deploy those funds.&nbsp; We expect that to occur.&nbsp; Once the oil price has come down, we are no longer in an emergency.&nbsp; You know, I direct you to the Department of Energy for more details on that.</p>



<p>The final thing I would say: You know, our commitment to restocking the reserve in order for it to be ready for future emergencies also can have good effects right now.&nbsp; It can encourage the additional production we need right now in order to respond to Putin&#8217;s action.&nbsp; So there really is a double benefit, both making sure that we are ready for future emergencies and also encouraging the production we need immediately in order to respond to Putin&#8217;s actions.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Next, we&#8217;ll go to Josh Boak from the Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much again for doing this.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve released &#8212; you&#8217;ve had two prior releases from the Strategic Reserve.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re describing this release, which is much larger as a bridge.&nbsp; Has the administration had talks or conversations with oil companies to ensure that the increased production will be out there and that this will be a bridge, since this also would reduce prices and presumably some of the incentives to pump more?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, appreciate the question, Josh.&nbsp; So, the President has had discussions with leaders in the industry.&nbsp; Senior administration officials have been closely monitoring and also in discussions with the industry as well.</p>



<p>You know, as I said, we believe that the industry needs to step up, it needs to do more, it needs to be investing in additional production.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are companies out there that have said they are; that are doing the right thing right now in increasing production.&nbsp; You know, that&#8217;s where, for instance, the million barrels a day that we &#8212; in additional production that we expect this year comes from.</p>



<p>However, there are also companies out there that haven&#8217;t said that.&nbsp; And, in fact, you know, some leaders in the industry who have said that it doesn&#8217;t matter where the price point is, they&#8217;re not going to produce more; they’re instead focused on returning dividends and other distributions to shareholders and their owners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s the right thing.&nbsp; We think these companies need to be stepping up, given the moment that we are in.&nbsp; There are some that have.&nbsp; And obviously &#8212; and I think you&#8217;ll hear the President say today: There is nothing standing in their way.&nbsp; There are, you know, thousands of unused</p>



<p>permits right now out there.&nbsp; There are the acres that aren&#8217;t being developed and they should be, given the current moment.</p>



<p>When it comes to the reserve and its effect on incentives, we do think that this is a bridge.&nbsp; And this is a discussion we&#8217;re having with the industry, but we &#8212; and I want to focus on, you know, two aspects of it.&nbsp; It, obviously, can help address the real lack of supply that exists right now &#8212; that difference between supply and demand as a result of Putin’s actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are committed, as I said, to restocking the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; Once we&#8217;re through this emergency and prices are down, our commitment to do that then provides an important signal to the market that, you know, additional production should be coming online, in part because the government will be purchasing that oil to restock the reserve, looking ahead to prepare for future emergencies.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; And next we’ll go to Kayla Tausche from CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I just wanted to ask for a little bit of clarification on the 1 million barrels.&nbsp; It looks, from the release, like the 1 million barrel total is the U.S. and allies combined.&nbsp; But I know it was also just said that other allies and the IEA would be discussing this at a meeting tomorrow and that their policy positions might not be final.&nbsp; So, could you just clarify that the 1 million barrels is specifically from the U.S. reserves?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, the United States will be releasing 1 million barrels per day, on average, for the next six months, and that will come from U.S. reserves.&nbsp; In combination with releases from other countries around the world, we expect it to be well in excess of 1 million barrels per day.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Next, James Politi from the Financial Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; I was just wondering, will there be any consequences for U.S. energy producers that don&#8217;t step up in this moment and produce more oil?&nbsp; What would those consequences be?</p>



<p>And in terms of the price for repurchasing and restocking the reserve, is that &#8212; you know, are you thinking a particular price where you could say, okay, well, it&#8217;s low enough now that we can buy; that it&#8217;s time to kind of shift?</p>



<p>And finally, what&#8217;s the state of the discussion with the Saudis?&nbsp; And should we be expecting them to increase production later this year as part of getting well over a million barrels per day?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, first, when it comes to the industry, we do think that there should be</p>



<p>consequences if you&#8217;re sitting on unused approved permits for production on federal lands and also undeveloped acres of land that have been leased. &nbsp;That&#8217;s why the President will today call for a “use it or lose it” policy that will charge companies if they&#8217;re sitting on &#8212; on wells that aren&#8217;t producing and leases that they&#8217;re not developing.&nbsp; We think that can help encourage additional production this year.</p>



<p>The &#8212; and I&#8217;m forgetting what your second question was.&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>We might’ve lo- &#8212; we can &#8212; and I can &#8212; I remember your last question was on the OPEC, and I can turn it over for &#8212; to [senior administration official] to respond to that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; So, regarding your OPEC/Saudi question, as you know, OPEC took a decision this morning, and we will not &#8212; you know, OPEC Plus will make the decisions as it always has, and we continue to be in touch with relevant OPEC Plus partners on energy security and supply.</p>



<p>The President has been clear that he will act, if needed, to provide additional oil supply to calm turbulent markets.&nbsp; And when there&#8217;s an oil disruption, such as the one that we&#8217;re facing today, we know that consumers need relief now and that&#8217;s why the President has acted.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m remembering the second question was on restocking the reserves.&nbsp; The bottom line is we are committed to doing so when the &#8212; when prices come down, both to prepare for future emergencies and also to provide the right signal to the market now.</p>



<p>We’ll defer to the Department of Energy on exactly how we&#8217;re going &#8212; on exactly the execution of that.&nbsp; But that is our strong commitment and an authority that the Department of Energy has.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; And we’ll do one final question.&nbsp; Timothy Gardner from Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, when exactly will we see the first million barrels of this release come to markets?&nbsp; And secondly, could you &#8212; obviously, with</p>



<p>Saudi Arabia and UAE and others playing a very important role in oil markets, can you say when this plan was communicated to them?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first question, the barrels will be coming to market very soon, so we&#8217;re already releasing barrels from the previous releases.&nbsp; We expect the Department of Energy to soon issue a notice, which would put additional &#8212; the additional barrels on the market starting in the month of May &#8212; for May delivery.&nbsp; And we’ll defer &#8212; we’ll refer you to them for additional operational details.&nbsp; But these barrels will be coming on the market very, very soon, and we expect a notice of sale that would begin making them available in the month of May.</p>



<p>And on the question around consultations, we&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve always done, we&#8217;ve always been in touch with relevant OPEC partners on energy security and supply.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve had those conversations over the last several weeks.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks to everyone so much for joining.&nbsp; Please feel free to send me your questions.&nbsp; We will do our best to get you an answer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I hope everyone has a great day and tunes into the President&#8217;s remarks this afternoon.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p> 11:18 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Plan to Respond to Putin’s Price Hike at the&#160;Pump</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/31/fact-sheet-president-bidens-plan-to-respond-to-putins-price-hike-at-the-pump/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Americans face rising prices at the pump because of Putin’s Price Hike.  Since Putin accelerated his military build-up around Ukraine, gas prices have increased by nearly a dollar per gallon.  Because of Putin’s war of choice, less oil is getting to market, and the reduction in supply is raising prices at the pump for Americans. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Americans face rising prices at the pump because of Putin’s Price Hike.  Since Putin accelerated his military build-up around Ukraine, gas prices have increased by nearly a dollar per gallon.  Because of Putin’s war of choice, less oil is getting to market, and the reduction in supply is raising prices at the pump for Americans.  President Biden is committed to doing everything in his power to help American families who are paying more out of pocket as a result.  That is why today, President Biden will announce a two-part plan to ease the pain that families are feeling by increasing the supply of oil starting immediately and achieving lasting American energy independence that reduces demand for oil and bolsters our clean energy economy. </p>



<p><strong><u>Immediately Increasing Supply</u></strong></p>



<p>At the start of this year, gas was about $3.30 a gallon.&nbsp; Today, it’s over $4.20, an increase of nearly $1.&nbsp; And now, a significant amount of Russian oil is not making it to market.&nbsp; The President banned the import of Russian oil – which Republicans and Democrats in Congress called for and supported.&nbsp; It was the right thing to do.&nbsp; But, as the President said, Russian oil coming off the global market would come with a cost, and Americans are seeing that at the pump.</p>



<p>The first part of the President’s plan is to immediately increase supply by doing everything we can to encourage domestic production now and through a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve to serve as a bridge to greater supply in the months ahead.</p>



<p><strong><em>Increasing Domestic Production</em></strong></p>



<p>The fact is that there is nothing standing in the way of domestic oil production. The United States is already approaching record levels of oil and natural gas production. There are oil companies that are doing the right thing and committing to ramp up production now.&nbsp; Right now, domestic production is expected to increase by 1 million barrels per day this year and nearly 700,000 barrels per day next year.</p>



<p>Still, too many companies aren’t doing their part and are choosing to make extraordinary profits and without making additional investment to help with supply.&nbsp; One CEO even acknowledged that, even if the price goes to $200 a barrel, they’re not going to step up production.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Right now, the oil and gas industry is sitting on more than 12 million acres of non-producing Federal land with 9,000 unused but already-approved permits for production.<strong> Today, President Biden is calling on Congress to make companies pay fees on wells from their leases that they haven’t used in years and on acres of public lands that they are hoarding without producing. </strong>Companies that are producing from their leased acres and existing wells will not face higher fees. But companies that continue to sit on non-producing acres will have to choose whether to start producing or pay a fee for each idled well and unused acre.</p>



<p><strong><em>Historic Release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve as a Bridge Through the Crisis</em></strong></p>



<p>After consultation with allies and partners, the President will announce the largest release of oil reserves in history, putting one million additional barrels on the market per day on average – every day – for the next six months.  The scale of this release is unprecedented: the world has never had a release of oil reserves at this 1 million per day rate for this length of time. This record release will provide a historic amount of supply to serve as bridge until the end of the year when domestic production ramps up.  </p>



<p>The Department of Energy will use the revenue from the release to restock the Strategic Petroleum Reserve in future years. This will provide a signal of future demand and help encourage domestic production today, and will ensure the continued readiness of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve to respond to future emergencies.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden is coordinating this action with allies and partners around the world, and other countries are expected to join in this action, bringing the total release to well over an average 1 million barrels per day.</p>



<p><strong><u>Achieving Real American Energy Independence</u></strong></p>



<p>The United States is the largest oil producer in the world and is a net energy exporter. &nbsp;Despite that, the actions of a dictator half a world away can still impact American families’ pocketbooks. The President will announce his commitment to achieving real energy independence – which centers on reducing our dependence on oil altogether.</p>



<p><strong>The President will call on Congress to pass his plan to speed the transition to clean energy that is made in America. </strong>&nbsp;His plan will help ensure that America creates millions of good-paying union jobs in clean, cutting-edge industries for generations to come. And it will save American families money in theimmediate future – including more than $950 a year in gas savings from taking advantage of electric vehicles, and an additional $500 a year from using clean electricity like solar and heat pumps to power their homes. <strong>&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>And, the President will issue a directive, authorizing the use of the Defense Production Act to secure American production of critical materials to bolster our clean energy economy </strong>by reducing our reliance on China and other countries for the minerals and materials that will power our clean energy future.  Specifically, the DPA will be authorized to support the production and processing of minerals and materials used for large capacity batteries&#8211;such as lithium, nickel, cobalt, graphite, and manganese—and the Department of Defense will implement this authority using strong environmental, labor, community, and tribal consultation standards. The sectors supported by these large capacity batteries—transportation and the power sector—account for more than half of our nation’s carbon emissions.  The President is also reviewing potential further uses of DPA – in addition to minerals and materials – to secure safer, cleaner, and more resilient energy for America.</p>



<p>This week alone, President Biden announced historic efforts to increase energy efficiency and lower costs for consumers.  The Department of Energy opened applications for more than $3 billion in new Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding—ten times the historical funding levels of the Weatherization Assistance Program—for <strong>energy efficiency and electrification upgrades in thousands of homes</strong> <strong>that will save families hundreds of dollars on utility bills</strong>.  The Administration also advanced smart standards that will lower consumer costs, including a roadmap of 100 actions this year that will <strong>save families $100 annually through more efficient home appliances and equipment, </strong>as well as<strong> new fuel economy standards for cars and trucks</strong> <strong>to save drivers money at the pump</strong>.  And the Administration is seeking additional opportunities to ramp up the deployment of <strong>heat pumps to displace fuel burned in buildings</strong>, as well as programs to drive <strong>efficiency, electrification, and use of clean fuels in the industrial sector</strong>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Advances Equality and Visibility for Transgender&#160;Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/31/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-advances-equality-and-visibility-for-transgender-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration recognizes Transgender Day of Visibility, an annual celebration of the resilience, achievements, and joy of transgender people in the United States and around the world. Every American deserves the freedom to be themselves. But far too many transgender Americans still face systemic barriers, discrimination, and acts of violence. Today, the Administration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration recognizes Transgender Day of Visibility, an annual celebration of the resilience, achievements, and joy of transgender people in the United States and around the world. Every American deserves the freedom to be themselves. But far too many transgender Americans still face systemic barriers, discrimination, and acts of violence. Today, the Administration once again condemns the proliferation of dangerous anti-transgender legislative attacks that have been introduced and passed in state legislatures around the country. The evidence is clear that these types of bills stigmatize and worsen the well-being and mental health of transgender kids, and they put loving and supportive families across the country at risk of discrimination and harassment. As the President has said, these bills are government overreach at its worst, they are un-American, and they must stop.<br><br>Transgender people are some of the bravest people in our nation. But nobody should have to be brave just to be themselves. Today, the Biden Administration announced new actions to support the mental health of transgender children, remove barriers that transgender people face accessing critical government services, and improve the visibility of transgender people in our nation’s data.<br><br><strong>Advancing dignity, respect, and self-determination for transgender people by improving the traveler experience. </strong>For far too long, transgender, non-binary, and gender non-conforming Americans have faced significant barriers to travelling safely and many have not had their gender identity respected as they travel within the United States and around the world. To create a safer and more dignified travel experience, the Biden Administration is announcing the following changes.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of State</strong> is <a href="https://www.state.gov/press-releases/">announcing</a> that beginning on April 11, 2022, all U.S. citizens will be able select an “X” as their gender marker on their U.S. passport application. This is a major step in delivering on the President’s commitment to expand access to accurate identification documents for transgender and non-binary Americans. Information on how to apply will be available at <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/passports/need-passport/selecting-your-gender-marker.html">travel.state.gov/gender</a>.<br></li><li><strong>The Department of Homeland Security</strong> is <a href="https://dhs.gov/news/2022/03/31/dhs-announces-new-measures-better-serve-transgender-non-binary-and-gender-non">announcing</a> several important reforms to improve the traveler experience for all Americans, particularly for transgender Americans:<br><ul><li><strong>Implementing enhanced screening technology. </strong>The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) will soon begin updating its Advanced Imaging Technology (AIT) body scanners with new technology that will increase security and efficiency by reducing false alarm rates and pat-downs for the traveling public. By replacing the current, gender-based system with this more accurate technology, TSA will improve the customer experience of transgender travelers who have previously been required to undergo additional screening due to alarms in sensitive areas.&nbsp; This new technology will help to improve the experience of travelers, particularly those who are transgender and non-binary travelers. TSA will begin deploying this new technology in airports throughout the country later this year.<br></li><li><strong>Expanding airline partnerships to enhance the overall travel experience. </strong>&nbsp;TSA is working closely with air carriers across the nation to promote the use and acceptance of the “X” gender marker to ensure more efficient and accurate passenger processing. As of March 31st, two major domestic air carriers already offer a third gender marker option in their travel-reservation systems, with a third air carrier planning to offer this option in the Fall of 2022.<br></li><li><strong>Streamlining identity validation. </strong>TSA has updated its Standard Operating Procedures to remove gender considerations when validating a traveler’s identification at airport security checkpoints. This ensures that TSOs can accurately and efficiently validate each traveler’s identity while avoiding unnecessary delays.<br></li><li><strong>Updating TSA PreCheck and CBP Trusted Traveler Programs enrollment to include “X” gender markers.</strong> The Department of Homeland Security is beginning the process of adding “X” gender markers options in Trusted Traveler programs and the TSA PreCheck program to enhance access for transgender, non-binary, and gender non-conforming travelers to these programs.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>Providing resources for transgender kids and their families. </strong>Transgender children are put at higher risk of attempted suicide or mental health challenges when they face bullying, rejection, or denial of health care. The Biden Administration is releasing several new resources to help transgender children and their parents thrive:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing mental health resources for transgender youth.&nbsp;</strong>In recent months, multiple states have removed critical information about mental health resources for LGBTQI+ youth from official state websites. Transgender youth often face significant barriers in accessing supportive resources, and are at greater risk of attempted suicide. In response, the Department of Health and Human Services released a <a href="http://www.hhs.gov/lgbtqi">new website</a> that offers resources for transgender and LGBTQI+ youth, their parents, and providers. These resources include best practices for affirming an LGBTQI+ child, and information about suicide prevention services.<br></li><li><strong>Expanding trainings to support transgender and nonbinary students in schools.</strong> The Office of Safe and Supportive Schools in the Department of Education will offer new training for schools with experts and school leaders who will discuss the challenges faced by many transgender and nonbinary students and strategies and actions for providing support.<br></li><li><strong>Confirming the positive impact of gender affirming care on youth mental health.</strong> The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) has posted <a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/blog/lgbtqi-youth-all-americans-deserve-evidence-based-care">LGBTQI+ Youth – Like All Americans, They Deserve Evidence-Based Care</a>, in which Miriam Delphin-Rittmon, Ph.D., HHS Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the leader of SAMHSA, shares how to engage LGBTQI+ youth, the evidence behind the positive effects of gender affirming care, and available resources for LGBTQI+ youth, their families, providers, community organizations, and government agencies.<br></li><li><strong>Confirming that gender-affirming care is trauma-informed care. </strong>The National Child Traumatic Stress Network (NCTSN), which is administered by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, is releasing new <a href="https://www.nctsn.org/sites/default/files/resources/fact-sheet/gender-affirming-care-is-trauma-informed-care.pdf">information for providers</a> confirming that providing gender-affirming care is neither child maltreatment nor malpractice.<br></li><li><strong>Providing resources on the importance of gender affirming care for children and adolescents.</strong> The Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health has developed a <a href="https://opa.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/2022-03/gender-affirming-care-young-people-march-2022.pdf">resource</a> to inform parents and guardians, educators, and other persons supporting children and adolescents with information on what is gender-affirming care and why it is important to transgender, nonbinary, and other gender expansive young people’s well-being.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Improving access to federal services and benefits for transgender Americans.</strong>&nbsp;With support and coordination from the U.S. Digital Service, federal agencies are removing barriers to access government services by improving the customer experience of transgender, non-binary, and gender non-conforming Americans:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Accessing retirement savings. </strong>The Social Security Administration&nbsp;is <a href="https://www.ssa.gov/news/press/releases/">announcing</a> that it is removing the requirement that transgender people show proof of identity such as doctor’s notes in order to update their gender information in their social security record by the fall of 2022. This will significantly improve transgender individuals’ experience in accessing their retirement benefits, obtaining health care, and applying for jobs.<br></li><li><strong>Filing an employment discrimination complaint</strong>.&nbsp;The U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) is <a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/newsroom/eeoc-add-non-binary-gender-option-discrimination-charge-intake-process">announcing</a> that it will promote greater equity and inclusion for members of the transgender community by giving individuals the option to select an “X” gender marker during the voluntary self-identification questions that are part of the intake process for filing a charge of discrimination.<br></li><li><strong>Applying for federal student aid.</strong> The Department of Education plans to propose next month that the 2023-24 FAFSA (Free Application for Federal Student Aid) will include an opportunity for applicants to indicate their gender identity as well as their race/ethnicity when applying for federal financial aid. The questions, which will be posted for public comment, will be in a survey that accompanies the application. This privacy-protected information would help to inform the Department about possible barriers students, including transgender and nonbinary students, face in the financial aid process.<br></li><li><strong>Visiting the White House.&nbsp;</strong>The White House Office of Management and Administration&nbsp;is announcing that it is beginning the process of implementing updates that will improve the White House campus entry process for transgender, gender non-conforming, and non-binary visitors by adding an “X” gender marker option to the White House Worker and Visitor Entry System (WAVES) system. This change will ensure that transgender, non-binary, and gender nonconforming people can visit the People’s House in a manner that respects and affirms their gender identity.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing inclusion and visibility in federal data. </strong>In too many critical federal surveys and data systems, transgender, non-binary, and gender non-conforming people are not fully reflected. To improve visibility for transgender Americans, agencies are announcing new actions to expand the collection and use of sexual orientation and gender identity (SOGI) data.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The White House</strong> announced that the President’s proposed Fiscal Year 23 budget includes $10 million in funding for additional critical research on how to best add questions about sexual orientation and gender identity to the Census Bureau’s American Community Survey, one of our nation’s largest and most important surveys of American households. This data collection will help the federal government better serve the LGBTQI+ community by providing valuable information on their jobs, educational attainment, home ownership, and more.<br></li><li><strong>The Department of Health and Human Services</strong> has <a href="https://wwwn.cdc.gov/QBank/Report.aspx?1225">released</a> the findings of the federal government’s first-ever user research testing conducted with transgender Americans on how they want to see themselves reflected on Federal IDs. This groundbreaking user research by the Collaborating Center for Question Design and Evaluation Research (CCQDER) at the National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS) directly informed the State Department’s adopted definition of the “X” gender marker.<br></li><li><strong>The Department of Health and Human Services&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.nih.gov/about-nih/who-we-are/nih-director/statements/nih-funded-nasem-report-highlights-critical-need-sgm-related-data-collection">has released</a> a comprehensive new consensus study on Measuring Sex, Gender Identity, and Sexual Orientation. This work, commissioned by the National Institutes of Health and carried out by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, will inform additional data collections and future research in how to best serve LGBTQI+ Americans.</li></ul>



<p><strong>These announcements build on the Biden-Harris Administration’s historic work to advance equality for transgender Americans since taking office, including:</strong><br><br><strong>Combatting legislative attacks on transgender kids at the state level.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Condemning anti-transgender bills. </strong>The President has consistently made clear that legislative attacks against transgender youth are un-American, and are bullying disguised as legislation. In his March, 2022 State of the Union Address, the President said, “The onslaught of state laws targeting transgender Americans and their families is wrong.&nbsp;As I said last year, especially to our younger transgender Americans, I will always have your back as your President, so you can be yourself and reach your God-given potential.” The White House has also hosted listening sessions with transgender youth and advocates in states across the country that are impacted by anti-transgender legislative attacks.<br></li><li><strong>Reaffirming that transgender children have the right to access gender-affirming health care. </strong>In March, following state actions that aim to target parents and doctors who provide gender-affirming care to transgender children with child abuse investigations, the Department of Health and Human Services <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/03/02/statement-hhs-secretary-xavier-becerra-reaffirming-hhs-support-and-protection-for-lgbtqi-children-and-youth.html">took multiple actions</a> to support transgender children in receiving the care they need and promised to use every tool available to protect LGTBQI+ children and support their families.<br></li><li><strong>Department of Justice statements of interest and amicus briefs.</strong> The Department of Justice’s Civil Rights Division has filed Statements of Interest and amicus briefs in several matters to protect the constitutional rights of transgender individuals, including in <em>Brandt v. Rutledge</em>, a lawsuit challenging legislation restricting access to gender-affirming care for transgender youth; <em>B.P.J. v. West Virginia State Board of Education</em>, a lawsuit challenging legislation restricting participation of transgender students in school sports; <em>Corbitt v. Taylor</em>, a lawsuit challenging legislation restricting the ability to change gender markers on state driver&#8217;s licenses; and <em>Adams v. School Board of St. John’s County</em>, which involves the right of a transgender boy to use the boys’ restroom at his school.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing civil rights protections for transgender Americans</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Fighting for passage of the Equality Act.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/fact-sheet-the-equality-act-will-provide-long-overdue-civil-rights-protections-for-millions-of-americans/">continues to call</a>&nbsp;on the Senate to pass the Equality Act, legislation which will provide long overdue federal civil rights protections to transgender and LGBTQI+ Americans and their families. As the White House has&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/fact-sheet-the-equality-act-will-provide-long-overdue-civil-rights-protections-for-millions-of-americans/">said</a>, passing the Equality Act is key to addressing the epidemic levels of violence and discrimination that transgender people face. The Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/SAP_HR-5.pdf">first Statement of Administration Policy</a> was in support of the Equality Act, and the White House has <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/21/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-lgbtq-advocates-on-the-equality-act-and-achieving-full-equality-for-lgbtq-americans/">convened national leaders</a> to discuss the importance of the legislation.<br></li><li><strong>Signing one of the most comprehensive Executive Orders on LGBTQI+ rights in history.</strong>&nbsp;Within hours of taking office, President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-preventing-and-combating-discrimination-on-basis-of-gender-identity-or-sexual-orientation/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;which established that it is the official policy of the Biden-Harris Administration to prevent and combat discrimination against LGBTQI+ individuals, and to fully enforce civil rights laws to prevent discrimination on the basis of gender identity or sexual orientation. This Executive Order is one of the most consequential policies for LGBTQI+ Americans ever signed by a U.S. President. As a result of that Order, the Departments of <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/05/10/hhs-announces-prohibition-sex-discrimination-includes-discrimination-basis-sexual-orientation-gender-identity.html">Health and Human Services</a>, <a href="https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/hud_no_21_021">Housing and Urban Development</a>, <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-confirms-title-ix-protects-students-discrimination-based-sexual-orientation-and-gender-identity">Education</a>, <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/about-us/newsroom/cfpb-clarifies-discrimination-by-lenders-on-basis-of-sexual-orientation-and-gender-identity-is-illegal/">Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</a>, and <a href="https://www.justice.gov/crt/page/file/1383026/download">Justice</a> have announced that they are expanding non-discrimination protections for transgender people in health care, housing, education, credit and lending services, and community safety programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting transgender service members and veterans</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Reversing the discriminatory ban on transgender servicemembers.</strong>&nbsp;In his first week in office, President Biden&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/25/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-enabling-all-qualified-americans-to-serve-their-country-in-uniform/">signed</a>&nbsp;an Executive Order reversing the ban on openly transgender servicemembers serving in the Armed Forces, enabling all qualified Americans to serve their country in uniform. President Biden believes that an inclusive military strengthens our national security As a result of his Executive Order, the Department of Defense issued new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2557220/dod-announces-policy-updates-for-transgender-military-service/">policies</a>&nbsp;which prohibit discrimination against transgender servicemembers, provide a path for transgender servicemembers to access gender-affirming medical care, and require that all transgender servicemembers are treated with dignity and respect.<br></li><li><strong>Supporting transgender veterans. </strong>To ensure that transgender veterans are treated with dignity and respect, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) launched an&nbsp;<a href="https://blogs.va.gov/VAntage/85152/secretary-orders-review-vas-transgender-policies/">agency-wide review</a>&nbsp;of its policies and practices to ensure that transgender veterans and employees do not face discrimination on the basis of gender identity or expression. In June, VA also announced that it is beginning the regulatory process to remove restrictions that prevent transgender veterans from accessing the gender-affirming care they need and deserve.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Responding to the crisis of anti-transgender violence and advancing safety</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Establishing a White House-led interagency working group on anti-transgender violence. </strong>To address the crisis of anti-transgender stigma and violence, during Pride Month in 2021 the White House established the first Interagency Working Group on Safety, Opportunity, and Inclusion for Transgender and Gender Diverse Individuals. The Working Group is co-led by the White House Domestic Policy Council and Gender Policy Council. To inform the priorities of the Working Group, throughout the fall of 2021 the White House convened 15 historic listening sessions with transgender and gender diverse people, advocates, and civil rights leaders from across the country and around the world, including a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-transgender-women-of-color-advocates/">White House roundtable with transgender women of color</a><strong>.<br></strong></li><li><strong>Releasing a White House report uplifting the voices of transgender people on gender-based violence and discrimination. </strong>On Transgender Day of Remembrance, the White House released a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Report_Memorializing-Transgender-Day-of-Remembrance_FINAL-002.pdf">report</a>&nbsp;sharing the perspectives from White House listening sessions, uplifting the voices and advocacy of transgender people throughout the country, and highlighting over 45 key, early actions the Biden-Harris Administration is taking to address the root causes of anti-transgender violence, discrimination, and denial of economic opportunity.<br></li><li><strong>Department of Justice civil rights enforcement actions. </strong>On September 14, 2021, the Department of Justice announced that it was launching a statewide civil investigation into Georgia’s prisons, which includes a focus on sexual abuse of transgender prisoners by other prisoners and staff. The Department of Justice’s Civil Rights Division and U.S. Attorney’s Office for the District of Puerto Rico also obtained a federal indictment charging three men with hate crimes for assaulting a transgender woman because of her gender identity.<br></li><li><strong>Ensuring non-discrimination protections in community safety programs. </strong>The Department of Justice issued a Memorandum from the Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights regarding the application of <em>Bostock v. Clayton County</em> to the nondiscrimination provisions of the Safe Streets Act, the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act, the Victims of Crime Act, and the Violence Against Women Act to strengthen non-discrimination protections for transgender and LGBTQI+ individuals in key community safety programs.<br></li><li><strong>Strengthening protections for transgender individuals who are incarcerated. </strong>In January 2022 the Bureau of Prisons revised its <a href="https://www.bop.gov/policy/progstat/5200-08-cn-1.pdf">manual on serving transgender offenders</a>, improving access to gender-affirming care and access to facility placements that align with an inmate’s gender identity.<br></li><li><strong>Honoring those lost to violence.</strong>&nbsp;The White House and the Second Gentleman of the United States <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/20/biden-harris-administration-memorializes-transgender-day-of-remembrance/">hosted a first of its kind vigil</a> in the Diplomatic Room of the White House to honor the lives of transgender and gender diverse people killed in 2021, and the countless transgender and gender diverse people who face brutal violence, harassment, and discrimination in the United States and around the world. The President also <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/20/statement-by-president-biden-on-transgender-day-of-remembrance/">released a statement</a> honoring the transgender people who lost their lives to violence.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing safety and justice for transgender and Two-Spirit Indigenous people. </strong>LGBTQI+ Native Americans and people who identify as transgender or “Two-Spirit” are often the targets of violent crimes. On November 15, 2021, President Biden signed an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/11/15/executive-order-on-improving-public-safety-and-criminal-justice-for-native-americans-and-addressing-the-crisis-of-missing-or-murdered-indigenous-people/">Executive Order</a> on Improving Public Safety and Criminal Justice for Native Americans and Addressing the Crisis of Missing or Murdered Indigenous People. The Executive Order directs federal agencies to work hand in hand with Tribal Nations and Tribal partners to build safe and healthy Tribal communities to address the crisis of Missing and Murdered Indigenous People, including LGBTQI+ and “Two-Spirit” Native Americans.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing health equity and expanding access to gender-affirming health care to support transgender patients</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Protecting transgender patients from health care discrimination.</strong> The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) announced that it would interpret and enforce section 1557 of the Affordable Care Act’s prohibition on discrimination on the basis of sex in certain health programs to prohibit discrimination on the basis of gender identity and sexual orientation.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing gender-affirming care as an essential health benefit.</strong> In 2021, the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/10/12/biden-harris-administration-greenlights-coverage-of-lgbtqplus-care-as-an-essential-health-benefit-in-colorado.html">approved the first ever application</a> from a state to add additional gender-affirming care benefits to a state’s essential health benefit benchmark plan.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing health equity research on gender-affirming care.</strong> The National Institutes of Health (NIH) announced that it will increase funding for research on gender-affirming procedures to further develop the evidence base for improved standards of care. Research priorities include a more thorough investigation and characterization of the short- and long-term outcomes on physical and mental health associated with gender-affirming care.<br></li><li><strong>Ending the HIV crisis among transgender and gender diverse communities.</strong> In December, 2021, in recognition of World AIDS Day, the White House Office of National AIDS Policy released a revised <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/National-HIV-AIDS-Strategy.pdf">National HIV/AIDS Strategy</a> which now identifies transgender and gender diverse communities as a priority population in the federal government’s strategy to end the HIV epidemic.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing access to gender-affirming care through Ryan White HIV/AIDS Program. </strong>The Health Resources and Services Administration announced that it has <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/03/25/icymi-hrsa-promotes-access-gender-affirming-care-and-treatment-in-ryan-white-hiv-aids-program.html">released a letter</a> encouraging Ryan White HIV/AIDS Program service providers to provide access to gender affirming care and treatment services to transgender and gender diverse individuals with HIV. The letter reaffirms the importance of providing culturally-affirming health care and social services as a key component to improving the lives of transgender people with HIV.<br></li><li><strong>Ensuring transgender patients can access birth control.</strong> In 2021 HHS issued a final rule to strengthen the Title X family planning program, fulfilling the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to restore access to equitable, affordable, client-centered, quality family planning services. The rule requires family planning projects to provide inclusive care to LGBTQI+ persons. Additionally, the rule prohibits discrimination against any client based on sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, sex characteristics, or marital status.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting transgender students and their families</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring educational environments are free from sex discrimination and protecting LGBTQI+ students from sexual harassment.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-guaranteeing-an-educational-environment-free-from-discrimination-on-the-basis-of-sex-including-sexual-orientation-or-gender-identity/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;recommitting the Federal Government to guarantee educational environments free from sex discrimination, including discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity. The Executive Order charged the Department of Education with reviewing the significant rates at which students who identify as LGBTQ+ are subject to sexual harassment, including sexual violence. The Department of Education has announced that it intends to propose amendments to its Title IX regulations this year.<br></li><li><strong>Protecting the rights of transgender and gender diverse students. </strong>The Department of Education has affirmed that federal civil rights laws protect all students, including transgender and other LGBTQI+ students, from discrimination. The Department published a <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-06-22/pdf/2021-13058.pdf">notice</a> in the Federal Register announcing that it interprets Title IX’s statutory prohibition on sex discrimination as encompassing discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Department of Justice memorandum on Title IX. </strong>The Department of Justice issued a <a href="/%3ewww.justice.gov/crt/page/file/1383026/download%3c%3c">memorandum</a> regarding the application of <em>Bostock</em> to Title IX.<br></li><li><strong>Speaking directly to transgender students. </strong>The Department of Justice, Department of Education, and Department of Health and Human Services issued a joint back to school <a href="/www.justice.gov/opa/video/back-school-message-transgender-students-us-department-justice-us-department-education-and%3c">message</a> for transgender youth.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Outreach and education to transgender and gender diverse students and their families. </strong>The Department of Education has published <a href="http://www.ed.gov/ocr/lgbt.html">fact sheets and other resources</a> showing the federal government’s support for transgender students, highlighting the ways schools can support students, reminding schools of their duty to investigate and address harassment based on sexual orientation or gender identity, and informing students how they can assert their rights and file complaints.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing research to address the harms of so-called conversion therapy.&nbsp;</strong>The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) announced that it will update its 2015 publication&nbsp;<em>Ending Conversion Therapy: Supporting and Affirming LGBTQ Youth</em>&nbsp;to reflect the latest research and state of the field.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Promoting fair housing and ending homelessness for transgender Americans</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Advancing fair housing protections on the basis of gender identity.</strong> In February 2021 the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) announced that it would administer and enforce the Fair Housing Act to prohibit discrimination on the basis of gender identity and sexual orientation.<br></li><li><strong>Ensuring safety and access to services for transgender people experiencing homelessness.</strong> In April, HUD withdrew the previous administration’s proposed “Shelter Rule,” which would have allowed for federally funded discrimination against transgender people who seek shelter housing. By withdrawing the previous administration’s proposed rule, the agency has restored protections for transgender people to access shelter in line with their gender identity. HUD has also released new tools for recipients to ensure compliance with these requirements in shelters and other facility settings.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing economic opportunity and protections for transgender workers</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring nondiscrimination protections for transgender and gender diverse workers.</strong> In November 2021, the Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs proposed to rescind the agency’s 2020 rule “Implementing Legal Requirements Regarding the Equal Opportunity Clause’s Religious Exemption,” an important step toward protecting workers from discrimination while safeguarding principles of religious freedom.<br></li><li><strong>Ensuring equal access to the workforce development system.</strong> The Department of Labor is enforcing discrimination prohibitions in workforce development programs funded by the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, protecting workers from discrimination based on their gender identity or transgender status.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing gender equity and transgender equality at home and around the world</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Advancing transgender equality in U.S. foreign policy and foreign assistance. </strong>In line with the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/04/memorandum-advancing-the-human-rights-of-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-queer-and-intersex-persons-around-the-world/">Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World</a>, the United States is making significant investments to uphold dignity, equality and respect for transgender persons globally. &nbsp;For example, USAID supports the<a href="/www.fandmglobalbarometers.org/%3c" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Global Barometer for Transgender Rights</a> and the<a href="/williamsinstitute.law.ucla.edu/projects/gai/%3c" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> LGBT Global Acceptance Index</a> which track progress and setbacks to protecting transgender lives around the world.&nbsp; The Department of Health and Human Services through the <a href="https://www.state.gov/pepfar/">United States President&#8217;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief</a> supports inclusive health care services for transgender individuals, enabling health clinics to provide care to the transgender community.&nbsp;And through the Department of State’s <a href="https://www.state.gov/global-equality-fund/">Global Equality Fund</a>, local transgender rights organizations receive support to document human rights violations and provide critical legal assistance to community members. &nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Establishing the White House Gender Policy Council to Advance Gender Equity and Equality.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-establishment-of-the-white-house-gender-policy-council/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;establishing the White House Gender Policy Council to advance gender equity and equality across the whole of the government, including by addressing barriers faced by LGBTQ+ people, in particular transgender women and girls, across our country. &nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting transgender leaders and public servants</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Making the Federal government a model employer for transgender public servants.</strong> President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/25/executive-order-on-diversity-equity-inclusion-and-accessibility-in-the-federal-workforce/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;which takes historic new steps to ensure the Federal government is a model employer for all employees – including transgender, gender non-conforming, and non-binary employees. The Executive Order charges agencies with building inclusive cultures for transgender employees by: expanding the availability of gender-neutral facilities in Federal buildings; ensuring that employee services support transgender employees who wish to legally, medically or socially transition; advancing the use of non-binary gender markers and pronouns in Federal employment processes; and expanding access to gender-affirming care and inclusive health benefits.<br></li><li><strong>Appointing historic transgender leaders. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration includes barrier-breaking LGBTQI+ leaders, including Assistant Secretary for Health Dr. Rachel Levine, who is the first openly transgender person ever confirmed by the U.S. Senate.&nbsp;In October, she was also <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/10/19/statements-officials-us-department-health-and-human-services-commemorating-first-openly-transgender-four-star-officer-first-female-four-star-admiral.html">named a four-star admiral</a> in the U.S. Public Health Service Commissioned Corps, becoming the first openly transgender person to hold that rank in any of the country’s uniformed services.&nbsp;Over 14 percent of Biden-Harris Administration appointees identify as LGBTQI+.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing visibility for transgender Americans</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Issuing the First White House Proclamation for Transgender Day of Visibility.&nbsp;</strong>On March 31, 2021 President Biden became the first U.S. President to issue a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/31/a-proclamation-on-transgender-day-of-visibility-2021/">proclamation</a>&nbsp;commemorating Transgender Day of Visibility.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Hosting a White House Virtual Convening on Transgender Equality.&nbsp;</strong>In June, White House Press Secretary Jen Psaki hosted a first-of-its-kind&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3WsnZUAXJLA">national conversation</a>&nbsp;on equality for transgender, gender non-conforming, and non-binary Americans.<br></li><li><strong>Releasing a toolkit on equality and inclusion for transgender Americans.&nbsp;</strong>The White House released a new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trans-Equality-Toolkit_REFORMAT-2_WHCO-fix.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">toolkit</a>&nbsp;with best practices for advancing inclusion, opportunity, and safety for transgender Americans.<br></li><li><strong>Establishing a National Pulse Memorial. On June 25, 2021, President Biden </strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/25/remarks-by-president-biden-in-bill-signing-of-h-r-49-to-designate-the-national-pulse-memorial-into-law/">signed H.R. 49 into law</a> to designate the National Pulse Memorial. As the President acknowledged in his <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-5th-anniversary-of-the-pulse-nightclub-shooting/">statement on the fifth anniversary</a> of the Pulse nightclub shooting, we must acknowledge gun violence’s particular impact on LGBTQ+ communities across our nation, and we must drive out hate and inequities that contribute to the epidemic of violence and murder against transgender women – especially transgender women of color. As the President has said, Pulse Nightclub is hallowed ground.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and Prime Minister Holness of Jamaica After Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/30/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-prime-minister-holness-of-jamaica-after-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 02:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial OfficeEisenhower Executive Office Building 5:13 P.M. EDT VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Mr. Prime Minister, I want to warmly welcome you again.&#160; It has been since &#8212; not since 1995 that a Prime Minister of Jamaica has visited the White House.&#160; And so, President Joe Biden and I are very honored&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial Office<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></p>



<p>5:13 P.M. EDT<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Mr. Prime Minister, I want to warmly welcome you again.&nbsp; It has been since &#8212; not since 1995 that a Prime Minister of Jamaica has visited the White House.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, President Joe Biden and I are very honored and &#8212; and very excited about your presence here today to reaffirm the strength of the relationship between the United States and Jamaica, and the Caribbean as a whole, but also, on this, the 60th anniversary not only of Jamaica&#8217;s independence but of the diplomatic relationship between Jamaica and the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>As I told the Prime Minister privately and I will say it again publicly, this is a very important relationship to the United States.&nbsp; We take very seriously our membership in the Western Hemisphere, and we are acutely aware of the interconnection and interdependence between the United States and Jamaica.&nbsp;<br><br>As a point of personal privilege, I grew up going to Jamaica.&nbsp; My family &#8212; half of my family is from St. Ann Parish in Jamaica.&nbsp; And I know I&#8217;ve shared that history with millions of Americans who have their roots through the generations in Jamaica.<br><br>In addition to, of course, then, those people-to-people ties between the United States and Jamaica, as I said, in context of being neighbors in the Western Hemisphere, we have a longstanding strategic relationship and a diplomatic relationship and a deep historic partnership.&nbsp;<br><br>And it is in furtherance of that that I&#8217;m proud and pleased to announce today three specific initiatives that the Prime Minister and I discussed that are in furtherance of the strength and the importance of that relationship.&nbsp;<br><br>We talked extensively about the Prime Minister&#8217;s approach and the need of Jamaica to continue to invest in its prosperity, in its economic health, and strength.&nbsp;<br><br>To that end, the United States &#8212; and I am announcing today &#8212; will be investing $20 million to assist in the strengthening and the expansion of Jamaica&#8217;s commerce in a way that we fully intend will have an impact in strengthening the economy of Jamaica and drive economic growth.&nbsp;<br><br>We also recognize &#8212; just as it has been in the United States &#8212; for Jamaica, one of the issues that has been presented as an issue that is economic in the way of its impact has been the pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>So, to that end, we are announcing today also that we will assist Jamaica in COVID recovery by assisting in terms of the recovery efforts in Jamaica that have been essential to, I believe, what is necessary to strengthen not only the issue of public health, but also the economy.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is on top of more than &#8212; what we have done throughout the year since the start of the pandemic: $12 million in COVID assistance and more than 600,000 vaccinations &#8212; or vaccines that have been donated.&nbsp;<br><br>Lastly, but most importantly, a great part of our conversation, Mr. Prime Minister, that we appreciate has been about the priority we share for security in the region, as well as the issue of crime prevention.&nbsp;<br><br>So we discussed, of course, the priority that your government places on both those issues.&nbsp; And we agree that one area of important focus is on youth and on, as you said, the human capital of Jamaica.&nbsp;<br><br>To that end, we have committed and we’re announcing now to provide $10 million to target at-risk youth in Jamaica through a number of initiatives that we believe will have exponential impact not only on the issue of crime prevention, but what we intend as well, which is to strengthen, as you have described, the natural human capital that exists in Jamaica among young people.<br><br>And finally, our conversation spanned not only those issues, but issues that are about a global significance.&nbsp; And to that end, I thank the Prime Minister for the leadership that he has offered in the context of votes that have been taken in the United Nations and in terms of Jamaica&#8217;s strong stand in joining the United Nations and the United States in condemning Russia&#8217;s aggression in Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>We also discussed quite extensively the impact of the climate crisis on island nations and, in particular, on Jamaica.&nbsp; We discussed &#8212; and from my perspective, I recognize and we recognize that the world&#8217;s emissions have an outsized effect in the Caribbean, including on Jamaica.&nbsp; And I thanked the Prime Minister for his leadership in that regard.&nbsp; And we are eager to partner with the Prime Minister on what we can do to invest and prioritize climate resilience, but also an investment in renewable energies, understanding that this is about energy sources, and it is also about human capital and development and supporting the economy there.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in conclusion, I will say that the United States and Jamaica continue to be close friends with many, many issues in common.&nbsp; And this partnership is an important one and an enduring one for the United States.&nbsp; And we look forward to strengthening and continuing to strengthen the relationship.&nbsp;<br><br>Mr. Prime Minister, again, welcome.&nbsp; And thank you.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Ladies and gentlemen, it is a great pleasure to be hosted here at the White House.&nbsp; My team and I are grateful for the very warm reception we have received.&nbsp;<br><br>Madam Vice President, from the outset, let me say thank you for the announcements that you have made for support for Jamaica in the areas of commerce, help on COVID-19 recovery, and &#8212; for us, very importantly &#8212; the human capital development; and also for the commitment for further strategic dialogue as to how Jamaica and the region as a whole can be supported, particularly in transitioning our democracies into prosperous economies.&nbsp; That has been the essence of our conversation.&nbsp;<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Indeed.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:&nbsp; Madam Vice President, let me say that you have been a source of inspiration and great pride for many Caribbean people &#8212; in particular, our young women in the region.&nbsp; And we are, indeed, seeing an increase in the political participation of young women.&nbsp; And this diversity in the political space will augur well for the &#8212; for the region.&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to congratulate you &#8212;<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:&nbsp; &#8212; on your leadership and your accomplishments.&nbsp;<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:&nbsp; This visit takes place in the context of Jamaica celebrating 60 years of independence and 60 years of diplomatic relations with the United States.&nbsp; The United States was one of the first countries to recognize newly independent Jamaica, and we have had a very strong relationship since.<br><br>The United States and Jamaica enjoys strong people-to-people economic and development partnerships, and we&#8217;re very proud of our continued strong relationship.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, our discussions reaffirm this strong partnership.&nbsp; And we discussed ways in which this partnership can be strengthened and expanded.&nbsp;<br><br>Madam Vice President, the Jamaican government and people have sacrificed and worked hard to successfully entrench macroeconomic stability and fiscal sustainability &#8212; and, in particular, in managing our debt.&nbsp;<br><br>It is a journey on which the United States has been a very good partner through several of your agencies and, indeed, various multinational &#8212; multilateral institutions.&nbsp;<br><br>Jamaica today is a model of a small, open economy which has transitioned its public financial management into a stable and financially prudent one.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To secure these gains, we must now turn our attention to addressing the vulnerabilities that have been exposed within the context of a pandemic and other global developments, particularly in relation to energy security.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In this regard, growth, infrastructure, human development, national security, and, as noted, energy security are areas of priority.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We believe these areas also coincide with the United States’ interest in ensuring that the region is secure, peaceful, stable, and prosperous.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have presented an overall plan to secure Jamaica&#8217;s prosperity and growth, and I&#8217;ve provided an outline on how our focused partnership with the U.S. can deliver on the promise of the great future that Jamaica envisions, particularly as we herald in our 60th year of independence.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In this regard, Jamaica will redouble our efforts in tackling illegal trafficking of weapons and persons, lottery scam, and other transnational crimes.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To address this in a decisive way, we are seeking to foster increased partnerships and collaboration on information and intelligence sharing, extradition, and other law enforcement efforts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the economic development front, we reiterated that we would welcome refocused attention on Jamaica in areas of security, energy capacity building, infrastructure, and nearshore digital technology hubs.</p>



<p>Madam Vice President, I thank you for your time today.&nbsp; And again, we welcome the announcements you have made in support of Jamaica.</p>



<p>Our strong and deep relationship with the United States is built on our shared democratic values and principles.&nbsp; It is an enduring relationship.</p>



<p>We look forward to working with you to leverage the strength of our partnerships to enhance the security, peace, wellbeing, and prosperity of the region.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Prime Minister.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;5:25 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Joey and Paula&#160;Reed</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-meeting-with-joey-and-paula-reed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 01:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met today with Joey and Paula Reed, the parents of Trevor Reed, who is wrongfully detained in Russia. During their meeting, the President reiterated his commitment to continue to work to secure the release of Trevor, Paul Whelan, and other Americans wrongfully held in Russia and elsewhere, and to provide all possible assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met today with Joey and Paula Reed, the parents of Trevor Reed, who is wrongfully detained in Russia. During their meeting, the President reiterated his commitment to continue to work to secure the release of Trevor, Paul Whelan, and other Americans wrongfully held in Russia and elsewhere, and to provide all possible assistance until they and others are free and returned home to their families who are advocating so passionately for their release. This is the President’s second interaction with the Reeds. On March 8, President Biden spoke to the Reeds by phone while he was in Texas.</p>



<p>The President’s national security team will remain in regular contact with the Reeds, the Whelan family, and other families of Americans held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad. We are grateful for their partnership and feedback. We will continue to work to ensure we are communicating and sharing information in a way useful to these families.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Previously, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with the Reed family in a virtual group meeting and then privately in December. He expressed our commitment to bringing Trevor home. We understand the pain felt by all of Trevor’s families and friends enduring the nightmare of his absence, which we are committed to bringing to an end.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress, on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Somalia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-somalia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C.&#160;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&#160;a&#160;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&#160;the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C.&nbsp;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&nbsp;a&nbsp;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date. &nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13536 of April&nbsp;12, 2010, with respect to Somalia is to&nbsp;continue in effect beyond April 12, 2022.</p>



<p>     The situation with respect to Somalia continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13536 with respect to Somalia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
