<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 21:39:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Fifteenth Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/president-biden-announces-fifteenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 21:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56895</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 3.1 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula on July 17 and 22 Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Kendamil baby formula from England to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 3.1 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula on July 17 and 22</em></p>



<p><br>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Kendamil baby formula from England to New York, NY via flights on July 17 and 22 respectively. These two deliveries will include in total approximately 200,000 pounds of Kendamil EU Classic First Infant Milk Stage 1 and Kendamil EU Organic First Infant Milk Stage 1, the equivalent of approximately 3.1 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available at Target stores. Parents and Pediatricians can learn more about Kendamil infant formula at <a href="https://us.kendamil.com">https://us.kendamil.com</a>  and compare its nutritional content per 100kcal with other leading formula brands at <a href="https://us.kendamil.com/pages/compare-kendamil">https://us.kendamil.com/pages/compare-kendamil</a>.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Kendamil can export additional infant formula into the U.S., including&nbsp;Kendamil EU Classic First Infant Milk Stage 1 and Kendamil EU Organic First Infant Milk Stage 1. Kendamil plans to export approximately 58 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market over the next 6 months.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By July 10, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 43 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img width="483" height="483" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-56896" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg 483w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=1200,1200 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 483px) 100vw, 483px" /></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kate Bedingfield to Depart the White&#160;House after Over 3 Years Leading the President’s Communications&#160;Operation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/kate-bedingfield-to-depart-the-white-house-after-over-3-years-leading-the-presidents-communications-operation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 20:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56889</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kate Bedingfield, a longtime trusted aide to President Biden and a senior strategist both in the administration and on his winning campaign, will leave the White House in late July to spend more time with her husband and young children after more than 3 straight years of leading his communications team. She first worked for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Kate Bedingfield, a longtime trusted aide to President Biden and a senior strategist both in the administration and on his winning campaign, will leave the White House in late July to spend more time with her husband and young children after more than 3 straight years of leading his communications team. She first worked for the President as his communications director during his time as Vice President.<br><br>Bedingfield previously served as the Deputy Campaign Manager and Communications Director on the President’s 2020 presidential campaign, playing a leading role advising him on messaging, building his communications and press operations, preparing him for debates and interviews, and devising and executing on strategy as he secured the Democratic nomination faster than any candidate since 2004 and became the first nominee to defeat an incumbent president in almost 30 years. She also represented the campaign on television at key moments, including before and after debates.<br><br>In the White House, Bedingfield continued as the President’s top communications aide and was similarly integral to every major public relations effort while leading the White House Communications Department, ensuring that each part of the team was working to deliver the President’s message and advocate for his agenda.<br><br>“Without Kate Bedingfield’s talent and tenacity, Donald Trump might still be in the White House, the Rescue Plan and the Infrastructure Law might still be unrealized goals, and Ketanji Brown Jackson might not be sitting on the Supreme Court,” <strong>said White House Chief of Staff Ron Klain.</strong> “She has played a huge role in everything the President has achieved – from his second term as Vice President, through the campaign, and since coming to the White House.  Her strategic acumen, intense devotion to the President’s agenda, and fierce work on his behalf are unmatched.  She will continue to remain a critical player in moving the Biden agenda forward from the outside.”<br><br>“From long before we launched the campaign, Kate Bedingfield was a fierce defender of the President and ensured that our message in 2020 and in the White House was consistent with his voice and principles,” <strong>said White House Senior Adviser Anita Dunn.</strong> “Her leadership helped us tell the story about the fight Joe Biden is making for the working families of America.  She’ll always be a core member of this family, even as she takes a little time to put her own family first.  We will miss her intelligence, her talent, her sense of humor, and her commitment to the values President Biden fought for as a candidate and fights for every day as president.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Fourteenth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/president-biden-announces-fourteenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 20:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 4.7 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Bubs Australia infant formula on July 10 and 21 Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Bubs Australia infant formula from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 4.7 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Bubs Australia infant formula on July 10 and 21</em><br><br>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport <em>Bubs</em> Australia infant formula from Australia to Ontario, California and Columbus, Ohio via flights on July 10 and 21 respectively. These two deliveries will include in total approximately 318,000 pounds of Bubs Organic Infant Formula S1, Bubs Organic Follow On Formula S2, Bubs Supreme Infant Formula Supreme Follow On Formula, Bubs Goat Milk Infant Formula S1, Bubs Goat Milk Follow On Formula S2, the equivalent of approximately 4.7 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available through national and regional retailers.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Bubs Australia can export additional infant formula into the U.S.&nbsp;Bubs Australia will import both standard and specialty infant formulas to the U.S. including&nbsp;Bubs Organic Grass Fed, Bubs Supreme A2 Beta-Casein Protein and Bubs Easy-digest Goat Milk. Bubs plans to export over 27.5 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. <em>By July 10, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 43 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</em></p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Cleveland,&#160;OH</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/06/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-cleveland-oh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 20:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Cleveland, Ohio 1:23 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Hey, everybody.  Okay, so today, the President is traveling to Max South [S.] Hayes High School in Cleveland, Ohio, to announce new protections for millions of workers in multiemployer pension plans thanks to the American Rescue Plan. Up to 3 million&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Cleveland, Ohio</p>



<p>1:23 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Hey, everybody.  Okay, so today, the President is traveling to Max <s>South</s> [S.] Hayes High School in Cleveland, Ohio, to announce new protections for millions of workers in multiemployer pension plans thanks to the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Up to 3 million Americans face significant cuts to their retirement benefits because their investments struggled during economic crisis just during the pandemic or more.  But tha- &#8212; but thanks to the ARP, over 200 multiemployer pension plans will receive special financial assistance and remain solvent through at least 2051 or longer.</p>



<p>The President is strengthening families’ retirement savings while Republican members of Congress, led by Senator Rick Scott, want to threaten it by putting Social Security on the chopping blocks every five years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the President will be joined today by Secretary of Labor Marty Walsh, Senator Sherrod Brown, ARP Coordinator Gene Sperling, and Cleveland Mayor Justin Bibb, as well as Representative Shontel Brown and Representative Marcy Kaptur.</p>



<p><a>And worth noting, as we are in route to <s>Chicago </s>[Cleveland], there is currently a bipartisan bill in Congress that would supercharge private sector investment in semiconductor manufacturing here at home.&nbsp; </a>The Bipartisan Innovation Act is good for workers, good for business, and good for communities.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s supported by mayors, governors, CEOs, manufacturers, and unions across the country, including the Republican Governor of Ohio, Mike DeWine.</p>



<p>Intel announced that it will invest $20 billion to open semiconductor factories in Ohio, and that could expand to as much as $100 billion if the Bipartisan Innovation Act is passed.</p>



<p>Senator Cornyn is joining Minority Leader McConnell in holding a bipartisan bill hostage that would make more in America in order to protect pharmaceutical companies’ profits.</p>



<p>But we believe we need to do both: increase American manufacturing and strengthen competitive edge against China and lower prescription drug costs.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we need Congress to pass BIA this summer.</p>



<p>And with that, Aamer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Has the President had a chance to reach out to the family of the Al Jazeera journalist since the State Department report?&nbsp; Or does he have plans to?</p>



<p>And just secondly, how big of an issue is he going to press this with the Israelis next week on holding someone accountable?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of a trip or ahead of conversations for a trip that hasn’t yet happened.&nbsp; So I won’t get ahead of that.&nbsp; But we have made very clear that we will continue to work both with Israel and Palestinian Authority to encourage them to bridge this investigation, because we do not want to &#8212; we want to see accountability, which is incredibly important for &#8212; not just for having accountability broadly, but also for the family as well.</p>



<p>So, to your first question, Aamer, I can say that senior American officials at the State Department have been in close touch with Abu Akleh’s fami- &#8212; her family and continue to be.</p>



<p>We again express our deepest condolences to the Abu Akleh family and remain engaged with Israel and, again, the Palestinian Authority on next steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one quick other one.&nbsp; Both Governor Pritzker, on guns in the aftermath of the July 4th shooting, and Gavin Newsom, since Dobbs decision, have become arguably more &#8212; the most outspoken voices of the Democratic Party on both of these very fragile issues in the country.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sort of wondering: Is there any concern that the President&#8217;s leadership is being overshadowed at this moment when the &#8212; a big part of the American public, including Democrats, that voted for him?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What was the first part of the question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, that both Pritzker and Newsom have sort of emerged on guns and on Dobbs, with &#8212; in Newsom’s case &#8212; as the loudest and, you know, most potent voices of the Democratic Party at this point.&nbsp; Where&#8217;s the President?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The President has been also very loud and also very focused on those two issues.&nbsp; When it comes to gun reform, the President led on that.&nbsp; One of the reasons that he was able to sign a bipartisan gun reform bill right before he left for G7 and NATO was because of his leadership, was because of him being very committed and being very consistent for more than a year, at least as President, talking about what we needed to do in light of this gun violence epidemic that we are currently in.</p>



<p>And let&#8217;s not forget this President has had the most executive actions on gun reform than any other President at this time.&nbsp; And he not only has led as President this past a year and a half, but also as Vice President and as senator &#8212; the very, very first, I would say &#8212; argue &#8212; the gun reform that we saw, or the last gun reform that we saw was 30 years ago, which this President led, which was on banning assault weapons.&nbsp; And so, you know, 30 years later, he was able to sign a gun reform &#8212; a bipartisan gun reform legislation that is now law.</p>



<p>Now, with all of that said, the President believes there is more work to be done.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to call on more to be done on dealing with this gun violence epidemic.&nbsp; And that does not stop here.&nbsp; And he welcomes &#8212; he welcomes other voices in the Democratic Party, and he welcomes other voices in the Republican Party as well to join him in really dealing with an issue that&#8217;s tearing up communities and families.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, is the White House tracking the drama in Boris Johnson&#8217;s government right now?&nbsp; And are you concerned at all about instability in the British government at a time when you&#8217;re working together on Ukraine and other international issues?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said this before when I&#8217;ve been asked questions about other governments’ elections &#8212; we&#8217;re just not going to comment on another government &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This isn&#8217;t an election though.&nbsp; I’m not talking about an election.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well &#8212; nope, you&#8217;re right, this is not an election.&nbsp; But to be clear, we&#8217;re just not going to comment on another government’s democratic process.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re just not going to comment.</p>



<p>Look, our alliance, our partnership with the United Kingdom continues to be strong.&nbsp; And so &#8212; but we&#8217;re not going to comment on their &#8212; kind of their political process</p>



<p>in their own country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on guns, does the President or the White House see this latest shooting in Highland Park as another perhaps opportunity to come out and try again to stop or to ban assault weapons?&nbsp; We haven’t heard the President talk about that since this latest shooting.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I mean, the President first wanted to make sure that the first responders had the space to do what they needed to do, which they have.&nbsp; And he has spoken to that.&nbsp; He wanted to also make sure that &#8212; you know, families and friends are mourning right now, which is incredibly important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We saw the Vice President in Chicago yesterday.&nbsp; She went to speak at NEA, and she stopped &#8212; she did a &#8212; she did a stop-by to thank the police officers, the first responders, and the work that they have done.&nbsp; So she did that representing, clearly, the administration and the President, which is incredibly important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the President is going to continue to speak about this.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to speak about what we &#8212; what else we can do to really deal with gun reform in a real way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He is &#8212; indeed, you know, welcomes and thankful for this bipartisan bill that is now law that he signed right before &#8212; like I said, right before he left for Europe.&nbsp; But the work doesn&#8217;t stop there, and he&#8217;ll continue to speak to that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on Ohio: You know, Tim Ryan, the Senate candidate, is not joining the President today and neither is the Democratic gubernatorial nominee, Nan Whaley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know you listed some people who are, but those are the main statewide candidates.&nbsp; And what does that say about the President&#8217;s clout in Ohio that they&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re not joining him today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I’ll say this: We&#8217;re in close contact with Congressman Tim Ryan in particular and work with him, and also &#8212; also Nan Whaley.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve worked &#8212; we&#8217;ve worked closely with him on &#8212; just as it relates to Tim Ryan &#8212; on ver- &#8212; on a variety of issues.&nbsp; And he released a statement in strong support of the actions we&#8217;re taking through the American Rescue Plan to protect American retirees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And though he can&#8217;t be there with us today, one of the things that the President looks forward to is to talk about building an economy around the power and possibilities of working families and providing financial relief to millions of workers in Ohio and the rest of the country.</p>



<p>I just listed out a long list of other elected officials who will be with him on this trip.&nbsp; And so, I think that counts for something as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, again, Tim Ryan put out &#8212; put out a statement supporting &#8212; supporting his trip, and we&#8217;re in constant communication with (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; His (inaudible) rating in Ohio is &#8212; it&#8217;s pretty low.&nbsp; The state has been moving to the right in recent elections.&nbsp; There are other states that he won that he&#8217;s, I think, spent less time in.&nbsp; This is his sixth visit to Ohio.&nbsp; Why has he been spending so much time in Ohio?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the President has said this himself many times.&nbsp; He’s the President for, you know, red states, blue states &#8212; for all Americans.&nbsp; And if there is something that he can speak to that’s going to help Americans and American families wherever he goes, he&#8217;s going to do that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, this pension announcement that we&#8217;re making via the American Rescue Plan is going to help &#8212; help families tremendously.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll hear directly from him, and he&#8217;ll &#8212; from the President in &#8212; you know, in a short few hours.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll lay out exactly what this &#8212; what this pension component of the American Rescue Plan is going to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, he will go &#8212; he will go wherever he needs to go to talk directly to the American people.&nbsp; And you guys have seen him.&nbsp; You guys have seen him deal with, you know, everyday Americans whenever he travels, and he connects, and &#8212; and I think it makes a difference for them to hear from &#8212; from their President directly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned the semiconductor legislation.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you can give us an update on the White House&#8217;s efforts to get that passed, given McConnell&#8217;s threat to pull Republican support for it last week.&nbsp; And are you prepared to roll that into a reconciliation package if he does follow through with that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on the &#8212; on USICA &#8212; this has many names &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; the COMPETES bill, CHIPS.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the &#8212; but the Bipartisan Innovative Act, one thing that we do know is that it would lower the costs of countless products, including cars, and end our reliance on imports, which is really important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the question is &#8212; and as you&#8217;ve heard me &#8212; and you heard me say earlier &#8212; is: Does Senator Mitch McConnell really want to hold hostage a bipartisan package that would strengthen the American competitiveness versus China and yield hundreds of thousands of manufacturing jobs, in particular in Ohio, as we&#8217;re headed there today, and Indiana, Idaho, and other states around the country?</p>



<p>So, we know that this is going to make a difference for the American public.&nbsp; And so, this is something that&#8217;s important.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to work with Congress on this.</p>



<p>To your question about reconciliation: I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here.&nbsp; That is another piece of legislation that we&#8217;ve been working very hard on that we know will also bring down inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So two pieces of legislation that we&#8217;re just going to continue to work hard on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you preview a little bit of what&#8217;s in the President&#8217;s letter to Brittney Griner?&nbsp; And does the public support coming out right now help or hurt the ability of the U.S. government to get her out of Russia?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let me just start with the first &#8212; the first part of your question, which is &#8212; and lay this down a little bit about what happened today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So President Biden spoke with Brittney &#8212; Brittney’s wife, Cherelle, today to make sure she knows we are doing everything we can to get Brittney home as quickly as possible.&nbsp; President Biden shared the letter with her &#8212; with her that he is sending back to Brittney after receiving her deeply personal letter on July 4th, which all of you read.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has been clear about the need to see every American who is wrongfully detained or held hostage abroad released, including Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Months ago, he directed his national security team to pursue every avenue to bring her home safely to her family, friends, and loved ones.&nbsp; This has been top of mind for the President.&nbsp; He receives daily updates about the status of her &#8212; of her negotiations to secure Brittney&#8217;s release, and the U.S. government continues to work aggressively using every available means to bring her home, along with other wrongfully detained Americans like Paul Whelan.</p>



<p>And so, this is, again, a top priority for this President. And like I &#8212; like I just read, he gets daily updates on what is happening, how we&#8217;re going to secure her ho- &#8212; her efforts to come home and also Paul Whelan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there&#8217;s been some reports in Russian media about a trade maybe for Viktor Bout and Gri- &#8212; Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Is that something the U.S. government would consider?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate in public on this.&nbsp; This is something, clearly, that the State Department, with the Special Envoy, they are focused on getting home &#8212; not just Brittney Griner and Paul Whelan, but all U.S. nationals who are wrongfully detained abroad or held hostage abroad home.</p>



<p>This is a priority for this President.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to negotiate in public on this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The &#8212; how does the White House justify &#8212; you&#8217;ve talked about abortion quite a bit.&nbsp; How does the White House justify the anti-abortion judge in Kentucky &#8212; nominating &#8212; attempting to nominate him even after the leaked document &#8212; leaked ruling on the &#8212; from the Supreme Court?&nbsp; You guys had that May 4th.&nbsp; We reported on that.&nbsp; And then weeks later, you still were thinking about putting an anti-abortion judge to a lifetime appointment.&nbsp; How do you &#8212; how does the White House justify that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, again &#8212; and I &#8212; I know I was asked this question yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Air Force One experiences turbulence.)&nbsp; Hold on, everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just not &#8212; we just don’t comment on &#8212; on vacancies, whether executive branch or judicial, in situations where we have not made a nomination.&nbsp; We just have not made a nomination on this yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do want to add and reiterate that the President is proud that we&#8217;ve confirmed more federal judges than tha- &#8212; during &#8212; than during any of the pa- &#8212; the last three presidents &#8212; presidencies at the equivalent time in their administrations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That includes so many history-making firsts to help our judiciary &#8212; judiciary represent the diversity of America, including groundbreaking new Supreme Court justice.&nbsp; And that is something that we&#8217;re going to continue to do, and we won&#8217;t stop there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Ukraine, Russia just captured its first full Ukrainian territory since Crimea in 2014.&nbsp; Is the United States and its allies going to push an enhanced response to the capture of Luhansk?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; An “enhanced response,” meaning &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whatever you guys &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; whatever you guys be &#8212; would be willing to do in seeing Russia take over this &#8212; the largest territory since Crimea.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so, you know, I was asked this question yesterday.&nbsp; And basically, you know, we have said for months that the fighting in the Donbas could be prolonged or protracted with gains and losses on both sides &#8212; you know, especially what we&#8217;re seeing today, as you just laid out, Eugene.</p>



<p>But that &#8212; that doesn&#8217;t mean that the Russians have been able to achieve their objectives here.&nbsp; And so &#8212; and the Ukrainians haven&#8217;t given up, right?&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to continue to fight for their democracy.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to continue to fight for their freedom.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to support them as we have been these past several months.&nbsp; We have given them the most amount of security assistance than any other country.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to make sure that they&#8217;re able to &#8212; you know, to fight for that democracy and their &#8212; and their sovereignty.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question: You mentioned the support that the United States has given Ukraine and continues to give to Ukraine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Ukrainian government says it&#8217;s going to cost upwards of $700 billion to kind of rebuild.&nbsp; Is the United States pledging to help lead that effort and give those &#8212; you know, a portion of that money, a lot of that &#8212; those billions of dollars to the government of Ukraine to help rebuild?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this: As the President said last week when he was in Europe, we will support Ukraine as it defends itself from Russia&#8217;s unprovoked attack for as long as it takes.&nbsp; The United States has been the world&#8217;s largest donor, as I just mentioned, of security, economic, and humanitarian assistance for Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will continue to coordinate with international partners on our support for Ukraine as they begin planning for how they will recover and rebuild after the war. &nbsp;And so, we&#8217;re going to just continue our support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  We&#8217;ll see you on the ground. </p>



<p>1:41 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56874</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&#160; Phillip (Phil) A. Washington, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration Henry V. Jardine, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mauritius and the Republic of Seychelles Diane Kaplan,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Phillip (Phil) A. Washington, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration</li><li>Henry V. Jardine, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mauritius and the Republic of Seychelles</li><li>Diane Kaplan, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors for the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</li><li>Jeffrey R. Gural, Nominee for Chair of the Public Buildings Reform Board</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Phillip (Phil) A. Washington, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration</span></strong><br><br>Phillip A. Washington was nominated by Denver Mayor Michael B. Hancock and unanimously confirmed by the Denver City Council as Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of Denver International Airport. Prior to this, Washington was the CEO of the Los Angeles County Metropolitan Transportation Authority (Metro). At Metro, Washington managed a budget of more than $8 billion and oversaw 11,000 employees that transported 1.2 million boarding passengers daily on a fleet of 2,200 clean-air buses and six rail lines. Washington also previously served as the CEO of Denver Regional Transportation District (RTD) and worked as the Assistant General Manager of RTD for nearly 10 years before being named CEO.<br><br>Originally from the South Side of Chicago, Washington is a 24-year veteran of the U.S. Army, where he held the rank of Command Sergeant Major. He retired from active duty, is a disabled veteran and was awarded the prestigious Defense Superior Service Medal for exceptional service to his country. He holds a B.A. in Business from Columbia College, and an M.A. in Management from Webster University.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Henry V. Jardine, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mauritius and the Republic of Seychelles</span></strong><br><br>Henry V. Jardine is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor. He currently serves as the Director of the State Department’s Office for Career Development and Assignments in Washington, D.C. Previously, Jardine was the Principal Deputy Director of the Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations for the State Department and, prior to that, the Executive Director of the Bureau for Western Hemisphere Affairs. He also held leadership positions overseas as Management Counselor of the U.S. Embassy in Bangkok, Thailand, as Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Tirana, Albania, and as Consul General of the U.S. Consulate General in Kolkata, India. Jardine also served at the U.S. Consulate General in Chiang Mai, Thailand, the U.S. Embassy in Bridgetown, Barbados and the U.S. Embassy, in Dhaka, Bangladesh. Prior to joining the State Department, Jardine served in the U.S. Army from 1989 – 1993. Jardine earned a B.S. Degree from the Georgetown University School of Foreign Service and an M.S. Degree from the National Defense University. His foreign languages include Bengali, Thai, Spanish, German, and Albanian.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Diane Kaplan, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors for the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</span></strong><br><br>Diane Kaplan is President and Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of the Rasmuson Foundation, based in Anchorage, Alaska. As President and CEO, Kaplan’s approach to philanthropy raised the bar for funder partnership with business, government, and other nonprofits. Before joining the Foundation, Kaplan provided consulting services for philanthropic organizations, Native corporations and tribes, and nonprofit organizations. Prior to that, she served as Chief Executive Officer of Alaska’s 28-station public radio network. She serves on the board of United States Artists, and is a member of the Anchorage Homelessness Leadership Council, Anchorage Rotary Club, the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco community advisory council, and Recover Alaska’s governance council. In 2019, Kaplan received the Anchorage ATHENA Society’s Leadership Award, the group’s highest honor. Kaplan earned a degree in Communications and Women’s Studies from the University of Pennsylvania, graduating summa cum laude.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Jeffrey R. Gural, Nominee for Chair of the Public Buildings Reform Board</span></strong><br><br>Jeffrey Gural is currently Chairman of GFP Real Estate LLC. Prior to his current role, Gural served in numerous roles at Newmark Knight Frank including as Chairman until 2017, after which he became Chairman Emeritus. Prior to that, he was a member of the staff of Diesel Construction Co., where he was responsible for the supervision and construction of more than one million square feet of new office space. Gural is a member of the Executive Committee of The Real Estate Board of New York, former Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Times Square Alliance, and member of the Board of Trustees of The New School. Gural was also Vice President of The Broadway Association, member of the Board of Directors of the Statue of Liberty Foundation, and President of The Realty Foundation of New York. Gural is a graduate of Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute with a degree in Civil Engineering. He is married, has three grown children, five grandchildren and resides in Manhattan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Cherelle&#160;Griner</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-cherelle-griner/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 16:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden, joined by Vice President Harris, spoke today with Cherelle Griner, the wife of Brittney Griner who is wrongfully detained in Russia under intolerable circumstances. The President called Cherelle to reassure her that he is working to secure Brittney’s release as soon as possible, as well as the release of Paul Whelan and other&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden, joined by Vice President Harris, spoke today with Cherelle Griner, the wife of Brittney Griner who is wrongfully detained in Russia under intolerable circumstances. The President called Cherelle to reassure her that he is working to secure Brittney’s release as soon as possible, as well as the release of Paul Whelan and other U.S. nationals who are wrongfully detained or held hostage in Russia and around the world. He also read her a draft of the letter the President is sending to Brittney today.<br><br>The President offered his support to Cherelle and Brittney’s family, and he committed to ensuring they are provided with all possible assistance while his administration pursues every avenue to bring Brittney home. Today’s call follows calls that National Security Advisor Sullivan and Secretary of State Blinken have had with Cherelle in recent weeks and this past weekend. The President directed his national security team to remain in regular contact with Cherelle and Brittney’s family, and with other families of Americans held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad, to keep them updated on efforts to secure the release of their loved ones as quickly as possible.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After Meeting with&#160;Firefighters</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/06/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-meeting-with-firefighters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 04:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Santa Monica Fire Station 2Santa Monica, California THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So the President and I have been in close coordination, and we are being briefed on what&#8217;s happening right now in terms of the active shooter situation.  We are sending federal resources to local law enforcement and the folks on the ground to make sure&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Santa Monica Fire Station 2<br><em>Santa Monica, California</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So the President and I have been in close coordination, and we are being briefed on what&#8217;s happening right now in terms of the active shooter situation.  We are sending federal resources to local law enforcement and the folks on the ground to make sure that we can help them in terms of the capture of the shooter and any investigation that will follow.<br> <br>But right now, we do have an active shooter situation.  And so we are putting all of the resources possible into monitoring that in a way that we can bring this to a close in terms of also capture of the individual.<br> <br>I am going to travel to Chicago tomorrow morning to address the National Association of Educators, NEA.  And I was just sharing with some of our heroes, our local firefighters, a part of what I&#8217;m preparing &#8212; sadly, I was preparing it before, but it is resonant every day &#8212; is a whole section on what our teachers go through.  They go to school to learn how to teach our children, to inspire their ambition, to create the future generations of leaders.  And our teachers are also in training to deal with an active shooter.  Our teachers are having to learn how to put a tourniquet on a kid if they have been shot.<br> <br>And so, when we look at the issue of gun violence and when we look at the dangers that it presents to communities, it ranges and it is something that we should take very seriously.<br> <br>The President recently signed bipartisan legislation to address the issue of gun violence, but we clearly have much more to do.<br> <br>So, thank you all. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Highland Park&#160;Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/05/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-highland-park-shooting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 03:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Highland Park, Illinois 7:18 P.M. CDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, to the community of Highland Park: I bring you condolences from President Joe Biden and from our country.  I&#8217;m so sorry for what you all have experienced and the pain, the suffering.  This should never have happened.  We talk about it being senseless; it is senseless. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Highland Park, Illinois</em></p>



<p>7:18 P.M. CDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, to the community of Highland Park: I bring you condolences from President Joe Biden and from our country.  I&#8217;m so sorry for what you all have experienced and the pain, the suffering.  This should never have happened.  We talk about it being senseless; it is senseless.  It is absolutely senseless. <br> <br>I want for you that you hold each other tight as a community, that you know that you have a whole nation who cares deeply about you and stands with you.  This is a &#8212; an incredibly tight community.  I know that.  And this person will be brought to justice, but it&#8217;s not going to undo what happened.<br> <br>And we &#8212; we’re here for you, and we stand with you.  And of course, as we always say &#8212; because it is true &#8212; our prayers are with you. <br> <br>The President and I and our administration have put all of the resources and will continue to put all of the resources that the Mayor and the Chief and others need in terms of the federal assistance.  So the FBI and the ATF are here.<br> <br>There&#8217;s a lot of healing that&#8217;s going to have to happen that is both physical and emotional.  There is no question that this experience is something that is going to linger in terms of the trauma.  And so, I&#8217;d like to urge all the families and all the individuals to do seek the support that you so rightly deserve. <br> <br>And &#8212; and we&#8217;ll deal with what we need to deal with in terms of also, as we move forward, all agreeing that we&#8217;ve got to be smarter as a country in terms of who has access to what and, in particular, assault weapons.  And we got to take this stuff seriously, as seriously as you are &#8212; because you have been forced to have to take it seriously. <br> <br>The whole nation should understand and have a level of empathy to understand that this can happen anywhere, in any peace-loving community.  And we should stand together and speak out about why it&#8217;s got to stop.<br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>                         END  7:21 P.M. CDT<br> <br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the National Education Association 2022 Annual Meeting and Representative&#160;Assembly</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/05/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-national-education-association-2022-annual-meeting-and-representative-assembly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 23:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[McCormick Place Convention CenterChicago, Illinois 5:12 P.M. CDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, NEA!  Good afternoon!  (Applause.)  Oh, what a sight my eyes behold.  I am so happy to be with you all this afternoon.  I am so happy to be with you.  And thank you for everything you do and everything you are.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  And,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>McCormick Place Convention Center<br><em>Chicago, Illinois</em></em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">5:12 P.M. CDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, NEA!  Good afternoon!  (Applause.) <br> <br>Oh, what a sight my eyes behold.  I am so happy to be with you all this afternoon.  I am so happy to be with you.  And thank you for everything you do and everything you are.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And, Becky, thank you for being such an extraordinary leader in extraordinary times. (Applause.)  Truly.  I’ve run into her in different places around the country, and she is always speaking about you and the importance of this organization and the importance of this organization to the future of our country.  Thank you, Becky, for that introduction.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, before I start with my address to you, I want to just briefly but importantly address the tragedy just miles away in Highland Park.<br> <br>As we all know, yesterday should have been a day to come together with family and friends to celebrate our nation’s independence.  And instead, that community suffered a violent tragedy.  Children, parents, grandparents &#8212; victims to a senseless act of gun violence. <br> <br>And Doug, who is here with me, he and I &#8212; of course, we mourn, as you do, for those who were killed.  And we pray for those who were injured.  And we all grieve, I know, for the lives that are forever changed in that community, including, of course, the students and the teachers of that community who have suffered great loss. <br> <br>And I don’t need to tell NEA: We need to end this horror.  We need to stop this violence.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And we must protect our communities from the terror of gun violence.  You know, I’ve said it before: Enough is enough.  (Applause.) <br> <br>I mean, here we are, and our nation is still mourning the loss of those 19 babies and their two teachers in Uvalde.  This massacre was the most recent reminder &#8212; in Uvalde &#8212; of the risks that our children and our educators face every day.<br> <br>Teachers should not have to practice barricading a classroom.  (Applause.)  Teachers should not have to know how to treat a gunshot wound.  (Applause.)  And teachers should not be told that “Lives would have been saved if only you had a gun.”  (Applause.) <br> <br>Now, we have made some progress.  For the first time in 30 years, our President, Joe Biden, signed a federal gun safety bill.  (Applause.)  And it strengthens background checks, and it closes what we call the “boyfriend loophole,” and it includes funding for mental health services and school security. <br> <br>But we have more to do.  We have more to do.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And Congress needs to have the courage to act and renew the assault weapons ban.  (Applause.) <br> <br>You know, I’ll talk in a minute about how you as educators teach the children so much.  And you teach the children, among many things, reason.<br> <br>So, let’s talk about what an assault weapon is designed to do.  An assault weapon is designed to kill a lot of human beings quickly.  There is no reason that we have weapons of war on the streets of America.  We need reasonable gun safety laws!  (Applause.) <br> <br>And we need to have Congress stop protecting those gun manufacturers with the liability shield.  Repeal it!  Repeal it! (Applause.) <br> <br>So we cannot be deterred.  We know we have challenges.  We cannot be deterred.<br> <br>And, NEA, we will not give up this fight.  We will not tire because I know who you are; that is just not in our nature.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And that, NEA, is why I am so honored to be here with you &#8212; because I do know this room.  This is a room of fighters.  And I know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; how deeply personal this work is to each one of you. <br> <br>As an educator, your work doesn’t stop at the end of the day when you walk out of your school.  Your work is full-time.  (Applause.)  I know that. <br> <br>Students come to your classroom before the day starts &#8212; for help with homework; sometimes with an empty stomach that you feed &#8212; (applause); or just to have someone they trust to talk with.  (Applause.)  Your students look to you to tell them everything is going to be okay, even sometimes when you may not be sure. <br> <br>But you continue to show up.  And that is why the President and I are honored to partner with the NEA to build our nation’s leaders.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And as a personal point of pride for all of us to have an educator and one of your active members in the White House as First Lady &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Dr. Jill Biden.  Yes.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And I can tell you &#8212; so I sometimes see her in a different situation than you might, and let me just tell you something.  I have watched her go from the classroom directly to events at the White House or across the country and around the world, grading papers in between.  (Applause.)  So, like you, she is a remarkable educator who inspires us all.<br> <br>NEA, who you are and what you do is also personal to me.  I’ve shared with some of you: My first-grade teacher, Mrs. Frances Wilson &#8212; God rest her soul &#8212; attended my law school graduation.  (Applause.)  And there are many people who have contributed to me to be able to serve as the first woman Vice President of the United States &#8212; (applause) &#8212; but I&#8217;m going to tell you, Mrs. Wilson was one of the earliest.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, you all, you not only shape lives, but you also shape policies. <br> <br>And we heard you when we took office when you told us about the issues that matter most to you and your students. <br> <br>We heard you when you told us about the fear and the uncertainty that you faced during the pandemic and about the extra help children needed once they returned to the classroom. So, with your help, we directed over $120 billion to our nation&#8217;s schools through the American Rescue Plan &#8212; with your help.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And this funding also led to a new initiative, launched just today, to help students who fell behind during the pandemic, which means 250,000 tutors and mentors across the country will be in schools to give students the support they need and to support your work every day.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We also heard you when you said your buildings are falling apart &#8212; that the school buildings are falling apart.  (Applause.)  We heard you that air conditioners were broken in the summer heat.  We heard you when you said too many of our children drink water poisoned with lead and breathe dangerous fumes from their bus ride to school.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We heard you when you said your students cannot do their homework because they cannot afford nor do they have access to be able to get online.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So we passed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and it will repair aging school infrastructure to save schools money.  It will replace lead pipes in 400,000 schools and childcare facilities across the country &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so that our children can drink clean water.  It will electrify our nation&#8217;s school buses so children can have clean air to breathe.  (Applause.)  It will make high-speed Internet accessible and affordable to every American household. <br> <br>And this will happen because of your support and your leadership.  Thank you, NEA.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And we still have more to do, and we have so much to do together.<br> <br>NEA, you are extraordinarily effective as a group advocate for change, which is why we know that you have been able to see the success you have achieved.  And it is no surprise why, because we know unions know how to organize.  (Applause.)<br> <br>I say all over the country: You may not be a member of a union, but you better thank the union for the five-day work week and weekends, paid leave.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And I often meet &#8212; and it&#8217;s &#8212; I know you do, and many are here &#8212; I often meet with young organizers from around the country.  And what&#8217;s exciting is that we are seeing in a new, younger generation that they want the benefits and the protections that come from joining a union.  (Applause.)  They want it.  They want it.  Because they know what we all know: Unions give workers a voice.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so, this is an historic moment, I think, for the labor movement.  Today, unions have their highest approval rating since 1965.  (Applause.)  About half of all non-union workers say they would join a union if given the chance.  That is almost 60 million people.  (Applause.)  Think about that.<br> <br>But we also know there are obstacles for them to meet that desire.  And we know what it is.  One is that many people still don&#8217;t know how to join a union, and so that&#8217;s part of the work we have ahead is to continue to remind them about how.  But even if they do know how, we also know, across our country, folks face barriers that have been built up over the years by corporate interests and anti-union politicians and regressive court cases.  (Applause.)<br> <br>I’ve fought many of those cases when I was Attorney General of California, so we know the obstacles are there.  (Applause.)<br> <br>California is in the house.  (Laughs.)  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so, our administration, together with you, we are all doing a lot to tear down those barriers. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ll tell you, I&#8217;m very proud to lead the White House Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment, along with my good friend &#8212; our good friend &#8212; Secretary Marty Walsh.  And &#8212; (applause) &#8212; from Massachusetts. <br> <br>And our President, Joe Biden, accepted all of our 70 proposals to make it easier for workers to organize.  And here&#8217;s the significance of that: It relates to federal workers, but the federal workforce is actually &#8212; the federal government is largest employer in the country.  And so, when you think about it, as we adopt the recommendations to make it easier for federal workers to organize, you will point to all of that to say, “If it can happen there, it can happen here.”  (Applause.)<br> <br>And there is more to do.<br> <br>So, we are looking at the fact that the President and I are determined to lead not only the most pro-union administration in American history but to move our country forward. <br> <br>We are determined to fight for a future where a teacher&#8217;s wage can provide for a family.  (Applause.)  Because I know it is still the case that some of you are working two jobs.  (Applause.)  Some maybe even three.  I know that. <br> <br>We are determined to fight for a future where you never again have to spend your own money on school supplies to meet your students’ needs.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We will fight for a future where teachers can educate our children with the resources, with the safety, and the respect that you deserve.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Because we are clear: When we do that, we can be sure that every child can reach their God-given potential.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, these are the values that our administration stands for.  And I think, when it comes down to it, it&#8217;s basically this: When you know what you stand for, you know what to fight for.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so much of what we just got through talking about is what extremist so-called “leaders” stand against. <br> <br>Since our administration has started, not one Republican leader in Washington voted to rescue our nation in the middle of a pandemic, including when we proposed resources for our children and our educators. <br> <br>Not one Republican leader in Washington, D.C., voted to extend the Child Tax Credit, which helps the poorest students and their families.<br> <br>Instead, these extremist so-called “leaders” fought against raising your pay. <br> <br>Instead, these extremist so-called “leaders” refuse to keep assault weapons off our streets and out of our classrooms and tried to silence your voice through your union.<br> <br>And instead, these so-called “leaders” have tried to make you pawns of their political agenda. <br> <br>Because while you work hard to inspire the dreams and ambitions of our next generation, they dare question your dedication, your motivation, and your value. <br> <br>While you work hard &#8212; (applause) &#8212; while you work hard to teach the principles of liberty and freedom in your classroom, these so-called “leaders” are taking freedoms away &#8212; (applause): freedom away from women and the freedom to make decisions over their own bodies &#8212; (applause); freedom away from a kindergarten-to-third-grade teacher in Florida to love openly and with pride &#8212; (applause); and away from every American as they intentionally try to make it more difficult for folks to vote.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We are 126 days away from an election, and we all know what we need to do.  (Applause.)  And, you know, I also think &#8212; I&#8217;m speaking to a group of educators &#8212; I also think that these extremist so-called “leaders” need to attend a civics lesson.  (Laughs.)  (Applause.) <br> <br>I think &#8212; I actually think it would benefit us all if they sat in your classroom for a few days to remember how a democracy works &#8212; (applause); to remember what freedoms stands for; and to remember what jobs they were elected to do.  (Applause.)<br> <br>All that to say that, as educators, you know, we all know that history has never been an unbroken line toward progress; that even when we have advances, there will be setbacks.  In certain times, those setbacks being more drastic than in others. This is one of those moments, but we will not be deterred. <br> <br>The President and I are counting on you to help us move forward as a nation, just as NEA has done throughout its history.  Because I remember that this organization fought to lower the voting age to 18.  (Applause.)  I remember that this organization fought to protect Black teachers from school districts that defied desegregation orders.  (Applause.)  I remember that this was the organization that stood with others to fight to pass DACA and ensure undocumented people can learn in our communities.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Again and again, you have been champions of social justice.  And it is clear: Educators are a central part, then, of moving our nation forward.  You are not only essential to our children&#8217;s future.  I&#8217;m here to share with you: You, I believe, are essential to the future of our democracy.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, we will do this work together because, NEA, when we look at where we are, we know that NEA has always been a powerful force &#8212; a powerful force whose members understand the power of unity. <br> <br>So, these may be difficult times.  And I know that at the end of this convening, you will each go back to your home district; you will go back and you will spend long evenings and nights preparing for the next day; you will go back and often be in a situation where it feels kind of like you might be the only one who sees what you&#8217;re seeing and understands what&#8217;s at stake.  (Applause.)<br> <br>But let&#8217;s remember moments like this.  And let us remember that the fight toward progress by its very nature is not linear. We&#8217;re going to have our ups; we&#8217;re going to have our downs.<br> <br>Let&#8217;s remember &#8212; I like to paraphrase all the time what Coretta Scott King said.  She said: The fight for justice, the fight for civil rights, the fight for freedom, the fight for equality must be fought and won with each generation.  And I think when she said that, she had two points in mind.  One is that it is the very nature of what we stand for and, therefore, fight for that whatever gains we make will not be permanent.<br> <br>There&#8217;s so much strength in what we achieve, but there is also fragility.  So, we must be vigilant.  And the second point then being: If we understand that&#8217;s the nature of it &#8212; it&#8217;s not going to be permanent; it is fragile, unless we are vigilant &#8212; it&#8217;s the nature of it, so do not despair.  Do not be overwhelmed.  Do not throw up our hands when it is a time to roll up our sleeves.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Thank you, NEA.  God bless you.  God bless our education.  And God bless the United States of America.  Thank you all.  (Applause.)<br>         <br>                         END                 5:38 P.M. CDT<br><br><br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/05/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:31 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Good afternoon, everybody.  I hope everyone had a restful long weekend. I actually don&#8217;t have anything for you at the top.  (Laughter.)  I know you guys are always excited to hear what I got to say. But, Darlene, you want to kick&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:31 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Good afternoon, everybody.  I hope everyone had a restful long weekend.<br><br>I actually don&#8217;t have anything for you at the top.  (Laughter.)  I know you guys are always excited to hear what I got to say.<br><br>But, Darlene, you want to kick us off?<br><br>Q    Yes.  Thank you very much.  Is the White House looking into the possibility of having the President visit Highland Park?  The death toll there has risen to seven this afternoon.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So, the President, as you all know, is going to be traveling to Ohio tomorrow to discuss the American Rescue Plan.  So that&#8217;s the trip that he&#8217;s going to be making tomorrow.<br><br>We don&#8217;t have any plans right now to go to Chicago.  I know some folks are asking if he&#8217;s going to go to Chicago, will he go &#8212; I mean, if he&#8217;s going to go to Ohio, is he going to go to Chicago. <br><br>The Vice President is going to be there, and she will speak to the devastation that we &#8212; that we all saw with our own eyes yesterday in Highland Park. <br><br>But I don&#8217;t have anything to share about &#8212; for President&#8217;s travel tomorrow.  He&#8217;ll go to &#8212; again, he&#8217;ll go to Ohio, where he&#8217;s going to talk about the Rescue Plan, the Special Finance &#8212; Financial Assistance Program, in particular.  This program will provide financial relief to millions of workers in multiemployer plans who face significant cuts to their pensions through no fault of their own.<br><br>But again, nothing to share about him going to Chicago at this time.<br><br>Q    Not necessarily tomorrow though, but later this week, next week, before he leaves for the Middle East?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I &#8212; we just don&#8217;t have anything to share.  But again, the Vice President is going to be there today.  She will certainly speak to &#8212; speak to the tragedy that we saw yesterday.  The President spoke to this yesterday during the Fourth of July in a very forceful way and laying out how he and the First Lady saw the tragedy, and he even had a moment of silence.<br><br>But we are not planning &#8212; right now, at this moment, I don&#8217;t have any plans of a future trip to Chicago.<br><br>Q    And since you mentioned the Ohio trip tomorrow, when the President is in Cleveland, which is relatively near Akron, do you expect him to address at all the fatal police shooting of Jayland Walker?<br><br>Q    I don&#8217;t have anything to share on that either, whether he is going to potentially &#8212; I know it&#8217;s about 45 minutes from Cleveland, where the shooting happened.  We just &#8212; right now, we&#8217;re going to be focusing on the trip that we have planned, which is to talk about the American Rescue Plan and how to help the American public.<br><br>Q    And then one final question.  Can you talk about the status of the letter that Brittney Griner sent to the President?  Has he been briefed on it?  Has he even read it?  Griner’s wife was on television this morning; she really wants to hear from the President.  Will he reach out to her in any fashion?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So, I can say that the President did read the letter.  I was there when he read the letter.  This is something &#8212; Brittney Griner being held in Moscow, we believe the Federation is wrongfully &#8212; she&#8217;s being wrongfully detained in Moscow at this time.  This is an issue that is a priority for this President.<br><br>As you have heard us say before, he believes that any U.S. national that is held abroad or detained or held hostage abroad, we need to bring back safely and we are going to use every tool that we possibly can to make that happen.  Again, this is a priority for the President. <br><br>I do want to share that, on Saturday, Mrs. Griner spoke with National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan.  That is their second call in the past about 10 days that they have spoken.  Secretary Blinken also spoke with Mrs. Griner as well recently.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have anything else to read out as far as a potential call or a meeting with her family.  But clearly, we believe she was wrongfully detained.  We believe she needs to come home &#8212; she should be home; as well as Paul Whelan, as well, who&#8217;s being held; and any other U.S. national who is wrong- &#8212; being wrongfully detained abroad.<br><br>Q    Thank you.<br><br>Q    Hi, Karine.  Just to follow up on that: Griner’s coach said, “If this was LeBron, <s>she</s> [he] would be home, right?  It’s a statement about the value of women, it’s a statement about the… Black person, it’s a statement about the value of a gay person &#8212; all those things. We know…” as true.  Do you see this as a double standard?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  This is a President who has put all of the things that you just laid out &#8212; the LGBTQ community, women, people of color &#8212; he has fought for those communities throughout his career.  And you &#8212; you have seen that in policies that he has put forward.<br><br>Again, this is a priority for this President.  He&#8217;s doing everything that he can.  The White House is closely coordinating as well with the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, who has met with Brittney&#8217;s family, her teammates, and her &#8212; her support network.<br><br>So we&#8217;re going to continue to have those conversations, and we&#8217;re going to make sure that she &#8212; she and others get home safely.<br><br>Q    And just to follow up since this is a priority for the President &#8212; I mean, she’s been detained for months now.  Her wife told “CBS This Morning” that she still has “not heard” from Biden.  “And, honestly, it&#8217;s very disheartening.”  I know it&#8217;s a priority, but why has it taken this long?  And why has it taken a letter from Griner in jail to reach the President to make this a priority?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Look, this has been on top of mind for the President.  Like, I was there when he read the letter.  And he takes this to heart.  He takes this job very seriously, especially when it comes to bringing home U.S. nationals who are wrongfully detained. <br><br>And you saw the work that his administration did to bring &#8212; to bring home Trevor Reed.  That is the same &#8212; the same work, the same focus that we did and put behind bringing Trevor Reed home, we&#8217;re going to do the same with Brittney Griner and others.<br><br>So, again, this is a priority.  We&#8217;re going to make this happen.  We&#8217;ve had &#8212; she&#8217;s &#8212; we have been in constant communications &#8212; Secretary Blinken; the Special Envoy, as I just listed out; and also Jake Sullivan, our National Security Advisor. <br><br>We&#8217;re going to continue to have those conversations, and we&#8217;re going to continue to make sure we use everything at our disposal to bring her home and also Paul Whelan and all the others U.S. nationals that are abroad.<br><br>Peter.<br><br>Q    Thanks, Karine.  How did the President go from blaming high gas prices on Putin to Big Oil to small-business owners now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Well, here&#8217;s the thing about that, Peter, is when you look at &#8212; as of this morning, when you look at the crude oil and when you look at wholesale oil prices as well, they&#8217;ve declined about 15 percent.  And so, retail gas prices, however, have only declined just about 3 percent over the same time period as we have seen with crude oil prices and the wholesale gas prices.<br><br>And meanwhile, those same retailers are profiting; their profit have gone up about 40 cents &#8212; nearly 40 cents in that same period of time. <br><br>So what the President is saying is that everyone along that chain, around that production chain line, needs to &#8212; needs to make sure that they&#8217;re doing what is possible, their part, in bringing down the costs for the American people.<br><br>That is what we&#8217;re asking.  Consumers should not &#8212; should not be the first to pay and the last to benefit.<br><br>Q    Jeff Bezos says the President&#8217;s tweet about this is “either straight ahead misdirection or a deep misunderstanding of basic market dynamics.”  Which is it?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  As you know, we completely disagree with Jeff Bezos.  Look, we will continue to call on everyone along that distribution chain, as I just mentioned &#8212; from oil companies, to refineries, to distributors, to retailers &#8212; to pass their lower cost through to consumers. <br><br>That is what is important: to make sure that we should not make, again, consumers pay first and get that re- &#8212; and get that relief last.<br><br>Q    Okay.  And then, on a different topic: Why is there a voicemail of the President talking to his son about his overseas business dealings if the President has said he&#8217;s never spoken to his son about his overseas business dealings?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Well, first, I&#8217;ll say that what the President said stands.  So if he &#8212; if that&#8217;s what the President said, that is what stands.<br><br>And second &#8212; secondly &#8212;<br><br>Q    He’s leaving a voicemail about a New York Times article &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  But secondly &#8212;<br><br>Q    &#8212; considering &#8212; concerning Hunter Biden’s business dealings.  And it says, “I think you&#8217;re clear.”  How is that not him talking to his son about his overseas business dealings?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  We&#8217;re not &#8212; from this podium, I am not going to talk about alleged materials from the laptop.  I will &#8212; I am not &#8212;<br><br>Q    So are you disputing that it’s President’s voice on the voicemail?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I am not going to talk about alleged materials on a laptop.  It’s not happening.<br><br>Q    Are you disputing then that it is not &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Peter, I refer you to his son’s representative.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The President said the other day that he would meet with governors and then consider some more potential executive actions in response to Roe.&nbsp; So now that that meeting has happened, is there anything on the table that you are considering in terms of executive actions?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as we have said, all options are on the table.&nbsp; The President is going to do everything that he can from his legal authority to make sure that we&#8217;re protecting women&#8217;s freedoms and women&#8217;s rights.&nbsp; So that still stands.&nbsp; That still is something that we are going to do.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an executive order &#8212; executive action to speak to at this time.<br><br>As you know, when &#8212; when the decision came down almost two weeks ago, the President took quick action and he announced executive &#8212; and he announced some executive authorities that we believe protect women, ensure that they &#8212; and ensure that they can get access &#8212; health &#8212; healthcare access as quickly as possible.<br><br>As far as executive actions, I don&#8217;t have anything for you to preview.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So just really quickly, is there an update on when the President will make a decision on Chinese tariffs?&nbsp; And will he be speaking to President Xi before he makes that decision?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you on that.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s team is continuing to look at our options on how to move forward.<br><br>As you know, the President and President Xi had a conversation back in March, and we continue to leave all communications lines open from the President on down.<br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just following up on that: The President did say he would have specific announcements out of the meeting.&nbsp; So has he changed his view on that, that there isn&#8217;t anything to announce right now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; No, not at all.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think he&#8217;s changed his view on that.&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;re going to do &#8212; he&#8217;s going to do everything in his legal &#8212; legal authority to make sure that we protect women and their freedoms and their rights the best that he can from, again, his legal authority.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything for you to share at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It just sounded like he had something in the pipeline there.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Once we have something, we will be sure to sho- &#8212; share it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the matter of the Griner letter: Now that the President has read it, does he feel it is the type of an outreach to him that he would want to do some kind of personal response back in a letter form or in some other way to Griner, if that is doable through channels, or to her wife or family members &#8212; to have a direct response from the President?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, you all read the letter, I presume.&nbsp; It was out there in the press.&nbsp; And it is a deeply personal letter.&nbsp; As you know, this President is &#8212; takes that very personally as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Brittney Griner talked about the Fourth of July, which we just celebrated yesterday, talking about freedom and how different it means for her.&nbsp;<br><br>You heard the President&#8217;s speech, which was also very powerful, yesterday speaking about that and the time and the moment that we&#8217;re in.<br><br>I just &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to share about what &#8212; if he&#8217;s going to respond or what that would look like.&nbsp; I can confirm, again, that he has read the letter, and it was, as we all know, deeply personal.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to do everything &#8212; the President is going to do everything that he can, in his power, to &#8212; to bring her home, along with other U.S. nationals who are being held &#8212; wrongfully detained abroad.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And any &#8212; any follow-up on the energy meeting that Secretary Granholm held?&nbsp; And the President had said he was looking for solutions from the oil companies and so forth.&nbsp; Has there been anything brought back to the President for him to review or any updates on that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, that meeting went very well.&nbsp; We even heard from some of the CEOs who came out of that meeting as well.&nbsp; We did a readout.&nbsp;<br><br>We are look- &#8212; still looking to get to solution.&nbsp; We think that was a first step.&nbsp; There&#8217;s going to be more conversations.&nbsp; I &#8212; we just don&#8217;t have more to share on the next steps &#8212; specific next steps and what has been presented to the President.&nbsp;<br><br>But clearly, we&#8217;re looking for solutions.&nbsp; We want to get that capacity up.&nbsp; We want to make sure that refineries are increasing their capacity so that we can get gas &#8212; gasoline out there, we can get diesel out there so that the cost for the American people come &#8212; come on down.&nbsp;<br><br>And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to continue to work on.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; On the China tariffs again, the AFL-CIO and other labor unions have urged the President not to use these tariffs.&nbsp; The President is going to Ohio tomorrow.&nbsp; The Democratic Senate candidate, Tim Ryan, has also said this would be a major mistake to use those tariffs.&nbsp;<br><br>So how is the President weighing those concerns among labor unions and some Rust Belt Democrats against other people who are saying these tariffs should be lifted?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, again, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview or announce at this time.&nbsp; Look, there are a lot of different elements to this, especially since the previous administration imposed these tariffs in such a haphazard way, in a non-strategic way.&nbsp; So, we are &#8212; we are &#8212; want to make sure that we have the right approach.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, his team is talking &#8212; is figuring it out and they&#8217;re talking through this.&nbsp; And once we figure out the right approach &#8212; this is about what is right for the American public, for the American people &#8212; we will have an announcement and we will let you all know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the stalled China competition bill, any calls to Capitol Hill to read out on that?&nbsp; What’s the White House&#8217;s strategy to try to get that across the finish line?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, it’s something that we believe is incredibly important to the American people, getting that competition bill done.&nbsp; We are &#8212; we are going to continue to have those conversations on the Hill.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know, we don&#8217;t read out any personal conversations, but we&#8217;re going to continue to do the work with folks on the Hill to get this done.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, thanks.&nbsp; A couple questions.&nbsp; Overall, there was a &#8212; there was a published report today that say overall frustration among Democrats with President Biden.&nbsp; Is this administration concerned about that criticism from Democrats?<br><br>And it also says that the President is incapable of the urgency needed because of Roe v. Wade being overturned.&nbsp; Any response from the administration to those published reports?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So when you say “Democrats,” you mean Demo- &#8212; elected officials or &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp; Elected Democratic officials’ overall frustration with the Biden administration.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, here&#8217;s the &#8212; here&#8217;s the thing I&#8217;ve &#8212; I’ve heard &#8212; I&#8217;ve heard of this.&nbsp; The President has shown, if you look at the different issues that have come up most recently &#8212; in particular, let&#8217;s start with gun violence:&nbsp; The President showed urgency.&nbsp; He showed fury.&nbsp; He showed &#8212; he showed frustration.&nbsp; He spoke to that issue every time that he could, whether he was in Uvalde or Buffalo or did a primetime address.&nbsp;<br><br>And we were able to get a first step &#8212; still a lot more to do &#8212; a bipartisan gun reform piece of legislation, which is something that has &#8212; we have not seen in 30 years.&nbsp;<br><br>A lot of that is because of his leadership.&nbsp; Something &#8212; the same thing that he was able to do 30 years ago, when we saw the assault weapons ban.&nbsp; So, that &#8212; he showed urgency there, and we were able to deliver in a bipartisan way.&nbsp;<br><br>When it comes &#8212; when it comes to Roe v. Wade, within hours of the announcement of the decision that we heard from SCOTUS, he put forth executive authorities that went into &#8212; that went into effect with the medication that&#8217;s approved medication from FDA, and also making sure that &#8212; calling on DOJ to protect women who are crossing the lines because they have to make a decision on their health.&nbsp;<br><br>And those are things that actually matter.&nbsp; There&#8217;s more work to do.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to look at everything that he can do on the legal authority.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but here&#8217;s the thing: When it comes to Roe, when it comes to a precedent that&#8217;s been around for nearly 50 years, what needs to happen is Congress needs to act.&nbsp; We have to codify Roe.&nbsp; We have to make sure that it is the law of the land.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to keep speaking to.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, with the criticism of the President, is this administration concerned about how the Democrats will perform in the midterm elections?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, I can&#8217;t talk about the midterms from here.&nbsp; That will get me into big trou- &#8212; (laughs) &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President concerned?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I&#8217;m just saying I got to be careful about that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he expressed any concern?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I got to be careful about that.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, the President wants to make sure that we continue delivering for the American people.&nbsp; He has said &#8212; what I can say from here &#8212; if we are in a position where Congress does not act, as we&#8217;re speaking to on Roe v. Wade, and does not codify Roe, make that &#8212; make Roe the law of the land, then the American public should make their voices heard.&nbsp; They should make their voices heard at the ballot box.&nbsp;<br><br>And that is something that he&#8217;s going to call on.&nbsp; That is going to be something that he&#8217;s going to speak on very loudly and very &#8212; very aggressively, as you &#8212; as you laid out.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is an important, important issue.&nbsp; He has said this was an extreme decision by the Court.&nbsp; He has said this is going to change the lives of so many women, upend their lives, if you will, because of this extreme decision.&nbsp; And it should not stand.&nbsp;<br><br>And what we saw a couple of weeks ago is not &#8212; almost two weeks ago &#8212; is not &#8212; is not the end.&nbsp; It is only the beginning.&nbsp; And we just have to keep working towards that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, as far as &#8212; a different matter entirely, but as far as a letter that was presented to you, signed by 70 members of the White House Press Corps, any reaction from the administration regarding that letter?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, you could say &#8212; I responded to you, didn’t I?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, you did say &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you would talk to us.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But that was all I heard.&nbsp; Is there anything else you could add?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, you know, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re coming &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re coming into a different &#8212; a different place of the CO- &#8212; of COVID.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Things are starting to open up.&nbsp; We&#8217;re even doing tours here.&nbsp; We had 7,000 people out in the &#8212; in the South Lawn yesterday, military families and others, to celebrate Fourth of July, which was a wonderful event.&nbsp; It was great to have &#8212; to see our military families out there.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, you know, we understand.&nbsp; We want to make &#8212; we want to be accessible.&nbsp; We want the President to be &#8212; his events to be accessible.&nbsp; And we are working to that, with the understanding that we have been working through, as we look at his events during this pandemic, and we&#8217;re trying to &#8212; we&#8217;re trying to see what the next steps are.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you’re going to open up everything for us?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not saying that. &nbsp;I&#8217;m just saying that we&#8217;re willing to work with you on this.&nbsp; And this is also a priority of ours.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; All right, great.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just following up on the executive actions &#8212; I mean, the ones that the President had hinted we might hear more of Friday, you say are still being talked about: I mean, there&#8217;s &#8212; there’s broad frustration among voters we&#8217;ve talked to, among many Democratic lawmakers that you had this unprecedented situation of more than a month of knowing pretty much what was going to be, likely, in the ruling.&nbsp; You had &#8212; the dynamics on the Court were clear in place when this case was heard.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s a lot of frustration of why weren&#8217;t those orders deliberated and decided and ready to roll out at a faster pace, and here we are, about two weeks later, talking about when that next wave might come out.&nbsp; I mean, what&#8217;s your response to that general frustration and &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I would &#8212; I would &#8212; look, I&#8217;ll say this: We understand that the &#8212; the frustration.&nbsp; What we saw the Court do almost two weeks ago should be frustrating, should be infuriating, and should have everyone angry &#8212; not just women, because this is not just about women&#8217;s rights.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s going to, as we saw &#8212; as you just mentioned, Clarence Thomas and what he just said in &#8212; in his remarks, it is &#8212; we are in an incredibly scary time.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we have to take their words very, very seriously.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not &#8212; let&#8217;s not forget what Republicans &#8212; national Republicans have been saying for the past couple of weeks: is how they want to make a national ban.&nbsp; And so, because of that, the President has been very forceful in saying that we have to take action.&nbsp; He cannot just do this alone; Congress needs to take action.&nbsp; So that’s number one.&nbsp;<br><br>But to your point: Within hours, when this decision came down, the President used his executive &#8212; his executive authority, which matters here because we know those &#8212; those who want to ban all abortions, ne- &#8212; their next moves are going to be medicated abortion and travel across state line.&nbsp; And so, we wanted to make that clear and get &#8212; and make sure we got ahead of that, if you will, as we&#8217;re seeing what we&#8217;re seeing across the states with the ban &#8212; the banning of abortion, for the next round of attacks.&nbsp;<br><br>So that&#8217;s what we did first.&nbsp; Now, we&#8217;re going to look at his legal authority on what he can do on executive actions.&nbsp;<br><br>But we &#8212; we jumped into action, I would argue, within &#8212; within hours of the decision.&nbsp; And the actions that we took &#8212; those author- &#8212; those executive authorities that we took were in consultation with groups, were in consultation with legal experts.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been having these conversations with them for many, many weeks since we heard of the draft &#8212; the draft proposal.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And quick follow-up on January 6th hearings.&nbsp; I mean, I know the White House has been pretty clear that due to the unique situation of January 6th, that executive privilege is not &#8212; is not a top concern about precedent.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m wondering, given the unique nature of a White House Counsel&#8217;s position, is there any conversations about whether that sets a precedent for White House Counsel going forward to have to answer to Congress about deliberations inside the White House?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just first say when it comes to January 6th &#8212; the hearings, the select committee &#8212; what we&#8217;re seeing: It is important &#8212; the President believes it&#8217;s important to get to the bottom of what happened, for the American public to see for themselves and get all the information that they can on what happened on that day.&nbsp;<br><br>So as it comes to executive privilege, there is no privilege for trying to overthrow the government.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the President believes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the President has consistently declined to assert executive privilege with respect to documents or testimony about the extraordinary events under investigation by the January 6th Committee.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re going to continue to defer to the &#8212; to the committee as it conducts its bipartisan, independent investigation.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; On Brittney Griner: You were there when the President read Griner’s letter.&nbsp; What was his reaction?&nbsp; And did he express a message for Griner and her family?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to share any personal interaction that I had with the President.&nbsp; I just wanted to confirm that he did read the letter.&nbsp;<br><br>And I will say, again, this is very personal to him, especially when someone writes a letter in such a personal way.&nbsp;<br><br>He &#8212; we have made this a priority.&nbsp; We have &#8212; you know, Secretary Blinken, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan has spoken to Mrs. Griner and her teammates and her family.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to continue to keep that &#8212; that open communication and have very honest conversations with them.&nbsp; They’re private conversations, so I&#8217;m not going to share what those conversations have been.&nbsp;<br><br>But this is also the case with all U.S. nationals abroad.&nbsp; Again, this is a priority for U.S. nationals who are &#8212; abroad who are wrongfully detained.&nbsp; It is important to the President to bring them home safely, just like we saw with Trevor Reed very &#8212; very recently ago.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we&#8217;re going to continue to make that a priority, but I&#8217;m not going to share any private conversations.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just a follow-up on the pleas from the Griner family on wanting to personally speak with the President.&nbsp; After reading this letter, is that something that the White House at this point is considering?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; there&#8217;s &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have anything to share on what communication the President is going to have with Mrs. Griner and her family.&nbsp; All I can confirm is that he&#8217;s read the letter, and he&#8217;s making this a priority.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, just on the Illinois shooting.&nbsp; Illinois already has a red-flag law.&nbsp; It isn&#8217;t used that often.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t used in this case, even though the suspect apparently had put some violent imagery online.&nbsp; Is your expectation that the gun bill that just passed is something that would have addressed this kind of situation?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I want to be very clear: Yes, the bipartisan gun &#8212; anti &#8212; the gun reform bill was an important first step.&nbsp; It was the first step that we have seen in 30 years.&nbsp; The last time was when this President led the banning assault weapons legislation that lasted for about 10 years and sunset in 19- &#8212; in 2004.&nbsp; And so, the President believes that we need &#8212; we need to make sure that we ban assault weapons.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;<br><br>That is one of the things that&#8217;s being reported that this suspect had.&nbsp; And so, banning assault weapons is something, again, that he&#8217;s going to continue to fli- &#8212; fight for.&nbsp;<br><br>With that said, he understand that there&#8217;s more work to be done.&nbsp; The bipartisan bill is going to save some lives.&nbsp; Like, that is &#8212; that is true; it will save some lives.&nbsp; But we need more &#8212; we need to do more work.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President is going to continue to do that &#8212; to do that fight.&nbsp;<br><br>What we know &#8212; one thing I would say about red-flag laws, as we&#8217;ve seen them over the past several years, is that when they are implemented, they do work in red states and in blue states.&nbsp; And they are also very much in lined of what a majority of Americans support.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, when they&#8217;re &#8212; when they&#8217;re actually enacted, red-flag laws are actually effective.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; do you &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t have any travel to confirm, but does the President wants to go to Illinois?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to say about any travel to Illinois.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just one other thing that I wanted.&nbsp; Is it accurate that the White House was planning to nominate this anti-abortion Republican judge, Chad Meredith, for a federal judgeship in Kentucky the day that Roe v. Wade was decided?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we don’t &#8212; we &#8212; we make it a point here to not comment on any &#8212; on any vacancy, whether it is on the executive branch or judicial branch, especially those that have not &#8212; have not &#8212; the nomination has not been made yet.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything to say on that.&nbsp; It is something that we just don&#8217;t comment on.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the President ever appoint a judge who doesn&#8217;t support abortion rights to the federal bench?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s a hypothetical that I can&#8217;t really speak to.&nbsp; I &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s not a litmus test for him though?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I’m not going to &#8212; I’m going on to litmus test.&nbsp; All I can tell you is that we don’t normally speak on vacancies that &#8212; where we haven&#8217;t made a decision yet, whether it&#8217;s on the judicial level or the executive branch.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’ve mentioned Trevor Reed a couple times.&nbsp; His release was part of a prisoner swap.&nbsp; Should we view that as a viable option when it comes to Brittney Griner or Paul Whelan or others?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I cannot speak to any discussions that are happening on how any U.S. national who’s being held abroad and wrongfully detained, how &#8212; what the process is going to be to bring them home.&nbsp;&nbsp; I just cannot speak to that from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a broad kind of contextual structure in which you look at prisoner swaps?&nbsp; Like, why &#8212; why was that considered an okay thing in the Trevor Reed case?&nbsp; Is there kind of a construct that the administration follows?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I cannot speak from &#8212; about that from here.&nbsp; Clearly, there are security and privacy reasons to not discuss the details of how &#8212; of how a release happens.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not something that I can speak from here.&nbsp;<br><br>I can say that we have the Special Envoy, that this is their focus.&nbsp; We are in constant communication with them on that process.&nbsp; But it is &#8212; just for safety, security reasons, this is not something that I can speak from here.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more on a different subject &#8212; on the China Competition Bill that Jordan asked about.&nbsp; The Senate passed that more than a year ago.&nbsp; Is there a concern that it was allowed to linger for too long and, in fact, gave Senator McConnell the opportunity to put the roadblocks he’s put up in front now because he didn&#8217;t move on it until 13 months later?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; look, it&#8217;s unfortunate that Senator McConnell has taken this approach.&nbsp; Clearly, that&#8217;s not an approach that&#8217;s going to help the American public.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we see it.&nbsp;<br><br>This competition bill is so &#8212; is important for many reasons.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to continue to work with Congress to get this done.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to just continue that process.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m not going to go into any personal conversations or negotiations, as we tend to say from here, but, again, this is an important piece of legislation that we would like to see move forward.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, thank you.&nbsp; Yesterday, President Biden, in his first opportunity to address the public in person, on the shooting, he did so sort of very obliquely and fleetingly.&nbsp; And then he came back out on stage about two hours later and spoke a little more.&nbsp; Was that because he fe- &#8212; he or his team felt he had initially missed the mark?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, he felt that he needed to speak on that himself.&nbsp; He just &#8212; that was his own decision to move &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But not from the statement.&nbsp; I mean, from &#8212; he came out and he verbally said at the Fourth of July, “You all heard what happened today.&nbsp; Things will get better still, but not without more hard work.”&nbsp; And then two hours later, that same evening, he came out and said a bit more.&nbsp; Is that because he felt &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No &#8212; no, my answer is still the same.&nbsp; He wanted to make sure that he had an opport- &#8212; he had an opportunity to speak to this, and he took that opportunity that second time.&nbsp; He spoke to it very briefly, as you just stated, the first time.<br><br>And the second time, you know, he &#8212; you know, he got on stage and wanted to give an update.&nbsp; He actually, if you remember, he gave an update of what was currently happening, and he gave a moment of silence.&nbsp; That was &#8212; that was &#8212; that was him.&nbsp; That was something he decided to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just briefly following up on that: Governor Pritzker said in a press conference &#8212; he said he was “furious,” it was a time “to be angry.”&nbsp; You have said, referring to what President Biden said, that he &#8212; he spoke “forcefully” yesterday; he spoke with “urgency.”<br><br>I guess I just want to make sure I understand: Do you and the President believe saying “You all heard what happened today” after yet another mass shooting &#8212; is that your definition of “forceful” and “urgent”?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What I’m saying is that there has been many times that the President has spoken forcefully, urgently about a moment that currently exists in our country, which is a gun violence epidemic.&nbsp;<br><br>And he has done that in primetime on many of your colleagues’ networks.&nbsp; He has done it Uvalde, when he &#8212; after coming back from Uvalde after he met with parents and family members in a dev- &#8212; they’re dealing with their devastation.&nbsp; He did that in Buffalo as well.&nbsp; And he has shown, over and over again, how important this issue is.&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s not just important during his presidency.&nbsp; It’s been important when he was the Vice President and it was important when he was a senator.<br><br>So to say that this President has not shown urgency, it’s just &#8212; it’s just false.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last final follow-up on that.&nbsp; On what we were just talking about, which is guns, but also on a range of issues &#8212; abortion rights, the threat to American democracy &#8212; why do you think so many members of your own party, elected leaders, voters, activists, pundits &#8212; why did they all seem to, in this moment, disagree with that assessment you just gave?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak for them.&nbsp; I can only speak to what we&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp; I can only speak to &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But why do you think that’s not coming through, what you’re trying to do?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I &#8212; again, I&#8217;m not going to speak for them. &nbsp;I would &#8212; I would speak &#8212; I would go directly to these folks, these activists, and our Democratic colleagues and speak to them directly.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure they will give you a very clear response on why they feel that way.<br><br>Look, you know, this is a President that has been working tirelessly, day in and day out, since he&#8217;s walked into this administration fighting for the American public.<br><br>That is what matters to him.&nbsp; That is what is important is delivering every way that he can to make sure that we get things done.<br><br>I mean, let&#8217;s not forget: While, again, there&#8217;s more work to be done, there was a bipartisan gun reform piece of legislation that has been done that has not been done in 30 years.&nbsp; That matters.<br><br>Is there more work to be done?&nbsp; Absolutely.<br><br>Is he going to call for more action and do the best that he can?&nbsp; Absolutely.<br><br>This is also a president, in his first year of office, has had more executive actions on gun reform, on fighting gun violence than any other president at this time.&nbsp; So that matters as well.&nbsp; His actions should peak &#8212; should speak as well for how he&#8217;s &#8212; how he&#8217;s delivering for the American public.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; I know you said White House doesn’t comment on judicial vacancies.&nbsp; But this case, the White House already provided a &#8212; an intent to &#8212; an intention to nominate to Kentucky Governor Beshear that it would intend to nominate Chad Meredith on June 23rd.&nbsp; So does the President plan to nominate this individual who has come under criticism for being &#8212; from Democrats in Kentucky and nationally for being an anti-abortion attorney and a member of the Federalist Society?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to comment on something that has not been decided on that &#8212; on any open vacancies.&nbsp; It&#8217;s still &#8212; currently, it is an open vacancy.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m just not going to comment from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any deal with Leader McConnell regarding this jump ship that the President has entered into whereby McConnell wouldn&#8217;t hold up certain judicial appointments moving forward?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to comment on an open vacancy at this point.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Then what’s your reaction to all of this response &#8212; angry response from a lot of Democrats in Kentucky &#8212; Representative John Yarmuth, Andy Beshear, others &#8212; who have criticized that Biden would nominate somebody who stands against abortion and holds conservative views?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we haven&#8217;t nominated anyone &#8212; that&#8217;s what I would say &#8212; as of yet.<br><br>Let me &#8212; okay, I guess I got everybody.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Following the Highland Park shooting, President Biden’s Fourth of July message was telling Americans to make sure they vote, but he didn&#8217;t make an explicit call for Congress to act.&nbsp;<br><br>So, is that tacit acknowledgment that he sees Congress, as it stands right now, unlikely to take any additional action?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Can you say the beginning part of your question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, in his Fourth of July message, he urged Americans to go to the polls and vote.&nbsp; But he didn&#8217;t specifically say Congress needs to act.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Act on?&nbsp; Is there something in particular?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Act on gun-control legislation.&nbsp; So, is that tacit acknowledgment that Congress, as it stands right now, cannot do that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, Congress did act on gun reform.&nbsp; There was a bipartisan bill that was passed.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he frustrated that it didn&#8217;t go far enough?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the President has been very clear that we need to go further on the gun reform, that he is pleased that there is a &#8212; that &#8212; that he was able to sign a bipartisan gun reform bill.&nbsp; And that has been the first time, again, in 30 years that we have seen that type of reform or any type of reform.&nbsp;<br><br>Do we need to do more?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; He has been very clear on that.<br><br>One of the things that I just mentioned a few moments ago was banning assault weapons.&nbsp; That is something that, as we saw yesterday, we saw an assault weapon was used in a horrific, horrific event yesterday in Highland Park.&nbsp; So that is something that he led on 30 years ago and he wants to continue to see &#8212; or see that happen &#8212; again, the banning of assault weapons.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is that something he believes this Congress can accomplish?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, we &#8212; this Congress was able to do a bipartisan gun reform legislation.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re going to continue to work with &#8212; work with members in Congress to see what else we can do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since those mass shootings, has he called any members of Congress?&nbsp; Has he planned to set up any meetings?&nbsp;<br><br>A mass shooting just happened.&nbsp; We’re just trying to understand what he&#8217;s done since then.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I mean, again, he &#8212; we saw a gun reform bipartisan legislation pass.&nbsp; He signed that into law, which was a first step.<br><br>Yesterday &#8212; this happened yesterday.&nbsp; You heard directly from the President in a statement.&nbsp; He spoke on this twice yesterday.&nbsp; We are always in constant communication with members of Congress on a slew of &#8212; a long list of issues that are important to the American public.<br><br>And so, we will continue to have those conversations.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it my turn now?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Just a &#8212; kind of a specific question.&nbsp; In a statement today, several prominent congressional Democrats criticized President Biden over his comments last week saying that he supports selling F-16 fighter jets to Turkey.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just curious if the White House has any response to that criticism, which came from several members of his own party.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Is it because after Erdoğan’s meeting that he had at NATO?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Is that what this is coming from?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve been very clear about this.&nbsp; The F-16 &#8212; that conversation about the F-16 and Turkey has been around for some time.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about this several months ago.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s really nothing new.&nbsp; The President has supported that effort.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s really nothing &#8212; nothing new to that.<br><br>Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Mid-East question and &#8212; I’m going to take this.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Mid-East question and also a Ukraine question.&nbsp; Let me start with the Mid-East.<br><br>A U.S. District Court judge has given the administration until August 1st to decide whether to grant immunity to the Crown Prince of Saudi Arabia in a civil lawsuit filed by his fiancée, obviously, in relation to his &#8212; to his death.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m just wondering if the President is willing or ready to weigh in on that, or if that&#8217;s going to happen during his trip, or if that&#8217;s something he&#8217;s going to discuss with the Saudis.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s a legal determination, so I cannot comment from here on that because it&#8217;s a legal determination.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Cool.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s move on to Ukraine then.&nbsp; Can I just get the White House&#8217;s assessment on these recent Russian territorial gains and whether that changes your approach?&nbsp;<br><br>And then also with the President of Ukraine calling for a swift end to this conflict by &#8212; by winter, is there a military solution to this conflict?&nbsp; And if not, what is the administration doing to reach a negotiated settlement?&nbsp; Could this happen at the G20?&nbsp; Who&#8217;s involved?&nbsp; Can you lay out any sort of roadmap?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as the President has said &#8212; to your last question, first &#8212; as the President has said many times: No conversation about Ukraine without Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>What we have been trying to do and have been doing for the past several months is to make sure that we put &#8212; with our assistance that we have been providing &#8212; make sure we put Ukraine in the most &#8212; in the most strongest kind of position so when there is that opportunity to do those negotiations, they&#8217;re able to do that.<br><br>But what we have seen from &#8212; from President Putin is he has &#8212; he is not in a place or has no desire to negotiate.&nbsp;<br><br>So, going to your first question now is: Our approach does not change.&nbsp; We are going to continue to support Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to help Ukraine fight for their democracy, fight for their territorial integrity.<br><br>And, you know &#8212; and then, to your second question, going to the second one &#8212; you know, we have said for months that the fighting in the Donbas, which is where I think you&#8217;re speaking about, could be prolonged and protracted.&nbsp; That is something that we have been saying for some time, and we would &#8212; we would see with gains and with losses on both sides.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing that today, as you just laid out.<br><br>But that doesn&#8217;t mean that the Russians have &#8212; have been able to achieve their goals, and that doesn&#8217;t mean that the Ukrainians have stopped fighting.&nbsp; They are &#8212; have &#8212; they have shown their bravery.&nbsp; They will continue to fight and &#8212; and fight for their democracy.<br><br>And so, we will continue to support Ukraine.&nbsp; We have given them the most amount of support than any other country as it relates to security assistance. &nbsp;And that is not going to &#8212; and that is not going to stop.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; I would like to ask you about the announcement that the President made in &#8212; at the G7 for the Global Partnership on Infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>But before that, I would like to know what&#8217;s the difference between President Trump watching TV, even pleading to go to the Capitol while &#8212; while the Capitol was being attacked, and President Biden going to the beach and having fun while Supreme Court justices are on the attack by a verbally violent mob?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the difference between those two leaders?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Wait, what&#8217;s the comparison you&#8217;re making?&nbsp; Could you say the first part?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I’m saying now: What’s the difference between President Trump not doing anything while the Capitol was being attacked and President Biden not doing anything when protesters &#8212; while the Supreme Court justices were under attack in their own homes with their families and with their children?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; there are two major differences here.&nbsp;<br><br>First of all, our predecessor was very &#8212; we have said that his behavior on that day, on January 6th, was atrocious.&nbsp; The President has said that.&nbsp; And we are going to let the Select Committee &#8212; the January 6 Select Committee continue to do their independent review of that &#8212; their hearing.&nbsp; And you guys all saw for yourselves, the American people saw &#8212; have seen for themselves what &#8212; what the &#8212; what our precede- &#8212; predecessor has done &#8212; his behavior and his involvement.&nbsp;<br><br>So that is not the same.&nbsp; That is absolutely not the same.&nbsp; We are talking about what we saw on January 6th.&nbsp; We are talking about an attack on our democracy.&nbsp; We are talking about a very dark day that the person who was here before us seemingly, if you watch, was very involved.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s very, very different.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, fast forward to &#8212; to this President.&nbsp; This President is fighting for women&#8217;s rights.&nbsp; He&#8217;s fighting for women&#8217;s freedom.&nbsp; He has spoken out.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been very clear about what needs to happen next.&nbsp; He put out two executive authorities that lays out ways that we can protect women.&nbsp; He has &#8212; he has said that he&#8217;s go- &#8212; everything is on the table.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to see what else we can do.&nbsp;<br><br>But he also has spoken very truthfully and very honestly with the American people, which is: If we want to see Roe become the law of the land, we also have to act.&nbsp; We have to hold Congress accountable and make sure that they act and that that cannot happen.&nbsp; Then Americans need to go to the ballot box. &nbsp;And that is &#8212; that is very different.&nbsp;<br><br>And to say &#8212; and to say that there is no difference, that is &#8212; that is just unbelievably wrong.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is it a concern that a Supreme Court justice may be harmed (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m moving on.&nbsp; I&#8217;m moving on.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Phil.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, hold on.&nbsp; Go ahead, Phil, and then I’ll come &#8212; I’ll come back to you, Ed.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I got a policy question about some of the oil that was released from the Strategic National Petroleum Reserve, but first a follow-up.&nbsp;<br><br>We have all heard it.&nbsp; The President likes to say “I will always level with you.”&nbsp; He says that again and again.&nbsp; Moments ago, though, you seemed to dismiss Peter’s question about his conversation with his son, Hunter Biden, with regards to his business dealings, and I&#8217;m wondering: How is that silence consistent with the President&#8217;s promise to always level with the American public?&nbsp;<br><br>Because, you know, in public, he says he hasn&#8217;t discussed these business dealings.&nbsp; And then, at least according to the voicemail that&#8217;s been obtained by the Daily Mail and the Washington Examiner, it certainly seems like he was seeking to do exactly that &#8212; have a conversation about these business dealings.&nbsp; Is he leveling with the American public on this?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Phil, I hear your question, but what I can tell you from here, standing at this podium, is that I cannot comment on any materials from the laptop.&nbsp; And I would refer you to the representatives of Hunter Biden.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I can share with you at this podium, at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then there&#8217;s a Reuters report out this morning that says that more than 5 million barrels of oil that were released from the emergency oil reserves were exported to Europe and Asia last month, and some of it, reportedly, was actually heading to China.&nbsp; Is the administration aware of those reports?&nbsp; And does the President mind that some of this oil that was meant to ease paying for consumers is headed overseas?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I have not seen that report, so I would honestly have to go look into it and see what &#8212; what the truth is in that &#8212; in that statement that you just laid out and see exactly what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; I &#8212; I just have not seen that report.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Ed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, so &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, and then &#8212; I’m so sorry &#8212; and then Ebony.&nbsp; I’m so sorry, I was supposed to go to Ebony.&nbsp; But you go quickly, and then we&#8217;ll go to Ebony.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, the Atlanta Fed GDPNow tracker is showing that the second quarter &#8212; it&#8217;s estimating second quarter is negative growth &#8212; 2.1 percent.&nbsp; Should that hold &#8212; the U.S. has been in recession for the first half of this year.&nbsp; Does the President believe that we are in a recession, first of all?&nbsp; Second of all, if that does hold, does the President accept responsibility for his policies as part of that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, first, do we believe we&#8217;re in a recession?&nbsp; No.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s my answer to you on that.</p>



<p>So, there is a nonpartisan data that came out recently &#8212; the National Bureau of Economic Research, which I&#8217;m sure you know, very well, Ed.&nbsp; It determines and defines recession.&nbsp; And so let me just quote here for a second.&nbsp; “In recent decades, the two measures we have put the most weight on are real personal income less transfer and nonfarm payroll employment.”&nbsp; So that is from the nonpartisan National Bureau of Economics Research, again, determines the definition of recession.<br><br>So here are the facts.&nbsp; The facts are this: We&#8217;ve averaged more than 400,000 jobs every month for the past &#8212; over the last &#8212; I should say, over the last month &#8212; three months.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve held steady &#8212; that 3.6 unemployment rate.&nbsp; Consumer spending remains strong and above pre-pandemic trends.&nbsp; Business invest- &#8212; investment remains strong, and household balance sheets remain strong.</p>



<p>So we do not believe that we are in a recession, and we have a nonpartisan entity to speak to that more directly and more specifically.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more quick one.&nbsp; At the G7, there is video of the French president running up to President Biden and relaying a message, saying that the Saudis are about at capacity through the UAE.&nbsp; Did President Biden ask the French to ask the Saudis to pump more oil through the UAE?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I did not hear this conversation, so I can&#8217;t speak to that conversation either.&nbsp;<br><br>But what I can say is, as we know, the early week of Jan- &#8212; of June, the OPEC+ announced that they were going to increase their capacity for July and August by 50 percent.</p>



<p>So I will &#8212; I will leave that there.&nbsp; And I think that says a lot about where they are with their capacity.&nbsp; And, of course, we welcome that.&nbsp; And &#8212; but &#8212; but, again, I&#8217;ll &#8212; I’ll leave it to OPEC+ to speak to that.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Ebony.&nbsp; I know I promised &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; you a question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two quick questions &#8212; one on gun reform.&nbsp; Is there anything or any consideration that the administration can do when it comes to regulating military-style ammunition, whether that be in production?&nbsp; Is there anything that the Fed can do to move in that capacity?&nbsp; Since you&#8217;re not getting anywhere with &#8212; on guns, what about ammunition?&nbsp; Any talks?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we believe that the best way to really have a comprehensive gun reform is through legislation, is to work with Congress as it comes through the federal level.&nbsp; The President has done the most executive action than any president at this time in their administration.&nbsp;<br><br>And so now what we are going to continue to do and &#8212; and continue to focus on is to &#8212; is to work with Congress to do more.&nbsp; And one of the things that I&#8217;ve just been pointing out is the banning of assault weapons, which we believe is incredibly important, as the President led on this issue back in 1994.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to &#8212; tha- &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The second question, really quickly.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Senate recesses in August.&nbsp; A lot of the President&#8217;s efforts on criminal justice basically have stalled, but I want to ask about the EQUAL Act legislation to end the disparity between crack and powder cocaine.&nbsp; The House passed a bill last September &#8212; overwhelming bipartisan support.&nbsp; Is the President leaning in at all on lawmakers to send &#8212; to get this bill to him?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I have to talk to our Office of Leg Affairs on that.&nbsp; I do not know where that &#8212; that legislation is currently.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if it went over to the Senate.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know in what &#8212; in what &#8212; where the mechanics are on that.&nbsp; But happy to take that question to you in the back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, one more &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, we got to go, guys.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be back &#8212; well, hopefully we&#8217;ll see you in Ohio tomorrow.<br><br>4:21 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
